Previously on Evangelion
New Theatrical Edition
Previously on Evangelion...
Evangelion New Theatrical Edition:
Opening
Mankind’s ultimate multi-purpose
humanoid decisive battle weapon...
The artificial human: Evangelion.
Ikari Shinji-kun,
you will be its pilot.
Launch the Eva.
There’s no way I can do that!
Stop wasting time.
If you aren’t going to pilot, leave!
I mustn’t run away.
I mustn’t run away. I mustn’t run away.
I mustn’t run away!
I’ll pilot it.
The Eva can beat an Angel.
CLASSIFIED
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT
INTERIM REPORT #27
Our future depends on
defeating the Angels.
Fifteen years ago, half of humanity died
in the Second Impact.
If the Angels set off a Third Impact now,
humanity will die out.
Why am I even here?
Don’t you have faith in
the work your father does?
Piloting the Eva is all I have, right?
It’s the only reason Dad sent for me.
That’s why I have to be the pilot.
You need to decide whether
you want to be an Eva pilot.
I’ll do it... I’ll pilot the Eva again.
You won’t die. I will protect you.
He didn’t run from piloting the Eva.
We should leave it to him
unless he wants out.
Countin’ on ya.
Do your best.
Goodbye.
I don’t have anything else.
Ayanami!
I don’t know how I should act
at times like this.
Smiling would be a start.
Children burdened by fate...
Evangelion New Theatrical Edition:
Break
Captain Shikinami Asuka Langley,
the pilot in charge of Unit-02.
Are you stupid?
I guess some people
enjoy being Eva pilots.
You don’t feel comfortable
around your dad.
He praised me for the first time.
Good work, Shinji.
Hearing that made me so happy.
This Human Instrumentality Project...
What’s NERV really planning?
Protect Katsuragi for me.
Being with Ikari-kun
makes me feel warm and fuzzy.
You’re in love,
that’s what that means!
You’re pretty interesting.
You can be happy without the Eva.
My “target”?
Asuka’s in there, Dad!
That is an Angel. Our enemy.
Stop!
It’s all Dad’s fault!
Running away again?
What’s wrong with
running away from pain?!
I never want to pilot an Eva again.
You’ll never have any fun
if you keep cowering at everything.
I’ll make it so Ikari-kun
never has to pilot the Eva again!
I’m the pilot of
Evangelion Unit-01, Ikari Shinji!
Give Ayanami...
...back to me!
Do it, Shinji-kun!
For the sake of your wish!
Even if I’m gone, I can be replaced.
Ayanami! Come here!
I’m sorry. I couldn’t do anything.
That’s okay. It’s okay...
It’s the continuation
of the Second Impact.
The Third Impact is starting!
The time has come.
The world is ending.
Evangelion New Theatrical Edition:
Q
Ikari Shinji-kun.
I want you doing nothing.
Shouldn’t I be piloting?!
This is crazy, Misato-san!
How am I supposed to take this in
all of a sudden?
Because it’s been fourteen years.
We’re WILLE, an organization
dedicated to the destruction of NERV!
I’m Kaworu. Nagisa Kaworu.
Like you, I’m another
child burdened by fate.
Evangelion Unit-13.
When the time comes,
you’re to pilot the Eva with him.
Please don’t go pilotin’
no more Evas!
Rei doesn’t exist anymore, Shinji-kun.
You’re lying!
Eva Unit-01 awakened
and opened the Doors of Guf,
acting as the trigger
to the Third Impact.
You were the cause of it all.
I saved you back then, right?!
I don’t know.
Let’s begin, Fuyutsuki.
Bratty Shinji! Are you trying to
cause the Third Impact again?!
I’ll take those spears for you,
Kaworu-kun... For everyone...
And then the world
will go back to normal!
And then even Misato-san
will have to...
Misato! Activate the DSS choker!
Don’t do this, Shinji-kun.
Stop it, you stupid brat!
What the hell’s going on...?
The Fourth Impact.
This is its opening rite.
Is it my fault...?
Because I pulled out the spears?
I was ordered to.
Don’t make that face.
We’ll meet again, Shinji-kun.
Kaworu-kun!
Nothing good ever happens!
You’re such a brat...
There is no unforgivable sin.
There is always hope.
No matter the circumstances.
The world is a long slope...
But it’s not about the length of your life...
If you’ve lived on the path of truth...
It doesn’t matter if it’s short, it doesn’t matter!
Paris Assault Fleet: fully operational.
Descending at 0-Point of former city.
All ships, assume defensive posture.
Slowly to stern.
Tambourine-rine-rine, tambourine...
Gravity restraint, autonomous movement,
remote control, all clear.
Tambourine-rine-rine, tambourine...
Skies over Paris clear in all directions.
Ground surface coreization status: Category 6.
Let’s ring the bell, the bell of love...
Confirming ship spatial coordinates.
Arrived at designated
operation start point.
Roger. All ships, assume on-alert
mode formation.
Tambourine-rine-rine, tambourine...
Let’s walk cheerfully...
All ships, switching formation
to screening positions.
Tambourine, tambourine, tambourine...
Eva Unit-08 and DSRV,
descending towards target point.
Tambourine, tambourine, tambourine...
Tambourine!
Landing absorption system:
no faults.
Hull fixed into place successfully.
The DSRV has landed.
Analyzing atmospheric composition.
Oxygen density is at -3 points.
Love, the two of us...
Carbon dioxide at tolerable level.
We’re clear to land.
Flowers, the two of us...
Roger. Begin the operation.
Romance, the two of us...
Dreams, the two of us...
Sixteen years since I last visited Paris...
The world exists for the two of us...
To see a city once hailed
as a Capital of Flowers like this...
It breaks my heart.
The world exists for the two of us...
L-Containment Field density
is greater than I anticipated.
We have 720 seconds for the Euro NERV
Containment Pillar No. 1 restoration, starting now.
Looking up at the sky with you...
Walking down the road with you...
What the hell? That’s 180 seconds
shorter than we planned, right?
Maybe they’re factoring in
the return time...
Gazing at the sea with you...
But anyway, I wish only the Eva pilots
had to wear these embarrassing suits!
Climbing the hills with you...
You’ll live.
Less talking, more working.
The world exists for the two of us...
So? Can we get
the Anti-L System running?
Yes, ma’am.
It should be possible to reboot in Stage 4.
The world exists for the two of us...
All thanks to our predecessors.
I leave it in your hands
We’ll carry on your wish
to preserve this city.
All right, let’s get to work.
I knew it, here they come!
Eva 44A, customized aerial types,
approaching from four o’clock!
An impressive single-line formation...
They’re practically a whole new organism now,
formed into a swarm like that.
Mari, I’ll need you to intercept.
Buy us another 560 seconds.
Loud and clear, ma’am!
I’ll do the honors of
handling all those 44As!
Okay, my dear Nagaracchi!
Take care of the cables!
Okey-dokey, now...
Yaw, roll, pitch...
It’s neat and all, but this setup’s
not the most comfortable.
Wish they at least kept
humanoid points of articulation, meow!
Unit-08, currently engaging
first wave of 44As.
Detected a second wave incoming.
All 44As are sticking to Unit-08, as planned.
Maximum operational time:
420 seconds.
Taking a while, isn’t it, Chief?
It’s like working with an 8-bit microcomputer...
It’s a foreign and unexplored system,
much like the Evas.
Not something easily controlled
via human language.
Stage 4 clear.
We’re way behind schedule...
Keep working. Don’t panic.
Yes, ma’am!
Maintain speed. +20 on guide rig.
Hold the leveler as is.
Keep her steady!
Don’t even think about it!
Uh-oh.
The fourth wave, huh?
They’ve got me outnumbered.
It’s just as they say...
“Many a small bird
drive away a hawk”, right?
Operational time remaining:
360 seconds!
We can’t do it!
I can’t find a shortcut to Stage 5!
Don’t give me that.
You’re not searching hard enough!
It’s just not possible!
We don’t have enough time to finish the overwrite!
Don’t give me that, either!
Add more bypasses!
But Chief...
We just don’t have long enough.
Quit whining!
I swear, you boys are so...
How do ya like that?!
Heave-ho!
And don’t show
your stupid faces here ever again, dorks!
Woo-hoo. Piece of cake.
My, my...
The pseudo-Angels are using decoys?
They’ve got some nerve.
Heads up! Boss battle incoming!
Military use of Evas like this
constitutes a violation of the Vatican Treaty...
A land-only 4444C
equipped with a positron rifle,
accompanied by specialized 44Bs
with an attached power supply...
Vice Commander Fuyutsuki
is certainly testing us.
Increasingly high energy readings
coming from the 44Bs!
All ships, shift to ground-to-ground
defense measures!
All personnel, begin anti-shock
and anti-EM protection!
The 4444C is in firing position!
44Bs generating massive surge of power.
Brave as the bravest
Great as the greatest
Energy being transferred to
ultra-high voltage system!
Strong as the strongest
Hard as the hardest
Entire 4444C power supply
system now online!
No lack of courage
No rack and ruin
No room for pity
Positron acceleration system
is in its final stage!
No disillusion
Brave as the bravest
Breech is locked!
Great as the greatest
Strong as the strongest
Hard as the hardest
Incoming!
No lack of courage
No rack and ruin
No room for pity
No disillusion
And she slides into base!
Holy crap... We’re totally screwed
if it shoots us again.
High energy readings coming
from the 44Bs again!
In the process of storing energy
in the high-power emission device!
Already?! 4444C, initiating acceleration!
Ready to fire immediately!
Real bad news!
Brave as the bravest
Second shot imminent!
Great as the greatest
This is literally the worst!
Strong as the strongest
Hard as the hardest
No lack of courage
No rack and ruin
Nagaracchi!
Create a diversion, please and thanks!
No room for pity
No disillusion
Roger.
Brave as the bravest
Great as the greatest
Strong as the strongest
Hard as the hardest
No lack of courage
No rack and ruin
No room for pity
No disillusion
This is nothing!
Excusez-moi, Eiffel!
No further reaction
from the 4444C detected.
Operational time:
thirty seconds remaining!
Algorithm analysis, switching to C.
Releasing final security lock.
Anti-L System, Stage 5, all clear!
Activating it now, Vice Captain, ma’am!
Restoring former Paris city area.
All frozen Euro NERV systems
are being reactivated, too.
Coming back online.
Fantastic work, Maya.
That was quite the close shave.
Assault successful.
Misato, if you could collect the cargo.
Roger. We’re descending to
the supply point now.
All personnel, prepare for resupply.
Priority One on spare parts for Eva units,
weaponry, and munitions.
Lower all supply management vessels.
Aircraft carriers go first. Hurry!
Scavenge for every single part
we’ll need to rebuild Unit-02!
And so, the end crowns the work.
With this, we’ll be able to build
the new combined-type Unit-02,
and have Unit-08 remodeled
for overlapping compatibility, meow.
Wherever you’re at,
I’ll come for you.
Just you wait for me, Pup.
Gutless coward.
Sorry I’m late.
You okay, Ikari?
Hey! The dog’s not supposed
to go in there.
Oh, ya came to?
Recognize me, don’t ya? It’s me.
Y’know, Touji! Suzuhara Touji!
Been a real long time, Shinji.
I couldn’t believe my eyes
when they brought ya in.
Heard a bit about what you’ve been through,
but I can’t say I understood much of it...
But you’re doin’ okay, that’s the main thing.
How’s it goin’? Can you move yet?
I think we’re good to go.
How about we go to my place?
You gotta be starvin’.
It’s a little on the cold side out there.
Doctor, that girl didn’t seem
to want to get changed.
Well, guess she’s fine the way she is.
We’re almost out of Tamiflu, by the way.
Got it. I’ll talk to the rations manager.
KEEP CLOSED
Hate to do this to ya,
but I’m gonna call it a day.
Okay, let’s get going.
What a strange place.
There are so many people...
What, this your first time
seein’ a crowd?
This’s one of the settlements
that people from all over came to...
Village 3.
‘Bout a thousand people livin’ here.
That over there’s the supply station.
They hand out food three times a week.
Good afternoon, Doctor.
Oh, Matsukata-san! You look about due.
Make sure you’re takin’ it easy.
Are these kids the ones
KREDIT asked you to look after, Doctor?
Yeah... Somethin’ like that.
Treat ‘em good, all right?
Of course.
Well then, if you’ll excuse me.
See ya.
What is “KREDIT”?
KREDIT’s the name of
a support organization WILLE created.
Not only do they supply for us,
they also help us trade between different villages.
Our village couldn’t survive
on its own, y’know.
What is that?
It’s shaped differently to a dog.
Hmm? Oh, that’s a cat!
A cat?
Never seen one before?
There’s about ten of ‘em
living under the train cars.
The dogs and cats here
really liven up the place.
In case of emergency, ring buzzer on right
CALL
BUTTON
This here’s our house.
It’s old, but it’s nice.
Real luxury,
livin’ in a single family home.
We’re home!
I’ll have dinner ready in a sec.
Hup...
Sorry I kept y’all waiting.
Eat up while it’s still hot!
You’ve gotta be hungry, Shinji.
Better have a little, at least.
Okay, that’s fine. Whenever you feel like
eating again, you’re welcome to join us.
All right, let’s eat!
Let’s eat!
What do you think? Tasty, right?
It feels strange in my mouth.
It makes me feel warm and fuzzy...
Yeah! That’s what “tasty” is.
My girl sure knows
how to prepare a meal.
For real. She’s the best wife
in the whole world.
You’re in for a shock
when you meet her!
I’m home! I’m sorry it’s so late.
Oh! Welcome home!
We’ve been waiting for you!
Shinji, you remember her, right?
My wife?
She was our Class Prez.
I couldn’t believe my ears
when I got the call.
And I still feel like I’m dreaming,
seeing you here.
It’s been so long, Ikari-kun!
And you too, Ayanami-san!
No, I’m not Ayanami.
What, you’re not? Well, then...
“Ms. Lookalike”, it is!
She’ll be “Ms. Lookalike”, then!
What is this?
Oh, that’s our daughter, Tsubame.
Cute, ain’t she?
It’s a human, but it’s so small.
Why did you shrink it?
Huh, you’ve never seen a baby, either?
She was even smaller
when she was first born.
Babies grow up real fast.
Is this... “cute”?
Yup! Cute, ain’t she?
She is our daughter, after all!
Oh, dear! I’m sorry.
Did he scare you when he got all loud?
Sorry, Tsubame! Did I make ya cry?
Oh, here comes the General.
Sorry I’m late.
Seriously, it’s a real miracle
seein’ ya again.
What are you doing?
Gonna lighten the mood with
a gentle little song.
Babies need to drink
their mother’s milk to grow.
The sun will rise in the morning...
So you don’t have to stay up...
It’s time to wake up...
You’re not ready to do that
just yet, Ms. Lookalike.
So let’s go somewhere...
I don’t understand.
What would Ayanami Rei do?
To bid farewell to what we’re taught...
You said you weren’t
Ayanami-san, didn’t you?
To feel close to something unreachable...
So don’t worry about that.
You should follow your heart.
Go beyond there, go beyond it...
I’m allowed to be different?
Don’t talk about... Don’t talk about life yet!
It’s been a while, Ikari.
It’s me, Aida. Aida Kensuke.
Okay!
Right, Kensuke here’s
the one who saved ya.
Couldn’t even count the times
this big ol’ survival nerd helped us out.
We’d have ended up dead in the gutter
a long time ago if it wasn’t for him.
Shinji-kun! Not speaking is one thing,
but eat the food you’ve been served!
Where’s your manners?!
Hey, Pops, it’s fine.
I shouldn’t have forced him to eat with us.
Don’t be too rough on him today.
But Touji-kun...
He has the gall to sit there after we offer him
invaluable food, and not have even one bite!
You listening, Shinji-kun?!
Dad, you’re going to wake Tsubame up!
Now, let’s clean things up
and roll out the futons.
Dear, grab a couple for
Ikari-kun and Ms. Lookalike, too.
Nah, I’m gonna look after Ikari.
I think that’s for the best.
Pretty unexpected, huh?
Touji and the Prez getting married, I mean.
They used to fight so much
back when we were in school.
Well, all the hard times they went through
after the Near Third Impact brought them together.
See, Ikari? It wasn’t just bad things
that came out of the Near Third.
Since the beginning of time from the dark
There emerged one true light
we would hail as the prettiest star
with a reverence that we endure
It’s just after this hill, Ikari.
That we use as a spiritual guide for all time
And here we are.
I refitted this abandoned
train station into a house.
Make yourself at home.
With a glow in a halo of trust
Bathroom’s at the back of that car.
You go inside, I’ll get some fuel.
We exalt in its shadow
We harbor all fear
Hmph.
You’re getting to see me naked.
You could at least try and get a little flustered.
Jeez. I can’t believe Ken-Ken
picked this annoying jerk up.
I’m back.
Oh, she’s my other guest.
She’ll probably be staying for a while.
Shikinami can’t show up at the village
for a couple reasons.
It’s not that serious... It’s just a pain.
Too many Lilin hanging around.
Guess it takes the DSS Choker
to get a reaction out of you.
Ken-Ken, you’re being too easy on him.
Let him clean up his own mess.
He’s not eating right now.
He can’t do anything by himself, either.
Must’ve had a really
traumatic experience.
How’s he any different from normal?
He shuts himself off
and ignores everybody.
Same old, same old for him, y’know.
Just leave him. He doesn’t want to live,
but he doesn’t want to die, either.
Ikari, you’re okay for now.
Us reuniting has got to be fate.
You can count on me.
I’m your friend, right?
I’m happy you’re still alive, Ikari.
Hey, Rations Manager,
no need to get worked up over all this...
Thanks for always working so hard.
Good night, dear.
What is “good night”?
Well... It’s a gesture where you
wish a peaceful night’s sleep on each other.
Good night, Ms. Lookalike.
Ugh... I’m sick of pretending to sleep.
Wonder if I’ll ever sleep again...
Yearning for your love
Good morning.
What is “good morning”?
Yearning for your love
Well... It’s a gesture where you
wish for another happy day together.
Good morning, Ms. Lookalike.
Ken-Ken wakes up at 6 every day.
He’s already gone to work.
Every time I see your eyes they draw me in
Your breakfast’s over there.
Hurry up and eat already!
I can feel you getting underneath my skin
Those’re some real tight-fitting
clothes you’ve got on there, girlie.
When you're not around the hours feel like days
This is Ms. Lookalike.
Doc’s wife sent her here.
She’ll be working with us.
Ms. Lookalike?
Well, there’s a name with baggage.
I can't wait until you take my breath away
You sure she’ll be right to join us?
Cos I'm yearning for your love
I’ll take anyone who can work.
“Work”? Is that my order?
All of the time
It’s not an “order”. It’s just a job.
What is a “job”?
Yeah I'm yearning for your love
Gotta say, that’s a good question!
Never really thought about it.
Well, I guess it’s
when all of us sweat together.
All of the time
“Sweat”.
I want your love!!
Use three fingers, nice and gently.
Good, like you’re pushing it in
straight and deep.
Don’t squeeze it, just hold it gently.
Aw, you’ll get the hang of it eventually.
Every time I see your eyes they draw me in
I can feel you getting underneath my skin
C’mon, slowpoke! Your tempo’s all off.
Keep up with us.
When you're not around the hours feel like days
Right.
I can't wait until you take my breath away
Is this “sweat”?
Cos I'm yearning for your love
All of the time
Is this a “job”?
Oh yeah I'm yearning for your love
Oh, dear! Those poor seedlings...
Never you mind. Here, give me your hand.
All of the time
I want your love!!
Good work, all.
Managed to meet our daily quota again.
Here. A special treat, ‘cause you
worked so hard on your first day.
How should I respond
in a moment like this?
“Thank you”.
Thank you.
Right, y’all. Let’s head to the baths.
What is a “bath”?
Memorial Bathhouse
Women's
SCHEDULE
TEAM 48: 5 PM
TEAM 49: 6 PM
TEAM 50: 7 PM
TEAM 46: 8 PM
REBIRTH BATHS
So this is a “bath”.
Your clothes are gonna make it tricky, girl.
The bath is strange. This is different to LCL.
It feels warm and fuzzy.
I have no orders, but I am alive.
Why?
Trying to make us
feel sorry for you, huh?
Lying in that corner
and refusing to talk.
HAND SWITCHES
TERMINAL BLOCKS
POWER CABLES
I can’t sweep with you there.
God you’re...
...annoying.
Aww, you’re not Mommy...
Welcome home, Ms. Lookalike.
Thank you for the hard work.
Sorry I’m late.
Yay! Mommy!
Have you been a good girl?
DOCTOR'S
OFFICE
Yup!
Thanks again, Hikari.
Don’t mention it.
We’re here to help each other.
Right, let’s go home.
Yup! Goodbye!
Yeah, goodbye.
What is “goodbye”?
Well... It’s a gesture for telling someone
we want to see them again.
Come on!
Okay.
Let’s play a game when we get home!
What are they doing?
Well, that’s a gesture for when
we want to bond with someone.
Ugh, I’ve had it with this.
Y’know... You’re a real load
for us to deal with.
Puking again?
Damn brat! You should be thankful
you get fed in the first place!
You’re still a pseudo-Lilin!
You need food to live!
So get it down already!
All I get is water!
Better savor this shitty food
before your body decides to stop growing!
Stupid brat!
You’re not doing anything ‘cause you’re too scared
of getting hurt again, aren’t you?!
If you’ve got so much
free time on your hands,
why don’t you at least think about
why I tried to punch your face in before?!
Your willpower is pitiful.
Everything you do backfires anyway,
and there’s no fixing it.
You just don’t want to do anything anymore
‘cause all this is your fault, is that it?
I know your dad told you to do it,
but with you having absolutely zero resolve...
...it’d be better
if you never piloted that Eva.
Have fun with your pity party, brat.
I’m back.
Oh, where’s Ikari?
Ran away.
That so? It might be best to
leave him alone for now.
Where’d he run off to?
The ruins by the lake up north.
Where the NERV facilities used to be...
Maybe that’s fate, too.
Where are the rations?
Forced them down his throat.
Should be okay for a while.
Thanks, Shikinami.
Meh. I’m not doing it for him.
I just can’t let him die before
he pulls his head out of his ass.
My name?
Yeah, we can’t keep on calling you
“Ms. Lookalike” forever, you know.
The doc tells us
you forgot your real name,
so why not just
give yourself a new one?
Give myself a name...
Is that allowed?
Library
Books...
AYA
NAMI
Ikari-kun mentioned these...
SUGAR
RUNE
I’m returning this to its owner.
Thank you.
Want it?
Ochibi-san and
the Porcupine
Art & Story: Anno Moyoco
Thank you.
I’m alone.
Always have been, always will be.
Totally alone.
And that’s just how things are, Asuka.
Who’s there?
It’s me.
Original Batch?
I’ll unlock the door.
I was told Ikari-kun was here.
Not here.
Currently mid-runaway.
I see. I’ll go look for him, then.
Got some news for you.
Us pilots and the Evas are the same—they gave us restraints
at design time, so we can’t transcend human limits.
See, the inefficient emotions
we’ve got...
They’re ‘cause we’re designed
to comply with human cognitive behavior.
You Ayanami Series were calibrated
to take a liking to the Third Boy.
The things you’re feeling now
were engineered by NERV from the start.
I see. But that’s okay.
I’m happy like this.
Fine. Suit yourself, then.
The object of your affection is at the N109 tower,
at the ruins of NERV’s 2nd Branch.
Thank you.
If you’re going, bring his rations with you.
He must be running out of fuel by now.
Do you not go out and work
even though you live in this village?
Are you stupid?
This isn’t my home.
It’s the place I keep safe.
Ikari-kun.
I’ve been taught to
return things to their owner.
I’ll come again.
The road I must take leads me into mystery
I'm lost in a daze, don't know if I've been there before
My future fair is fate
I can only take a little courage and conviction of my thoughts
If I will ever see it through
Such is the hand of fate
Have I ever been here before?
Is it better that I don't know?
Have I anything left but fate?
Can I trust in my destiny?
Is it out of my hands to see?
Must I live by the hand of fate?
Is it playing a trick on me?
Is it making me thing I'm gonna be somewhere in the past with love that
I thought was gone for good?
It's just that I'll never see the day if you're another world away
Then I will never see the day if you're a million miles away
Who holds all the aces in the hand of fate?
Is it fine to just leave Shinji on his own?
Kinda think it’s dangerous...
Let’s leave him be for now.
He needs time to himself.
But, Kensuke...
You’re bein’ kinda cold to him,
don’tcha think?
Worrying too much
isn’t gonna help either of us.
He’ll come back. Just have faith in him.
Guess you’re right.
Hoping he’ll be able to settle
in the village soon.
Why don’t you come back
to the village, Ikari-kun?
You aren’t doing anything here, either.
Do you keep the village safe, too?
I’m not keeping anything safe.
I destroyed everything!
I don’t wanna do anything! I don’t wanna talk!
Everybody needs to stay away!
I just...
...want you to leave me be!
Why are you all so nice to me?
Because we like you, Ikari-kun.
Thank you for talking to me.
This is a gesture for when
we want to bond with someone.
All done with your runaway?
Original Batch’s doing?
Yeah.
Feeling refreshed now that
you’ve shed all your tears?
Yeah.
Right.
Now that you can move again,
go help Ken-Ken.
Nice to hit the road every now and then, eh?
To take your mind off things.
Our chief industry is agricultural labor,
but I don’t have to participate since I do a lot of other handiwork.
Today’s main job will be to check
the outer infrastructure and environment.
It’ll be a busy day.
Mind you, the infrastructure’s basically
at the end of its life. It doesn’t really work anymore.
It’s too hard to repair,
so we leave it alone.
We only use branches that have fallen off
or that we had to prune.
Wanna take good care of
what’s left of the woods.
Village 3’s livelihood depends on the water here,
so checking on the water level’s vital.
It’s a matter of survival for us.
Quite literally the water of life.
I’ll go check the spring up ahead.
The trek’s too tough for you,
so I’ll have you do some work here.
Here, take this and
help secure some food.
I won’t be of any use.
I’ve never done this before. I can’t do it.
It’ll be fine. You’ll never
know if you don’t try.
Eh, don’t sweat it.
Our quota’s one fish per week.
There’s always next time.
That’s WILLE’s parting gift.
A “Complementarity L-Containment Field
Purification-Invalidation Interference Unit”.
Thanks to that thing,
Village 3 has avoided coreization.
We owe Misato-san and her team.
They’ve been showing up lately.
We call them “Wanderers”.
Headless Evas that had been buried for ages
suddenly just started moving around.
We’re monitoring them today.
The containment pillars are keeping them away,
like we thought they would.
They work against the Wanderers, too.
There’s jobs even a handyman like me can’t do.
If that thing stops working, that’ll be it for us.
As you can see, there’s no telling
how long this place will last.
But we’re going to struggle on
and live until the very end.
Those are pickled plums.
My husband looks forward to
eating them every year.
Life is a continuous cycle
of tough times and good times.
There’s nothing wrong with every day feeling the same.
Isn’t that how it should be?
I’m the youngest I’ll ever be right now,
so I want to live life to the fullest.
Plus, I have Tsubame.
She’s sure taken a liking to you!
More than she did with me!
You should live here
with us forever, Ms. Lookalike.
My name?
Yeah, decided on one yet?
No, I still haven’t thought of one.
Well, ask someone to
pick one for you, then.
Your name?
Yes. I want you to give me a name.
I want to stay here.
I need a name to do that.
So I want you to give me one.
You want a name...
But you’re not Ayanami...
Any name will do.
I want to become the name you give me.
Is Original Batch functioning all right?
Yeah. She came to see me again today. Why?
I see. That’s fine, then.
the big chestnut turned around
Then, all of a sudden
and ran off.
Ochibi-san chased
after it.
"Hey! Hey!
Wait for me!"
I see. I can’t live away from NERV.
TODAY
NUTRITION SUPPLY STATION
SCHEDULED
HAND OUT
STARTING
TIME
So, Shinji, gotten used to livin’ here?
Yeah, a little.
That’s nice to hear.
This village was just
a ragtag buncha strangers,
but after all was said and done,
we managed to make it work.
Was it hard at the beginning?
Yeah, well...
A whole lotta stuff happened.
Definitely wasn’t the kinda world
clueless kids could survive in.
We had to grow up real fast and
learn to do everything ourselves.
I’ve done things for my family
I don’t even wanna admit.
Couldn’t afford to be idealistic
if I wanted to survive.
I’m not a real doctor
or anything respectable like that.
I’m only playin’ dress-up.
Just a self-taught helper.
I only scrape by thanks to
the medical equipment KREDIT’s provided.
You are respectable, Touji.
You’re saving people’s lives.
There’s lives I can’t save, too.
But I keep on going, since toughin’ out
all the grief and anger is part of the job, I think.
I’ve gotta pay for my mistakes.
Take responsibility, I mean.
That’s what I’m tryin’ to live by.
Shinji, you’ve done more than enough
fightin’ for us already.
Ya oughta just stay here
and live with us from now on.
That’s what I think.
Thanks for coming with me
this early in the morning.
My father survived Near Third.
HERE
LIES
AIDA
HAJIME
Never even crossed my mind at the time
that he’d die in an accident, just like that.
If I knew this would happen, I’d have really talked with him,
drank with him, listened to his grumbling.
Your father’s still alive, right?
It might sound like a waste of time, but you should
try talking with him. You’ll regret it if you don’t.
That’d be way too much for this guy.
This is Ikari Gendou we’re talking about.
But they’re father and son.
That bond always remains.
I heard old Matsukata had a real hard time
during labor, but she pulled through.
All distribution operations for daily necessities
in the Nishinaka district have ended this afternoon.
So glad the baby was born healthy.
Her husband was a complete mess.
Tomorrow morning, rationing for the Sukeda district
will take place in the General Distribution Center, as scheduled.
Will you look at that?
You do know how to smile.
Yeah, you’re pretty cute.
Really. You have the loveliest figure, too.
Why not try on other clothes sometime?
Yes... I’ll try wearing
something different.
Hey, how about trying this one on today?
Children's clothes
Summer
Now, doesn’t that look great?
You really are cute.
You should marry my boy.
Is this... “blushing”?
How cute!
Is this... “embarrassment”?
Sorry about this. I know it’s stuffy,
but you’ve gotta wear it while we’re here.
Since I take all kinds of work,
I also liaison with KREDIT.
The L-Containment Field is relatively weak out here,
so they’re working on restoration experiments.
This is KREDIT’s outdoor lab.
There’s a guy on the staff
I’d like you to meet, actually.
Aida-sensei!
It’s been too long, sir.
Is this your new assistant?
Yeah, something like that.
I’ve never met an outsider before.
I’m Kaji. Kaji Ryouji.
What’s your name?
What’d you think? Nice guy, isn’t he?
Yeah...
But that name... Kaji...
Yeah. He’s Misato-san and Kaji-san’s son.
He’ll be fourteen soon.
He doesn’t know his parents.
That was what Misato-san wanted.
She felt like she couldn’t be
much of a mother to him,
so she decided she’d protect him as the head of WILLE
rather than involve herself in his life.
Um... And Kaji-san...?
He passed away.
Someone had to make the sacrifice
in order to stop the Third Impact.
Kaji-san decided he’d be the one.
Misato-san let him go.
She’s always regretted making you
bear all the responsibility, Ikari.
She feels it should have been her.
Couldn’t that be why she doesn’t
want to let you pilot the Eva?
Ikari...
You’re not the only one who’s hurting.
Misato-san is in pain, too.
The scent of the earth...
Kaji-san...
The Wunder’s coming to pick you up tomorrow.
Negotiated your return route.
The records of the village
Misato-san asked for.
Has photos of the WILLE crew’s
family members.
And that’s a letter from Touji to his sister.
Told me to tell you he “owes ya one”.
Okay, got it.
I’m back.
Tears?
They’re coming from... me?
Is this... “loneliness”?
Good morning, Ms. Lookalike.
Good night
Good morning
Thank you
Goodbye
“Good night. Good morning. Thank you...”
“Goodbye.”
Good morning.
Is everything okay? You’re here early.
I wanted to see you, Ikari-kun.
Here.
Thank you.
Um, I know you asked
about a new name, but...
You’re Ayanami.
That’s all I can picture.
Thank you for thinking about it.
That alone makes me happy.
I can’t live here.
But I like this place.
Ayanami?
I learned what it means to “like”.
I’m happy.
Ayanami, what’s wrong?
I wish I could have
harvested the rice.
held Tsubame more.
I wish I could have
stayed with the person I like, forever.
Goodbye.
Ayanami!
Okay, you said she went that way...
What’s wrong?
So that’s the Wunder, huh? It’s huge!
The people who want to stay
are disembarking.
Finally heading into the final battle, huh?
Cut it out! Don’t film me!
Sorry, just... I want to
keep a record of today.
Fine. Suit yourself.
Well? Why are you here?
Ikari...
You’re allowed to stay, you know.
Thank you, Kensuke.
Say thanks to Touji
and the others for me, too.
Asuka, I’m coming with you.
I see. Well, there are rules
I gotta follow...
Suzuhara... Sakura-san?
I toldja to not pilot no more Evas,
but ya went and ran off and did just that!
Dumbass! Dumbass!
You’re such a huge dumbass, Ikari-san!
What are you, his wife?
The status of the escapee
has been verified.
From here on, I will take responsibility for
monitoring and restraining BM-03.
Please sign here,
Temporary Special Senior Major Shikinami.
No DSS choker?
No need for it.
He’ll be held in a blast-proof
containment chamber until the end of the operation.
Monitored Target Subject BM-03 arrived
at Chamber 2. Ready detonation systems.
Figured that’s the best course of action
since he managed to take it off himself, huh?
MAGI Copy has a record
of choker activation.
It shows an instance of another pilot
being executed right before his eyes.
Even after such a traumatic experience,
he still returned to the Wunder...
Why?
Beats me. If you ask me, the bigger mystery is
why Captain Katsuragi’s letting him on board.
Village 3 records compiled by the rep,
and personal correspondence from Suzuhara.
To Sakura
With love,
your Big Bro!
To Sakura
With love,
your Big Bro!
To Sakura
With love,
your Big Bro!
From Big Bro?
Chamber 2 closure complete,
and emergency blast activation system online.
Quarantine procedures for
Monitored Target Subject BM-03 are now complete.
Covering for disembarked
personnel is a go.
New-02’s site is on track, begin integration
of 08γ’s power shift as planned.
Sitrep on each main turret
and exterior works?
Replacement of Turret 4 and addition of
the aft turret is proceeding nominally.
Work on Evas in the ship external dock
is lagging behind by a total of 3%.
Speed is Priority One.
We’ll rush through the first fifth of the checklist!
Yes, ma’am!
N1 Rocket’s secondary coupling
will restart in five minutes.
Got no problem with picking up
Major Shikinami.
But why did that jinx
come along with her?
Better than cutting him loose
and letting NERV use him again.
All personnel have been granted unconditional permission
to shoot if he tries to get in an Eva.
Isn’t that enough reassurance?
You know that’s all talk, right?
I mean, the Captain couldn’t bring herself
to neutralize him when he escaped.
I have zero faith in her right now.
The person in question is a child.
I understand her hesitation.
Well, that child caused Near Third
and massacred my entire family!
Near Third was collateral.
It was never his intent.
And the Captain is devoting
herself to atoning for it.
I agree. Kaji entrusted WILLE to her.
I trust her all the way.
You’re all too gullible.
Three minutes to resume loading
of large unguided N2 mines.
Like with this water made
from God knows whose pee.
You really think purifying it is enough?
It’s not that easy.
New Unit-02, JA components
connection test successful.
Start left arm independent coordination
system work as planned.
They’ve added even more explosives.
They’re losing faith in us.
I’m back.
Welcome back, Princess!
The trip must have been hard.
I missed you very much!
Jeez, what have you
done to this room?
What happened to cleaning out the books?
You got even more!
Books are the sum of
all human wisdom.
My impossible dream is to read every book,
from every time and every culture.
By the way, any progress with Pup?
Who cares? I’m not interested.
Ooh! She cares not for teenage boys.
That brat doesn’t need a lover.
He needs a mother.
All delivery operations from
logistic support ships are now complete.
Logistics personnel,
vacate support ships immediately.
Sign here to permit the operational independence of KREDIT,
and removal of all restrictors on both Evas,
Captain Katsuragi.
Approval from both Captain
and Vice Captain verified.
Maya, please get started.
Roger that, Vice Captain, ma’am.
You always come here
when you want to be alone, Misato.
Maybe we ought to move
the Captain’s Quarters nameplate here.
You can’t bury your feelings
for Ryou-chan so easily, it seems.
It’s not about Kaji.
I can relax better here. That’s all.
This section is home to
the original purpose of this ship, isn’t it?
Conservation of all species...
An unmanned, fully-autonomous ark with
near-perpetual operation, built to that end.
The true nature of the AAA Wunder.
From Kaji’s point of view, the survival
of mankind wasn’t the biggest issue.
He felt a need to preserve the natural state
of all the diverse life forms...
...that would have become collateral damage
in the Instrumentality Project.
And to do that, he would need to evacuate as many
Seeds of Life as possible out of Earth’s atmosphere.
So, to realize his plan, he seized this ship
from NERV while it was still being built.
He also felt it was impossible for humanity
to stop the Instrumentality Project.
But he gave his life
to stop the Third Impact in the end.
He died in the most self-contradictory, selfish way...
What an utterly infuriating man.
And now, he’s gone.
So I’ll use this ship to annihilate NERV...
...and put an end to
their Human Instrumentality Project.
For the sake of revenge?
No. This ark was made to leave life behind.
I’ll turn it into a battleship that protects the living.
You know full well that you sound
like a mother right now, yes?
I’m as far from a mother
as you can get.
Captain and Vice Captain
currently on navigation bridge.
NERV HQ has started moving.
It is believed to be on course to the site of the former
South Pole hypocenter, with the rising Black Moon.
The rebirth of the Black Moon,
which shall be a cornerstone of the Fourth Impact...
The rebirth of the Advanced Ayanami Series,
untainted lifeforms, made with pure souls
free of distinction between sex, who shall serve as...
...the sacrificial offering
to the Vessel of the Adams.
And the Human Instrumentality Project,
humanity’s attempt at self-salvation...
Look at where that arrogance has led us.
The Third Boy has returned to WILLE.
Ayanami-Type No. 006 was not properly calibrated,
and seems to have been unable to retain its form.
Did you believe it would benefit him
to suffer the same loss you did, Ikari?
He seems to be psychologically stable.
So, Captain Katsuragi? What do you want to do
about Provisional Name: Ikari Shinji-kun?
Never see him again,
just like your son?
Keeping him in our custody will be enough.
No need for me to visit him.
You’re sure we don’t need to
put a DSS Choker on him?
Unless it’s of your own volition,
atoning for your sins is a meaningless idea.
Misato, I know you’re trying to act tough,
but the truth is you’re happy he’s back.
Acting on emotional impulse only brings trouble.
You know that from experience.
You never pull your punches, huh?
Being soft on you only brings trouble, too.
That, I know from experience.
The rest of my body doesn’t change at all,
but my hair keeps growing. Pain in the ass.
God, corruption, and desires...
They dwell within the fibers of hair.
It truly is the manifestation of the chaos
that is the human heart.
Unequivocal proof that you are
still human, is it not, Princess?
The cursed epicenter
of the Second Impact.
All of the Vessels of the Adams are ready.
Furthermore, the reactivation of Unit-13
is only a matter of time.
Yes. Then let’s begin, Fuyutsuki.
I’ll leave the rest to you.
Everything up until now has followed
SEELE’s design, I suppose...
Do it, Shinji-kun!
Not for the sake of anyone else!
For the sake of your wish!
To: Colonel Katsuragi Misato
Enclosed: Records of Village 3
and Ikari Shinji-kun
From: Aida Kensuke
Captain, I have bad news.
NERV HQ has arrived at its final destination.
They’re moving to reactivate Unit-13 now.
I feel like I am lost in a place
So in other words,
we only have a few hours left.
that has no concept of who I am
Yes. Also, some good news.
The shutdown signal plug is complete.
And both Evas are in a functional state, if only barely.
Like a ghost between worlds I am trapped
Understood.
All stations, prepare for launch.
Abort all current work in twenty-five minutes.
We’ll depart in thirty minutes.
And I'm losing belief in myself
Your requests are as unreasonable as ever.
All stations, ready launch in
battle stations condition 2!
When I speak, no one hears
Depart in 25 minutes.
When I touch, no one feels anything that I do
All hands, complete all work
in twenty minutes.
I repeat, all stations, ready launch
in battle stations condition 1.
Unmanned fleet, final adjustment
to launch position.
When I try to stand up be counted
N1 Rocket propellant injection complete.
Switching to internal power supply.
It's like everyone looks right through me
Final status check is a go.
All extra-vehicular work crew, vacate now!
Loneliness isn't the way I wanted to be feeling
You have so many bandannas, Chief Takao...
Yeah. One for each comrade who died
when we rose against NERV.
Emptiness, ebbing away like some forgotten story
These bandannas were how you identified allies
during the revolt, weren’t they?
Yeah. “To bring this color
back to the red land and sea.”
It’s a symbol of our oaths.
Our wish embodied by color.
Helplessness, what can I do to make you all remember
Thanks.
This bandanna has become
a memento of Ryou-chan.
Sadness is all that I have, and it's no comfort to me
Katsuragi...
Take care.
Truth be told...
I wanted to stay behind
with him back then.
Of course you did.
And perhaps he would have let you...
if you weren’t expecting.
We’re takin’ up combat positions,
so I’m headin’ for the medical ward.
Please stay put, Ikari-san.
Call me with the red button
if ya need somethin’.
All right, bye for now.
A pressure-resistant experimental
plugsuit for deep-diving.
Looks fresh outta the oven, meow.
Yeah, they would give us
new suits for this.
They’re our burial clothes.
New Unit-02, JA reactor activated.
Output stable. Start energy circulation.
Unit-08-Gamma’s coupling
with the Dragon Carrier is nominal.
No separation test required.
We’ll launch it as it is!
Releasing temporary cage’s
final lock bolt.
Both Eva units currently locked
in ejection position.
Four-Eyed Crony.
I wanna make a quick detour.
Roger that.
Adjusting New-02 and
08γ entry plug position.
120 until ready position lock.
Guess who!
Um, I’m not sure...
Here’s a hint.
“Rooftop”... “glasses”...
“Gorgeous girl with big boobs.”
Uh... The parachute girl?
Bingo!
I’m yet to introduce myself.
I’m Mari. Makinami Mari Illustrious.
Once again, pleasure to make your acquaintance,
WILLE’s little Pup.
Ooh, that’s a bit different.
You smell more grown up, I think?
That brat doesn’t change so easily.
I guess I’ll ask since this is the last time.
You figure out why I tried to
punch your face in yet?
Because back when you were in Unit-03...
...I didn’t make any decision.
I didn’t decide to help you,
I didn’t decide to kill you.
Because I didn’t want
to take responsibility.
Guess you have grown up a bit.
Since this is the last time,
I’ll just say...
That lunch you made that one time...
It tasted great.
I think I had a crush on you back then.
But I became an adult before you did.
Bye.
Hup!
You’re doing great.
You should be proud, Ikari Shinji-kun.
Zàijiàn!
Bit of a weight off your chest, Princess?
Yeah. A little.
Both Eva pilots have begun boarding
their respective entry plugs.
Shinji-kun, you need to find peace of mind
and a place where you belong.
Fate will guide you there.
We’ll meet again.
Yeah...
You’re right, Kaworu-kun.
APU power output stable.
Main engine threshold achieved.
Thrust increasing to 11,600,000 tons.
Gyrocompass in operation.
Helm and gravity controls all green.
Both Evas secured in launch position.
Start entry sequence.
Routing power to main guns.
No abnormalities in energy flow.
Unmanned fleet has been
locked into position for launch.
Stop all extravehicular work at once.
Non-combatants in stand-by.
All stations are now
in battle stations condition 1.
Captain, all stations ready for launch.
Ready to storm NERV HQ anytime.
Roger.
This is your captain speaking.
To ensure beyond all doubt
that the Fourth Impact never occurs,
this ship will now assault NERV HQ
at the former South Pole Ground Zero.
Furthermore, for the purpose of neutralizing
Eva Unit-13, now acting as the Trigger of the Ritual,
we will carry out Operation Yamato.
We will put an end to
all the chaos that has taken place.
All stations...
Launch!
Entry sequence complete.
Command control transferred to battle bridge.
Reaching seed storage units
ejection point.
Roger. Sever linkage with the Wunder.
Switch to internal power and
set control systems to independent states.
Eject all seed storage units.
Before turmoil comes serenity reflected
in your soul to see you through adversity
All units ejected into L5.
Autonomous systems nominal.
Start descent to target.
Initiate atmospheric re-entry.
Roger that.
Initiating atmospheric re-entry.
Monitors back online.
Proceeding to former
South Pole Ground Zero area.
Entering L-Containment Field boundary.
Navigating L-Containment Field boundary surface.
All systems go.
This is the top of the L-Containment Field
said to be keeping out all lifeforms tainted by original sin.
Man is advancing through this
purified area without blessing.
All thanks to Kaji’s data
and the Anti-L System.
Twenty to diving point
in L-Containment Field.
Roger. All stations, ready for dive.
Starboard Hull 2 hit!
Damage unknown!
Enemy ship sighted at three o’clock!
Ship No. 2 with Opfer-Type
system integration, Erlösung...
So they have completed it, after all...
My apologies. I must ask you to play along with
Ikari’s selfish whims for a little while longer.
Trying to buy time until
Unit-13 reactivates, huh?
Same God-slaying power as us. Tricky.
Bring it on!
Starboard guns, ready to fire!
Hurry to the dive point,
and hold that NERV ship at bay as we go!
Fire!
Hits all over the ship!
They outgun us like crazy!
Dammit! How’s that
the same type of ship as ours?!
The difference between a finished and an unfinished model.
But our propulsion engines...
...blow theirs away!
L-Containment Field diving point reached!
Execute rapid dive!
Roger that!
Passed through L-Containment Field layer 1!
Entering layer 2.
L-Containment Field density, +30.
Eva Infinity swarm,
dead ahead at twelve o’clock!
Pay them no mind!
Keep pushing forward!
Enemy ship sighted.
Twelve o’clock, dead ahead!
An ambush?!
Ship No. 3, the Erbsünde...
A perfectly executed pincer attack.
This is bad! If we take any more hits,
it’ll disrupt our navigation!
Ship No. 3 has poor outfitting.
We’ll sink it first.
Helm steady. Maximum battle speed!
Roger that!
Ship No. 3 taking evasive action!
Don’t let her get away! Ram into her!
This is nuts!
Turn us around!
Roll 180 degrees!
Switch position with the enemy ship!
Roger that!
Using Ship No. 3 as a shield, hmm?
As reckless as ever.
We’ve broken through the Infinity swarm.
Entering L-Containment Field layer 3.
NERV HQ, our target, in sight.
It has already shifted below the Black Moon.
As you just lie and wait
in such a sorry state
Not long ‘til Unit-13 reactivates now.
the metamorphosis
has turned you into this
Ships No. 2 and No. 3
approaching on our stern.
As you just lie and wait
We’re out of time. Use the Black Moon as cover
and continue on course for assaulting NERV HQ.
in such a sorry state
the metamorphosis
has turned you into this
Ready launch of guided munitions.
Set target to Unit-13 re-adjustment sector.
NERV Battleships approaching
our stern at six o’clock!
Tilt the ship.
Reduce our target size to a minimum.
Roger that!
Port gravity ballast blow. Down twenty.
Once a man, no longer can you share what was, the world you once had
Protecting the fleets on the wings
is Priority One.
Concentrate our A.T. Field!
Heavy damage to primary stern gun!
They’re beating us blind!
Don’t panic!
Just need to hold until launch point!
Everyone will be glad when it's all over
Ten until optimal
guided munitions launch point.
Trajectory clear!
Everyone will be glad when it's all over
Fire all guided munitions!
Firing all guided munitions!
Visual confirmation on final target, Unit-13!
Like we expected, it hasn’t been reactivated yet.
Unit-13 is still immobile.
Eva-07 Series is inbound!
Gazillions of them!
Impossible to count!
Ignore the cannon fodder.
Expedite launch of both Evas!
Maya! Ready launch of both Evas!
Roger that, ma’am.
Both Evas, ready to launch!
Launch!
Mari, Asuka, we’re counting on you.
Yahoo!
Outta my way!
Comin’ through! Sorry, guys!
Everyone's out to get me, I can tell by the shifting eyes
Four-Eyed Crony! More prey incoming!
Okey-dokey!
that follow me, but they can't catch me cos I can hear them
Next!
Snakes in the grass sneaking up on me
Princess!
Try this on for size!
Pseudo-Evas bunching up to form a blockade?
Get the hell outta here!
Four-Eyed Crony! Gimme a hand!
You got it!
Both Evas have successfully
touched down on NERV HQ!
Target point is underneath that crater, I guess.
These guys are seriously
getting on my nerves!
Go ahead, Princess!
After you!
Sorry for the trouble, Four-Eyed Crony!
Eva Unit-13...
We made it...
For all the praise about it being
“the machine frame of God”, it’s still just man-made.
The thirteenth ultimate multi-purpose
humanoid decisive battle weapon.
If I can force the shutdown override
signal plug into its core,
I’ll at least stop it from moving,
even if we can’t destroy it.
This is...
...the...
...end!
An A.T. Field?
Unit-13’s not supposed to have one...
Why?
Wait! Is this my Eva’s A.T. Field?
Does that mean...
New-02’s scared of Unit-13?!
Something’s off.
What are you scheming, Gendou-kun?
This is weird. The NERV ships are
pulling back from the line of fire.
They’re descending.
Calvary Base, the cursed Ground Zero
of the Second Impact...
The Gates of Hell are open once more.
It can’t be...
Wings of Light?
Are they trying to cause the Fourth Impact
using the same method as the Second?
No, these ships were built to be the Guardians of Guf.
They can’t be used as a trigger.
Besides, what’s happening to
the Black Moon isn’t part of the plan.
This isn’t in SEELE’s design.
It’s a rite we know nothing about.
So, it’s a totally unpredicted event...
Another Impact, then?
This changes nothing. We’ll crush anything
NERV is planning, no matter what!
Ready main guns.
Take out Ship No. 3 first.
All available guns, target No. 3!
Ready super EM direct impact shells.
No director calculations needed.
All turrets, initiate fire
as soon as you’re ready!
The construction plan should have
called for four ships, though...
Fire!
Status report?!
Direct hit, ma’am! Something pierced
our starboard and port secondary hulls!
Stern damaged!
Main gun systems are down!
Ship No. 4, Gebet.
We’ve fallen right into their trap.
They’ll need this thing to complete
the final Impact anyway.
So I’ve got no choice but to finish it now,
once and for all!
My prey’s right in front of me
and I can’t do a thing...
Time for the last resort, then.
I’m sorry, New-02.
Gotta push you to the limit again.
Disable all restrictors.
Backdoor code, 999!
Pattern blue! I have readings
of the 9th Angel within NERV HQ!
Princess! Are you gonna
use the Angel’s power?!
Angel Blood...
Full injection!
You’re throwing away your
humanity, Princess?
I’ll use my own A.T. Field
to neutralize New-02’s!
It wasn’t a single entry system...?
Crap! So what Gendou-kun wanted
was the Angelified Princess?!
A Shikinami-Type...
My original, huh?
The last Eva’s form mirrors that of God.
All you need to do is
accept me and my love.
Now, come to me.
Tough luck.
It’s no use, stupid girl.
Asuka!
New Unit-02’s signals have all gone dark!
Pilot status, unknown!
N2 reactor APU, heavy damage!
Dammit! What now?
Some sort of Eva-like thing!
It’s clinging to the ship!
Pattern blue. It’s an Opfer-Type Eva.
They’ve reconstructed Mark.09,
pilot and all?!
This is bad! Our ship’s being
physically eroded on the inside!
Expunge it now!
We’re trying, but the contamination speed
is too fast! We can’t keep up!
Mark.09 has broken through the VD firewall!
There’s nothing we can do!
All control systems hijacked!
Well, we’re in a real bind.
Impressive... Wouldn’t expect
any less from Vice Commander Fuyutsuki.
The artificial recreation of Lilith...
And the forced conversion
of the Black Moon into spears...
The stage is set.
How will you bring the drama
to a close, Ikari?
Intruder sighted on bow deck!
Commander Ikari...
Sorry, Princess.
The shame I feel
can hardly be conveyed in words.
At this stage, it seems all I can do is
make a temporary retreat.
It’s been quite some time...
...Commander Ikari.
I compliment you on your efforts,
Colonel Katsuragi.
As intended, we shall now
make full use of this ship.
It’s you...
No interest in discussion, then...?
As always, you show no indecision
when it comes to accomplishing your objectives.
Indeed. I learned that from you.
With your beauty, you consume me always
A God knows no barriers.
It simply accepts everything
that comes its way.
With your voice, your velvet tones, they soothe me too
Ikari Gendou.
You’ve used the Key of Nebuchadnezzar
and willingly abandoned your humanity?
I have merely appended information upon my body
that transcends the Word of our realm.
There are no concerns.
Suck me in and spit me out like candy
I shall slay God, intertwine God with humanity,
and through the sacrifice of the Angel,
realize the deification
and the Instrumentality of mankind.
And you plan on throwing
Asuka’s life away to do this, Ikari Gendou?!
I can never work you out, you make me cry
The Ayanami and Shikinami-type pilots
were designed for this very purpose.
There are no concerns.
Cos you turn and your face twisted in utter rage
Nothing needs to be said for you to lose your head
Can't believe that I cared, for someone who makes me scared
Now I need out for sure, I can't take anymore
This is... humanity...
No... This is the commodification
of all ancient life on this planet.
With your beauty, you consume me always
Turning every soul into a core
and melding them with the Eva Infinities...
Is this the start of the Fourth Impact?
Correct.
With your voice, your velvet tones, they soothe me too
The purification of the seas,
carried out in the Second Impact...
The purification of the land,
carried out in the Third...
And the purification of the soul,
carried out in the Fourth.
The core that forms each Eva Infinity
is the materialization of a soul.
Suck me in and spit me out like candy
We shall cast aside
the vessel of mankind,
and our collective intelligence
will be guided to untainted paradise...
...in this final rite.
The hypothesis of your father, Dr. Katsuragi,
which he verified at the cost of causing the Second Impact:
I can never work you out, you make me cry
The Human Instrumentality Project.
I’ll put an end to my father’s nonsense,
no matter what it takes.
God bestowed two paths upon humanity,
who had consumed the Fruit of Wisdom.
Be exterminated by the Angels
that have been given the Fruit of Life...
...or exterminate the Angels
and rob them of their place,
surrendering our wisdom to enjoy
an eternal life as the Children of God.
We can only choose one or the other.
NERV’s Human Instrumentality Project,
the product of SEELE choosing the latter,
and what they employed the Adams for...
...is nothing but a feeble
resistance against God.
Nevertheless,
a worthwhile cause to pursue.
We choose not a despair-filled “reset” through
the Instrumentality Project and succumbing to God...
...but rather a hopeful “continue”.
I place my trust in human wisdom and will,
strong enough to conquer even the might of God.
It’s all a matter
of interpretation of the truth.
Colonel Katsuragi,
it’s the world you are ignorant of.
You, Akagi-kun, are blind to
what true happiness looks like.
Human sentiments cannot change anything.
With this, all of the horsemen have assembled.
So, you will now return the Eva Unit-01
that I had you look after for me.
Dad!
In for the kill, I feel nothing
All my memories are filled with hate and I can think of no joy that endures
We survived the Near Third
and everythin’.
I’m gonna have faith in our luck
and Misato-san’s WILLE.
Beyond the Doors of Guf lies the minus-universe,
which the Wunder cannot enter.
I’m afraid WILLE has no means left
with which to stop the Instrumentality Project.
We’re at the end of our rope.
Misato-san.
I’ll pilot Eva Unit-01.
When I went home
after Ayanami disappeared,
I could smell the scent of the earth...
Kaji-san taught me about it.
I’ll take on half of the burden
you’re carrying.
To that end,
you’ll have to fight Ikari Gendou.
I want to make amends
for the mistakes I made.
Hey, hold it, you!
Is this a joke? You’re not actually
going to let him pilot an Eva, are you?
I had a feeling something
like this would happen.
You gave us unconditional permission to shoot
in this situation, didn’t you, Captain?
Hey, you! The jinx!
That Near Third you caused
completely messed up our lives!
The root cause of it all...
You and your dad...
You will pay for it!
Sakura?
Ikari Shinji, you will not pilot the Eva.
We suffered real bad ‘cause of
you pilotin’ the Eva, Ikari-san..
And it made you suffer, too!
That’s why you ain’t ever doin’ it again!
I’m sorry, Sakura-san.
Please let me pilot the Eva.
You gotta be kiddin’, Ikari-san!
You won’t hafta do this
if you get hurt real bad...
This’ll hurt, but pilotin’ the Eva’s
a whole lot worse!
Please bear the pain!
Misato?!
Captain!
Misato-san?!
It’s okay, Shinji-kun.
If you hadn’t piloted
Eva Unit-01 fourteen years ago,
we would have been
wiped out back then.
So I’m grateful to you,
even though the Near Third
happened as a consequence.
The full responsibility
for the actions you took lies with me.
I, Katsuragi Misato,
still have custody of Ikari Shinji,
so I’ll take complete responsibility
for his subsequent actions.
I want to entrust everything
to the boy standing with us today.
Right, yeah!
We all owe Ikari-san for savin’ us!
But all of us lost loved ones
in Near Third, like my daddy!
Ikari-san is both our salvation
and our damnation!
We don’t got a choice!
Quit it.
That’s enough, Sakura.
Let’s just focus on
living until tomorrow.
This is... all so...
Soz, folks!
Prep work took longer than I thought.
Now, let’s go,
Pup.
Maya, bring the plug suit
from the Captain’s Quarters.
The bullet will dissolve in no time.
I’m gonna give you first aid right away.
It’s okay, Lieutenant.
Ikari Shinji-kun...
All a son can do for his father...
...is pat him on his shoulder...
or kill him.
Kaji’s words, not mine.
Misato-san...
I met Kaji Ryouji-kun, you know.
Was he doing well?
Yes.
I see... That’s great to hear.
He was such a nice guy.
We didn’t talk for too long,
but I liked him.
Thank you for this.
I’ll do whatever I can
to support you.
We’re counting on you, Shinji-kun.
Right.
I’m going now, Misato-san.
Take care.
Now, let’s get back to work.
The ship is falling apart.
We’ve lost our main and auxiliary engines.
It’s a miracle we’re still afloat.
Good enough.
We’ll make another miracle happen
before the backup power runs out.
Thanks to the overlapping-compliant
Unit-08-Gamma...
...being in a plus-four-in-one state
after having taken in the Vessels of Adams...
...we’re advancing smoothly
through the anti-universe.
Real blessing, meow.
Okay, Pup.
Your job is to destroy Unit-13
before all the Anti-L Systems fail...
...and everybody gets coreized.
Snatching victory from the jaws of defeat.
It’s our only bet.
Right. Understood.
But jeez,
you can’t underestimate the guy.
He’s taking advantage of the anti-universe
and keeps using quantum teleportation.
Catching him’s gonna be a real
bone-breaking task at this rate, meow.
It’ll be okay, Mari-san. I’m off.
Pup, there’s a chance the Princess’s soul
still lingers inside of Unit-13.
So please, the Princess...
Asuka needs your help.
I’ll try.
Ayanami...
Wherever you are,
I’ll come for you.
So you better wait for me, Shinji-kun!
Okay. Thank you.
I’ll be waiting.
Good luck.
Is this quite enough, Rei?
Ayanami...
Ikari-kun...
I’m sorry.
I couldn’t keep you from
needing to pilot the Eva.
It’s okay. Thank you, Ayanami.
I’ll take it from here.
Yes, please.
So, the pilot of Unit-01
has awakened, has he?
Incoming transmission from
the minus-universe via 08γ.
Eva Unit-01 has reactivated!
What?! No way in hell!
The jinx’s sync rate is zero!
Could it be that
Shinji-kun’s sync rate isn’t zero...
...but the value closest to it?
Yes, ma’am. His sync rate is...
...infinity.
Pillars of faith, shake like a movable force in a storm
Oh?
So it transformed into Cassius,
the Spear of Hope.
Testing your trust in your god to extremes
You have to stop this now, Dad!
Will your conviction withstand contradiction and fight off temptation to
I cannot.
I have...
discard your virtues to be true?
...a duty I must see through!
What is that man trying to accomplish,
triggering Another Impact by force?
Spirits that will dance with the devil, to the rhythm of evil
Only one possibility comes to mind.
He created a new spear
for the Fourth,
but he reserved two spears for
the Additional, until the very end.
will take hold if you let them, so repel with all your purity
Most likely to make
one wish of his a reality.
But that’s so stupid!
Dude’s just selfish!
We’ll be reunited soon, Yui.
It won’t move!
Dad, let me go!
Wash them away, banish all immorality
What’s that?
Pure is the soul that is bathe in its chastity forever more
That is the Golgotha Object.
Something not human left behind the World of God
in this place, with the Adams and six spears.
To the spirit that prays be not guided by fate
For the spirit of goodness will always lead unto the Lord
My wife—your mother—was here as well.
The Promised Land,
the beginning of everything.
The one and only place wherein fate, which humans
cannot control by their own might, may be altered.
Isn’t this...?
The Eva cage?
What is this place?
This is the world of your memories.
Dad?
Our senses are incapable
of perceiving the minus-universe.
Consequently, the LCL has formed
a virtual environment we’re able to comprehend.
Do as I say and hand over Unit-01.
Then you, too, will be able to
reunite with your mother.
You mean to attempt a futile resistance, then?
This is why I dislike children.
Fine. Then we’ll simply have to
take the long way.
Voices in my head say that the world has ended
Voices in my head keep telling me I'm not wrong
Dark, light, grey, let me out
Cold, warm, hot, I'm on fire
CLASS 2-A
From sublime to despair, every second is changing, it's mass confusion
What’s going on?! We’re making
the exact same moves!
How do I fight him?!
The thirteenth Eva...
The machine frame of despair...
The equal opposite to Unit-01, the embodiment of hope.
They are synchronized
and attuned to each other.
This is yet another rite I must carry out.
From sublime to despair, every second is changing, it's mass confusion
Please just stop this, Dad!
This is futile.
Your feeble strength
cannot stop me!
Trapped inside this living hell
I can't stay sick, I can't get well
My body aches, my mind will break
I wish to die for my own sake
You still don’t understand?
Power will not avail you here.
In fact, violence and fear...
...are not the measure
for settling our conflict!
That’s right. This is not something
that can be resolved through strength.
No...
I want to talk to you, Dad.
Dad...
What are you trying to do here?
The Additional Impact, which can only be
initiated here at the Golgotha Object.
It shall pave a road I may walk
in order to slay God.
To that end, I delivered
the final two spears upon this land.
I had a feeling... MAGI Copy
predicts a high likelihood...
...that Commander Ikari will dispose
of the last two spears at the very end.
Once all the spears are gone, Shinji-kun will have no way
of stopping the Impact from activating, will he?
So what the hell do we do?
We’ll make a new spear
and bring it to him.
You know there’s no way!
How the hell are we supposed to do that?
When the Wunder was hijacked
and reverted to the Buße,
the ships used the Black Moon as raw material
to generate unfamiliar spears.
So there must be a way we can use this ship
to create a new spear of our own.
If the Wunder was imbued with human will,
it could work another miracle.
I will trust in Ritsuko’s intelligence
and the spirit of WILLE and the Wunder.
Quite the unreasonable ask.
The only sample we have
is the activation data from before.
I’m sure that’s enough for you.
I suppose. I’ll give it a shot.
The key to it is probably
in the spinal linkage system.
I’m sorry, Maya.
We’ll have to do this on the fly.
Not a problem, Vice Captain, ma’am.
That’s what we always do.
We’re in luck, Chief! Backup power systems
and spinal linkage system still good to go!
Let’s swap the components out right here!
No! You guys need to evacuate!
You’re in danger just being here!
It’s our final duty!
Let’s do whatever we can!
I swear, you boys are so...
Now... Let’s get to backing up Shinji-kun
before Commander Ikari pulls some other stunt.
Yes, ma’am!
Pilot of Unit-01, there’s something
I want to show you.
That’s...
A black Lilith?
So that is what your memory
interprets it as?
This is Evangelion Imaginary.
A non-existent, fictitious Eva
that Dr. Katsuragi theorized about.
Only humanity, with its ability to believe equally
in both fantasy and reality, can perceive it.
The spears of despair and hope
become each other’s sacrifice and trigger.
The Imaginary and Reality blend together,
and everything becomes
homogenized information.
Thus begins the Additional Impact, which shall rewrite
our cognizance—or in other words, the world itself.
This is the only means
by which my wish can be granted.
What if we just hadn't said goodbye?
Would your love now have been as good as mine?
Would I still think love is impossible to find?
This is the Additional Impact?
Yes, that’s probably Eva Imaginary.
To think it actually exists...
This is crazy!
Completely crazy!
Would I still think love is impossible to find?
Mm... At long last, it begins.
It’s you.
It’s been quite some time,
Professor Fuyutsuki.
Might I add, though... The L-Containment Field
density in here seems a little too high.
Yes, well, this ship was
never designed to be manned.
I realize I’m being reckless.
A light known as hope
is ever bestowed upon humanity.
But it is also the nature of man
to cling to and drown in the sickness known as hope.
Both Ikari and I are guilty of
clinging to that sickness for far too long.
Gendou-kun is trying to fulfill his wish
by becoming the center of Instrumentality.
I can sympathize with how you want to help him—
Or rather, how you’d project your own wish onto him.
But I’d prefer you not drag
the whole of humanity down with you, y’know.
I can understand.
My role here is done.
I’ve assembled the things you wanted.
Do as you best see fit from here,
Mary Iscariot-kun.
Wow, haven’t heard that name in forever.
Right-o.
This is farewell, then.
What if we just hadn't said goodbye?
Yui-kun...
This will do, won’t it?
Would your love now have been as good as mine?
Would I still think love is impossible...
We’ve gotten it moving!
We can work with it now!
Captain, we can handle the rest
with the crew present here.
Roger. All personnel, abandon ship.
All hands, abandon ship!
I repeat. All hands, abandon ship!
Priority One to wounded personnel!
Head to the escape pods now!
Here we have the full lineup of
the Opfer-Type Evas, the Vessels of the Adams.
That’s Professor Fuyutsuki for you.
Very resourceful, meow!
Hate to do this,
but I’ll have you become...
...sustenance for my overlapping!
Now, we’re at 08, plus 09, plus 10.
Plus 11!
Okay, now how about...
...we get to the finale?!
Escape pods 1 through 4,
hatches closed.
Any remaining crew,
please get to Escape Pod 5 immediately!
I need to go back to the helm.
Our job now is to survive.
No matter how bitter it feels.
This path I choose as a show of love
Captain, we’re done swapping things out.
I think we can try it now.
Roger.
may be long or never-ending
Direct all helm control systems
to the Captain’s seat.
Then disembark immediately.
Misato?
But I will never falter from its course, my aim is true
Someone has to stay behind
and make absolutely sure it activates.
And this ship’s
commanding officer... is me.
I leave the remaining lives—
the children—in your care, Ritsuko.
Should it be, that I tire on the way
Understood, Misato.
I’ll do my best.
Then Lord, please comfort me with love unbounded
Thank you.
And I will gladly follow you
Our EM power reserves are running low...
Well, when all else fails...
...there’s good ol’
reaction-propulsion engines.
The Lilin will never use you again.
Sleep well, Adams.
The Wunder’s on the move.
Guess I better catch up with them, meow.
But, oh boy... Carrying out both physical and mental
Human Instrumentality at the same time... Well...
Gendou-kun, what is it you...?
Dad, what do you wish for?
The world which you did not choose...
One where A.T. Fields do not exist.
A world where all is equal,
where we share a single human mind.
No differences between individuals.
No rich nor poor, no discrimination,
no wars, no abuse, no pain nor sorrow.
A world consisting only
of cleansed souls.
And above all, a restful world
where I can be with Yui once more.
Yui! Yui!
Yui! Yui! Yui!
Yui, where are you?!
Where are you, Yui?!
Everything here... It’s all Rei?!
Where?! Where did you go?!
Yui!
Dad, you have to stop this.
Why? Why are you here, Shinji?
Because I want to know you.
I always tried to stay away from you,
even when I didn’t want to be alone.
I was scared of finding proof
that you hated me.
But I want to know now...
To know you.
An A.T. Field?
Even having abandoned my humanity?
Could it be that... I’m afraid of Shinji?
Me?
This was never meant to be thrown away...
...but to be handed over, wasn’t it, Dad?
So you were just like me.
Yes, I was.
My headphones cut me off
from the outside world.
They protected me from the noise of others,
helped me feign indifference.
But when I met Yui,
I no longer needed them.
Have you decided on a name?
If it’s a boy, Shinji.
If it’s a girl, we’ll go with Rei.
Shinji... Rei...
I became a parent despite
never knowing my own parents’ love.
There is no question this world
is unstable, imperfect, and irrational.
It is a world where nothing works out
if you take what people say at face value.
They will tell you different things
at different times.
What the truth is—what I’m expected to
go along with—is a mystery to me.
Perhaps all of it was true to them,
and the discrepancy came from how they felt each time.
I feared connecting with others.
I hated this world,
brimming with people.
Being alone has been my daily life
since I was young.
So I never felt loneliness.
But there are some in our world
who frown upon such a life.
I always disliked visiting other people;
being taken to the homes of classmates
who didn’t interest me, or to my relatives...
I hated being forcibly informed of,
and made to participate in, their lives.
Being with other people
was excruciating.
I always just wanted to be alone.
Ever since I was a child,
there have been two things I liked.
The first was knowledge.
I satiated my starving heart through
the intake of information, on my own terms.
Knowledge demands no thoughtfulness.
I could serve upon myself
as much knowledge as time would allow me.
The other was the piano.
A finely-tuned sound would answer acutely
to the key that was touched.
There is no deception there.
No betrayal nor disappointment.
No compassion, tortured soul
I would be solemnly translated
into a stream of sound.
I liked this system.
I liked being alone.
It meant neither I, nor
anyone else, would get hurt.
Evangelion
Alone, I could be at ease.
However, after I met Yui,
I learned that living could be
an enjoyable experience.
Yui alone accepted me for who I was.
Armageddon day is here
When I lost her,
the faith I had in my ability
to live on my own went with her.
Living hell has come
For the first time,
I knew the anguish of loneliness.
I couldn’t handle the pain of losing her.
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY PROJECT (TENTATIVE)
PROJECT EVANGELION
PROPOSITION OUTLINE
I just wanted to cry against her chest.
World's worst nightmare has happened
I just wanted to change myself
by being at her side.
I just wanted to make that wish come true.
Evangelion
Am I... Am I unable to reunite with her
because of how weak I am?
Shinji...
I think it’s because you’re
in denial about being weak.
You’ve always known,
though, haven’t you?
What is that?
It must be Misato-san.
All of the world in unison, welcome and rejoice
I’m not done yet!
Awaited and promised long, the Lord has come
The Lord has come, the Lord, the Lord has come
Ludicrous... All of the holy spears
have been lost.
There cannot be any new spears
capable of rewriting the world!
Breaking open the bondage of Satan
Cassius, the Spear of Hope...
and Longinus, the Spear of Despair;
both of which God bestowed upon us...
Even having lost them, the will to return the world
to the way it was has created the Spear...
The prisoners to release, the Lord has come
...of Gaius.
No, the Spear of WILLE.
Humanity, with its knowledge and willpower,
The Lord has come, the Lord, the Lord has come
has made it this far without divine help,
Yui-san!
Shining down upon the dark roads of this world
He of glorious light, the Lord has come
Made it!
Mari! Go to Shinji-kun!
The Lord has come, the Lord, the Lord has come
Already on it!
I’ll bring him back! Promise!
I’m counting on you!
Breaking open the bondage of Satan
The prisoners to release, the Lord has come
The Lord has come, the Lord, the Lord has come
It seems a new spear will be brought to us
before I could be reunited with Yui...
How unfortunate.
This was the only thing
your mom could do for you.
I’m sorry, Ryouji.
Thank you, Misato-san.
You’re able to accept the deaths
and wishes of others...
You’ve grown up, Shinji.
Until the very end, I had no idea...
...whether or not you would prove to be
a necessary material in Yui’s reconstruction.
Fulfilling a wish entails recompense.
I felt that a child was
a punishment upon myself.
Not seeing my child, not being there for him...
I deluded myself into thinking that would be my atonement.
I also believed that would be
what was best for my child.
I’m sorry, Shinji.
I see...
Were you there the whole time, Yui?
Ikari Gendou...
He was the center of Instrumentality this time,
the origin of the cycle.
I’ll take over from here.
Ikari Shinji-kun,
what is it you wish for?
I don’t need anything.
Even if it’ll be tough, I think I can manage.
Rather than myself...
I want to save Asuka and the others.
I see.
You’d already gotten back on your feet...
Not in the Imaginary, but in Reality.
Yeah.
I have to pay for
the mistakes Dad’s made.
Asuka.
I don’t know my Papa.
Mama’s not around, either.
So you don’t need anyone, Asuka.
I’m gonna make sure I don’t.
It’ll be unbearable otherwise.
Because living is painful.
I’ll pilot my Eva.
Even if people hate me,
even if they speak badly of me...
...none of it matters,
as long as I can pilot.
I have no other worth, after all.
I’ll have a strong body and heart
that doesn’t need anybody else.
So...
Praise me!
Acknowledge me!
Give me somewhere I can belong!
The truth is that I’m lonely...
All I ever really wanted was for
someone to pat me on my head.
It’s all right.
You’re Asuka.
That’s enough.
Was I... asleep?
Stupid Shinji?
I’m glad I could see you again.
I just had something
I wanted to tell you.
Thank you for telling me you liked me.
I liked you, too.
Goodbye, Asuka.
Tell Kensuke I said hi.
Take care of yourself, Princess.
She’s gone, then.
Won’t you be lonely, Shinji-kun?
No, I’ll be all right.
Now it’s your turn, Kaworu-kun.
I remembered.
I’ve come here and met you
so many times before.
Our names are together in the Book of Life.
We’ll meet over and over.
I am you. I’m just like you.
That’s why I was drawn to you.
I wanted to bring you happiness.
Right...
Kaworu-kun, you really are a lot like Dad.
That’s why you piloted
the same Eva, right?
You’re different from
your usual self, Shinji-kun.
You’re not going to cry?
No.
The only one
my tears can save is myself.
Me crying wouldn’t save anybody else.
So no, I’m not going to cry anymore.
I see... You’ve already grown up.
I’ll be a little lonely,
but this is a good thing.
Kaworu-kun, I’m going to
dispose of Unit-13... Your Eva, too.
I see. You’re casting the Evas aside.
I’m sorry.
I was mistaken about your happiness.
Exactly. That was your happiness,
Commander Nagisa.
You didn’t want to
make Shinji-kun happy...
You wanted to gain
your own happiness through his.
My existence can only be erased
in the event of vacuum decay.
So for all eternity, I must repeat my performance
inside of a predetermined circular narrative.
This is a gesture for
bonding with someone.
You seek a world of complementarity...
You never change, Shinji-kun.
That’s exactly why you chose him
and wrote his name in the Book of Life.
Thank you, Ryou-chan.
You saved me, too, you know.
It’s an honor, Commander Nagisa.
Oh, cut it out, Ryou-chan.
It’s high time you start calling me “Kaworu”.
I’ll postpone for now,
Commander Nagisa, sir.
“Nagisa” means seashore,
the space between sea and land.
And you intertwine humanity,
as the 1st Angel that became the 13th.
That name truly suits you.
You’ve thoroughly
fulfilled your duty here.
I think it’s fine
if he takes over now, don’t you?
How about working in the fields with me
and Katsuragi once you retire?
Yeah...
That sounds nice, too.
You’re the only one left...
Ayanami.
tsubame
I’m fine here.
Another one of you found a home for herself,
somewhere that wasn’t here.
I think Asuka’s going to find a place
she belongs when she gets back, too.
Happiness without piloting the Eva.
That was what I wanted for you.
Yeah.
So there’s a life outside of here
you can live, too.
Is there?
There is.
I’m going to choose a life
without piloting the Eva, as well.
I won’t turn back time
or revert the world.
I’m just going to rewrite ours
into a world that doesn’t need the Evas.
Into a new world,
where people can live.
The birth of a new world.
Neon Genesis.
Yeah.
And besides,
Mari-san’s coming to get me.
So don’t worry about me.
Okay. I understand.
Ikari-kun...
Thank you.
I’ll give it a try, Ayanami.
A Neon Genesis.
O Soldier who can abandon even a wounded friend
Let me be the only one to hear your pain
Who is it?
Ayanami?
No, you’re not her...
I see...
You were waiting for this moment...
I won't forget you
You were inside me all this time, weren’t you?
The lonely man who never got to live for his own sake
Mom...
I finally understand.
Dad wanted to see you off, right?
We got to know one another
That was what he meant...
...by “slaying God.”
We got to love one another
I want to be proud of that until the moment I die
O Voyager embarking on a cold dream, vanishing into the blue
Goodbye, all Evangelion.
Humans are always blind to that which will change them
How far away is your destination?
Will you never again return home?
We got to know one another
We got to love one another
I want to be proud of that until the moment I die
We got to know one another
We got to love one another
I want to be proud of that until the moment I die
We got to know one another
We got to love one another
I want to be proud of that until the moment I die
Woo-hoo! I made it!
Reached base just in time!
Mari-san!
Thank you,
Unit 08+09+10+11+12.
Thanks for all your hard work, Final Evangelion.
Mari-san!
Sorry I’m late, Shinji-kun!
The train will arrive shortly.
For your safety, please stand behind
the yellow braille line.
Guess who.
A gorgeous girl with a big chest.
Bingo.
You smell as nice as ever.
More grown up, I think.
And you’re as cute as ever.
My, my...
Got a real mouth on you now.
C’mon, Shinji-kun. Let’s go.
Yeah, let’s go!
My first time at the Louvre was really nothing special
hajimete no Louvre wa nante koto wa nakatta wa
Because I'd long since met my very own Mona Lisa
watashi dake no Mona Lisa mou tokku ni deatteta kara
The day I first laid eyes on you, wheels began to turn
hajimete anata o mita ano hi ugokidashita haguruma
I couldn't shake this feeling of impending loss
tomerarenai soushitsu no yokan
Though we've had so many already,
mou ippai aru kedo
why not add one more?
mou hitotsu fuyashimashou
Can you give me one last kiss?
Something we don't want to forget
wasuretakunai koto
Something I don't want to forget
I love you more than you'll ever know
You don't like being photographed
shashin wa nigate nanda
But I don't need a picture
demo sonna mono wa iranai wa
Your image is forever burnt
anata ga yakitsuita mama
onto my heart's projector screen
watashi no kokoro no projector
I was pretending I wasn't lonely
sabishiku nai furi shiteta
Well, I guess that makes two of us
maa sonna no otagai sama ka
Yearning for someone
dareka o motomeru koto wa
came hand in hand with heartache
sunawachi kizu tsuku koto datta
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
A kiss as hot as fire
moeru you na kiss o shiyou
With such passion
wasuretakutemo
that I couldn't forget it even if I wanted to
wasurerarenai hodo
I love you more than you'll ever know
I already know
mou wakatte iru yo
Even if the world ends
kono yo no owari demo
Or I grow old...
toshi o totte mo
There's someone I can never forget
wasurerarenai hito
There's someone I can never forget (There's someone I can never forget)
wasurerarenai hito (wasurerarenai hito)
There's someone I can never forget
wasurerarenai hito
I love you more than you'll ever know
There's someone I can never forget
wasurerarenai hito
There's someone I can never forget (There's someone I can never forget)
wasurerarenai hito (wasurerarenai hito)
There's someone I can never forget
wasurerarenai hito
I love you more than you'll ever know
can never forget, can never forget, can never forget
wasurerarenai wasurerarenai wasurerarenai
There's someone I can never...
wasurerarenai hi
can never forget, can never forget
wasurerarenai wasurerarenai
There's someone I can never forget
wasurerarenai hito
I love you more than you'll ever know
Chasing after a breeze that blew by
fuite itta kaze no ato o oikaketa
One dazzling afternoon
mabushii gogo
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
If I can be granted just one single wish,
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
then lay me to rest by your side,
kimi no soba de nemurasete
wherever that may be
donna basho demo ii yo
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
If I can be granted just one single wish,
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
then lay me to rest by your side,
kimi no soba de nemurasete
wherever that may be
donna basho demo ii yo
Beautiful world
I only have eyes for you, no question
mayowazu kimi dake o mitsumete iru
Beautiful boy
Yet unaware of his own beauty
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
It's only love
Day in, day out
nete mo samete mo
Boys' comics and daydreams
shounen manga yume mite bakka
He doesn't like who he is
jibun ga suki ja nai no
Not knowing what he wants, yet longing all the same
nani ga hoshii ka wakaranakute tada hoshigatte
A lukewarm tear runs down his cheek
nurui namida da ho o tsutau
There isn't anything I want to say
iitai koto nanka nai
I just want to see you one more time
tada mou ichido aitai
Maybe I'm just a coward
iitai koto ienai
who can't say what I want to say
konjou nashi kamo shirenai
Which is fine, but...
sore de ii kedo
If I can't see you before my world disappears,
boku no sekai kieru made aenu nara
then lay me to rest by your side,
kimi no soba de nemurasete
wherever that happens to be
donna basho demo kekkou
Beautiful world
In the days so fleeting
hakanaku sugite yuku hibi no naka de
Beautiful boy
It's only natural to be temperamental
kibun no mura wa shikata nai ne
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
It's only love
If I can be granted just one single wish,
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
then lay me to rest by your side
kimi no soba de nemurasete
Beautiful world
It's only love
Beautiful boy
Beautiful world
It's only love
Beautiful boy
Beautiful world
It's only love
Beautiful boy
THE END