Pocket Monsters: Audio Drama...
Sakuragi Park
at
Night
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Airs Fridays at 6:55 PM
on TV Tokyo Network!!
* Airs at different times in some regions
Airs Fridays at 6:55 PM
on TV Tokyo Network!!
* Airs at different times in some regions
“Sakuragi Park at Night!”
All right! Time for another exciting
nighttime patrol around Sakuragi Park!
Hey, Satoshi...
If you’re too loud,
you’re gonna wake everyone up!
Oh, right.
Pikachu and Sarunori, shh, okay?
Let’s move, Go.
Yeah.
Everyone looks sound asleep.
It’s a precious sight because you don’t really
get to see sleeping Pokémon out in the wild.
Raichu, Baope, and Hiyape
are sleeping together!
Oh, that’s really cute!
Huh?
That sounds like...
Oh, it’s Inteleon! Hey!
Satoshi!
Huh?
Inteleon is shy, so he trains all alone
in the middle of the night.
So...
Got it.
Let’s go.
That should cover
just about every area...
“Nothing to report,” huh?
Huh?
What was that?
I think it came from above...
Ah!
Over there!
Gorone!
I had no idea they can sleep
on cliffs like that!
Don’t start turning in your sleep!
Wake up, Gorone!
You’re gonna fall!
It’s coming this way!
Run!
Oh, no!
Gorone don’t like water!
It’s fast asleep on the grass...
Good grief...
Ah-choo!
Shh!