PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hallowed God, Arceus
Heatran's Explosive Advance!!
Kurogane City
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
Is there something there?
What’s this noise?!
Rishan!
Dotakun!
Hey, cut it out!
What’s the matter
with you guys?!
Pochama!
Whirlpool!
Bet that cold shower
helped clear your heads.
Rishan!
They’re hurt!
What’s going on?
Agnome!
Uxie!
M'rit!
The Legendary Pokémon of Sinnoh?!
Agnome! Willpower Pokémon!
Psychic type!
Known as “The God of Willpower!”
It is said to have endowed humans with
the determination to face any of life’s difficulties!
Uxie! Knowledge Pokémon!
Psychic type!
Known as “The God of Knowledge!”
It is said to have endowed humans with
the intelligence to solve various problems!
M'rit! Emotion Pokémon!
Psychic type!
Known as “The God of Emotion!”
It is said to have endowed the human heart with
emotions, such as sorrow and joy!
This is absolutely amazing!
What’s...?
What is this?!
Arceus...
They were trying
to tell us something.
Yeah.
How the heck
can you two be so calm?!
Go...
When we were adventuring
through Sinnoh,
we worked with Agnome and the others
to rescue Dialga and Palkia.
What?! That’s incredible!
Arceus and those flames...
They must’ve been
some kind of message.
C’mon!
We have to go to the Pokémon Center!
Hypervibration rate
and expansion rate are stable.
Saturn.
Right.
To all Team Galactic staff...
It is finally time
to enact our plan.
We shall bring back our Leader Akagi,
the king of the new world!
Team Galactic...
A secret society who once
attempted to destroy the world,
in order to create
a new world free of conflict.
Their boss was a charismatic figure
by the name of Akagi.
In pursuing his ambitions,
he took advantage of the power of Dialga and Palkia,
the Legendary Pokémon he had summoned,
to open the space-time gate.
But once his plans were foiled
by Satoshi, his friends, and Agnome’s trio,
he abandoned his subordinates
and vanished through the space-time gate.
All our preparations are now complete,
thanks to Heatran’s power.
The time has come to open
the space-time gate!
This is...
...the first step towards
the creation of our new world!
The plan will commence
at 1800 hours.
All staff, stand by!
Yes, sir!
The Pokémon reportedly showing strange behavior
were all Pokémon residing on Mount Tengan.
Disturbances in the magnetic field
of Mount Tengan...
...have also been observed in the last few hours,
and some suspect these two events may be linked.
Rishan is all better now.
Takeshi!
Small world, huh?
I can’t believe
all three of us are here!
Listen, we just saw Agnome...
Agnome and the others
showed us Arceus...
Calm down!
I can’t understand you
if you both talk at the same time!
Pleasure to meet you!
My name is Go!
Ooh...
Nice to meet you! I’m Takeshi.
Satoshi and I go way back.
Satoshi’s told me about you!
He said you’re a former Gym Leader
and Pokémon Breeder,
and that you’re aiming
to become a doctor!
Go’s adventuring with me.
Is this Happinus yours?
Yeah.
Pinpuku evolved into Lucky,
and is now
my brilliant assistant.
As is Gureggru.
I see!
Long time no see,
Gureggru!
But anyway, Takeshi...
Yeah.
That news report...
The magnetic field must be
what made Rishan confused.
Let’s go scope out
Mount Tengan!
We’d better figure out the cause!
Okay. I’ll get us there!
Whoa, this thing’s fast!
It’ll be fine, it’ll be fine!
I use it for house calls
to treat Pokémon.
Handles like a dream.
Comes in handy.
It’s time!
Commence the operation!
Commencing operation!
I see.
Maybe that message wasn’t
from Agnome, but from Arceus.
Of course!
I’d better tell
Ms. Shirona about this!
She could help us!
Plate B standing by.
All systems operational.
Let’s go, Heatran.
Magma Storm!
Energy expansion rate rising!
Critical threshold breached!
Activating energy generator!
Fire!
Firing!
Over there!
It’s coming from
the mountainside!
Takeshi, take us there!
Sure.
Just as we calculated.
Changes in space-time
topology detected.
The space-time gate
is rapidly expanding.
Leader Akagi...
We’re almost there!
Heatran! Magma Storm!
Keep up the Magma Storm!
Energy expansion rate
rising even higher!
Look!
The space-time gate is...
More, Heatran! More!
No, wait! You’re putting
too much strain on the system!
Don’t try to stop us, Jupiter!
The space-time gate
is almost open!
Exactly!
We cannot stop now!
We will reach Leader Akagi!
The energy generator
is malfunctioning!
The energy is flowing back!
Flowing back?!
No way!
Not when we’re this close!
What’s wrong with you,
Heatran?!
Return, Heatran!
Everybody, retreat!
What happened?!
We almost had it!
Could it be?
Has Heatran’s ability,
Kindled Fire, gone berserk?
Kindled Fire?
You think a Pokémon ability
can do this?!
The energy generated
by the Plate was much too great.
It must have assumed that form as a result of
receiving more power than it could handle!
Heatran’s...!
We must pursue it!
What’s that?!
It couldn’t be... Heatran?!
How’d it end up like that?!
So the fire Agnome
and the others showed us was...
This is bad!
The forest is gonna...
Where’s it going?!
Could it be going
to the Spear Pillars?!
Good... Keep going!
Open the space-time gate!
Is it headed for the Spear Pillars?
What is it trying to do?
Team Galactic summoned
Dialga and Palkia there once!
Could this be Team Galactic?!
Let’s try to cut ahead of
Heatran and stop it!
Got it!
So... hot...
First we have to put out
those massive flames!
Yes. Fight fire with water!
Okay! An all-out offense
with Water types!
Wait! It’s too big!
A Pokémon battle isn’t the solution.
We need to formulate a plan!
Dokurog?!
Is that...?!
Team Galactic!
Go, Bunyat!
Go, Skutank!
What are you doing here?!
I did not expect
to meet you again!
But the Sinnoh Police
dismantled Team Galactic!
Thanks for the explanation.
So useful.
But would you mind
staying out of our way?
So it’s your fault
Heatran’s like that?!
What’s your game?!
We have no obligation
to answer your questions.
Hey, look at that!
Agnome!
Uxie!
M'rit!
Are they attempting to foil us?
Not on my watch!
NEXT TIME
THE HEATED
BATTLE OF
MOUNT TENGAN
!