PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hallowed God, Arceus
A Wondrous Radiance! The Legend of Sinnoh!
Power Whip!
What’s the big idea?!
Let us go!
Skutank!
Just bite through it!
Just give up.
The space-time gate
you were trying to reach is closing.
Stop, Arceus!
Arceus...
Whoa...
Arceus!
We want to save Heatran!
Please help us!
If that gigantic Heatran explodes,
it’ll cause tons of damage to Sinnoh!
Please, Arceus!
Arceus...
Everyone!
Ms. Shirona!
You’ll do it?
Thank you, Arceus.
It turned Water type?
Whoa!
It’s like it’s creating an ocean!
An ocean, huh?
This is the Creation Pokémon’s power!
Arceus, it’s dangerous to get it wet!
When we tried using Water attacks on Heatran,
they caused an explosion!
Is it saying...
It’ll be fine?
Yeah, that’s how
it seemed to me, too.
Okay! We’ll trust you!
Let’s do what we can, as well.
All right!
Let’s save Heatran!
But how do we get it out of
that blazing inferno?
I know!
Fight fire with fire!
Go! Have Inteleon and Aceburn
help us out!
Aceburn?
And you too, Pikachu!
You have something in mind,
don’t you, Satoshi?
Yeah!
Water-type moves on their own won’t cut it!
Okay, I’m in!
That’s crazy!
It’ll be fine!
It’ll be not fine...
Pochama,
you’re up for trying?
Oh, geez!
I’ll come, too!
Thanks, Hikari!
There you have it.
What do we do, Ms. Shirona?
We’ll provide backup.
Turn back immediately
if you feel threatened.
All right!
Agnome! Uxie! M'rit!
You’re coming with us?
We’re grabbing Heatran
and then getting straight out of there, okay?
We’re going in, Arceus!
Amazing... The water and intense heat
are colliding, yet it’s not exploding...
That’s Arceus’s power. It can even
overturn the laws of nature.
Psychokinesis?!
They’re using it on us?
Amazing! We’re flying!
Let’s go, everybody!
Okay!
You ready, Pochama?
We’re counting on you...
Pochama...
Whirlpool!
Pikachu!
Hit the Whirlpool with 100,000 Volts!
You coated the water
in electrical energy?
Was that your plan?
Now, Pochama!
Okay! It worked!
Now it’s our turn!
Inteleon! Snipe Shot!
You did it!
Great work, Inteleon!
Let’s charge in!
There! It’s Heatran!
We’re gonna save you right now!
The Plate’s going haywire!
We have to hurry!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Okay!
We enveloped it with the Pyro Ball!
Great work, Go!
Pikachu! Let’s finish the job
with an Electric Net!
Now an Electric Net!
Yeah! Fire and electricity...
Two layers of coating!
We’re protecting it with flames,
and the Electric Net even keeps the water out!
Now we can break through
the water dome and save Heatran!
Now...
There’s no time to waste!
Break out!
It’s exploding!
Oh, no!
Everybody pull!
Don’t you dare let go!
Hang in there, Heatran!
Come on!
Satoshi!
Are you all okay?
Heatran...
Hang in there, Heatran!
Open your eyes!
You okay?
You’re not hurt, are you?
Thank you, Arceus!
We were able to save Heatran
thanks to you!
We saved Mount Tengan and the whole
Sinnoh Region! Thank you, everyone!
Arceus!
You’re going already?
Wait, Arceus!
Surely you must know!
Where is Leader Akagi?!
It’s easy for you to
go to that other world, right?!
We need Leader Akagi!
If you know,
tell us where he is!
Leader Akagi...
Arceus is always watching over us.
It wishes for people and Pokémon...
...to stand together
in the face of adversity.
When there is nothing
we can do on our own,
it will provide a hint
for how to solve the problem.
A hint...
But we must overcome
the adversity on our own.
That is why Arceus
left the task of rescuing Heatran to us.
Ms. Shirona!
What happened to Heatran?!
The situation’s been resolved.
All thanks to some
brave trainers and Pokémon.
Brave?!
Excuse me?
Would you go on a Mount Tengan date
with me to celebrate saving the—
I feel numb...
Haven’t seen that in a while...
Is Mr. Takeshi all right?!
This research trip sure wound up
bigger than I expected.
Yeah.
Satoshi!
Yeah!
An assignment for the research fellows
turned into an unexpected ordeal.
Satoshi, Go, and all their friends...
...were able to protect the Pokémon
and the natural landscapes of Sinnoh.
The Sinnoh Region...
A vast world
of legends and challenges...
...where since ages past,
the Creation Pokémon, Arceus,
has galloped across the land.