One Morning With Dande
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Airs Fridays at 6:55 PM
on TV Tokyo Network!!
* Airs at different times in some regions
Airs Fridays at 6:55 PM
on TV Tokyo Network!!
* Airs at different times in some regions
Pocket Monsters: Audio Drama...
“One Morning With Dande.”
Oh, Lizardon...
Thanks for waking me up every day.
What a great day!
Some mixed Momon and Kago Berry juice
is just what I need to start the day!
Incoming call from Sonia.
Good morning, Dande.
What’s up, Sonia?
That Daimax Band you asked me
to have repaired...
It’s good to go.
Good to know. Thanks for helping.
I’ll come over and pick it up, then.
Right now?
Got it.
I’ll be waiting.
We’re heading for Sonia’s place!
Is that an Aogarasu?
You wanna race it, Lizardon?
You’re no pushover, huh?
Let’s chase it, Lizardon!
What are you doing here, Dande?
Well...
I was racing this Aogarasu...
...and ended up getting lost.
Why are you here, Kibana?
Why am I here?
This is my home turf.
So I ended up in Knuckle City!
I was on the way to Brassie Town.
You’d have to cross
mountains and lakes to get here!
How bad is your sense of direction?!
Incoming call from Sonia.
Incoming ca—
Ooh!
Dande!
I’ve been waiting for you.
When are you going to get here?
Oh, my bad.
I’m in Knuckle City.
Huh?!
I’ll be right there.
Wai—
Sorry, Kibana. I gotta go.
Let’s battle again sometime!
Lizardon!
Gah...
And yet he’s crazy strong when he battles...
I’ll never understand him.
Well, better snap a pic of me
and this “Lost Champion”...