Let’s go!
Aim for Kiraflor!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Water Gun!
Now, it’s time you feel firsthand
why I’m at the top.
Kiraflor! Magical Shine!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Over the Top
The Rising Voltteccers
have returned to Paldea.
As for how that led us three to battle Omodaka-san,
who’s the academy board chair and League Chairwoman...
Well, what happened was...
What brings you
to the Pokémon League today?
Huh? Chili-san has a completely
different energy compared to last time.
Um...
We’re here because we have
a request for Omodaka-san!
We wanna go to Paldea’s Great Crater!
Just messin’ with ya!
Been a while, eh?
Just your ol’ pal Chili-chan here!
Is that so?
Ms. Briar made that very same request.
We heard there’s been an account of
an Entei sighting in Paldea’s Great Crater.
There’s a chance
it’s one of Lucius’s Six Heroes!
Could you go into
further detail on that?
In order to find a Pokémon paradise
known as Rakua,
we’re following the trail of the adventurer Lucius,
who traveled with Pokémon referred to as the Six Heroes.
I can see Terapagos is doing well.
Yes. We’re looking for the six Pokémon
who traveled with Pagogo here.
Rekkuuza,
Oliva,
Galar Fire,
Laplace,
Basagiri,
and Entei.
We only have Rekkuuza and Entei left.
We managed to meet Entei
in an archipelago near the Johto Region. But—
That’s amazing! Isn’t it, Chili-chan?
You said it.
Ooh...
But that Entei wasn’t the one we’re after
in our search for the Six Heroes.
That was when Ms. Briar told us...
First, take a look at this.
It’s a page from the Scarlet Book...
...containing a rendition of a Pokémon
purportedly sighted in Area Zero.
Doesn’t it look like Entei?
Now that you mention it,
there are parts that resemble one...
And that’s not all!
Recently, what may well
have been an Entei was spotted...
...on footage recorded
by Area Zero observation cameras.
That just might be
the Entei from the Six Heroes.
Ms. Briar thought so, too.
I see...
In order to confirm our suspicions,
we’d like permission to enter Paldea’s Great Crater.
Solving the mysteries of Terapagos
would be beneficial to Terastal research.
Previously, we were told there’d been
an accident and no one was allowed in...
That problem has already been resolved.
And I did tell you
I would guide you there someday.
If you would, please!
Very well.
I will permit Professor Friede
to enter with Ms. Briar.
Huh?! What about us?
Unfortunately, the general public
is not allowed access to Area Zero.
One of the reasons we prohibit entry is, after all,
that it is inhabited by dangerous Pokémon.
There’s Pokémon with unknown biology
running all up and down the place.
They’re called Paradox Pokémon!
Paradox Pokémon?
Yes. Even among researchers,
very few are permitted entry.
Ms. Briar is a special exception, made with
consideration to her many years of research findings.
Please, wait! Let us...
...go to Area Zero, too!
Please!
Chairwoman Omodaka...
They are fellow members of the Rising Voltteccers,
and have been vital companions on our adventures!
Please, consider it my request, too.
We may not have
much experience as trainers...
...but I made a promise to Pagogo.
We want to investigate this
for ourselves!
That’s why we took that course
at Orange Academy!
Please!
I understand how you feel.
Then please demonstrate
your capability to me.
Huh?
Top?!
How do you intend
to have them demonstrate?
It’s simple.
Namely...
You three must face me, the Pokémon League’s
Top Champion, in a battle... and win.
That would be ample demonstration.
The three of us...
have to face Omodaka-san...
...in a Pokémon Battle... and win?
What’ll you do, guys?
Will you go for it?
Yeah!
Before we begin,
I should apologize for one thing.
When it comes to Pokémon Battles,
I never hold back in the slightest.
But perhaps you three
will manage something monumental.
With that, are you all ready?
Yes!
Kirame. Ore Pokémon.
Rock/Poison type.
It absorbs nutrients from cave walls.
It wears petals
made from crystallized poison.
A Rock/Poison type, huh?
Water moves and
Stomping Tantrum could work.
Kiraflor. Ore Pokémon.
Rock/Poison type.
If it detects danger,
it opens up its crystalline petals...
...and fires a beam
from its conical body.
Kirame evolves into Kiraflor.
I’ve never seen either of
those Pokémon before.
These are Pokémon that inhabit Area Zero,
where you seek to go.
Pokémon from Area Zero...
So that’s the deal...
We’re actually getting to battle
the Top Champion!
We’ve gotta show her
what we’re made of!
Let the battle begin!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
My Kirame... Use Rock Cut!
Their speed rose?!
We can’t hit them like this!
Roy! Dot! Attacking separately
might not be good enough.
Right. Let’s focus in on one point.
In that case...
That one!
Let’s go!
Aim for Kiraflor!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Water Gun!
Now, it’s time you feel firsthand
why I’m at the top.
Kiraflor! Magical Shine!
Now, my Kirame... Use Power Gem.
Kiraflor. Magical Shine!
Where?
Where’re they gonna attack from?
By the time we take aim,
they’ll be gone...
In that case... Oh, I got it!
Achigator!
Aim a Charm Voice up there!
All right! Charm Voice hits a wide area
and removes speed from the equation!
It’s truly astounding how quickly
young sprouts will grow.
Nice one, Achigator!
Welcamo! Aqua Break!
Use Needle Guard, Kiraflor.
Welcamo?!
Nyarote, now!
Kiraflor. Magical Shine.
Surprise Attack!
All right!
They got poisoned?!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Poison Spikes?!
Despite appearances that Liko-san and her friends
were handling the battle well...
...it was all part of her strategy to activate
Kiraflor’s ability, Poison Coating.
Top’s got ‘em dancing
in the palm of her hand.
Now’s when things really get scary...
The Poison Spikes
make it hard to get in close...
And close-range attacks
will be blocked by Needle Guard.
But if we attack from here,
we’ll have Magical Shine to deal with.
Yeah. And we’ll be targeted
by the Kirame, too.
What’s the matter?
Being flustered by something
like this is beneath you.
My Kirame! Use Venom Shock!
Teaming up on us with
Magical Shine and Power Gem...
Plus Venom Shock,
now that we’re poisoned...
And Poison Spikes on top of all that...
I’ve never seen someone
battle like this before.
But we’ve never given in before,
no matter who we were up against!
I’ve got it!
Liko! Dot!
Let’s use Basagiri’s strategy!
Basagiri...
From back in the bamboo grove?
Just like Basagiri did then...
We’ll find them by sound!
Yeah. If we concentrate
and work in perfect sync, I bet we can do it!
Got it. Let’s give it a try!
Yeah!
Welcamo! Use Water Gun on Kiraflor!
Kiraflor. Magical Shine!
Team-up attack incoming!
My Kirame! Power Gem!
Nyarote! Dodge to the left!
Now! Catch them with your bud!
Achigator! Use Stomping Tantrum!
Good work, Achigator!
What marvelous adaptability!
But you mustn’t relax just yet.
My Kirame. Parting Gift!
My Kirame. Return.
Thank you for your hard work.
That move exploited Kirame’s biology!
Yes. Because of the Kirame’s Parting Gift,
Achigator and Welcamo’s attack
has harshly fallen.
They’re all puny-wuny!
And they’re taking a beating
from the poison!
Talk about stumped.
She went as far as knocking out
her own Kirame to make this happen...
Omodaka-san sure is incredible...
About the only strategy I’ve got left
is hoping for a lucky critical hit...
She focuses on winning,
no matter the sacrifice needed...
Depending on luck just won’t cut it
against someone like her.
I need...
...a strategy that can fool everyone!
Roy, Dot! Let’s all attack at once!
Got it!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Welcamo! Aqua Break!
I cannot allow you to
rely on brute force.
Kiraf—
Nyarote! Surprise Attack!
Use Needle Guard.
Sorry! Surprise Attack on Achigator!
Liko?!
Liko... Why?
Please! Use Stomping Tantrum again!
I get it!
Achigator, use Stomping Tantrum again!
Needle Guard.
He was spared from being knocked out
thanks to the effect of Parting Gift,
but my Kiraflor has taken great damage.
The powered-up Stomping Tantrum!
Using the frustration of
missing once to hit harder!
So that was your goal!
But even that wasn’t enough
to corner her...
And that strategy won’t work again.
They’ve done well to get this far.
If Kiraflor switches to defensive tactics now,
and drags out the battle...
...the poisoned trio
will wither away on their own.
It’s over already, Chili-chan?
Nah, the toppest thing about the Top
is that ain’t how she rolls.
I have greatly enjoyed our battle.
And I haven’t the least intention
of waiting for you to wither away.
Omodaka-san...
As the chairwoman of
the Pokémon League,
I wish to reward your hard work
with everything I have.
Be the light that guides trainers...
Kiraflor!
Now, it’s time to settle this.
A Rock-type Terastal?
We’ve gotta Terastallize, too!
Yeah. With Nyarote’s attacks...
...we might just find our chance!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Shine in full bloom!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
This is how you unleash a move...
Tera Burst on Nyarote!
Look out!
Achigator, push back the attack
with Flamethrower!
Welcamo! Get in front of Nyarote
and use Water Gun!
Nyarote!
Nyarote, you toughed it out for me...
Got it, Nyarote.
This is our last chance.
Give me a whole lot of Magical Leaves!
Use Tera Burst, Kiraflor!
Liko...
We won...
You easily sailed past my imagination.
What a bitter loss.
That deserves a standing ovation.
You truly did achieve
something monumental.
That was a fine demonstration.
Nicely done, guys!
Yeah!
You have the skills to enter Paldea’s Great Crater,
where dangerous Pokémon reside.
Congratulations.
Seriously, congrats!
Yay! You did it!
Buh-huh... Exceptional!
Id moved me—
This is the Zero Gate.
The Pokémon League
controls the systems here.
Where’s Ms. Briar?
She’s meeting us
at a research facility inside.
Let’s go! To Paldea’s Great Crater!
See you. You were cool out there.
Thank you. See ya.
Your mission is simple.
As you can see, members of the Rising Voltteccers
are most certainly headed towards Area Zero.
As such...
You’d like us to monitor their actions?
What a total drag.
I was gettin’ psyched for the first raid in forever,
but it’s just more recon work?
Correct.
You are to ascertain their goals and any progress
they make, and report back regarding the situation.
And if we do happen to
come into contact?
You must only monitor them.
Onyx-sama, with your
composed power of judgment.
Sango-sama, with your
bold power of adaptability.
This is a difficult mission that would
be impossible without your skills.
As you command.
Hmph. Well, if you need me that badly,
how can I say no?
Right, Onigohri?
Let’s go, Sango.
Wahoo! This rules!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Ore Pokémon, Kiraflor.
A Pokémon with crystalline petals
that resemble jewels.
Kiraflor
Ore Pokémon
Type: Rock/Poison
Kiraflor
Ore Pokémon
Type: Rock/Poison
Height
1.5m
But do you know what kind of
crystallized energy they’re made from?
Weight
45.0kg
Its petals are crystallized what?
Grass energy
Rock energy
Poison energy
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Its petals are crystallized what?
C: Poison energy
The answer is C: Poison energy!
Its petals of crystallized poison
are fragile,
and the poisonous particles
that scatter when they break...
...can give it the upper hand in battle!
Next episode
Sango-chan’s Totally Awesome
Drawing Song!
Wait, what are you starting now?
I found myself a great big plate.
Slap on a ton of triangles...
Circle, circle, circle, circle,
and a bridge to cross.
A bean sprouts up, then stretches out.
It’s awesome!
Totally awesome!
And, before you know it...
And so, next time on Pocket Monsters:
Totally Awesome Pokémon in Area Zero?!
Wait, so what did you just draw?