In search of Ms. Briar,
who is researching Terapagos,
we’ve arrived at Suiryoku Town
in the Kitakami hamlet.
The town happened to be holding
the hamlet’s Harvest Fête at the time!
We had so much fun!
On top of that,
we got some promising info.
Ms. Briar is at the Shining Pond!
Soon as we get past Hell Valley here,
we’ll hit the Shining Pond.
I hope we get to meet Ms. Briar!
Huh? By the way,
where are Murdock and the others?
They said they were gonna do
some cultural exchange thing with Kitakami folks.
Finished!
One baked apple candy!
Ooh! The caramelized aroma and the faint note
of tartness from the apple are exquisite!
And though it’s but a simple apple
on a chopstick, it just looks so cute!
Baked apple candy
is the ultimate sweet!
Just holding one
makes you look cute!
Aren’t you exaggerating a bit?
Sure, it tastes good, but...
Holding one makes you
look cute? Really?
Cute!
I mean, like, I saw you had that Lucky,
that’s why I even asked...
But who’da guessed?
Ya got some real-deal healer vibes!
What exactly are
“real-deal healer vibes”?
Actually, forget it.
Just get to work instead of snacking.
We’ll have lots of Pokémon coming by,
worn out after the festival.
Uh-oh!
What’s wrong?
Oh, I got summa this baked candy apple
stuck on my back tooth.
What am I gonna do if it,
like, yanks my filling?
Ah, hmm.
Apples fall, all things attracted
by the pull of gravity.
By an invisible force,
diverse things fall.
A red apple, then a white apple,
such diverse things fall in turn.
Whoa!
That made me jump...
What was that?!
Where did these washtubs come from?!
Otoshidori. Item-Dropping Pokémon.
Flying/Evil type.
It wraps food in the pouch on its chest
and carries it back to the nest.
It enjoys dropping things
that make loud noises.
Otoshidori tend to enjoy seeing
people and Pokémon getting startled.
Aww...
Here.
Are you okay, Kanuchan?
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Kanuchan's Hammer
Wasn't Built in a Day
A! A! Aga-ga!
Aga-aga-agaga!
A! A!
Hey, what’s that?
Oh! A Chiriin and a Pippi!
Think it’s listening to Chiriin’s cry?
You’d never get to see
something like this in the city!
There’s aspects of Pokémon you’ll never see
without heading out into the wilderness.
Absolutely...
Better record this!
This might even be good material
for a Gurumin vid!
Pichu!
Ooh! Record, record...
Aww! That’s so cute!
Oops! I said it on accident. Sorry!
Huh? What?
Cap’s allergic to “cute.”
“Allergic to ‘cute?!’”
I’ve never even heard of that...
Despite that, though,
he sure is popular.
Found some good iron, huh?
Kanuchan’s hammer...
It’s a lot longer than it used to be, isn’t it?
Yeah.
But man, when she gets like this,
she sure can go on and on.
She gets so locked in,
she doesn’t pay attention to anything else.
Just like Dot
when she’s editing videos.
You’re so right!
Well then, how about we stop here
for a little break?
Yeah!
Welcamo.
Thanks, Welcamo.
Dot!
Is Kanuchan okay?
Yeah.
Everyone okay?
Terapagos, Nyarote...
Are you okay?
Achigator?
Welcamo?
Huh? Kanuchan?
Kanuchan?!
Kanuchan’s not here!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Kanuchan!
The iron plate she was
hammering on is gone, too...
What if she was
kidnapped by that Otoshidori?!
Let’s split up and look.
Yeah.
Got it.
Let’s go, Welcamo.
Kanuchan!
You find Otoshidori?
Odoridori...?
Kanuchan!
Where could she be?
What if she’s out there crying?
What was that noise?
What if...?!
Kanuchan?!
What is she doing up there?
I get it now!
Water Gun!
Kanuchan! Found it, huh?
She can get totally locked in
no matter where she is, huh?
Work your magic, Kanuchan!
Whoa! Welcamo, are you okay?!
Water Gun!
No way...
Wild Pokémon can Terastallize?!
Welcamo!
It’d be my first time Terastallizing
out in the wild, but I guess I’ll go for it!
Glitz it up, go viral—
Nobody told me it had a mate!
It’s gone!
My Terastal Orb!
Where’d it go?!
Huh?! Huh?! Huh?!
Where is it?
Please come out!
I’ll never ask for anything else ever again!
Welcamo! Another Water Gun!
I can’t let them interrupt Kanuchan!
Water Gun!
Where is it, where is it?!
Welcamo, use Water Gun!
Welcamo!
Kanuchan?
Run for it!
She evolved!
Kanuchan!
Wait, no, uh... Nakanuchan!
Welcamo, use Water Gun!
Nakanuchan, use Brutal Swing!
Kick Down!
You were amazing, Nakanuchan!
You learned a new move...
Play Rough!
Oh, there it is!
What a relief!
Thought I lost it...
You finally finished it.
You did great, Nakanuchan...
Nakanuchan. Hammer Pokémon.
Fairy/Steel type.
They make their homes
in piles of scrap metal.
They fiercely trade blows
to test the strength of their hammers.
Her hammer sure turned out well!
I’ve never heard of wild Pokémon Terastallizing
outside of the Paldea Region before.
It sure surprised me.
Does that mean you Terastallized
Welcamo to battle it?!
Huh?!
Oh, uh, you see, I just...
Well, I had Nakanuchan, and um...
Huh? Nakanuchan?
You wanna make your hammer
even bigger?!
You’re incredible!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Hammer Pokémon, Nakanuchan.
Nakanuchan
Hammer Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Steel
Nakanuchan
Hammer Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Steel
Evolving has greatly improved
her physical abilities.
Height
0.7m
Weight
59.1kg
Now then...
Do you know what exactly she needed to do
to evolve from Kanuchan?
What did she need to do to evolve?
Make friends
Make memories
Make hammers
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What did she need to do to evolve?
C: Make hammers
The answer is C: Make hammers!
It’s thought that the only Kanuchan
capable of evolving into Nakanuchan...
...are the disciplined ones
that forge and reforge their hammers.
Next episode
Come on, come on!
We’re almost at the summit!
Dot, are you okay?
Need a little rest?
Yeah... I’m okay...
I’ll never understand
mountain hiking...
I can’t believe there are people
who do this as a hobby!
Ah! Sure is fun to climb a mountain
every now and then!
Am I right, Cap?
And we had one of those
unbelievable people with us all along...
Think we’ll get to meet Ms. Briar?
I can’t wait!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
The Meeting at the Shining Pond
Can we stop for a sec?