Plusle, Minun! Speed Star!
Daikenki, Sandpan!
Charge in with Drill Liner!
I see.
Well then, Minun...
Helping Hand!
Plusle! Grass Knot!
The effect of Helping Hand
powered up Grass Knot?
Sandpan! Rapid Spin!
The things you’ve learned
at Blueberry Academy are on full display...
...Ms. Anne!
Yeah!
I’ve figured out the trick
to doing good in Double Battles!
A fine reply!
But we’re barely getting started.
Right, miss!
Daikenki! Hydro Pump!
Both of you... Discharge!
Both abilities activated?!
Right. Plusle powers up
with Lightning Rod.
Minun recovers
with Electricity Reserve.
This is my plus-minus strategy!
You’re even using your own attacks
to turn the battle in your favor...
A battle style only possible
in Double Battles...
Ms. Taro’s considered every angle!
This is so much fun!
I’m learning a ton!
Oho! A new wind is blowing
through my grounds, I see.
Principal Cyano.
Uh-huh! And you were, uh...
Nemo, from Orange Academy.
Of course! You were Ms. Nemo.
Taro’s facing Anne
from Sekiei Academy, right?
When did she get here?
Ah, well, you see...
Er... Why is she here, again?
Huh?
Hmm...
Ah, of course!
When I was out on a look-see
‘round Sekiei Academy,
she struck me as
such an interesting scamp...
...that I invited her here
as an exchange student.
Ooh! That’s Blueberry Academy!
Isn’t it amazing, Masquernya?
I hear it’s a school built for Pokémon Trainers,
decked out with all the latest amenities.
Mega-awesome...
It really is out in the middle of the ocean!
We, the Rising Voltteccers...
...have arrived at Blueberry Academy,
floating in the sea of the Isshu Region.
I stepped out upon a question with no answer
pOCket Monsters
Rising Again
Starting a story from here, a place nobody knows, sends the message
That even if I take detours, I still took the shortest route
Tucking fear and excitement away in my pocket, I ran straight over
Let me hear about all of your tears
This adventure can’t be overcome alone
We will go beyond where the wind points
The iolite connected by meeting you
resonated in the midst of battle
Having you by my side was all I needed
To feel like I could walk anywhere
The answer is inside of me
The world has always been in my hands
Having you there for me was all I needed
To make my heart leap with joy
Tera    Sparkling! Blueberry Academy
☆
Our goals in coming here...
...are to ask Ms. Briar
about Pagogo once more...
...and to train, in order to gain the strength
we need to rescue the captive Six Heroes.
After setting us down,
the Brave Asagi...
...returned to a nearby port
to be serviced and resupplied.
Welcome to my very own
Blueberry Academy.
I am the Principal, Cyano.
And you were, uh...
We’re here to meet with Ms. Briar.
Oh, the Rising Voltteccers!
Li’l Briar’s mentioned ya.
Investigating something, are we?
Yes!
Oh! And I’ve prepared
rooms for you in the dorms, too.
Thank you very much.
What you can see here
is only the entrance,
as most of the academy
is actually beneath the sea!
Ain’t that something?
Hey! I wanna get mega-stronger!
Lemme train here! Train!
Train? Oh, that’s right!
Li’l Velly tells me that you are
trainers well worth my attention!
Velly...?
Principal Clavel, naturally.
You did a course at Orange Academy, yes?
Please do enjoy your time here, as well!
Okay!
Awright!
We get to train, Yamirami!
Li’l Briar!
We’re all waiting at the entrance,
but where might you be?
Where? I’ve got my hands full
with maintenance on the Terarium Core.
Ms. Briar, it’s Liko!
Oh! Today’s the day you were coming?
Oh dear...
Huh? You mean you forgot?
What a scatterbrain you are!
Coming from you, that really stings...
Kids, I apologize, but let’s meet
in my office tomorrow morning.
Principal Cyano,
if you’d please show them to their dorms.
Well then, kids, see you tomorrow.
Oh... Why, I must apologize.
No, it’s fine.
That’s just like Ms. Briar.
It is, eh?
Well then, what to do...?
Um... Why did you build a school
in the middle of the ocean?
Huh?! Your mind sure goes
strange places, eh?
Well you see,
that’s because... uh...
Because it’s attached to a resource development plant operating on the seabed.
Exactly! Took the words
right out of my mouth.
Li’l Taro’s always on the ball!
It was nothing.
Are these folks here guests of ours?
Yep. Here to see li’l Briar.
Uh. Oh, I never got your names...
Liko and Masquernya.
I’m Roy.
These are Achigator and Cap.
I’m Dot.
Welcamo’s my partner.
I’m... Ult.
This’s... Yamirami.
My, you all seem to be
such lovely friends.
Ah!
And that cap suits you quite well!
Oh! Is that why your name’s “Cap”?
How cute!
Oh dear! What happened?
Whenever someone calls Cap cute,
he can’t stop sneezing...
Oh, is that so? I’m sorry.
It was just such a cute cap...
“Cap” comes from “Captain Pikachu.”
He’s the captain of our airship.
Oh, the one that flew away earlier!
Incredible!
It’s nice to meet you, Mr. Captain.
Ah, I’ve yet to introduce myself.
I’m Taro.
These are Plusle and Minun.
I know! If you’re inclined, li’l Taro,
how about you give them all a tour of the academy?
You want me to do it again?
I mean... I’m sure you’re aware
that I can’t be trusted with tours...
Well, that’s true, but...
There really must be someone better suited than me...
Oh, I’m sorry!
It’s not that I don’t want to or anything...
It’s just that Mr. Cyano is always
pushing his duties onto me like this...
Simmer down, now...
I say that’s just not right!
A tad harsh, no? I implore you...
As an itty bitty favor for li’l Briar and I?
There’s no other way, huh...?
I understand.
I will take on this task!
Hurrah!
Thanks for having us!
Well, I’ll leave ya now.
Remember to enjoy
your student life to the fullest!
Right.
That’s one mega-innerestin’ principal.
“Mega-innerestin’,” you say...?
I’m delighted to hear
he came off that way, Mr. Ult.
Y-Yeah...
Well then, everyone.
What say we head into the academy?
Here you’ll see the undersea park that has garnered
Blueberry Academy such worldwide acclaim...
...the Terarium Dome!
The Terarium Dome...!
It’s mega-huge!
This is under the ocean?
How come we can see the sky?
Projectors are casting images onto the walls and ceiling,
so it does look like we’re outside, doesn’t it?
Oh! There’re even Pokémon here!
We have created a man-made environment
that’s comfortable for Pokémon.
All of this is man-made?!
Yes.
The inside of this dome is split into
four environmental areas.
First is this one here,
the subtropical-esque Savanna Area!
If you look to your right,
there’s the southern-esque Coast Area.
On the left is
the ravine-esque Canyon Area.
Lastly, deep within
lies the arctic-esque Polar Area.
The temperature, humidity, and more
are finely tuned for each area,
so every area has completely different
Pokémon inhabiting it!
Mega-awesome...
This really is the perfect place
to do some training! Right, Yamirami?
Hey! Hold up, Yamirami!
A Terastallized Kentauros!
Yes! And if you’d like to know why,
then have a look towards the ceiling.
That’s the Terarium Core,
which oversees the Terarium Dome.
The Terarium Core?
Isn’t that what Ms. Briar said
she was doing maintenance on...?
Yes.
Terastal energy radiates out
from up there,
so aspects of Terastal
are highly active within the dome.
Ms. Briar really is incredible,
isn’t she...?
Well then,
let’s head to Center Square!
There are some people there
waiting to see you all.
To see us?
Who could it be?
It’s really sparklin’!
Huh? Where’d those guys go?
This is Center Square.
Liko! Everyone!
Anne!
Nemo!
It’s been ages, Roy...
Everyone else, too!
Why are you here, Nemo?
I came here with Botan,
but when I heard Roy was bringing you all here,
I had to wait for you!
That so? Where’s Botan at, then?
She’s running maintenance on the League servers,
so she said she’d catch up later.
Now then, you’ll show me
the fruits of your labors, won’t you, Roy?
Of course. It’s a battle!
I’m getting fired up!
pOCket Monsters
Rising Again
Hey, that’s Ms. Nemo, isn’t it?
Huh?! From Orange Academy?
Well then, let’s go... Lucario!
Then we’ll do the same!
Ooh, you’ve got a new friend!
Yeah! This’s Ju'niper.
Ju'niper. Arrow Feather Pokémon.
Grass/Ghost type.
It nocks and fires arrow feathers
kept hidden within its wings.
Its aim is sharp enough
to pierce a pebble a hundred meters away.
I caught a Mokuroh
after I arrived here.
And I raised her
all the way into a Ju'niper!
That’s so you, Nemo.
Always evolving!
Are you each prepared?
Whoever defeats two Pokémon first
will be the winner.
Well then... Let the battle begin!
Let’s go, Achigator!
Use Flamethrower!
Ju'niper! Ghost Dive!
Aim for Lucario!
Lucario, behind you!
Parmot!
Use Mach Punch on Lucario!
A move combo,
predicting the opponents’ actions...
We can do that, too!
Here they come, Ju'niper. Take to the air!
Parmot, you Dig!
In that case...
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Lucario, aim a Luster Cannon
at Ju'niper!
Use Leaf Blade on Lucario!
Lucario, use Metal Claw!
We don’t know
where Parmot might come from.
And Ju'niper’s tough to hit...
During my time here,
I’ve been studying Double Battles all over again.
Now, Parmot! Aim for Lucario!
Here it comes, Lucario!
Get behind Ju'niper!
Lucario’s pretty good.
Achigator, aim for Parmot
with a Stomping Tantrum!
Lucario, use Metal Claw
on Ju'niper!
Here it comes, Ju'niper!
Use Shadow Stitch on Lucario!
Let’s finish this, Parmot!
Use All-Out Lightning Attack on Lucario!
Take the blow with Metal Claw!
Go, Parmot!
Lucario is unable to battle!
You did well, Lucario.
That All-Out Lightning Attack
was amazing.
Yeah, it’s a powerful move that hits with
all of Parmot’s Electric energy.
It certainly was powerful, but...
...Roy and Achigator
still have plenty left in them!
Hang in there!
That Roy jerk’s so mega-unfair!
Ult! Where have you been?
Oh, here and there. Not lost!
Anyway, that Nemo gal
is real mega-strong...
The basic strat of Double Battles
is to turn them into 2v1s.
Plus, Parmot is no longer
an Electric type.
Which means...
Achigator’s Stomping Tantrum will be less effective.
She attacked and managed to
restrain my moves all in one go?
That’s Nemo for ya!
Now comes the crucial part.
We need to lay on the pressure without letting up.
We’re at a disadvantage, no doubt about it...
But we can still fight!
Right, Achigator?
Great look in the eyes, there!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
All right! We’ll hit you with
everything we’ve got, too! Parmot!
Shine your light!
My greatest treasure!
Now, charge up your power, Parmot!
I won’t let you!
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
I won’t let you, either!
Ju'niper! Shadow Stitch!
Achigator!
She restrained
the Terastallized Achigator,
and is now having Parmot
charge up his fighting spirit!
Yeah. It’s a tactic to ensure
his full-hearted Fighting Spirit Punch will land.
Go for it, Achigator!
Achigator!
Go!
Too slow! Get ready to face
the full brunt of my fighting spirit!
Parmot! Fighting Spirit Punch!
It landed!
Achigator!
Achigator is unable to battle.
The winner is Nemo!
You really tried your best.
Fighting spirit alone...
...ain’t enough to make things
go your way, eh?
Not only did you raise a Ju'niper
in your short stay here,
but your battling
was exemplary as well.
Yup. Visiting Blueberry Academy
really paid off!
Mr. Roy,
you battled marvelously, too.
I’ve gotta think up
more combinations between Pokémon.
I hope you can
learn all about that here.
You were incredible, Roy.
That was a great match.
Thank you.
Hey! Next, you’re gonna battle me!
Ooh, good idea! All right...
That’s the signal for the end of classes.
Ms. Nemo, you’re going back
to Paldea today, aren’t you?
There’s not much time
before the ship leaves.
Gah, that’s right!
The heck?!
You never mentioned that!
Sorry! Next time though, okay?
Everyone! I’ll be waiting for you
back at Orange Academy!
This place is incredible,
isn’t it, Anne?
Right?
There’s loadsa different trainers,
and loadsa battle courts,
so you can battle
anytime and anywhere!
This really is...
...not just the ideal environment for Pokémon,
but for trainers, too!
I’m glad to hear it pleases you.
Ms. Taro, we want to get stronger.
There are some Pokémon
we want to rescue!
Yeah.
We have to get stronger.
Yeah. If I can’t get mega-stronger,
I’ll be lettin’ down Yamirami ‘n’ Kairyu!
So I can’t get shown up!
It sounds like you have
important personal reasons.
How about this, then?
You could ask the older students here to train you!
I’m having them teach me!
Huh? Ms. Anne...
After all, Ms. Taro’s
in the Bluebeleague Elite Four!
Elite Four?!
Oh, that’s... Well...
Please!
Beggin’ ya!
Looks like you gotcha self
caught up in more trouble.
Kakitsubata!
Perfect timing!
You’re one of the Elite Four, as well!
Help me—
Elite Four?!
Well, yeah.
Please!
Beggin’ ya!
I don’t wanna.
It ain’t even a Blu-Rec.
I say that’s just not right!
I say it is right!
I say it is!
I say that’s just not not not right!
After a rough start,
our training at Blueberry Academy began.
We’ll have two of the Elite Four train us,
and we’ll get stronger.
No...
We have to
get stronger!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Embrace Pokémon, Sirknight!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Embrace Pokémon
Fairy
Sirknight
Embrace Pokémon
Psychic
Fairy
Synchro
Trace
Sirknight
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Embrace Pokémon
Psychic
Synchro
Trace
Sirknight
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Embrace Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
The time has come
Even if I tried to count, I couldn't put a number to it
Asleep or awake
We're together forever, taratta!
How 'bout we postpone that doughnut dessert to next time?
This is the big 1, gotta make up our minds
Let's go meet up with the kids
who are walking along the railroad tracks
I simply can't wait
Even when I'm scared, my heart's still thumping from excitement
Asleep or awake
We'll be together forever!
Let's go on an adventure
I bet we'll snag 1st place
Just 1 more time, yeah, in 1 great, big
"What if?" story
Where I'm just a caterpillar
and you Fly high above
Just 1 more time, just 1 more time, and
we can become friends
Let's go on an adventure
I bet we'll snag 1st place
Just 1 more time, yeah, with 1 great, big
squeeze of kindness
The best kind of things
I bet aren't listed in the Index
I wanna see them with you, yeah, time and time again
break 'em down and remake 'em
OK!
Welcome back future, come on back soon
Let's do a super cool Encore
C'mon, sing it with me
Forever until the end, taratta!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Sirknight
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Embrace Pokémon
Psychic
Fairy
Fairy Skin
By unleashing its heart, Mega Sirknight...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
...has gained formidable psycho-power!
Eee... Eek!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It’s a reliable partner that exhibits
its utmost power when protecting its trainer!
Next episode
Here, we can battle Pokémon
we’d never normally meet!
I’m gonna get way, way stronger!
No, I have to!
I’m gonna find some mega-strong foes
and beat ‘em to a pulp!
You’ve all got such intense fighting spirit...
We’ll have to try our best, too!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Begin the Training! The Terarium Dome
I’ll give it all I’ve got!
Let’s take it easy, brother.
Begin the Training! The Terarium Dome