Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
This planet’s strange, strange creatures.
The sky, the sea, forests, cities...
You can spot them
just about anywhere you look.
Some live together with humans.
Others live out in the wild,
either alone...
...or in packs with their friends.
And there are even some
that live aboard the Brave Asagi.
By the way,
do you know who these Pokémon are?
Yep, it’s Loudbone and Lugarugan.
Right now, these two...
...are incredibly hungry!
Hmm? Are they here for
some secret midnight snack time?
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Secret Metamon Rhapsody
You can find tons of stuff you’re not using
if you just poke around a bit, eh?
Clean-out events like this are great.
They make for a nice refresh.
Huh? You’re throwing that out?!
Didn’t you film with that?
In a way, that makes it a highly prized collectible, no?
Ehh... I’ve still got
another ten or so anyway.
Hey!
Look, look! I found a super cool rock!
I’m puttin’ this in my room!
No way!
Why not?!
Why not...?
Ooh, you likin’ it too, Yamirami?
All right! This’s goin’ in my room!
Like I said, there’s no way.
We’re trying to clean out
unneeded stuff, you know...
Put it back where you found it.
Aww!
The ship’s been feeling
pretty cramped lately as it is.
We can’t go bringing more aboard...
Hmm?
Doesn’t something seem odd here?
Masquernya!
I’ve got more stuff I want to throw away in my room,
so let’s go grab it.
Hm?
Huh? Did I just...?
Must’ve imagined it.
Let’s go, Masquernya.
Were you trying to hide Metamon?
But...
This one I’m keeping...
And this one I’m not...
Oh, this is important.
All right!
Masquernya, take this for me!
Huh?
Masquernya?
Wait, what are you doing?
H-Huh?! Your tail?
Your tail?!
Your tail’s really stretched out!
What?! What? What? What?!
I just heard a weird noise!
What was all that...?
Thank goodness...
I thought you tore it off.
Let’s go!
Here’s more for you!
What’re they racing around for?
Huh?
Are there... more than usual?!
They look like they’re having fun!
Looks like they decided to ask
the other Pokémon for help, too.
Ahh, I’m starvin’!
I wonder what’s for lunch today...
I have been smellin’ something
for a while now.
Ult, what do you think it’ll be?
Hmm...
Ain’t it gonna be that?
Y’know, that.
Here you go.
Thanks for waiting!
Thanks.
Hey, where’s Lugarugan’s lunch?
Ah... I’ve been letting it taste test
too much again lately.
Its belly and jaw
are getting a bit pudgy...
So Lugarugan’s getting...
...the special diet menu!
I know you don’t like Matoma Berries...
But they’re healthy, and they’ll make you sweat
and speed up your metabolism.
That makes ‘em perfect for dieting.
Can’t you try them?
Even just one bite?
Ooh, you ate them!
I’m so proud of you.
Now, all this pudginess will just...
Huh?
That feels more drippy than pudgy...
Gah!
Whoa!
What the...?!
What’s gotten into all of you?
C’mon! Cloth, cloth!
Huh? Aren’t the Sharitatsu
being squashed?!
Are they okay?!
Cloth, cloth!
Dekanuchan, calm down!
Hold up, ain’t Yorunozuku’s
eyebrows fat-lookin’?!
There you are! Masquernya...
Have you seen
my Ikirinko wood carving?
It was about this big,
or if you include the tail, about this big...
And it had this lumpy bit on its head...
No, I guess you wouldn’t
know anything about it...
It’s so strange, though...
I was sure I put it in the box of things to keep...
I’ll go look one more time!
Well now...
I wonder how this is all going to turn out...
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
It’s not here...
Huh?
Oh! You found it for me?!
Thank you, Masquernya!
Oh, you know what?
I found this earlier.
You used to play with this so much!
It really takes me back!
I didn’t know you still liked it,
Masquernya...
Don’t you worry.
I’ll make sure to keep it for you.
All right...
Time to make one final push!
Hmm? Those are some serious faces.
I wonder what’s about to happen...
Oh, my! It’s purposefully trying
to get Alolan Betobeton to eat it...
...in order to fetch
the Ikirinko wood carving in its belly!
What are you doing, Masquernya?!
Hold on! Stop! Stop!
Stop it!
What’s wrong with Masquernya?
What the...?!
H-Huh?
Metamon?!
A cattail?!
Thank you.
Whoa, it really is a Metamon!
Gotta wonder
when it got aboard the ship.
Metamon. Transform Pokémon.
Normal type.
It can freely recombine
its own cellular structure to Transform.
If it laughs and relaxes,
its transformation comes undone.
Cool! Ain’t never seen
a Metamon before!
Gah!
Everyone...
Wait!
Our ship...
The Brave Asagi...
You’ve taken a liking to it, haven’t you?
Which is why you all want to
stay together with Metamon...
Isn’t that right?
Cap gave his okay!
Welcome aboard the Brave Asagi.
Let’s get along good, ‘kay...
...Metamon?
Is that a souvenir for Ms. Diana?
Yeah, it is.
Grandma likes Ikirinko.
Oh, yeah...
It’s good you found that, then.
Mm-hmm!
Here you go.
A heaping helping of Matoma Berries!
By the way, about Metamon...
They turn into a rock
when they sleep,
so Yamirami and Masquernya
fight over who gets it at night.
Overcoming countless trials,
and embracing the delight
of new encounters,
the travels of those
aboard the Brave Asagi...
...continue on,
even today.
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Metamon!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Metamon
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Transform Pokémon
Normal
Limber
It’s a Pokémon with
a knack for Transforming,
but if two Metamon meet,
do you know what they do?
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Run away
Become friends
Fight
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
Run away
Become friends
Fight
C: Fight!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
They can Transform and make friends with anyone,
but apparently Metamon don’t get along with other Metamon!
Huh?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
When they meet up,
they get into Transform contests!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Eek! Gurumin!
Since Metamon’s our new pal, how ‘bout comin’ in for a min
to have some Gurumin bread together?
Next episode
Gurumin bread?
Gurumin’s gonna become bread?!
Let’s go see all sorts of Pokémon bread
at the Bread Fest!
Wahh!
Next episode
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Bread, Bread, Bread! Mini Gurumin!!
Huh? Mini Gurumin?!
Huh?! What is that?!
Bread, Bread, Bread! Mini Gurumin!!