My name is Liko.
I failed my implementation test.
On top of that, I got trapped in a cave
on a snowy mountain with Amethio. It was intense...
But seeing the view from Paldea’s Highest Peak
with Roy and Dot managed to cheer me up again.
The Terastal Course is over now.
I’m back, Orange Academy!
Good work, everyone.
Those of you who passed your implementation tests
will be officially awarded their Terastal Orbs later.
All right!
Oh, sorry...
So they’re going to take them back
from people who failed...
This is the last day you will spend together
as course students.
So what say we all deepen our bonds
while we still have the chance?
To that end,
there’s only one thing to do...
Indeed.
You will all take part in 1v1 battles.
I call it... The Course Students
Battle Tournament!
Um! Are we allowed to Terastallize?
Even if we failed?
Yes, you have my blessing
during the tournament.
Good news, eh?
This’ll be our final Terastal.
Let’s give it all we’ve got!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
System Breach!
A Crisis at Orange Academy!!
Futachimaru,
use Turning Swallow Strike!
This battle’s just getting started!
Anne’s amazing!
You all look fired up!
Nemo! You’re here!
Of course!
Even the Gym Leaders are here.
They all wanna see the fruits
of the implementation tests.
Grusha-san’s not here...
When’re you battling?
We’re all in the second half.
Gotcha. I’m looking forward to seeing
the well-ripened fruits of your Terastal!
It’s from Botan?
Hello?
We need to talk. Come quick.
I’m busy with
the tournament right now...
I know that.
Meet me in the nurse’s office.
Hey!
Inconsiderate much?
Dot?
Sorry, something just came up.
I’ll be right back.
I wonder what happened...
Botan?
Botan, you there?
She’s not even here...
She is.
Don’t scare me like that!
Why are we in the nurse’s office, anyway?
Nobody will overhear us here.
More importantly,
the school’s in danger.
Look at this.
Huh? You mean it’s being hacked?!
From the inside, at that!
I knew you’d catch on fast.
I don’t have any proof,
but the culprit is most likely...
...Agesen.
Agesen?
But why would a teacher...?
I looked into her. Turns out she’s connected
to a group known as the Explorers.
The Explorers?!
You know them?
W-We’ve got a long history with them...
Fill me in...
On these Explorers.
An organization chasing after
the black Rekkuuza and Terapagos...
They sound crazy dangerous for sure.
So why’re they here, at this school?
What are they after?
One time, Principal Clavel showed us some info
on Terapagos sightings in Area Zero.
That’s got to be why.
Principal Clavel...
So, was that in the principal’s office?
Yeah, why?
That’s the place, then!
Hey, wait!
I get it...
They wanna steal the Terapagos data
from the PC in the principal’s office!
Since all the teachers
are outside for the tournament.
Nobody here.
The PC’s doing something!
No good.
It’s being controlled remotely.
But from where?
Right now, only the teachers’ on-campus PCs
can connect to the principal’s office.
The teachers’ PCs?
But the staff room was deserted.
The only other places with them...
...are the art room, the biology lab,
and the home economics room.
So Agesen must be in one of those.
I’ll try to stop the breach from here.
Dot, you go track down Agesen.
Got it.
I’ll have my friends
split up and look for her.
Let’s go, Welcamo!
It’s from Dot.
What’s going on?
Listen...
The Explorers have infiltrated the school.
You mean Onigiri...
...and Sandwich?
Not just them!
There’s a teacher with the Explorers, too!
They’re after the data on Terapagos.
There’s no time.
We need to act fast.
Got it!
What should we do?
I’m going to check out the biology lab.
I’ll tell you two where to go now.
Roy, you go to the art room.
Liko, you go the home economics room.
Don’t run, it’s dangerous!
I’m sorry!
There’s nobody in the art room.
Nor in the home economics room.
Got it...
Then Agesen must be in the biology lab.
Everyone, meet me there!
Right!
What?!
Are you okay?!
What happened?
It was so sudden...
I don’t know what happened...
Blegh, so salty...
Salt Pickling!
Tebrim, help them.
Th-Thank you.
Tebrim, you look after them.
What’s wrong, Liko?
The Explorers are here!
It’s got to be Onigiri!
Which means that Sandwich—
You rang?
...is here, too.
But... I’m all done being “Sandwich-chan.”
I’m Sango-chan, from the Explorers!
What’re you guys up to?!
Who knows? Not me!
Huh?
That so totally doesn’t matter!
We’re picking up right where we left off!
Time to have some fun!
As we arranged, I’ve secured an escape route.
Security has been neutralized.
Understood. I’m nearly done here.
The Explorers!
So, you’re here...
Onigiri and Sandwich
have both shown up.
If they’re dealing with those two...
I’ll have to be the one
to handle things here!
Charem!
So it’s you.
Agesen...
Don’t call me by that name.
Agate. That is my name.
This is bad! If I don’t do something soon,
she’ll steal the data!
Our goal was simply
to gather info on Terapagos...
But if we can secure the genuine article,
that changes things.
Hand it over.
I won’t give you Terapagos!
What can a mere child hope to do?
I can fight, Explorers!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah... Somehow...
What now?
Welcamo, bust down the door!
Aqua Break!
Mind Power!
Now I’ve got a troublemaker
over here, too...
Okay. You won’t be getting your hands
on that data now.
The culprit is Agesen.
And we’ve got some solid evidence.
What now?
She doesn’t know when to quit!
I’ve gotta hurry
and meet up with Dot...
Play with Sango some more!
Onigohri, use Blizzard!
Dodge it, Hogator!
You can’t run away forever!
Hogator, Flamethr—
Wait, no!
You’d burn up everyone’s art...
Huh?! Why would you care about
dumb junk like that?
Taikaiden!
Over here!
Hold up!
No more running for you.
I wasn’t running!
I can go all out here!
So you’re totally ready to fight?
Then I’ll go all out playin’ with ya!
Flamethrower!
Blizzard!
Go for it, Onigohri!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Salt Pickling!
Stone Edge!
Nyarote!
Another Magical Leaf!
Salt Pickling!
Lightning Speed!
Dodge with Acrobatics!
Now!
All right!
Kyojiohn! Self-Regenerate!
No way...
Tower above all, Kyojiohn!
Terastal!
When did she...?!
Kanuchan!
Nice!
She got us...
Gotta be kidding me...
Breaking that PC was pointless.
The data has already been transferred.
We were so close to stopping her...
I win this time.
Charem!
Natio. Teleport.
She got away!
Kyojiohn! Salt Pickling!
Dodge it!
Magical Leaf!
I need not even block
such weak attacks...
Self-Regenerate!
Nyarote won’t last long
against that Salt Pickling...
You can’t even move now.
So how about you
hand over Terapagos?
I won’t give it to you.
For Terapagos’s sake...
For the school’s sake...
I can’t afford... to lose!
Please, Terastal...
Shine in full bloom!
Nyarote!
Not on my watch!
Stone Edge!
Magical Leaf!
Salt Pickling!
Return, Kyojiohn.
Liko of the Rising Voltteccers...
My name is Onyx.
Don’t forget it.
Let’s go.
Onyx...
Hogator, use Flamethrower!
Don’t forget about us!
Use Blizzard!
Go!
Huh?!
Onigohri! More power!
Total Blizzard!
Onigohri!
We did it, Hogator!
We did it! We did it!
Sango can’t lose! It ain’t possible!
Sango. Mission complete.
Withdraw.
I can still fight!
Hey, wake up!
Wake up, Onigohri!
Withdraw, Sango!
Huh?
Return, Onigohri!
Don’t you freakin’ dare think you won!
Huh?! Whaddaya mean “ting-tong-tang-tong”?!
What’re ya tryin’ ta pull?!
Tebrim!
Arukujira?
Does that mean...?
Grusha-san?!
Um...
Meet me in the principal’s office later.
Understand?
I’m told you used Terastal in a battle.
I did.
So that’s the kind of person
you really are.
I-I’m sorry!
I’m the one who should apologize.
I misjudged your strength.
Huh?
It seems when you fight
on someone else’s behalf,
your true strength shines through.
Um...
I hear you protected the school.
Thank you very much.
Yeah. You got results.
You pass.
I pass? I pass?!
D-Does that mean...?!
It means you have passed
your implementation test.
A-Are you really sure?
Naturally. Grusha-san has
given you his approval.
Indeed.
Those skills show
you’re worthy of a Terastal Orb.
Thank you so much!
The Explorers retreated,
but they took the info on Terapagos with them.
But we got proof
that Agate was the intruder.
Plus, we kept the damage
to the school to a minimum.
And the battle tournament
didn’t get called off.
Th-Th-Thank... y-you very much.
Don’t sweat it...
Liko!
I hear you passed!
That’s amazing! You did it!
I sure did! Thank you!
This means we all passed!
We can all use Terastal!
Yeah!
Osu! The second half battles start now!
Oh! Liko, Roy... Glad I found you.
Your battle pairings have been changed.
Students who passed their implementation tests
are facing one another, so...
Look!
I’m up against...
Roy?!
Liko?!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Discipline Pokémon, Futachimaru.
A serious Pokémon that doesn’t
go a day without training.
Futachimaru
Discipline Pokémon
Type: Water
Futachimaru
Discipline Pokémon
Type: Water
Height
0.8m
It puts in all that effort
to learn how to use a certain thing.
Weight
24.5kg
But do you know what that thing is?
What does it train to learn how to use?
Bud
Hammer
Shells
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it train to learn how to use?
C: Shells
The answer is C: Shells!
To acquire a flowing swordplay style
using its two shells,
it puts itself through
strict training day after day.
Next episode
It’s finally our turn
in the battle tournament!
I’m up against Liko!
I won’t lose!
Same for me!
Who am I supposed to root for here...?
Agh... Liko and Roy, go for it!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Shine, Terastal!
Liko!
VS!
Roy!
Shine, Terastal! Liko VS Roy!!