Mist rolled in out of nowhere, huh?
Do we turn back and sail around it?
Oh, please, we can handle—
There’s a reef nearby!
If we keep going...
We’re in big trouble
if we hit those rocks.
What is that?
Singing?
Is that... Laplace?
Is it telling us to follow?
All right... Let’s trust it.
We’re safe!
A song in the white mist...
The rumors were true!
Thank you, Laplace.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
The Song in the White Mist
A song in the white mist?
Yeah. It’s a rumor the sailors have been
whispering amongst themselves.
There’s a mysterious Pokémon guiding ships that
have gotten lost in the mist to safety with its song.
With its song?!
That sounds lovely!
Furthermore, they say
this Pokémon is a shining Laplace!
Laplace...
From the Six Heroes?!
We can’t be certain, of course.
But there’s a good chance
it’s a special Laplace.
That song has been heard
all around the world for a long time, after all.
I, too, pursued this mystery once
when I was young.
Are you saying you met it?!
No...
Unfortunately not.
Oh...
I’d hear a rumor about Laplace and follow it,
only to find that it had already left.
Just that, over and over again.
In the end, I gave up on it.
But it’s in the mist, right?!
Let’s have a look from up on deck!
Hold it!
It won’t be that easy to find!
Aww, really?
Any other info, Diana-san?
I’ve got you covered.
What? Did you find all this?!
Of course not.
I asked Dot for help.
Lately, fog has been popping up
left and right in this part of the sea.
Amazing! You’ve looked into everything!
That was crazy fast!
It’s no big deal.
This stuff is pretty easy to find online.
The power of science sure is incredible!
You’re something special,
you know that, Dot?
Uh... Sure...
She even managed to
befriend Dot at some point...
You’re incredible, Grandma.
I was unable to reach Laplace on my own.
I didn’t even have a ship, after all.
But...
Things are different now.
You have the Brave Asagi.
Even things that were impossible
for me to do alone...
...are in reach now,
thanks to all of you.
Which means we can catch up to Laplace!
All right!
Seems like one of our Laplace witnesses
is stationed at a nearby port!
I suppose the first step
would be to talk to them.
All right! Off we go!
Yeah!
Yes, and truly a beautiful song it was...
So Laplace really is...
The fog showed up out in the open sea,
and we couldn’t tell where we were going.
But then Laplace saved us.
Where is this Laplace?
Hard to tell...
It vanished before we got out of the mist.
Captain!
We’re gonna start restocking the goods!
Good! I’m counting on you!
Restocking?
The ship shook something fierce
in the mist, you see.
All our cargo fell off.
What?!
That’s awful!
Because of that,
we had to repurchase everything.
But we got to meet Laplace,
and the ship itself was unharmed...
All’s well that ends well, eh?
Thank you very much.
Liko. Roy. Let’s get back to the ship.
Yeah!
Don’t panic even if you do run into fog!
Laplace will lead you to safety, no doubt!
Indeed.
Thank you very much!
Nosepass, which way’s north?
All right!
Laplace. Transport Pokémon.
Water/Ice type.
A kind-hearted Pokémon,
clever enough to understand human speech.
It glides across the surface of the sea
while its beautiful song echoes around it.
They can understand
human speech... Amazing!
They’re super kind, too!
You’ve met one, Roy?
Yup!
Back when I was lived on the island,
Laplace would play by the seashore a lot.
They were really friendly with people
and would let us ride them!
Really? That sounds great!
Do you think I’ll be able to
befriend this one and ride it?
For sure!
I can’t wait!
Kuwassu... What are you...?
I’m gonna capture every moment!
I think using this for a Gurumin stream
would be a bit, um...
I know.
This is just for personal interest.
Laplace of the Six Heroes
gets my heart racing too, you know!
Kuwassu!
Don’t let the snacks
distract you from Laplace, got it?
Is it just me, or are we dropping?
We are!
Is there another air leak?!
What? That’s awful!
I’m putting the ship
down on the water, everyone!
It’ll be easier to search
for Laplace that way.
Let the Brave Asagi take you
from a sky voyage to a sea voyage!
Awesome! We’re racing across the water!
This was a fishing boat once, after all.
Look over there!
Huh?
Laplace?!
No... But it might be treasure!
Too bad. Guess it wasn’t.
Darn... It’s empty, too.
Another one over there!
Terapagos?!
Could it be Laplace?!
Is it really the one we’re after?
It’s gotta be!
Everybody!
We’ve reached the target area!
The ship will now slow down
and cruise the waters at a leisurely pace.
Liko, Roy, and Diana-san...
You better find Laplace, you hear?
And once we’re done, we’ll have a party!
I’m whipping up some premium doughnuts!
Yay! Doughnuts!
Hey, now... We’re not going on a picnic.
I wonder what
Laplace’s song sounds like.
You wanna sing with it too,
right, Hogator?
I’m sure this one will understand us
right away, unlike Galarian Fire!
It’s a Pokémon
that rescues ships, after all!
It’ll help us for sure!
Be wary of making assumptions.
Huh?
The deeper your knowledge,
the greater the value of an open mind.
You can’t foresee what will happen.
That fog came in awfully fast...
Which means...
It was clear until just a second ago...
I can’t see a thing.
A song!
Laplace?
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Just like the rumors said!
Here it comes!
It really is Laplace...
What a beautiful song!
I can’t make it out at all...
Visibility being this poor is a problem.
We’ve gotta get out of here first.
So it really has come to save us?
All right... Let’s follow it, Cap.
How odd.
Liko.
Yeah.
Can’t it hear us?
Roy. Let’s try calling out for it, too.
Yeah.
Lapl—
Hogator?!
Huh?!
Wh-What?!
Pokémon?!
Well, well...
Guests on the open sea...
What are you doing?!
Are you okay, Hogator?
Nyahoja! Lightning Speed!
Stop!
Where’d they go?!
What is this?
The fog...
Laplace is...
...gone.
Back to square one, huh...?
Laplace seems to have dove underwater.
Yeah... We lost track of it.
Good thing the ship’s safe, though.
Imagine if we ran into a storm
or something in the mist...
We’d be blown to smithereens.
Thank you, Laplace!
Listen to this, Friede!
There were Pokémon that tried to
steal our berries in the mist!
Did some Camome fly by?
That’s just what wild Pokémon do.
Don’t be too hard on th—
They sprayed mud on Hogator’s face, too!
Mud Spray?
It was a Rikukurage
and an Eteboth, if I recall.
What?!
Yeah, that’s them!
I saw them too!
But both Rikukurage and Eteboth
are Pokémon native to forests.
They can’t live on the ocean.
They’re not known to
live anywhere nearby, either.
How did they get on board
when they can’t swim?
Are they really wild Pokémon?
There’s something I want you to see.
Dot?
What’s this?
I filmed it right next to the ship earlier.
But the fog’s too thick
for me to tell what it is.
A boat?
Does that mean
the Pokémon had a trainer?!
There’s something else
I’m curious about...
What?
You mean the timing
of the mist appearing?
You noticed too, then?
There tends to be some forewarning
that fog is gonna roll in...
But here it appeared
right out of the blue, which means...
You mean it’s a Pokémon move?!
Laplace can use a move
called White Mist.
Huh?
But Laplace saved us! And—
Hold it!
Uh?
I see!
Friede?
All right! We’re heading back!
We’re going to see Laplace again!
Huh?
Orio, head to the engine room.
Gramps, I’d like you to steer the ship.
Okay.
A simple matter.
Murdock and Molly,
I have a different mission for you.
You too, Cap. Come with me.
Sure, but... a mission?
What are you planning now?
Oh, just a little change of approach.
The fog’s completely gone...
So how do we find it?
Hup.
What?!
What’s going on?
That was heavy...
What are you doing?
See, Friede...
...asked us to pull all the Pokémon food
out of storage and onto the deck!
The Pokémon food?
Why, though?
He didn’t say why.
If my hunch is right,
it should happen any second now.
And there we go!
The fog’s back!
Hogator!
Terapagos!
I can hardly see a thing.
However...
The name “Captain Pikachu”
isn’t just for show!
Let’s go, Cap!
Higher than the sun!
Rising Voltteccer!
Hey!
Who are you?!
Those’re the guys from before!
So you did have pals after all.
“Guiding lost ships” turned out
to be one big sham...
Didn’t it, Laplace?
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
Exciting and thrilling
An adventure is starting
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cheerful bird Pokémon!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Y'all been groovin'? It's Gurumin!!
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Liko and the others have finally
met Laplace of the Six Heroes!
But this Laplace is nothing
like what anyone expected, huh?
Its pals all seem kinda scary,
but they’ll run if you try to chase them...
Wait, what’s this?
Terapagos wants to talk to Laplace!
You kidding me? You think it’ll listen?
And that’s all next time
on Pocket Monsters:
Laplace’s Feelings For Its Friends
Laplace's Feelings For Its Friends
Another day bursting with energy!
Terapagos’s Sparkly Exploration Diary!
Terapagos's Sparkly Exploration Diary
There you are.
You two are such good friends.