We’ve finished our
Terastal course Basics tests!
What could be in store for us next?
My heart is racing!
Thank you for submitting
your reports, everyone!
I’ll be giving them all
a good read later!
Now, I should give you
your next assignment...
But first, I have prepared
a little something fun.
Something fun?
What could it be?
I have set up...
...some friendly matches!
I will have you battle
against some special guests.
All right! Battles!
Just what I hoping for!
If we’re doing battles,
I better be up against someone totally strong!
Fret not.
Oh, it appears our guests
have just arrived.
Sorry for the wait.
Ms. Omodaka
is our school’s board chair,
as well as chairwoman
of the Pokémon League.
Today, by special arrangement,
members of the Elite Four will serve as
your opponents in these friendly matches.
The Elite Four?!
Awesome!
Oh?
Guess this could be fun after all.
I look forward to seeing you demonstrate
your skill in these friendly matches.
Yeah!
I’m all fired up now!
They’re really strong, aren’t they?
Winning’s gonna be
out of the question...
Oh, don’t you worry about that.
Nemo! Wait, what do you mean?
The friendly matches will be Tag Battles.
I hear you’ll be paired up with
the Gym Leaders that held your Basics tests.
With the Gym Leaders...?
Ooh, then maybe...
We might stand a chance!
Everybody!
Electrowebbing your eyes!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
It’s Nanjamo... But that means...
Madam Dot! Come on!
I’m up first?!
I am the hot-blooded Kihada!
Allow me to be your judge!
Osu!
Osu...
Good.
So then, who’s our opponent?
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Showdown! The Paldea Elite Four
Missies! Nice to meet you!
Poppy of the Elite Four...
Don’t you underestimate her, now.
Age means nothing
when you’re battlin’ it up!
I-I know!
Come on out, Poppy’s friends!
This is Dekanukins and Daioukins!
The final evolution of Kanuchan?
Evolved Pokémon can be scary opponents!
If the student’s Pokémon is knocked out,
the battle is over!
The student wins if even one of
the Elite Four member’s Pokémon is defeated!
Got all that?
Osu!
Also, the Gym Leader
is forbidden from Terastallizing.
A-Ack! Even though Harabari’s
hyper-dazzly when he Terastallizes?
The student is the star of this battle.
Sniff...
Okay!
Mm-hmm.
You look fired up, Kuwassu.
I’m counting on you!
Harabari, you’re looking
nice and squishy too!
And so!
Let the battle begin!
Let’s go! Harabari, use Discharge!
Poppy’s cute li’l Pokémon
are all steely-hard,
so soft attacks like those
are no sweat, adorbs!
“Soft” squishy bodies can be cute, though!
Well, my Daioukins
is super cute, too! So...
Sandstorm!
All of ‘em got caught in it!
Dekanuchan and Daioudou
are Steel types,
so the Sandstorm
doesn’t affect them.
That’s an Elite Four member for ya! She’s got Double Battles down pat.
Dekanukins! Giant Hammer!
Reflector!
Kuwassu!
U-Umm...
Sitting still won’t make
the sandstorm stop stinging!
This is turning into a battle
between Elite Four and Gym Leader...
It’s too much for the student...
The battle has only just begun.
Dot can handle it!
Kuwassu, hang in there!
The Reflector’s gonna protect
Kuwassu for a while.
You can try anything you want!
Go get ‘em!
All right...
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
Now! Aqua Break!
No good?
That was a good idea, miss!
But don’t forget about my Daioukins!
Dekanukins! Brick Break!
Ack! My Reflector!
It went “Crick-crack, snap!”
She’s so strong...
Missies! Time to say bye-bye!
Daioukins, you use Rock Slide!
Dekanukins, you use Rock Smash!
Wellzen, Harabari...
Slack Off!
Poppy’s Pokémon are the strongest!
That’s it!
Kuwassu!
Do that on Harabari’s belly!
Hmm, hmm?
Faster!
Is that...?
Harabari’s ability...
Making Electribbity!
It generates electricity
when its abs shake from impact,
and it can store that electricity up!
Belly-ve I getcha!
Didn’t expect a Kuwassu
and Harabari collab!
That squishy belly’s so funny!
Then we’ll use
a steely-hard Giant Hammer!
Nanjamo!
Quick, do something!
Got it!
Harabari! Sit-Up Max!
Is that even a real move?!
Now!
Dazzle and sparkle
as bright as you can!
All right...
Dazzle, go viral, and shine on!
Kuwassu!
Aqua Break!
Go for it, Kuwassu!
Dekanukins! You can’t lose!
No good...?
Everybody! Attention!
Oh my, when did he get there?!
Let’s go! High voltage rolling in!
My bad if you get shocked!
Electromagnetic Cannon!
Daioudou is unable to battle!
The winners are Dot and Nanjamo!
The steely got a shock from the squishy!
Nose wet, adorbs...
Oh, right! Since they
took one of them down...
Dot’s side wins!
Thank you!
Nanjamo really is good at this...
Ain’t that just like me?
Madam Dot, the viewers,
even the opponent...
You gotta make sure everyone’s pumped!
That was an interesting battle.
I hear they call them “dazzling” battles.
I see... So this is what “dazzle” means...
I’m glad Poppy is enjoying herself as well.
I lost, but that was still
a wowie fun battle!
Yeah...
Huh?
You beat me,
so how come you’re not happy?!
Right, right!
The winner’s gotta live it up a little!
You lined everything up for me.
I didn’t win because I was any good...
Miss, I think you’re thinking too hard.
Huh...?
Next time we battle,
I hope it’s a battle where we can
really live it up and really get all moody!
Yeah!
But more importantly...
The next battle’s starting!
See ya!
Bye-bye!
Kuwassu...
You did great.
I’m gonna get stronger, too...
So let’s try our best...
Us and Kanuchan!
Wh-What was that?!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Onigohri, use Self-Destruct!
U-Umitrio!
Hooray!
All Pokémon are unable to battle!
The battle is over!
The winner is Aoki!
Huh?!
But Onigohri just blew him to bits!
If all Pokémon are knocked out
via Self-Destruct,
it counts as a loss for
the side that used Self-Destruct!
Why’s that matter?! A win’s a win!
Your personal rules don’t apply
once you’ve entered society.
Too bad, eh Sandwich gal?
I never lose when it’s
no holds barred, you hear me?!
That was a shock...
Crazy stuff...
I’m up next!
Do your best, Roy!
We’ll follow your lead, Dot!
Right, Hogator?!
You’re brimming with enthusiasm!
Yeah!
Students!
Mr. Colza!
Hah!
Now, get over here, Roygarde.
Roygar... Oh, you mean me?
Show me how well you’re bearing fruit.
I can’t wait!
Mr. Colza, let’s have a good battle!
Indeed. I can see you’re raring to go.
We’re facing Mr. Hassaku!
This battle is a sure bet for us.
Hass uses Dragon types.
You can learn much from him, too.
I get it!
Rekkuuza’s a Dragon type, too...
Okay! Now I’m even more fired up!
I apologize for the wait.
Roy... Colz...
Please go easy on me.
I wanna learn more about Dragon types!
So I’m gonna fight with all I’ve got!
Even a baby dragon aspires
to spread its wings...
Then I shall respond
with my full power in turn!
Seglaive! Appryuu!
Go, Oliño!
Everyone ready?
Well then, let the battle begin!
Let’s go, Hogator! Nitro Charge!
Seglaive, use Ice Shard!
Dodge it!
Appryuu, use Acid Bomb!
I don’t think so!
Oliño, use Seed Bomb!
Hogator, keep charging in!
Keep up that fighting spirit!
What happened?
Not good! Get back!
Hogator!
Seglaive! Giant Sword Charge!
There’s Hass for you.
Sensitive, yet intense.
What do you mean?
Seglaive’s ability
is Thermal Exchange.
Fire moves raise Seglaive’s attack.
Tell me that ahead of time!
Preconceptions are an artist’s bane.
If Fire won’t work,
then use Charm Voice!
Charm Voice is super effective
on Dragon types!
Appryuu, use G-Power!
Dodge it, Hogator! Look up!
That’s not an apple!
Hogator...
What should I do?
When you feel lost,
fall back on passion!
Let your passion topple the walls
that stand before you!
Got it.
Hogator, let’s fight with Fire moves!
Flamethrower!
Let me join in on your passion!
Oliño, use Helping Hand!
He’s got good taste in moves!
Roy really is bearing fruit!
Collaborative art by Roy and Colz!
A truly fine work of fire art!
Appryuu! Twister!
This is way too hot!
What’s he planning,
powering up his opponent’s moves like that?
Allow me to participate
in this collaboration of yours.
Seglaive!
Like a moth to a flame...
Ah!
Thermal Exchange?!
Indeed!
Seglaive! Giant Sword Charge!
That’s Oliño’s Grass Knot!
What a relief!
Our art is not yet complete!
Dragon types really are amazing...
But we’re no pushovers, either!
Mr. Colza, gimme a Seed Bomb!
Hmm?
Very well.
Oliño, use Seed Bomb!
Hogator, use Flamethrower!
Seglaive! Appryuu! Use Protect!
Let us create yet more art!
Oliño, fire a giant Energy Ball!
We’ve gotta move too, Hogator!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Terastallize!
Hogator!
Go all out with Flamethrower!
Raging passion and energy!
As you’ve told me before, Colz...
Art is creation and destruction!
In which case...
Seglaive, use Blizzard!
What’s this?!
Giant Sword Charge!
What?!
This battle is over!
The winner is Hassaku!
Excellent work, Hass.
You destroyed, and you created!
A marvelous work of art!
That was a good battle.
Roy, Colz, I thank you.
That was so much fun!
Me and Hogator got to do stuff
we could never do alone!
All the Pokémon moves
kept adding onto one another...
I get it...
Battles are made together!
Avant-garde! Well said!
A battle is built together with
those you compete against!
Yeah!
Perhaps I’ve come to understand a little more
about Hass’s devotion toward teaching.
As a Gym Leader, I am pleased to
watch your skills improve, Roygarde.
Huh?
Hmm?
Roy has grown!
Colz has grown as a Gym Leader!
And so have I...
Hass is a passionate man
through and through.
Huh?
You fought well,
considering it was Mr. Hassaku!
But I still don’t stand a chance
against Rekkuuza.
I’ve gotta get stronger.
You can still get much,
much stronger!
Thanks, Nemo!
I’m gonna lose a whole bunch
and get a ton stronger!
I can’t wait!
You’re up next, Liko.
Yeah. Look after Terapagos for me.
Show ‘em your stuff!
Liko! Go for it!
Thank you!
Let’s go, Nyarote!
I’m giving this battle all I’ve got,
just like Dot and Roy did!
Kyojiohn is unable to battle!
The winner is Chili!
Weren’t you listening?
You lose if your Pokémon is knocked out.
I cannot sacrifice my backup
just to ensure my own survival.
You serious?! Throwing it over that
makes the whole thing pointless.
Nor is there any point
in a disgraceful victory.
It’s nonsense, but I think I get it.
Gotta stick to your aesthetic,
I suppose.
Well that’s that, then.
‘Preciate the hard work!
Thank you for your hard work.
I’m glad I get to battle
alongside you, Ms. Kaede!
Let’s put our hearts
into enjoying this battle.
Right!
Heyo! Your pal Chili here!
I’m on a winnin’ streak right now,
but don’t let that psych you out.
Come at me!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Ice Dragon Pokémon, Seglaive.
Seglaive
Ice Dragon Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ice
Seglaive
Ice Dragon Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ice
Its most prominent feature
is this large dorsal fin.
Height
2.1m
It can absorb a certain thing through its fin
to convert it into power,
Weight
210.0kg
but do you know what that thing is?
What does it absorb through its fin?
Cold air
Electricity
Heat
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it absorb through its fin?
C: Heat
The answer is C: Heat!
It can absorb heat though its fin,
and convert it into power.
With that power,
it can make its fin into a giant sword of ice!
Next episode
Roy and Dot, your battles were amazing!
Mr. Hassaku was so strong...
I wanna get stronger,
and then face him again!
I’d like to test my strength
without Nanjamo helping, too!
It’s finally your turn next, Liko!
Ms. Chili sure seems strong,
so I’m kinda nervous!
Thank you, Nyarote.
I’ll be fine.
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters:
Liko VS Chili! Beyond the Battle
Make sure to watch!