We have finally arrived at Rakua.
Wild Pokémon—including Legendary Pokémon—
live in complete comfort...
It’s truly a Pokémon paradise.
When we headed deeper
into Rakua, we discovered...
...the barrier that Pagogo formed
to protect these lands, one hundred years ago.
Then, after removing the barrier
and going inside...
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Rising Voltteccers VS The Explorers!
Rakua...
Paradise.
Journey’s end...
Betrayal...
Be prepared.
My wish...
Rakurium...
Eternal...
...Blessing.
How did the Explorers...?
So we were followed?
You guys’re total suckers!
We knew Rakua’s location
right from the outset.
For quite some time,
we Explorers have watched over these lands.
So that place I saw back then...
But to reach the location
where the Rakurium slumbers...
...we needed the barrier
to be removed.
And the only one able to do that...
Yes.
The sole key to it: Terapagos.
We were seeking Terapagos to make it
remove the barrier with its awakened powers.
And while cute li’l Sango was
runnin’ ‘round nibbling on sweets,
you were doin’
our whole job for us!
No way...
Then, our whole adventure...?
They’ve been using us
the whole time?!
You, the Rising Voltteccers,
traveled the world, gathered the Six Heroes,
and bore the burden
of awakening Terapagos on our behalf.
Meaning the reason
you didn’t come to steal Terapagos...
...was to get us to
lift the seal on Rakua?
Thank you so much
for your cooperation.
You have simply been dancing
in the palms of our hands!
You sure about that?
I betcha those kids...
...would tell you something like:
No!
Our adventure was ours,
and ours alone!
We decided to do this!
Aided by my team with Nyarote...
...and by Roy and Dot, Friede and his crew,
and everyone else...
We came all this way
for Pagogo’s sake!
None of this has been for you!
Liko!
Yup, dead-on!
As you like.
We will eliminate you now.
So now that Rakua’s opened up,
we’re just a bunch of nuisances to you?
Our goals will be accomplished
in short order.
Master Gibeon will most assuredly obtain the Rakurium,
leading the Explorers to even greater heights.
Not if we can help it!
Blacky! Ohbem!
If it’s a 2v2 you’re after...
Lizardon!
That Ohbem in the back bothers me...
But Blacky comes first!
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Blacky! Foul Play!
Lizardon! Air Slash!
Ohbem! Psychokinesis!
Dodge it with
your Shadow Clones, Cap!
Just warming up, were you?
Cap! Lizardon!
Use Thunder Punch
and Dragon Claw on Blacky!
Reflector!
Ohbem, use 100,000 Volts
on Lizardon!
Cap!
So he was targeting
Lizardon’s weakness...
But...
Too bad, eh?
Cap’s ability is Lightning Rod.
He absorbs Electric moves
and powers himself up.
How very careless of me.
In which case, Blacky...
Bark Out!
Hang in there!
Ohbem.
Cap! Hit ‘em with a Voltteccer!
Skill Swap.
What?!
The move that trades abilities
with the target... Skill Swap.
Indeed. Ohbem has taken
that Pikachu’s ability, Lightning Rod.
Meaning that we’ll
get to power up instead.
So that’s it...
When Ohbem used 100,000 Volts before,
it was to determine Cap’s ability.
All part of my plan.
You’re tough...
We’re fighting just as intently
as you are, after all.
So, now that
the Pikachu is worthless...
Ohbem! Blacky! Target Lizardon!
Bark Out! 100,000 Volts!
Do not let up!
This is bad...
Looks like Cap’s got an idea...
Okay.
Lizardon!
For now, just pull back!
Full-on defense. How pitiful.
Huh?
Trying to isolate Blacky...?
Use Thunder Punch, Cap!
Ohbem!
Too bad for you, hmm?
No dice, huh?
What is that?!
A huge Purin?
A pink Onigohri?
Whaddaya think? This here’s the Onipurin
I caught in Paldea’s Great Crater!
That cry... That’s a Paradox Pokémon
called Screaming Tail!
Does that mean you were
even watching us in the Great Crater?!
Enough chatter. Let’s get going!
Let’s kick it!
Onipurin! Blast Waves!
Kyojiohn! Wide Guard!
Achigator! Charm Voice!
We need to break through
that guard...
Nyarote!
Use Magical Leaf on Kyojiohn!
Kyojiohn! Stone Edge!
Okay, then...
Try a controlled Magical Leaf!
Stone Edge!
What a noisy crowd.
Charem! Meditation!
Welcamo!
Use Aqua Break on Charem!
We’re not done yet!
Aim for the feet with Kick Down!
You’ve gathered
your strength, Charem...
Assisted Power!
Welcamo!
Onipurin! Play Rough!
Don’t give up, Achigator!
Nitro Charge!
Then... try a Flamethrower!
Blast Waves!
Achigator!
Ain’t no way I’m losing,
not to you! Got that?!
One more round of Blast Waves!
Kyojiohn! Wide Guard!
Nyarote! Lightning Speed!
Cancel the guard!
Nyarote, switch to a Surprise Attack!
Nyarote!
Kyojiohn has a complete grasp
of your attack patterns.
Salt Pickle her!
Get back!
They just keep
predicting our attacks...
Give up.
You’ll never topple our wall.
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Liko... Roy...
You haven’t time
to worry about them!
I’ve really gotta
come up with a strategy...
Welcamo!
Fire a volley of Aqua Cutters!
If I can throw off Charem’s footing,
that should disrupt its movement.
A terribly shoddy strategy.
They saw right through us!
Mind Headbutt!
Oh, no!
Hang in there, Welcamo!
Charem is a Pokémon that excels
at predicting its foe’s movements.
Any tactic you might think of
will be meaningless.
There has to be
some way through this...
If they can predict our tactics, how about
we make something unpredictable happen...?
Blast Waves!
Charm Voice!
That’s it! Welcamo!
Launch a volley of Air Cutters!
Do not panic.
Dodge them.
Hasty tricks won’t save you.
What?!
Now’s our chance, Welcamo!
Aqua Cutter!
Good going, Welcamo!
What’s wrong?
Stumped already, are we?
Lizardon!
Take Cap with you and fly up!
Just as I was trying to guess your next move,
you form up into a single target!
Blacky! Bark Out!
Ohbem! 100,000 Volts!
Hang in there!
Cap! Use Shadow Clones and jump!
A distraction...
It matters not. Target Lizardon!
Blacky! Hurry and thr—
Lizardon.
Surpass...
...your potential!
So, that was your goal...
Ohbem! Get away from Lizardon!
Cap! Use Thunder Punch on Blacky!
Now! Tera Burst!
He lured it in
with an Electric move?!
It’s super effective on Ohbem!
Blacky...
managed to hang on, huh?
Taking out your own ally...
I never imagined you would
sacrifice your Pikachu.
I took advantage of Ohbem’s ability,
which you traded over to me.
My Ohbem’s ability allows it to predict
and avoid attacks from allies... Telepathy.
With that effect on Cap,
Lizardon’s Tera Burst can’t hit him.
This can’t be...
How did you know my Ohbem’s ability?!
Oh, that was... Well, y’know...
My intuition.
Intuition?
You made a decision like that
without a shred of proof...?
You never know what’ll happen
in a Pokémon Battle.
No matter how much data you analyze,
you’re never gonna beat us.
Blacky... Bark Out!
Give ‘em a real good wallop, Cap!
Use Voltteccer!
Let’s keep up the momentum!
Dot...!
All right... Nyarote!
Hop around with your bud!
Acrobatics!
This can work, Nyarote!
Keep attacking like that!
That strike was faster than I anticipated.
Admirably done.
Kyojiohn. Self-Regenerate.
It recovered...
But the way things are,
the battle’s just being dragged out...
I’ll stamp you out
in one fell swoop!
A Terastal Orb!
Tower above all!
Kyojiohn!
Kyojiohn...
...Terastallized?!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
Stone Edge!
The way things are,
we’re going to lose...
Right now is
our last chance to win!
This is the end! Salt Pickling!
Nyarote! Surprise Attack!
Dodge it, Kyojiohn!
Got you! Succumb to Salt Pickling!
Nyarote!
That was still a Surprise Attack?
Right!
A whole lot of Magical Leaves!
It’s super effective!
Hey, now... What’s the big idea?!
You’re all so awesome...
Achigator! Let’s show ‘em
who’s got real spirit!
Huh?! Don’t you even dare
get fired up like that!
Onipurin, use Play Rough!
We’re not scared!
Burn bright! Nitro Charge!
Put him in the dirt, Onipurin!
You are strong, Achigator!
That totally cracks me up!
Where’re ya goin’?!
Achigator went flying!
Huh?!
Go! Flamethrower!
Dodge it, Onipurin!
Rargh!
Now you’ve done it!
Onipurin!
Get dolled up all glittery-like!
She Terastallized... But...
Achigator! Nitro Charge!
Play Rough at full power!
Blast Waves!
Charm Voice!
Blow ‘em away, Onipurin!
Don’t give in, Achigator!
She only just caught that Pokémon...
It must lack experience
in real battles.
That’s not all.
Even in the midst of battle,
We did it, Achigator!
those three are
inspiring each other.
Roy...
Amazing...
This ain’t over yet, ya hear?!
I accept defeat.
Cap! Lizardon!
You did great. Thank you.
Now do you get it?
I’m not letting you have your—
Where’d he go?!
Huh?!
Is that...
...the Rakurium?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Paradox Pokémon, Sandy Locks.
Sandy Locks
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Electric/Ground
Sandy Locks
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Electric/Ground
A certain magazine claims it’s
a ten-thousand-year-old Rarecoil.
Height
2.3m
Weight
60.0kg
But do you know what the black,
fur-like substance covering its body is?
What is the black fur-like substance covering its body?
Rubber
Iron sand
Wigs
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What is the black fur-like substance
covering its body?
B: Iron sand
What is the black fur-like substance
covering its body?
B: Iron sand
The answer is B: Iron sand!
It sticks to its body due to
the strong magnetic force emitted by its units.
You can tell how strong a Sandy Locks’s
magnetic force is by how much iron sand it has!
Next episode
What?
What happened?!
Let’s go check it out!
There’s so many pink crystals...
Are these all Rakurium?!
Amethio, Spinel...
And is that... Gibeon?
It looks like the Explorers are doing
something with the Rakurium, but...
What’s wrong, Pagogo?
Look! From inside the crystal!
Could it be...? Are you...?!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Guidance of the Black Rekkuuza!
The Guidance of the Black Rekkuuza
Don’t miss it!