An old friend of my grandma stole
the Ancient Monster Ball and caused quite a panic!
We managed to get it back,
and then he told us about a ball artisan
who is interested in rare Monster Balls.
Hopefully this person knows something
about the Ancient Monster Ball...
I swear...
What were you thinking?!
I’m so sorry... I was practicing
throwing Monster Balls...
Do that stuff outside!
There’s important wiring
running through the entire ship.
If even a single wire—
Orio, the gauges aren’t working right.
You gotta check ‘em ASAP.
This is awful!
The refrigerator is broken!
Orio!
The elevator’s stuck!
Lucky can’t get out!
Hey... I’m not getting enough voltage here.
I can’t recharge.
You gotta do something!
Gah... Okay, fine, I get it!
You all need my help, right?!
I’m sure she’s used to it,
but Orio really has it rough...
Is that our stop?
What’s that?
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Orio and the Monster Ball Artisan
Whoa! Those things were Monster Balls?!
It’s really imposing...
So, what’s Orio up to?
Hmm, yes, I see...
I see... So that’s how it is.
Absolutely no good!
“No good”?!
Sure, it looks nice,
but the gears are out of sync.
And there’s so much
redundant piping.
No good at all!
Absolutely no understanding
of the machinery!
That’s what you were looking at?
When it comes to machinery...
...she’s got very particular standards.
Such a shame...
With just a few tweaks, it could make for
a really impressive installation.
Uh... Visitors?
Yes...
Hang on just a sec...
I’ll prepare some tea.
Um...
It should be here somewhere...
There!
Are you all right?
This is what happens
when you don’t stay tidy.
I’m just fine!
She’s quite a lively person...
Is this a Monster Ball?
Yeah.
It’s a recreation of the balls they used to make
in the Hisui Region way back when.
You do this, and then this, and...
Wow, that’s so cool!
You’ve got a discerning eye,
young lady!
Name’s Karna.
It’s a pleasure to meet you!
Thank you, Booby.
I’m sorry... I never knew that Tepen-san
was such a dishonest man.
I told him that money is no object
when it comes to me and rare Monster Balls...
You collect Monster Balls?
Sure do! Monster Balls
are the stuff of dreams!
The unfading love
and passion of their makers!
Plus, the particularities of individual styles!
I, too, want to make balls
tightly packed with such particularities!
Hmm...
Roy, didn’t you have something to ask?
Yup!
This is my treasure,
the Ancient Monster Ball!
Do you know any—?
What is this?
I’ve never seen anything like it!
The shape, the patterns,
the elegant coloration, and this antique motif!
This is simply, simply wonderful!
You figured something out?
Not even a little bit!
But I don’t mind
not understanding a ball fully.
Its mere existence is fascinating!
Whoa, look at all the balls!
Did you craft all of these?
Yup. They’re prototypes!
Some don’t open right...
Others open too readily...
Some might be the wrong size.
But all those failures
will eventually lead to success!
In other words,
they’re finalized products-to-be!
Talk about optimistic.
I could learn a thing or two from her.
Karna-san! Mind if I test those balls?
Huh?
I want to do some
ball-throwing practice with those!
I wanna try throwing
lots of different kinds of balls!
Wow... You have
a discerning eye, young man!
My design notes for each ball
are in there, too. Help yourself!
All right!
Let’s get right to practicing, Hogator!
Be careful! There are a lot of
strong Pokémon wandering about the area!
Got it!
Aw, again?
That’s a machine that makes
Monster Balls, right?
Yeah.
I got lots of orders for original balls,
so I bought a machine
that could mass-produce them.
But...
Machines just aren’t any good.
Have you kept up with maintenance?
Maintenance?
The blades here are worn down.
Ah, and this needs oil.
Oh, and over here...
It’s all out of coolant!
No wonder it keeps exploding!
Let me borrow this.
Right, and then this goes...
And this plug goes here, I see...
Sorry she’s so gung-ho.
Okay, turn it on!
All right!
It’s beautiful!
See, Karna?
Just like that, with a little love
and care, it’s up and running.
So don’t call it useless, okay?
Ah, yes, you’re right. Sorry.
It’s not the machine’s fault.
Machines have their own feelings,
passions, and particularities.
While we’re at it...
Why don’t your Pokémon help out, too?
All right, let’s give it a go!
Just imagine that there’s
a Pokémon over there...
Hup!
Yeah! That felt great!
Let’s see...
“Rocket Ball:
“Flies much straighter than regular balls.”
I see...
Okay, next up...
Hup!
Uh?
Ow!
Wh-What the heck?
“Boomerang Ball:
“Will come right back when thrown, so it’s handy
for catching Pokémon that are at your feet.”
That’s way too hard to use!
Okay, next!
“Bomb-Bomb Ball:
“May sometimes explode
before being thrown. Exercise caution.”
The heck is that?!
So, Orio got real chummy with Karna,
and started tinkering with her machines.
We just left her to it.
She won’t be back for a while.
She’s a total sucker for
tinkering with machinery, after all.
Sounds fine to me.
Orio needs a breather, too.
Yeah, she always seems so busy.
Because you keep making
such crazy demands.
Wha—?! No!
It’s Murdock constantly
keeping her busy!
Huh?! N-No, it’s not me!
Molly asks way too much of Orio, too!
I don’t...
It was Friede!
No, Murdock!
Gotta be Molly!
Friede!
Murdock!
Doesn’t look like
it’s any one person’s fault to me.
Molly!
Just you watch!
I will catch you,
Pokémon over there!
...or something like that.
Wow!
All right! That ought to
up the efficiency by about 30 percent.
Turn it on.
Wow! Incredible!
It’ll mass-produce these
without a hitch now!
Getting the Pokémon to help out...
I never would’ve considered it!
And look how much fun
they’re having!
You’re a real genius!
It’s a lot like the engine room on the airship,
so this stuff’s pretty routine for me.
And I gotta say, the Monster Balls
you make are really beautiful.
Not many craftsmen can pull off
delicate ornamentation like this.
Something my teacher
made sure to impress upon me...
...was that you may as well keep Pokémon in the best balls.
Ones that show the creator’s particularity.
I get you!
I want to create the best environment
for our Pokémon, too!
In the sense that we make stuff
to keep Pokémon comfy,
you could say our jobs
are pretty similar!
Hey, Orio?
Would you like to stay here
and work with me?
Huh?
With your engineering
and my ornamentation...
I’m sure we could make
something amazing together!
Like, hmm, let’s see...
Like a flying Monster Ball!
A flying Monster Ball?
I like the sound of that!
Orio might be leaving the crew!
Th-Th-This is awful!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Man, I just keep messing up!
Okay! Next up I’ll read the note first!
“Chase Ball:
“Automatically heads towards
nearby Pokémon.”
That’s it!
Right, then...
Huh?
“But it often fails to open.”
You’re kidding me!
Ga—
Galarian... Matadogas?!
Okay!
Is Orio going to stay here
and work with Karna-san?
And... does that mean
she’ll be leaving the crew?
Hmm? What’s up, Liko?
Your pep battery out of juice?
No, um...
I need a quick break, too.
Orio... Is every day fun for you?
Huh? Sure is.
Even if it can get pretty hard to deal with at times.
Why did you start traveling with Friede?
What? Did I never tell you?
I never asked...
I used to work at a shipyard
in the Hoenn Region.
It was fun, and the work was rewarding.
My coworkers were nice, too.
I felt fulfilled.
I had a nice, stress-free job.
But sometimes I found myself thinking...
“Is this really what I want out of life?”
“Is this job I have right now
really the most important thing to me?”
“What is it I really want to do?”
And that’s when Friede contacted me.
Orio. I’m here to ask you
to lend me your expertise.
Convert the Asagi into
the best airship in the world!
Mmm—
Eh?!
Are you an idiot?
Can you do it?
Those words lit a flame in my heart.
I’ll just have to try!
I had no idea
if I could pull it off...
But the only way
to know for sure was to try.
It’s a simple fact that Friede’s words
were the spark that started it all.
But, just maybe...
...I had always wanted
to put my own skills to the test.
And so, I realized something
the moment I finished converting the ship.
Namely, what I really wanted to do.
What you wanted to do?
Yeah, it was...
Roy! Hogator!
The Pokémon Karna mentioned?!
Nyahoja?
Hogator!
Oh, no!
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Nyahoja!
A Poison type!
This is a hopeless match-up...
Let’s do this, Metagross!
Poison attacks don’t work
on Steel types!
What’s all the noise?
Send it flying, Metagross!
Well done, Metagross!
Follow it up with a Metal Claw!
All right!
Amazing, Orio!
Cap!
Counting on you, Cap!
Ugh... There’s just too many of them!
That’s it!
Orio! Boost the output
on the machinery!
Huh?! You’re telling me
to make them run faster?!
Yeah! Right up to the limit
of what they can handle!
Can you do it?
I’ll just have to try!
Metagross! Elekid! Come with me!
What are you doing, Orio?!
You come, too!
Uh... Huh?!
Orio, it’s gonna go just like last time...
Friede! The machine can’t handle much more!
Do you want to destroy it?!
Just a little more!
Oh, fine! We’ll make it hold out!
But...!
It’ll be fine!
This is Friede we’re talking about.
He must have some sort of plan!
That’s what I was waiting for!
Huh?
What’s going on?
Matadogas: Galarian Form.
Poison Gas Pokémon. Poison/Fairy type.
Consumes particles
that contaminate the air.
Instead of leaving droppings,
it expels clean air.
I see...
The smoke from the chimneys
is a delicious meal to them!
I swear... That guy’s always up to something wild,
or asking for something totally crazy...
All right. Now the air’ll be cleaner, too.
Thank you for everything, Orio.
Karna... I’m sorry.
I can’t work here.
I thought you’d say that.
Hmm?
A parting gift.
Don’t forget to do maintenance
on your machines!
Will you come back if I do forget?
I’ll come back,
even from the ends of the earth!
What I wanted to do?
Yeah.
I wanted to do...
...things that I’d never done before.
Eh?
It was gonna be rough,
but I figured if I got on this ship,
I’d have plenty of “firsts”...
Plenty of chances to do
stuff I’d never done before.
Wasn’t it the same for you?
Perhaps it was.
Orio! The propeller’s acting strange!
You gotta come have a look!
Something’s weird
with the air conditioning!
Orio! The stove won’t light!
The observation deck’s
doors won’t open!
Sorry! I made another hole in the wall!
You gotta do something!
Oh, my. What a mess.
Okay, fine, I get it.
You all need my help, right?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today we’ll be looking at
the Poison Gas Pokémon, Galarian Matadogas.
Matadogas (Galarian Form)
Poison Gas Pokémon
Type: Poison/Fairy
Matadogas (Galarian Form)
Poison Gas Pokémon
Type: Poison/Fairy
This Pokémon sucks in dirty air through its mouth,
then expels it via the hat-like protuberance atop its head.
Height
3.0m
Weight
16.0kg
Do you know what state the air exits in?
In what state does air exit the protuberance?
Clean
Dirty
Poison gas
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that end in "-s"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Orio here! You can leave machines and rap to me!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
In what state does
air exit the protuberance?
A: Clean
In what state does
air exit the protuberance?
A: Clean
The answer is A: Clean!
Galarian Matadogas gets its nutrition
from poisonous substances in polluted air.
It takes the poison into its own body,
and the leftover clean air exits through the protuberances.
A true gentlemanly Pokémon,
helping everyone out without them knowing it...
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
I bring you today’s Gurumin vid
while doing squats!
I have to hone my senses, or else I’ll tumble
and fall on the mysterious purple liquid!
One!
Two!
Three!
A-Aggh! I cramped my leg!
I’m not okay...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Slippery, Clangy Mystery Pokémon?!