We went to see the former president of Exceed,
Mr. Crave, but what we found waiting for us...
...was a trap set by the Explorers.
While under the effects
of the Super Strong Spheres,
the Six Heroes attacked us.
We managed to negate the Rakurium
using Pagogo’s might,
but now, the Six Heroes seem to be
shrouded in an even stronger power.
Seems the experiment
was largely a success.
With Terapagos in such a state,
they have no chance of winning.
What a letdown.
Tebrim, Pagogo...
Thank you for all your hard work.
Roy! Ult!
Masquernya! Carbou!
We’re going to save the Six Heroes!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Powerfully Strive for Greater Heights
That power’s unreal...
If those attacks land...
Even so,
let’s just try to find our chance!
Their speed’s on another level, too...
Everyone!
Keep a close eye on your foe!
Stay calm and dodge!
I... can’t do this...
Ult!
What’re you doing?!
At this point...
We’re outta luck...
Cap, that’s too reckless!
If you use Voltteccer
in that state...!
Cap!
Yamirami!
Masquernya!
Taikaiden! Achigator!
They put ‘em on the ropes
in no time flat!
The equilibrium they fought to maintain
has collapsed.
Thousand Arrows!
That’s... Zygarde’s...
Amethio!
You came to help!
Thanks for the save.
But... who’re you?
That can wait.
Ooh...
Choosing this moment to arrive...
Now things are getting interesting.
An unforeseen nuisance has arrived.
Pampered li’l Amethio!
Let’s have some fun!
I leave it to you, Zygarde.
Armorgaw, counting on you too!
Onigohri!
Kyojiohn!
Let’s go!
Right!
Amethio.
Lend Carbou Soublades’s power.
His power?
Of course!
Soublades!
Use Sword of Regrets on Carbou!
The ability Kindled Fire...
Now, Carbou can push even further!
All right!
We’ve gotta fire ourselves up again, too!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Gah! I wanna join in!
Help me out, Kairyu!
Six Heroes!
Get them!
Carbou, use Fire Vortex on Oliva!
It’s super effective!
That’ll stop it from moving.
Soublades! Sword of Regrets!
Carbou!
Remember your battle with Windie!
Ember!
Carbou, jump!
It hit! A Kindled Fire Ember!
Kairyu!
Uhh... Just get ‘em!
It’s gonna catch up!
We need a plan...
Ult! Bring Kairyu over near Lucario!
Huh?!
Kairyu!
Over there!
Now! Lucario, pull back!
Just like that time
those Haganail collided...
Time to finish it!
Lucario! Luster Cannon!
Kairyu! Destroyer Beam!
Go!
Carbou!
Soublades!
Armorgaw!
Onigohri, pummel ‘em!
No way...
How do we...?
We can’t...
Just stop already!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Just stop already!
The effects wore off?
Record this data!
Sir!
Quite right.
Then, as you wish,
we shall “just stop already.”
Superb results. Withdraw.
Understood.
Liko! Roy!
Dot!
Wh—
She evolved into Dekanuchan!
We’ll get you fully treated
once we get back to the ship.
Take a nice long rest.
Capabilities that far outclass
those of Strong Spheres...
Yet another vexing item
for us to contend with.
I can’t believe those scumbags
used the Six Heroes like that...
Zygarde’s power was also not yet complete.
I apologize for my inadequate strength.
Not at all! Thank you for
saving Liko and the others!
Rising Voltteccers, I wish to sincerely apologize
for the difficulty I’ve caused you.
I don’t like the way
the Explorers do things one bit!
Wait, Ult!
My name is Roy.
I’m Liko.
We’ve been investigating
Exceed’s Strong Spheres for a long time.
We wanted to show you
the effects they have on Pokémon...
...and just how dangerous
they are, Mr. Crave.
Um... I’ve gathered together
all the info we’ve researched so far.
I myself had gotten the feeling
that Strong Spheres were dangerous.
Then you mean...?
But it’s too late to stop them.
Spinel holds the real power at Exceed.
But if you have data...!
Spinel will simply refute it,
using his own research data.
He’ll say that Rakurium is safe...
That Strong Spheres
are perfectly safe products...
I’m not the director,
so there’s nothing I can do.
I’m sorry I couldn’t be of any use—
You’re saying that now?!
You’re really saying that now,
despite knowing all this,
you’re just going to
sit and do nothing?!
What am I supposed to do?
That’s for you to figure out!
I won’t allow you
to simply run away!
Master Amethio...
If we don’t act now,
there’ll be no stopping them!
Once people have Strong Spheres
in significant numbers, it’ll be too late!
I, too, had given up at first,
believing there was nothing I could do.
But then I was reminded...
...to not give up,
and to follow my own path!
Amethio...
What is your path...?
I will gather Grandfather’s Zygarde...
...to aid in erasing the Rakurium!
Crushing Spinel’s ambitions...
That is my path!
And what will you do
once you’re at its end?
I’ll figure that out
when the time comes.
How I can best support
the futures of Pokémon and people...
I’ll figure it out as I proceed!
Was I alone
in living my life this way...?
Gibeon placed me
in a figurehead role as “Director”...
...only for Spinel to now
steal that title from me.
And so on. I’ve lived my whole life
just making excuses.
But as Exceed’s former director,
I do have a responsibility here.
I won’t let the Explorers
do whatever they please any longer!
I’ll fight too! Let me help!
Thank you...
...Father.
I should be the one thanking you.
Thank you, Amethio.
Rising Voltteccers.
We’re aligned in our goals.
Our paths will cross again someday.
Yeah!
How about we head back
to the ship, too?
Good thinking.
I ain’t going.
Huh?
You’re not going?
What’s wrong?
I saw it plain as day
in that battle earlier...
I’m only gettin’ in your way.
That’s not like you...
The Six Heroes got me scared...
I couldn’t do squat!
‘Cause of me,
Yamirami and Kairyu were both...
More... I need more...
More, more, more, more!
I need more strength!
Ult...
Yamirami, you get how I feel?!
All right!
We’re off on a training journey!
A training journey?!
Hold on,
where exactly are you going?
No idea!
Somewhere with strong guys!
Okay but, like he said...
Where, exactly?
What’s wrong?
Achigator...
Carbou...
What’s up with you guys...?
Ult.
Achigator, Carbou,
and all the rest of us...
We all feel the same way.
We want to get stronger,
and rescue the Six Heroes...
That’s how we feel.
So we should all train together!
Let’s get stronger together!
Fine by me, but...
where’re ya gonna train?
Um, well...
Let’s start looking now!
What, you didn’t have
anything in mind?
You didn’t either, remember?
We can just run around all over,
and battle everyone
we mega-lock eyes with!
Training’s got to be
more concrete than that!
Well what the heck’s
a “concrete” then?!
Uhh, well...
The phone! Who’s calling...?
Hey! It’s me!
Ms. Briar?!
Ooh! And I’ve caught you all at once!
Splendid, splendid!
Ms. Briar, you sound kinda...
Precisely right!
I’ve finally been freed from my deadline woes!
My book on Terapagos
is finally going to be published!
Never before have there been
such good tidings!
C-Congratulations...
Now, I’ve kept you waiting
far too long already!
What was it you wanted before?
Um, we were wondering,
about Pagogo...
Pagogo?!
Why, if it’s anything
about Terapagos, fire away!
Or better yet,
you can come meet me!
Huh? Meet you?
I’m currently at Blueberry Academy!
I’ll be waiting for you!
She still ain’t listenin’
to a word anyone says, huh?
But she did get back in contact with us.
She said Blueberry Academy, right?
Tasty-soundin’ school!
It’s Orange Academy’s sister school.
Anne should be there. She was invited
to study as a foreign exchange student.
Of course!
I’ve heard that Blueberry Academy
puts a lot of emphasis on Pokémon Battle education!
Battle?
Which means...
We might be able to
learn more about battling there!
Nice!
All right!
That’s our chance
to get stronger, Achigator!
Training time! Our goal’s to be
the mega-strongest, Yamirami!
Ah, but... I dunno if they’ll even
let us train there...
Let’s go check it out!
I bet it’ll be fine!
I’m sure Carbou
wants to get stronger, too.
And if we want to ask Ms. Briar
about Pagogo,
I think meeting her in person
is our best option!
Right.
Ms. Briar always has perfect timing!
Awright!
We’re headed to Blueberry Academy!
Get a move on, you guys!
You won’t make it there on foot!
We should go back to the ship
and discuss it with everyone first.
Guess you got a point.
In order to rescue the Six Heroes,
we’re going to become stronger.
And we’ll learn more about Pagogo,
so that this time...
Even Terapagos
can threaten us no longer.
Now...
It’s time for
the next stage...
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Mega Evolving today is
the Dragon Pokémon, Kairyu!
Dragon Pokémon
Flying
Kairyu
Dragon Pokémon
Dragon
Flying
Force of Will
Kairyu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Dragon Pokémon
Force of Will
Kairyu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Dragon Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Kairyu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Dragon Pokémon
Dragon
Flying
Mega Evolving has dramatically
powered up its kindness!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It mistakenly thinks it’s kind to end battles early,
rather than letting them drag out!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Burying its foes with mercy
in its heart!