And so!
That’s it for my “Monthly Occulture:
Fact or Fiction Checker” special!
Did y’all have a good time?
And finally, I’ve got a special guest
here with me today!
Grabbing your eyeballs
in my Electric Net!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Nanjamo! It’s been forever!
Madam Gurumin!
Sure been a long brillian-time,
ya read me?!
Now, we’ve got
some news for you guys!
This is short notice, but we’re gonna be
holding a collab event tomorrow!
That’s right!
Details are in the description!
Anyone who wants to meet
Nanjamo and Gurumin,
gather up in
the Hakkou City Central Plaza!
It’s your big chance to meet
in-person at Central Plaza!
We’ll be doing handshakes...
And hugs, if we feel like it! Got all that?
Huh... guhs...?!
I’m gettin’ anxious...
To participate, you’ll need one of these numbered tickets
given out before the event!
Well then, well then...
Grabbing your eyeballs in my Electric Net!
The Electrical Streamer!
This was Nanjamo!
Groovin’!
All right, then...
See ya!
A handshake... from Gurumin...
Or a hug...
I’ve gotta go to that event!
An empty stomach may relish
even a bentou with no main course.
Relish the event-ou!
If I collab with Nanjamo,
my videos are bound to get a ton of hits...
...and my sub count will go up, too.
All so I can raise funds!
Wow! Amazing!
Ahh... I can’t wait!
Ult, you come along with us!
Why should I? I couldn’t care less
about some goofball in a costume.
She’s not just goofing around!
Gurumin’s always holding fun chats
and giving out fantastic advice...
...in order to cheer people up
all over the world!
Clues to Master Amethio’s
whereabouts...
We’re still coming up short, huh?
Yeah.
But we’ve already checked
every likely spot...
But this is no time for us to be kicking back
and musing on things!
Nothing else we can do.
We couldn’t find any trace of
the submarine being moored at any port.
We’re all out of options.
But still... Master Hamber trusted us
with this personally, you know!
Starting tomorrow,
let’s check every last port one more time!
Huh? Tomorrow?!
There a problem with that?
No! I-I just...!
Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
Everyone! Nanjamo and Gurumin’s
event is tomorrow!
Meet up at Central Plaza!
Gurumin...
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Burn Hot, Gurumin Love!
People are having to line up.
That’s good.
Huh?
What are you doing?
What? I’ve got to get my number...
Huh? You’re really...?
I’d let you in without one!
No way!
If I don’t line up and get one fair and square,
I won’t be qualified to meet Gurumin!
Now that’s an ardent Gurumin fan!
Well, if you really want to...
I’m glad you got one, Liko!
Yeah! Number 78!
That’s a pretty good number!
Mr. Grusha!
You’re... Liko.
Mr. Grusha, are you here
for the event, too?
Yeah... I watched a Nanjamo video,
and she mentioned she was holding an event.
So you’re a fan of Ms. Nanjamo!
Well, I suppose I do the sorta stuff
you’d expect a fan to do, at least...
See you around.
Number 6... He got here pretty early...
So Mr. Grusha’s an ardent fan, too...
Wouldn’t have guessed.
There’s a coin over here!
And over here, too!
Nice, I got it! Number 112!
Saidon’s Index number.
That’s some luck!
Honestly...
That happy about it, eh?
With this, I get to meet Gurumin!
Just you wait, Gurumin!
You’ve gotta be kidding me...
Hey! Hey!
Saidon, help me out here!
My number!
My handshake with Gurumin...
My hug with Gurumin...
He’s so beside himself,
I feel like I should hold back...
Are you heading
to the venue already, Dot?
Rehearsal will be starting soon.
I’ve gotta go hash things out
with Nanjamo.
Give it all you’ve got!
The Explorers!
The Rising Voltteccers!
Zir! It’s the Rising Voltteccers!
Ah. That so?
Hey! You’ve gotta
show some enthusiasm!
Huh?
So he’s a fan of Gurumin...
But he lost his numbered ticket?
And by now,
they’ve stopped giving them out...
Are you going to the event, too?
Yeah.
Zir was really
looking forward to it, too...
Mr. Zir.
Um... I don’t really care about it
all that much, so...
How about you go instead of me,
if you wanna?
Don’t lie to me!
C’mon! You have the exact same
Pokémon that Gurumin does!
U-Uh, well, that...
You’re a huge Gurumin fan,
too, aren’t ya?
I could never rob
someone like you of a ticket!
Without that number 112 ticket
I got with my own hands,
I’m not qualified
to go to the event!
Exactly right!
I know how you feel!
Huh?
Let’s look for it!
We’ll help you look for your ticket!
Huh?!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Sorry, Nanjamo.
Ran into a little trouble, so I’m gonna be late.
Hey, hey, Madam Dot!
Rehearsal’s about to start!
I’ll explain what happened later.
By the way,
where do Hakkou City’s drains lead?
Drains?!
What? You’re... that NyahojaSuperfan?!
Yes! I was also shocked when I found out
you were Muscles_of_a_Saidon!
I looked into it, and apparently there’s a big
drainage outlet under the central plaza, but...
Thanks, Nanjamo!
Start the rehearsal without me!
Huh? H-Hold on, Madam Dot!
You mean it might’ve been swept away to somewhere around here?
Apparently, but...
All right!
Let’s get straight to the search!
How do you plan to look for it?
Oh, I know!
Golduck would be good at swimming, so...
Well, about that...
It’s got sensitive skin and can’t swim in sea water.
Blargh!
B-But still, it should be
somewhere around here, right?
Well, there’s a chance
it might’ve washed up somewhere.
Then let’s all split up and search!
Yeah!
Thank you!
I’ll find that ticket,
no matter what!
Still coming up short, huh?
Maybe it’s not here...
Madam Dot!
We’re gonna have serious problems
if you don’t get here soon!
I hear you, Nanjamo.
Sorry. I’ve gotta get going...
Ah, right.
Go on ahead.
Right!
Where’s she off to?
Oh, she left to
get to the event early...
Thank you, everyone.
You’ve done plenty.
Huh?
It wouldn’t be right for you to
run late on my account.
Mr. Zir...
Are you really okay with
not meeting Gurumin?
Got no choice.
And you’re okay with that?
You want to shake hands
with Gurumin, don’t you?
Of course I do, but...
Well, then...
If you want to meet her,
then do it!
Let’s keep searching
until we find it!
Search until we find it...
You’re right.
I’m gonna shake hands
with Gurumin no matter what!
Yeah. Let’s give it one last shot!
I’m sure we’ll find it!
A-Are you okay, Achigator?
Ah! Hey, isn’t that thing stuck to it...?
Number 112...
That’s my numbered ticket!
Whoa! Stop, Saidon!
Saidon!
Umitrio. Garden Eel Pokémon.
Water type.
Despite appearances,
it has a vicious temperament.
It wraps its long bodies around its prey,
then drags it into its den.
That’s really bad...
In that case...
Masquernya,
stop Umitrio from moving!
It burrowed into the sand?
That’s Dig!
Masquernya, on your right!
It did it again...
Golduck!
Saidon, over there!
Saidon!
Nice! Looking good, Achigator!
Are you okay, Achigator?!
Very formidable...
How can we catch it...?
Cap! Thunder Punch!
It stopped moving!
Now! Saidon!
Saidon!
You did it, Saidon!
Saidon, thank you.
And thanks to all of you, too!
You did it!
We’d better hurry!
The event’s about to start!
I’m gonna meet Gurumin!
We made it!
Yo-ssu! Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
It’s everyone’s pal, Gurumin!
Gurumin!
Amazing!
Grabbing your eyeballs
in my Electric Net!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
They’re both so popular.
Everybody! Today, we’ve got
an event with Gurumin and me!
So enjoy to your heart’s content!
Next up is a dance segment!
Yay!
Try dancing along with Welcamo,
a real dance pro!
Now then, who should I call up
to do a powerful dance for us...?
That Saidon there!
Huh?
Yay! Looking good, Saidon!
You’re really gettin’ down!
I’m dancing with Gurumin...
It’s like a dream come true!
Huh? What?
Huh? You wanna dance
with Gurumin?!
No! I told ya,
Gurumin is not a Pokémon!
Why’s this happening?!
Gurumin! I-I love you!
Please keep on doing your best!
Huh? O-Oh, sure!
Thanks, NyahojaSuperfan!
G-Gurumin!
Y-You were incredible!
And so were you!
Thanks for the info on the Pero-Fluffy Cotton Candy
that one time, Muscles_of_a_Saidon!
Gurumin...
Whoa! Sir Grusha!
Nice to see you here!
This event was fun.
I’m counting on you
to keep up the nice streams.
Understood! Well ‘n’ good!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
U-Um! Are you Grusha, by chance?
Yeah.
I’ve always been a huge fan!
Your joyful pro-boarder days were great too,
but I adore “cool-as-ice” Grusha even more!
Ah! Please, let me shake your hand!
Sure.
Thank you so much!
Your Arukujira’s cute too!
Ahh... Now that was fun!
Liko, let’s go pick up Dot.
Yeah!
I have to go and thank them!
Good work today!
Thanks, everyone.
That was so much fun!
Ahh! I’m not looking!
I didn’t see anything!
What?!
Gurumin was a member of the Rising Voltteccers
this whole time... Imagine that.
All this time...
All the things I’ve done...
Guess it really came as a shock...
Yo-ssu!
Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
Didja have fun
at the event tonight?
I had loads of fun!
You’re the best, Gurumin!
Thank you, everyone! For real!
Hey, Zir... That girl...
Yeah. I was thinking the same thing.
Liko.
Could we have a moment?
Amethio is missing...?
We’re searching for Master Amethio...
Not as Explorers, but for ourselves.
Which is why we have
something to ask you.
Please...
Help us look for Master Amethio!
Huh?
Me?
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Mega Evolving today is...
The Shadow Pokémon, Gänger!
Shadow Pokémon
Poison
Gänger
Shadow Pokémon
Ghost
Poison
Cursed Body
Gänger
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shadow Pokémon
Cursed Body
Gänger
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shadow Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Gänger
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shadow Pokémon
Ghost
Poison
Shadow Tag
It’s said that the reason you can’t see its lower body
is because it’s burrowed into another dimension!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Bonds with a Mega Gänger
are twisted indeed.
It will even try to place curses
upon its very own trainer!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Next episode
I never would’ve imagined I’d be
working alongside NyahojaSuperfan someday!
Um...
I never would’ve thought I’d get a chance
to see li’l Nyahoja all grown up, face-to-face!
No! I mustn’t, I mustn’t...
For now, I must prioritize finding Master Amethio.
I can’t let my emotions interfere!
Um...!
No! I can’t, I can’t!
I can’t simply gaze at li’l Masquernya...
I need to focus on my mission!
And... so... To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Carbou’s Wish
Carbou's Wish