Man, this is a mega-drag...
Where’d that jerk Roy get to...?
Hey, you seen somebody
who looks like this?
He should have an Achigator
and Lucario with him.
Oh, that boy had a girl with him.
A girl?!
My name is Liko.
To get back what was stolen from us by the Explorers...
the truth of the Rising Voltteccers,
we’ve set out on a journey once again.
Now having been contacted by Dot,
we’re pursuing a sighting
of Pokémon acting abnormally.
It was around here, wasn’t it?
I think so, yeah...
I know, let’s ask Dot.
It’s been so long...
I’m getting nervous.
Why? That’s kinda weird.
Liko!
Dot! Long time, no see.
I feel kinda bad for
dragging you into all this.
No, I was curious about this myself...
I’ve wondered what happened since then,
and whether it’s truly over...
If the effects of Rakurium really are
what’s behind all these tips, then it’s not over.
And that calls for an investigation.
The three of us have got to do it. And then,
we’ll get back the truth of the Rising Voltteccers!
No doubt.
Hey... If I remember right, the sighting
this time was somewhere around here, yeah?
I’ll send it over now!
Finally found ya, Roy!
Ack! Girl!
Wait, Yamirami!
Let’s see what’s going on first.
What?! I am not scared!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Follow the Rakurium Signs
This is the right area.
It might be dangerous,
so you two be careful.
Right.
Achigator, you go search
from the skies with Taikaiden!
I’m counting on you!
We’ll look from ground level.
So this is how you’ve been
investigating with them.
Yep.
You and your team
should catch up with me later.
He kinda feels
more dependable now...
Let’s go!
What a beautiful place...
It’s right nearby Kanto... But we’ve never even
been here, have we, Masquernya?
Ahh... This brings back memories...
Back when we traveled around Paldea together.
The Terastal Course?
That’s so nostalgic.
What a crazy time that was.
Kanuchan always bawling,
Pagogo going missing...
That reminds me...
Where is Pagogo?
It hasn’t left its Monster Ball
even once since we escaped from Rakua.
That so, huh...?
Tebrim... Thank you.
If Tebrim’s relaxed,
it must be okay in there.
Over there! Let’s check it out!
What’s with all this?!
They spotted me!
Did you hear a voice just now?
Did I imagine it...?
Is something wrong?
Liko... Look at that.
There’s so many holes.
Ow, ow, ow...
Well, least that kept ‘em
from finding me.
What kinda hole is this...?
Guess we just gotta get moving.
The ground’s been softened up.
Almost like it’s been tilled by Mimizuzu.
You’re right.
But those holes are
too big for Mimizuzu...
There’s a pink mist in the air...
Yeah. That’s the kind of evidence
we call “Rakurium Signs.”
What is this place...?
What’s that?
Hey, hey...
What’s up with that thing?!
This is bad!
It’s just like that Kekking!
It spotted me!
Yamirami, run for it!
What is that?!
Haganail. Iron Snake Pokémon.
Steel/Ground type.
Tempered underground under high pressure and heat,
its body is harder than any metal.
A Haganail?
But something seems strange about it...
Look out! Run!
It really is under
the effects of Rakurium...
We’ll just have to battle it!
Taikaiden! Achigator!
Masquernya! Tebrim!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Masquernya! Trick Flower!
We can’t hit it!
We’ve gotta track its movements!
Right.
Lucario, sense its Guiding Waves!
You got it?
Infight!
Masquernya! Trick Flower!
Our attacks aren’t working?!
Haganail’s defense is top-class
among all Pokémon.
Physical attacks
will barely hurt it at all.
Plus, Electric moves
won’t have any effect.
Listen up, you two!
Dot!
Have Achigator ride Taikaiden
and fire a Flamethrower from the skies!
I get it! If we use Flamethrower,
it doesn’t matter how hard its body is!
Have Lucario and Masquernya use their speed
to create an opening for Achigator!
Got it!
Cap and Tebrim should
keep their distance and play support.
Taikaiden! Attack from above
with Achigator on your back!
If only we could hold it still
the next time it pops out of a hole...
Then you just leave that to me!
Masquernya! When it pops out,
grab it with your vine!
Lucario!
Support her with Guiding Waves!
Look out!
Tebrim! Mind Power!
Cap! Thunder Punch!
It burrowed down again!
Not if I can help it!
Achigator! Charm Voice!
Taikaiden, fire an Uproar
down the hole!
Now’s your chance!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
There are two Haganail?!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
We’re trapped!
That much power?!
From a Haganail’s Sand Hell?!
So that’s what Rakurium is capable of...
Cap! I’m counting on you!
Masquernya! Trick Flower!
Masquernya, behind you!
Power Gem!
A Yamirami?!
Huh?
The black Rekkuuza...
belongs to me!
Gah...! Ult!
Hmph! Looks like you’re
in a mega-pinch, eh Roy?!
Another troublemaker...
Someone you know?
These guys are just like
the Kekking from last time, eh Roy?
Plus, the Haganail’s bodies are too hard
to be affected by normal attacks.
Plus, they came in double
this time, huh...?
Hmph! Feelin’ your back
against the wall?
No way!
Let’s wrap this up
nice and quick, Lucario!
Yamirami! Let’s do this!
Let’s go!
What?
Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Mega Evolve!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Lucario! Metal Claw!
Finish it off with Infight!
Thanks to Mega Evolution,
their attack and speed have gone up dramatically...
...and now their moves
can pierce through!
So that’s... Mega Evolution...!
Good going! Now, Eerie Light!
Power Gem!
Amazing...
Now!
Cap!
All right! Taikaiden! Nosedive!
Achigator!
Flamethrower on both of ‘em!
Great work, Achigator!
Hold on a sec!
No way...!
Weren’t they teamed up? What gives?!
Stop it! Don’t!
Ugh... With Rakurium affecting them,
they can’t tell friend from foe!
They think anyone
they can see is their foe...!
Stop...
You have to stop!
Liko?!
Please! Just stop it!
Pagogo!
What’s that Pokémon?!
Pagogo got rid of the Rakurium...
Haganail...
So it’s called Pagogo...
No clue what just happened,
but I guess that thing got it all under control.
So you woke up, Pagogo!
I’m glad it’s okay.
Good morning, Pagogo!
This is Ult.
I met him in Kalos while I was training.
Hey...
Ult-san, thank you for
saving Masquernya earlier.
Wasn’t anything special.
And you can drop the “-san.”
Just “Ult” is fine.
My name’s Liko.
I used to travel with Roy.
Nice to meet you.
S-Sure.
Guess you’re a friend of a friend.
What’s up with you, Ult?
You’re acting weird.
Shut it!
Ain’t nothing up with me!
Right, Yamirami?
Huh? Yamirami?!
Yamirami?
That isn’t food!
Hey, that thing that
Lucario and Yamirami did earlier...
That was Mega Evolution!
Yo-ssu! Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
It’s everyone’s pal, Gurumin!
Hey, have you heard of
Mega Evolution?
A phenomenon only observed
in certain Pokémon...
I’m talking about evolution
that transcends evolution: Mega Evolution!
By temporarily releasing
a Pokémon’s latent power,
it can unleash power
beyond the limits of evolution!
Necessary for Mega Evolution
are items bestowed only upon the chosen...
A Key Stone and a Mega Stone!
And most important of all is the bond
between Pokémon and trainer!
The strength of their bond is
what allows Pokémon to Mega Evolve!
Why are Rakurium reactions popping up
in so many different regions?
So, Ult... Why were you all the way
out here, anyway? Just a coincidence?
Oh, right! I almost forgot.
Roy! How dare you stoop to
leaving me behind last time?
Oh, sorry...
Wait, does that mean
you’ve been following me?!
Wuh...?
‘Course not, but...
“But”...?
The black Rekkuuza...
belongs to me!
Huh? The black Rekkuuza?
Well now!
I am ever so glad you asked!
Indeed... To me,
it’s the mega-strongest of the strongest,
Huh? Should we really...?
He gets annoying
when he’s all fired up.
a super-mega-mega-mega-...
And we can’t exactly let him
get all tangled up in our journey.
Right. We need to get back the truth
of the Rising Voltteccers on our own.
Mega Evolution is truly—!
Huh? They’re gone!
Those... jerks...
They left me behind!
It has been some time since last we spoke.
One year, if I’m not mistaken.
There is no possible excuse
for our failure.
Though we were accompanying him...
...we were unable to protect Amethio-sama,
and we continue to regret it.
If we’re to be discharged,
we have no objections.
I have no intention of blaming you,
nor of discharging you.
The new head, Director Spinel, reported that
Amethio-sama betrayed Gibeon-sama...
...and that they both perished
in the ensuing struggle.
But Crave-sama, who vacated his seat
as director, does not believe this report...
...and neither do I.
Which is why...
What’s that?
A Zygarde Cell...!
I place my trust in you two,
to whom Amethio-sama opened his heart...
...and entrust to you this Cube,
which shall lead you to Zygarde.
I wish for you to discover Amethio-sama’s whereabouts,
without him discovering you.
Sir!
Before it becomes too late
for us all...
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Iron Snake Pokémon, Haganail!
Iron Snake Pokémon
Ground
Haganail
Iron Snake Pokémon
Steel
Ground
Rock Head
Haganail
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Iron Snake Pokémon
Steel
Rock Head
Sturdy
Haganail
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Haganail
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Iron Snake Pokémon
Steel
Ground
Sand Power
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The cells within its body have crystallized,
and are now stronger than any mineral
and able to withstand any temperature!
By the way, the things surrounding it
are metal plates that have detached from its body.
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
And if they hit you,
it sure does... hurt...
Next episode
Liko, what’re you watching?
A Gurumin vid!
That one’s pretty old!
How many times have you rewatched it...?
Umm... I lost count!
Okay, then! Enlighten us!
What’s so fascinating about Gurumin?
You can’t help but laugh
at the funny way she moves,
you can learn so much from her,
and her dialogue timing is perfect,
plus choosing Nidorina shows
she has refined and cute taste,
I just knew she was bound for stardom
from the first time I saw—
Enough! I appreciate it,
but it’s also really embarrassing!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Diehard Follower?! A Gurumin Fan Showdown!!
Wait, showdown?!