The Rising Voltteccers, a band of adventurers
led by Friede, continue their journey.
The awoken Terapagos was a peculiar Pokémon
that wasn’t even in the Pokémon Index.
Terapagos hopes to find Rakua.
But to do that, we must find
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes...
...and recover Terapagos’s power.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we’re headed to the Paldea Region.
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’? It’s a vid from Gurumin!
Today, we’re doing a livestream!
I’ll be responding to all your comments!
So keep ‘em coming!
Let’s comment... Or, wait, but...
What do I say?! What do I say?!
Make sure to brush your teeth before bed!
Let’s do one last comment.
This one comes from Yunorin-san!
“Gurumin, yo-ssu!”
Yo-ssu!
“I always have fun
watching your videos.
“Recently, I became
the trainer of a Perfuton.
“In Pigton Town, where I live, there’s going to be
a Pokémon Tag Battle tournament soon...”
Ooh, sounds like fun!
“But my Perfuton doesn’t want to team up
with anyone, and seems really down.
“Gurumin, what do you think I should do?”
Good question...
Ooh!
I know just the girl for the job!
Look forward to that!
All right, that’s it for today.
Let’s go groovin’ again sometime!
It’s from Dot.
Huh?!
That girl you had in mind... was me?!
Yeah!
Go hear what Yunorin-san has to say,
and get some footage
of Pigton Town with Kuwassu for me.
I’m countin’ on ya, NyahojaSuperfan!
G-Gurumin asked me for a favor...
So, what’s Pigton Town like?
Apparently it’s jam-packed
with trainers of pig Pokémon!
And their Tag Battle tournaments
get pretty heated!
If I make a vid on it, my views and subs
will rise like a Shibirudon going upriver!
Ooh! Sounds fun! I wanna go, too!
Leave it to me, Gurumin!
For you, I’ll give it all I’ve got!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Operation Perfuton Pals!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
Today, Kuwassu and me
are reporting in from Pigton Town!
The rumors were right!
It’s jam-packed with trainers of pig Pokémon!
This weekend, they’re having
a Tag Battle tournament!
Kuwassu, get some good shots for us!
Okay, cut.
Am I really tagging along
for a Gurumin shoot?!
Any idea what that girl’ll be like?
It’s Kuwassu!
It’s really you!
I watch you in videos all the time.
Are you Yunorin-san?
Yep!
Are you Gurumin’s friends?
F-Friends?
Yes!
That’s awesome! I’m Yuno!
And this’s my Pokémon, Twirly-chan.
Twirly-chan?
Her tail’s all twirly,
so I call her Twirly-chan!
Cute, ain’t she?
Perfuton: Female Form.
Hog Pokémon. Normal type.
Meticulous and likes to
keep things tidy.
It shrouds itself in a floral aroma
that soothes the Pokémon around it.
My, my... She sure ain’t groovin’.
Wh-Wh-Whoa! It’s Gurumin!
Huh?! Liko, you’re NyahojaSuperfan?!
Y-Yeah...
I saw the collab you were in with Nanjamo!
You and Nyahoja really are great friends.
It’s the same with me!
I’m a total TwirlychanSuperfan!
But lately...
Twirly-chan is sighing a lot,
and I don’t know what to do.
She doesn’t look so good...
It was the same for me.
When I first met Nyahoja,
I could never tell how she felt.
Really?
Yeah. But then, I learned something...
That if you want to understand how Pokémon feel,
you have to start by letting them know how you feel.
How I feel...
Twirly-chan...
I’d like to enter the Tag Battle
tournament with you.
But I don’t want to do it
if it’ll make you sad.
So, Twirly-chan... If something’s
worrying you, just tell me.
What is it, Kuwassu?
Kuwassu’s cheering her on, too.
Yeah.
Whoa! Twirly-chan?!
What’s wrong?
Is that...?
It’s a male Perfuton.
Could it be...?
Twirly-chan, are you interested
in that Perfuton?
Think she wants to team up with him?
Oho? Do we have
a smitten Pokémon on our hands?
No way...
No, no, no!
How come?
Well...
His trainer is...
Well, if it ain’t Yuno.
You lookin’ for me?
Gah... Why would I ever
be looking for you?!
You know him?
My childhood friend Renta.
Total creep. I can’t stand him!
Huh? Whaddaya mean?
You’re the one who’s
always freaking out at me.
Nuh-uh, other way around!
This is going nowhere...
Oh, uh... Um!
Renta! I-I’m not super happy
about it, but...
Twirly-chan wants to
team up with your Pokémon.
Oh? Your Perfuton with my Prince?
What a riot!
He calls him Prince...
What a name...
Just team up with me, would ya?
Should we, Prince?
What do you say?
Twirly-chan!
Prince says he’s not interested!
Besides, Prince could have
any teammate he wanted!
Right, Prince?
What is it?
What’s going on?
Perfuton: Male Form.
Hog Pokémon. Normal type.
It emits a sweet, alluring scent
from all over its body...
...which makes female Pokémon
go weak at the knees.
He weakens their knees?!
Not Nyahoja too!
Get a hold of yourself!
Twirly-chan!
Stop!
Twirly-chan...
What should we do?
Hmm...
Prince just doesn’t seem
interested in Twirly-chan...
She needs a glow-up!
A glow-up?
If she wants to catch that Perfuton’s eye,
she’s gotta stand out and be more confident!
Be more confident? How?
Oh, I know!
Yuno! Twirly-chan!
I’ve got a good idea!
Huh?
All done!
You look super cute!
Twirly-chan! This’ll knock the socks off
that mean old Renta and the others!
For sure, for sure!
Guess Yuno really
can’t stand that Renta guy.
That... might not quite be it...
Twirly-chan, keep your posture steady!
You’ve got this!
Concentrate on your forepaws!
N-Not perfect, but you’re doing fine!
You look fantastic, Twirly-chan!
We’ve gotta put Renta and the others
in their place, no matter what!
For sure, for sure!
Does... Yuno like Renta...?
Renta!
What now, Yuno?
Prince told you he didn’t
wanna team up, didn’t he?
This’s a whole new Twirly-chan!
You’re the one who really
wants to team up with me, right?
I-I would never!
I knew it.
N-Now, Twirly-chan!
Go teach Prince a lesson!
Go for it!
All right!
Strike that pretty pose like before!
Twirly-chan!
No way...
It didn’t work?
Didn’t we show you before?
Prince is the crowd favorite.
Your Perfuton doesn’t stand a chance.
See ya!
Let’s go, Prince.
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Hey! Kuwassu! What’s this about?!
What are you doing?!
Was that Gurumin’s voice?
Then, that Kuwassu...
is hers?! Seriously?!
Amazing!
Cool!
When did you learn those moves?
What’s that Kuwassu doing?!
Yuno! What are you doing to Prince?!
Huh?
Your Prince attacked Kuwassu first, didn’t he?
Still, Twirly-chan shouldn’t just butt in!
Prince got what he deserved!
You’ve got some nerve!
Who, me? You’ve got some nerve!
What a mess...
What a lovely scent...
So sweet and flowery...
It’s probably the soothing aroma
of a female Perfuton...
But I can’t smell it
through the Smartphone Rotom!
Smells great...
I get it! Twirly-chan is giving off this scent for those two,
who weren’t being honest about their feelings...
Uh, Yuno. Looks like Prince is
interested in teaming up, too...
So I guess I can team up with you.
N-Not like I even really
want to team up with you!
Wh-What’s up with that attitude?!
Hmph!
Oh boy...
Those two never change, huh?
But when all’s said and done...
They do seem to be getting along, in a way.
I’m happy for you, Yuno.
Renta begged me to team up with him!
So I had no choice!
And so, um...
We wanna ask you guys something.
We want to practice Tag Battling
before the tournament.
Would you be our opponents?
Huh? Tag Battling?
Ooh! Sounds fun!
Let’s do it!
Yeah!
And then, a Tag Battle
suddenly broke out!
Team... NyahojaSuperfan!
Versus... the Yunorins!
You don’t wanna miss this battle!
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
Hogator, let’s do our best!
Yuno, we’ll make the first move.
All righty, but...
you sure you know what you’re doing?
Let’s go, Prince! Desperate Tackle!
Nyahoja, dodge it!
Hogator, now!
Ember!
Leave it to me!
Twirly-chan, use Mud Spray!
Ooh! They’re perfectly in sync!
Amazing...
Our turn! Nyahoja, use Leafage!
Twirly-chan, jump!
Oh my! Twirly-chan dodges by using
Kuwassu’s smooth moves!
Twirly-chan! Body Slam!
Good work, Yuno!
Prince! We’ve gotta
get ourselves fired up, too!
Work Up!
Liko, let’s do this together!
Got it.
Lightning Speed!
Tackle!
Whoa! Nyahoja and Hogator
both attack at once!
Renta, watch out!
Leave it to me!
I’ll strike from below!
Prince, use Dig!
Nyahoja!
Pretty good, Renta!
Nothing to it.
Nyahoja, are you okay?
They make a good pair!
Yeah. But we won’t give in, either!
Whoa! Neither side is giving any ground!
Renta, time for us to go all out!
You can count on me, Yuno!
Desperate Tackle!
We did it!
And so! The Yunorins claimed a marvelous victory
in Pigton Town’s Tag Battle tournament!
Now for Yunorin-san’s victory interview.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
We couldn’t have won without Gurumin,
NyahojaSuperfan-san, and everyone else’s help!
Glad to hear!
Are you getting along well
with your super perfect partner?
H-H-He is not super perfect for me!
And it’s definitely not
like that with us!
Huh?
I thought your partner was Twirly-chan...
I-I’m getting along great
with Twirly-chan!
That was Yunorin-san, who’s getting along great
with Twirly-chan and her teammate!
You’ve got it all wrong!
They went on to win!
That’s amazing!
I’m so happy for you, Yuno!
Just as planned,
views and comments are flooding in...
Huh?
“So Gurumin plays Cupid, huh?”
“Help me out with my crush!”
“I think I’m in love!
How do I approach them?”
Hey! I’m not taking
those kinds of requests!
Aaagh! Now what do I do?!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Hog Pokémon, Perfuton.
A Pokémon that gives off
a sweet scent from the tip of its tail.
Male Form
Female Form
Perfuton
Hog Pokémon
Type: Normal
Perfuton
Hog Pokémon
Type: Normal
Height
1.0m
It has a trait that is closely linked to that scent,
Weight
120.0kg
but do you know which trait that is?
Which trait is linked to its sweet scent?
Gourmet palate
Neatness
Heat sensitivity
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that live in water!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Whaleoh, Kaiogre,
Numacraw, Kamasujaw, Gekkouga!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
This is Landau. "Rap" is as freeform as water.
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Nuoh!
Whaleoh, Kaiogre, nyoh...
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
Which trait is linked to its sweet scent?
A: Gourmet palate
The answer is
A: Gourmet palate!
Perfuton is a Pokémon gourmet,
being quite picky about its food.
It came to smell so nice due to
having eaten tasty food for a long time.
Even Cap can’t resist that scent.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
A job turned up
for the Rising Voltteccers!
The job’s at a ruin excavation site and has ‘em
using the airship to move a rock out of the way!
And then, a new door
finally opens for Hogator!
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters:
Hogator on the Vile Side?!