My name is Liko.
The drive to discover, the drive to learn...
These are the feelings
that set us on our journey.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we, the Rising Voltteccers,
are headed to the Paldea Region.
Everyone, listen up!
The Rising Voltteccers’
coffers have run dry.
Huh?
Dry?
So it’s finally time.
If we spend all our time
trekking around, never working...
...of course we’ll run out of funds.
We’re going to keep looking for Rakua.
But I need everyone to put some effort
towards earning money, too.
Roger!
Earning money...
Isn’t adventuring
the Rising Voltteccers’ job?
Adventures don’t put
food on the table.
If we’re going to keep traveling,
we need some other way to make money.
I see...
Maybe I could start delivering sweets...
I should ask my pals if they know anyone
in need of mechanical repairs.
Molly, you could offer
medical consultations for Pokémon, right?
Yeah. Dot, could you
make me a publicity video?
You’re good at that, right?
Ooh, good idea!
Make one for my sweets, too!
Huh? Sounds like a pain.
Don’t be like that!
The revenue from your videos
has you covered, so...
Okay! I can do heavy lifting!
And I’m good at mountain hiking!
I... I’ll do anything, too!
Students should
put their studies first.
Huh... So adventures cost money?
Seems like it.
Huh?
Hmm?
Did you catch that little one?
Oh, yeah. This is Mibrim.
She’s so cute!
Nice to meet you, Mibrim!
It’s class time. Talk to you later!
Right.
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
If any would not work,
neither should he eat.
And that’s today’s assignment:
“The Ideal Bond.”
Pick a trainer and Pokémon pair
you know personally and that you look up to,
and write a report on
why you admire them.
Next class, I’ll have you
present them one at a time.
The ideal bond...
A trainer and Pokémon I look up to,
that I know personally... It’d have to be...
We got a job already!
A friend wants to hire us
to find a lost Pokémon.
I’m heading out.
You don’t need any help?
Nope. Me and Cap can handle
a lost Pokémon, no sweat.
Right, Cap?
...Friede and Cap!
Yeah! They’re even good in battle.
They’re the perfect example of an ideal bond!
Hey, Friede! Let me help out!
Oh! Me, too!
Hmm? Sure, be my guest.
Sure!
I’ll study their ideal bond!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Friede and Cap: The Duo in the Wilderness
So, this is the place.
Watch yourselves.
People ‘round here can be pretty rough.
Friede!
Thanks for coming!
Hey! Been a while!
Oh?
These are a few
of my traveling buddies.
They’re here to help with the job.
I’m Liko.
I’m Roy.
Shine! Nice to meet you!
This is the Pokémon
I want you to find.
That’s a Pokémon?
That’s... an Anokusa.
Yeah.
I caught it when I went
to Paldea last month.
I’ve been taking it
on walks now and then,
but yesterday
a strong wind blew it away.
A Pokémon was
blown away by the wind?
I’d look for it myself,
but I have work.
To tell the truth,
I’ve heard there’s a gang of hunters in the area
snapping up random wild Pokémon.
I see.
Shine works to protect wild Pokémon.
Catching evil hunters is part of his job.
Whoa...
I understand the situation.
You can leave Anokusa to us.
We’ll find it no matter what.
Right, Cap?
They really are an ideal pair! So reliable!
Anokusa. Tumbleweed Pokémon.
Grass/Ghost type.
A soul unable to move on
to the afterlife...
...that got tangled up with dried grass
and tumbles around.
Even it doesn’t know where it is headed.
Sounds tough...
Judging by the winds since yesterday,
it should be somewhere around here...
Bingo!
Hey! Anokusa!
Mr. Shine asked us to look for you!
Wait!
Cap! Can you catch up to it?
Leave it to me!
Whoops!
We lost track of Anokusa...
Desert to the left,
oasis to the right, huh?
All right, let’s head left.
Huh? Why?
Anokusa usually hate getting wet.
It’d want to steer clear of water.
Whoa! That’s a Pokémon Professor for ya!
Now, let’s go.
What is it, Cap?
Cap says it’s that way.
C’mon. There’s no way, Cap.
An Anokusa’s instinct
would be to turn left here.
You’re not convinced?
There’s not a chance. That way.
That way!
It’s that way!
Should we just check both ways?
Guess they don’t always
see eye to eye...
Up there!
They were both wrong!
After it!
We wound up back in the desert!
It’ll be easier to spot
in a wide open area.
There’s loads of Anokusa!
No, those are tumbleweeds.
They look just like Anokusa,
but they’re only clumps of dry grass.
Anokusa! You out there?
It is here!
We’ll just have to
check them one by one.
Not it...
It’s not here...
Guess we couldn’t find it, Nyahoja...
Huh?!
Wasn’t that Anokusa?
Everyone! Anokusa is— Ah!
Terapagos?!
Are you okay?
What is it?
Was Anokusa here?!
Y-Yeah, just now—
It’s already gone...
Hey! Can’t you find some cuter Pokémon?
I wanna pack my place full of cuties!
Maybe I should hire different hunters...
I-I do apologize, ma’am.
We’re looking as hard as we can.
Ma’am! We found this
out there and nabbed it!
Is that really a Pokémon?
This thing isn’t cute at all!
Th-This is Anokusa!
It’s an incredibly rare Pokémon!
Look at those beady eyes.
Aren’t they cute?
You think so?
Well, whatever. Toss it in the cage.
Ma’am!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Anokusa, huh?
Haven’t seen it.
No, I wouldn’t know.
Nobody’s seen it...
Maybe it didn’t
come through this town...
Look! Look!
That Pikachu...
He’s wearing a hat!
So cute!
Hey, what’s wrong with Cap?
Good grief...
Guess his allergy’s acting up.
Allergy?
Cap’s allergic to “cute.”
If someone calls him cute,
he can’t stop sneezing.
What? Really?
So cute!
That must’ve been rough, Cap.
Well, being popular can’t be all bad.
Ow, ow, ow!
Don’t take it out on me!
Hmm... Is this the ideal bond?
Anokusa! Answer if you can hear me!
Where could it have gone?
Huh?
Hey, would you say this one’s cute?
She didn’t like that Anokusa
we grabbed earlier, either...
They grabbed an Anokusa?
Could they be...
...the hunters Mr. Shine told us about?
Yeah. Let’s go!
Stop right there!
I’ve got some questions for you!
Ack!
The hunter ring?! You serious?
Yeah. Head straight here.
We’re about to go see their boss.
Apparently, that’s where
Anokusa’s being held.
Yeah. Talk to you later.
Now then, let’s go rescue Anokusa.
The others still aren’t here?
I wanna see all the cute Pokémon
they’re bringing, already!
They should be here any minute now!
Hey! Go get the lady
something to drink, will ya?!
I see, so this is the place.
There’s Anokusa!
That Anokusa is my friend’s partner!
Sorry, but we’ll be taking it back.
Huh?! Who are you?
You’re, like, way too loud!
Don’t you worry, ma’am.
He won’t bother you much longer.
Hey! Shut him up!
Yes, sir!
Well, then! Ready for a fight, Cap?!
Strinder! Acid Bomb!
Omustar! Rock Blast!
Thunder Punch!
That Pikachu...
Aww! So cute!
I want it! I want it! I want it!
I must have that Pikachu!
Consider it done.
Banbadoro, use Mud Spray!
Watch out, Cap!
Strinder! Acid!
Omustar! Water Gun!
Cap!
We gotta save him!
Hogator, use Ember!
Nyahoja, use Leafage!
Banbadoro, use Bulldoze!
Won’t let us near the cage, huh?
Is that Power Whip?
Good going, Anokusa!
Break yourself out and escape!
Gah, not strong enough...
Sheesh! What’s taking you all so long?!
Crebase, darling, use Blizzard on the cage!
Anokusa!
‘Kay! All of you
stay right where you are!
Or my darling Crebase will hurt
all these Pokémon!
Though this isn’t very cute of me...
We can’t afford to be reckless here...
Was that...?
What should we do?
Hmm...
All right, I’ve decided!
We’re breaking through by force!
Everyone ready?
Yeah!
Got it!
Huh? Cap doesn’t want to?
Cap! We’ve gotta do this!
Rush in!
For now, just do what I say!
If I tell you to go, you go!
They’re fighting again?
Ah! Cap!
Well, fine!
Be like that!
Liko, Roy, you take it from here.
Huh?!
You’re kidding!
They’re fighting now?!
What happened to their ideal bond?
What’s this?
Squabbling between friends?
Don’t just stand around laughing!
My Pikachu is getting away!
R-Right!
Take ‘em out and
track down Pikachu!
Yes, sir!
Liko! We’ll just have to
handle this ourselves!
Yeah! I’ll have to revise my report!
Huh? What report?
Strinder! Electric Shock!
Hogator, use Ember!
Omustar! Water Gun!
Nyahoja, use Leafage!
Banbadoro, use Bulldoze!
Crebase is the only one left.
Now!
Huh?
Whah! Crebase, darling!
Oh, no! Banbadoro, use Mud Spray!
Cap?
What’s going on?
Nice timing, Cap!
Huh? H-Huh?!
We better save Anokusa while we can!
Don’t worry.
Anokusa! Rapid Spin in place!
It evolved?!
Anokusa may not have been strong enough to break out,
but now that it’s evolved into Anohoragusa...
Anohoragusa! Power Whip!
Wow!
Anokusa is a Pokémon that evolves
by walking around a lot.
It must’ve been ready to evolve
after tumbling around in the wind so much.
I saw a hint of it earlier,
so I figured it could escape
if those guys took their eyes off the cage.
So, that argument
was part of your plan?
Well, uh... I was sorta ad-libbing.
Cap seemed like he had
something planned,
so I figured it’d work out
if I played along.
Great work, Cap!
Argh! Can’t you just shut up?!
C...
Cu...
Cute?! Not one bit!
Strinder! Acid Bomb!
Omustar! Rock Blast!
Thunder Punch!
Thunder Punch won’t work
on a Ground type!
Stomp!
Th-This can’t be happening...
Good job, Cap.
Friede and Cap...
Those two really are amazing!
They continue to impress me.
I can’t quite describe what makes them
so amazing to me, or even what their bond is,
but there’s one thing I do know...
When I’m with that trainer
and his Pokémon,
My heart races...
I get excited...
We wind up in some
pretty bad spots now and then,
but once we’ve made it through,
I feel like I’ve grown a little stronger.
Just having him there
gives us all courage.
I hope to be a trainer like him someday!
And that’s why I intend...
...to keep on watching them!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, we’ll be taking a look at
the Tumbleweed Pokémon, Anokusa.
Anokusa
Tumbleweed Pokémon
Type: Grass/Ghost
Anokusa
Tumbleweed Pokémon
Type: Grass/Ghost
A Pokémon which tumbles and rolls
around the windy wilderness.
Height
0.6m
Weight
0.6kg
But do you know
the effect rolling has on it?
What effect does rolling have?
Stress relief
Energy gathering
Nothing
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
Exciting and thrilling
An adventure is starting
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! This'll be a snap!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What effect does rolling have?
B: Energy gathering
The answer is...
B: Energy gathering!
As it rolls, it sucks up energy
from nearby plants.
By rolling so much,
it’s storing up the power needed to evolve.
Its way and whether it evolves
are at the whims of the wind.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
A super popular Gurumin vid
brought in a request for advice!
A certain trainer girl says...
“As of late, my Pokémon’s had
no energy at all! What should I do?!”
What? “Leave it to me,” you say?
Then, check out the results next time
on Pocket Monsters, in Operation Perfuton Pals!
Operation Perfuton Pals!