We’ve finished our friendly matches
against the Paldea Elite Four.
Now, it’s finally time
for our implementation tests.
We were each assigned
a Gym Leader to battle,
so we headed to the town
where Dot’s set to face hers.
Champuru Town is such a lively place!
It’s an important hub
for people trekking across Paldea.
Wow!
It’s a full-fledged culinary town,
so there’s lots of great restaurants around!
Sounds awesome!
Hogator, what do you wanna eat?
Eating is important and all,
but I wanna hurry up and
take my implementation test.
Look! You’re not getting
the gunk off that way!
I told you!
Shut it, will ya?
Look here! And here!
There’s charred bits!
I told you, no!
What’s that?
So loud!
Oh dear, looks like our little Dodogezan
gave you quite a start.
Sorry ‘bout that.
It’s just trying to bring in customers,
in its own sorta way.
I-It’s very... intense.
How’s about a meal from the Anything Eatery,
to make it up to ya for the scare?
Huh? Are you sure?!
Yeah!
Be our guests.
Right, Dodogezan?
Oh dear, our little Dodogezan’s
just gone and startled you again.
Sorry ‘bout that.
It wouldn’t even hurt a Bachul, though!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
The Mascot Pokémon is Dodogezan?!
Dodogezan. Glaive Pokémon.
Evil/Steel type.
Though it commands
a massive army in battle,
it has no aptitude
for complex strategy.
It just uses brute strength
to push forward.
It pushes forward
with brute strength?
Oh, so that’s why
it flung the door open so hard...
Sorry to bother you on your break.
What’re ya talkin’ about?!
We’re open and ready for business!
Huh?! Oh, sorry...
Be careful, Dodogezan!
Nearly had it!
Just put a bit too much force into it.
While I appreciate the help,
you should go try and
drum up some customers.
Order up!
Comin’!
Umm... What is this?
It’s our Anything Meal.
Anything Meal...
Hmm...
How do I even describe this flavor?
It’s really got every kind of flavor...
What’s in it?
You heard ‘em, Mokichi!
Don’t look at me! I just toss in
a pile of tasty stuff without thinking.
There you go, not thinking again!
What, now?!
You got some kinda problem with that?!
“Some kinda problem” is puttin’ it lightly!
I’m always complainin’ about it!
What was that?!
Honestly, you’re just a big ol’ brat!
Oh, this kamaboko looks tasty!
Huh? Where’s that?
A big ol’ Ratta? If I’m a big old Ratta,
you’re a big ol’... O... Ordile!
Y-Yeah! Sure tastes great...
Well that’s perfect,
because I love Ordile!
It’s hard to relax and eat...
Yeah...
There’s noodles at the bottom...
Delicious!
Right?!
They’re udon noodles
made by Dodogezan.
By Dodogezan?
Kid’s great at jobs that
call for some muscle.
The noodles turn out real chewy.
Wow!
I’ve got some for your Pokémon, too!
There.
Even the Pokémon get Anything Meals...
Uh... Why exactly do you put
so much stuff in these?
’Cause we don’t want to get shown up
by the Treasure Eatery.
The Treasure Eatery?
The biggest restaurant
in Champuru Town, huh?
They’re awfully popular.
Even our old regulars
have started goin’ there instead.
And that’s why...
Most days, we’re deserted. Like now.
That adventurer guy
ain’t stopped by lately...
We get a bone-tired office worker
now and then, but that’s about it.
All the same, we didn’t want our offerings put to shame
by the Treasure Eatery, so we came up with...
The Anything Meal!
Though we ended up tossin’ everything into
a single bowl so it’d be easier for Dodogezan to carry.
So that’s why...
Hungry for seconds?
This time,
I’ll use my prized iron griddle...
H-Huh?
Hey... What the...?
Huh? Where’d me iron griddle go?
Hey! Where is it?!
Iron griddle... Don’t tell me...!
I’m gonna have to help out at the restaurant
to make up for this, aren’t I...?
Sorry for getting you two
caught up in this.
It’s fine! I’m gonna
make this place sparkle!
We’re gonna go advertise
the Anything Eatery around town!
Right, Hogator?
Hey, you think you could
take Dodogezan with you?
You bet!
Come along with us, Dodogezan!
We’ll meet up with you
once we get a new griddle.
You’re taking Kanuchan with you?
Yeah.
Won’t she just throw herself
at any iron stuff she sees?
Mm...
But if we find a griddle that grabs her attention,
I bet you it’ll be a good one.
She’s got a good eye for iron, after all.
Good thinking!
I always thought you were struggling
when dealing with Kanuchan...
I didn’t realize how in-tune
you were with her, Dot!
Well then,
we’ll leave things in your hands!
Right!
Come on in! Come on in!
If it’s good food you’re after,
head on over to the Anything Eatery!
Hey, Roy!
How’s it going?
Getting people to stop and listen
isn’t easy, I guess...
I see...
Whoa!
So cool!
There, there...
He laughed...
This is fun!
What?
So precious!
I wanna try!
Whoa...
Roy, now’s your chance!
Oh, yeah!
Um...
Step on up, take a look!
This merry Kuwassu loves the Anything Meals
at the Anything Eatery!
Anything Meals?
What’s the Anything Eatery?
All right, Kuwassu! Let’s keep things rolling!
Lead them all to the Anything Eatery!
They’re all following him!
We totally did it!
Three meals for the counter!
Four for the tables!
Coming!
Sorry for the wait!
I can take that!
Leave it to us.
Hey! Don’t just stand there!
Not tired already, are ya?
Just keep the food coming. Anything will do!
R-R-Right...
Just... Hold... I can’t...
I’m no good at stuff like this...
Just let me take a little break.
Sorry to do this right after
you brought in so many customers...
Ack!
Mind if we join you for a spell?
You needed a break, too?
Nah, just...
This guy ain’t lookin’ too cheerful, is all.
Huh?
It’s not...
...cheerful?
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Not looking cheerful, huh? Uh...
I guess... maybe...
it does look a little blue?
Yeah. We met years ago,
and this’s the first time
I’ve ever seen it like this.
I fell in love with that booming voice,
and the two of us opened
the Anything Eatery together.
Huh?
You didn’t start it with Ms. Nandy?
Far from it!
Nandy threw out her back
‘cause of Dodogezan hollerin’.
I treated her to a meal to apologize,
and that’s how we ended up together.
These days, Dodogezan’s the one
who keeps us feeling cheerful.
Here, thanks for waitin’!
I’ll have an Anything Meal too!
Comin’ right up!
So if it’s lost its cheer,
everything goes outta whack.
Maybe... We’re the reason
Dodogezan’s lost its cheer.
Huh?
Us helping out to make up for things...
Bringing in customers...
Maybe we shouldn’t have butted in.
Naw, don’t think like that!
But we came in and changed things
where Dodogezan feels most at home...
As for that... Some things change,
and some things don’t.
The eatery can change.
That don’t matter.
I just wanna know how I can
get this guy back to hollerin’ like usual.
I was just having a li’l grumble
about something I’m not sure how to fix.
Thank you for coming!
Please come back again!
Oh... S-Sure.
If we get the chance...
Huh?
They seem...
Hey, what did you think of the food?
Hmm... I dunno.
Sadly, I get the feeling...
...that the customers you had earlier
won’t be back again.
Kuwassu was able to make them
aware of the Anything Eatery.
But the meal didn’t leave
a lasting impression.
Even though it’s got so much stuff in it?
It’s because there’s so much in it
that no one can remember exactly what they ate.
While it tastes good overall,
you can’t pick out any part as your favorite.
As a result,
you’re left with the impression...
“Eh, guess there’s no point
coming back here again.”
You’re somethin’ else!
How’d you figure all that out?!
I... do a bit of livestreaming.
For my streams,
I’ve always got to think about...
...how I can keep people coming back
to watch and comment every day.
You’re a smart one!
That’s really cool!
I-It’s no big deal...
But hmm... A restaurant that
keeps people coming back...
Where would we even start?
The key to it...
...is Dodogezan!
Dodogezan?!
The udon at the very bottom
of the Anything Meals!
That was way delicious, right?
Yeah, sure was.
But since there was so much else
piled on top of it,
the taste of the udon
didn’t leave a lasting impression.
So!
Your new specialty meal...
...should let Dodogezan’s udon
stand on its own!
It’s... you...
What are you doing?!
A-Are you okay?!
Right... I understand.
You’re issuing a challenge against me!
This is a request for a Pokémon battle!
Huh?!
I accept your challenge.
I think he got the wrong idea somewhere...
Yeah... And now he’s really
itching for a battle...
Will you be okay, Dot?
This could be the chance we need!
Huh?!
Dodogezan!
I want you to have udon dough
ready for the afternoon opening!
The future of the Anything Eatery
is riding on you!
Let’s go, Kyojiohn! Salt Pickling!
Dodge it, Kuwassu!
Turn and use Aqua Break!
Iron Defense!
People are showing up...
All right!
Looking good!
If we can keep gathering a crowd here,
we can attract customers to the Anything Eatery!
And to do that...
Kyojiohn! Salt Pickling again!
Kuwassu! Kick Down!
Make it really flashy!
Kick salt everywhere!
He’s attacking head-on?!
Ooh... Pretty...
Good work, Onigiri!
Give us another Salt Pickling!
You seem to be underestimating me.
As you wish, then! Salt Pickling!
Kuwassu! Kick Down!
Attacking head-on again?!
What’s going on?
Is this... salt?
Yes! Dodogezan!
Liko, open the door!
Okay!
That smells good...
St-Starting this afternoon!
The Anything Eatery’s new specialty meal!
Dodogezan’s udo—
Groveling Cleave Udon is now available!
Now come on everyone,
let’s head inside!
What? What’s the meaning of this?
What happened to our Pokémon batt—?
Here, order up!
One Groveling Cleave Udon!
The fine handiwork
of our pride and joy, Dodogezan!
This Groveling Cleave Udon is tasty!
I’ll have another!
Coming right up!
It really is good...
Thank you for coming!
Thanks for the meal.
Next time, I’ll bring my whole family!
Dodogezan’s really cheered up!
What a gal.
You sure know your stuff.
One Groveling Cleave Udon!
Coming right up! Awright!
Time to make a whole lot more!
Time to dig in!
They’re really chewy!
Delicious!
Thank you so much for today.
Aw, I didn’t do anything special...
I just did what little I could...
Doing what little you can
still takes hard work!
Plus, you helped us remember...
...the most important thing of all,
which we should never let change...
Really, thank you so much.
Yeah.
Hey! How long’re ya gonna keep chewin’ the fat?
We gotta stock up for dinner!
Shut it! You don’t gotta tell me,
I was just getting to it!
Bah! Excuses, excuses!
I was just givin’ ‘em my thanks!
It really is delicious!
I’m gonna have another bowl!
When you keep remindin’ me,
I lose all me motivation!
Your “motivation”?! Bet you could search
the whole world for that and never find it!
What was that?!
I’m gonna keep on makin’
Groveling Cleave Udon!
Right with ya!
That was delicious.
Thank you for the meal.
Come again!
Simple really is best, after all.
A reminder to never lose
your beginner’s spirit.
What’s wrong?
No, it’s nothing...
Hogator, you want another bowl too?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Glaive Pokémon, Dodogezan.
Dodogezan
Glaive Pokémon
Type: Evil/Steel
Dodogezan
Glaive Pokémon
Type: Evil/Steel
A pack-leading Pokémon
that commands a massive army in battle.
Height
2.0m
Weight
120.0kg
Do you know how it has its army fight?
What battle style does Dodogezan specialize in?
Brute force
Mind games
Surprise attack
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What battle style does
Dodogezan specialize in?
A: Brute force
What battle style does
Dodogezan specialize in?
A: Brute force
The answer is A: Brute force!
Though it commands a massive army,
it has no aptitude for complex strategy.
It uses brute force and overwhelming numbers
to keep on pushing forward!
Next episode
Wasn’t it fun helping out
at the Anything Eatery?
Yeah! Wait, why were we
in this town in the first place?
My implementation test!
Ahaha, right, that...
Sheesh...
But I bet you’ll pass, Dot!
You’re raising event flags again...
Kuwassu, do your best
alongside Kanuchan, okay?
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Dance, Kuwassu!
The Blue Champuru Step!!
Blue? Aoki?!
aoki