Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Mega Evolve!
He did it! He Mega Evolved!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Lucario! Luster Cannon!
Yamirami!
You were in mega-top form!
You did amazing too, Lucario.
That was a great match!
Seeing the power of Mega Evolution
blows me away every single time!
Yeah.
Roy, Ult... You guys trained
and mastered it together, right?
Sure did.
I did it faster, though.
We were neck-and-neck.
Nuh-uh!
I was one step ahead of ya.
Why do you make everything
a competition?
I do not!
Does it even matter who was first?
Of course it matters—!
You’d never guess
they trained with each other...
How did you end up
meeting Lucario, Roy?
I guess we never asked,
come to think of it.
Huh? Did I forget to mention?
One year ago,
the Rising Voltteccers disbanded...
...and I set out on a journey
with Achigator, Taikaiden, and Cap.
And then, I met Lucario...
...in Kalos’s Miare City!
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
Roy—Training
Whoa...!
Awesome!
It’s so beautiful!
And so crowded!
Achigator...
Do you think...
...we can get stronger here?
Huh?
We’ve been through here already...
Er...
I got here from this street, right?
Oh, or was it the next one down...?
Argh, they all look the same...
Look at that Pikachu!
What a stylish hat.
That’s so Miare!
So cute!
Aww, how cute!
Ahh! Cap!
Wait!
What’s gotten into you, Cap?!
Ooh!
The Prism Tower!
It sure is huge...
Go, go!
Lookin’ good!
What’s going on?
Let’s check it out!
Whoa!
Ah, I’m sorry!
That hurt!
Geez, look where you’re goin’,
why don’t ya?!
This’s why I can’t stand tourists.
What’s with you?!
I said I was sorry!
Huh? Don’t throw a fit at me, dude.
You weren’t looking
where you were going either, were you?!
Well if you’da been more careful,
you wouldn’t have hit me!
A Pokémon Battle!
Sirknight! Moonforce!
Yadoran! Mind Blank!
Now! Hydro Pump!
Dodge it, Sirknight!
Looks like it’s almost over.
Yeah, it’ll be coming any moment now.
Let’s finish this, Sirknight!
We’re up for the challenge, Yadoran!
Mega Evolve!
Awesome!
So that’s Mega Evolution!
Magical Shine!
Destroyer Beam!
Man, this is so cool!
Right, Achigator?
Typical tourist,
freakin’ out over nothing.
Mega Evolution
is nothing special in Kalos.
Then can you do it, too?!
Huh? I’m...
not really interested in it.
Oh. So you can’t do it, then...
I said I’m just not interested in it!
If I wanted to, even my Yamirami here
could do it, no problem!
What’s with you...?
That was incredible!
Now, now, did you see that?
That was Mega Evolution!
Trainers out there seeking strength!
Why not try using the power of these stones
and the strength of your bonds...
...to Mega Evolve your partners?
Ooh!
Huh?
Random rocks?
Something seems fishy...
Let’s get out of here.
The battle was nice and all,
but that guy...
Please teach me about Mega Evolution!
Tell me about Mega Evolution!
Quit copyin’ me!
I wasn’t copying you!
I said it first, y’know!
You weren’t even interested!
Shut up! I’ll show you
how dead simple this stuff is!
Ahem!
There is no need to rush. See?
That said, that said, it seems like you two
have an interest in Mega Evolution.
Yeah!
My name’s Roy.
I’m traveling because I want to
get stronger as a trainer.
I heard rumors about Mega Evolution,
so I came here to Miare City!
Ult. Grew up in Miare.
Mega Evolution comes second nature
to a true-blue Miare kid like me.
Outsiders should buzz off.
So what if I’m an outsider?!
Huh?!
Hmph!
Mm-hm, mm-hm...
Good to see you’re both brimming with energy.
My name is Master Mayonnaise!
Mr. Mayonnaise?
Non, non...
Ma-yo-nnai-se...
...the Master!
That’s part of yer name, too?!
To spread the word
of the wonders of Mega Evolution,
I search for strong trainers,
day in and day out!
You can’t take that, Yamirami.
I’m pretty sure he’s trying to sell it.
You, Pikachu over there!
What sharp eyes you have!
As you can see, I carry any stone
you might need in order to Mega Evolve.
Wait... Hmm?
Mmm...
Aha... I can tell you’re quite skilled.
And the trainer accompanying you...
You truly are a cut above.
Huh? Oh, Cap isn’t one of my Pokémon.
A more experienced trainer left him with me
after some stuff happened...
Mm-hm, mm-hm...
Forget about him, old dude!
You gotta tell me
about Mega Evolution!
I’d like to know, too!
Oh, yes, that’s right...
Rather than standing around chatting...
Since you’re in Miare, would you care for some café?
What is this...?
What’s it look all fancy for?
It’s sweet and tasty!
Hmph! I prefer mine bitter.
It’s... not bad.
Café time is emblematic
of Miaresien refinement.
So, what say
we get down to business?
What is Mega Evolution?
It is...
...evolution that transcends evolution!
Ooh!
Pokémon that Mega Evolve
temporarily unleash their latent power,
empowering them
beyond their normal limits!
Amazing!
Awesome!
There are two requirements
for Mega Evolution.
Firstly! The Key Stone, which hides a mysterious power,
and which is to be carried by the trainer...
...must resonate with the Mega Stone,
which is to be carried by the Pokémon.
Secondly!
The other necessary factor...
...is that the trainer and Pokémon
must share a strong bond!
When their feelings align,
and their two stones resonate...
...the miracle of Mega Evolution occurs!
Hoo...
Meaning my Yamirami
gets to become a Mega Yamirami!
I wanna Mega Evolve
my Achigator, too!
Unfortunately, no one has ever discovered
a Mega Evolved Achigator...
Huh? You mean...?
Achigator cannot Mega Evolve.
No way!
You sure give up quick!
I’m not giving up!
Oh, I know!
It’s gotta be possible for Achigator,
it’s just that nobody’s discovered how!
Let’s try to Mega Evolve!
Passionate ambition...
Good, good.
In the future yet to come,
many more Mega Evolved Pokémon
are bound to be discovered.
Hear that? You’re gonna be
the world’s first Mega Achigator!
Well then, youngsters...
You ought to try your hand
at Mega Evolution training!
These are Mega Rings,
inset with Key Stones.
Whoa! This is dope!
So cool!
Thank you, Master Mayonnaise.
Your next step
is to search for Mega Stones.
Huh? You’re not gonna give ‘em to us?
They’re precious!
They aren’t something that’s easily found.
Got it...
I’ll give it all I’ve got!
Hm? Hold on...
This one of ‘em?
Ooh! That is indeed
a Yamirami’s Mega Stone!
Why do you have that?
My Yamirami loves sparkly things.
It’s always bringing me
rocks and stuff.
And out of all of them...
This one’s its favorite.
Now I’m closer
to Mega Evolution than you are.
You can go waste your life
hunting down a stone.
You’re... going with that?
Mm-hm. Take it, for now.
They’re so lame.
Yamirami, I’m gonna get to
Mega Evolve you for sure!
We won’t fall behind, either!
Let’s set our sights on Mega Evolution!
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
This should be the right area, but...
...there’s no one around.
These parts ain’t exactly
crowded with people.
Hmm... Where could it be?
Mayo... Mayo...
Mayo-Maze Palace!
Mayo-Maze Palace
Go there!
My recommendation
for Mega Evolution training...
...is to challenge the Yellow Blast!
The Yellow Blast?
What’s that?
The Mayo-Maze Palace,
on the far east outskirts of Miare City...
...is home to proud warrior Pokémon.
The Yellow Blast is one of their number,
and many regard it as the strongest.
Ooh... “Strongest,” huh?
We’ll see about that.
Yearning for strong foes,
it awaits the arrival of challengers!
Many trainers have challenged it,
yet all have walked away in defeat.
If you have a strong bond
with your partner,
and skills sufficient
to prevail against it,
you will undoubtedly
be capable of Mega Evolution!
Awright! Now I’m gettin’ fired up!
But why is it called the Yellow Blast?
Well, well, that...
...is something
you ought to see for yourselves.
Who cares what it’s called?
Yamirami! Let’s move!
Ah... Hold on!
Honestly...
Rushing in headlong!
Not a bad approach!
Master Mayonnaise!
We’ll head there too!
I wish you good luck.
Plus...
You may, perhaps, be the one to...
Huh?
No, no... Worry not.
The Yellow Blast is a fierce opponent!
Face it with your full power!
Right!
Let’s give it our best shot,
Achigator!
A lot of these back streets are so narrow,
they’re not even on here...
Huh?
Ult, you’re a volunteer street cleaner?
Gets me some pocket money.
Walk all over Miare,
and eventually it adds up.
Cleans the city up too,
and Yamirami can look for gems.
“All over Miare”...
Then...
Wouldn’t you know the way there?
‘Course I do!
You know how many years I’ve lived in Miare?
Then show me the way!
Fat chance!
For an outsider, finding the place’ll
just have to be part of the training.
I’ve traveled the whole world!
I can handle it!
Oh, is this it?
I almost walked right past it.
When this alley... Opens back up...
There it is!
Mayo-Maze Palace.
Is it really gonna be in there?
What, you gettin’ scared?
You just got scared, huh?
I was not scared!
You were scared, weren’t you?!
I was just startled
‘cause the Yamikarasu suddenly cried out!
Well, guess it ain’t empty, at least...
What even is this place?!
Aw, this’s such a pain!
Left, Yamirami!
Let’s go through the right door.
What?! I’m goin’ right!
That guy sure gets
under your skin, huh?
Ack!
That hurt!
Hmm... Which way?
Ah... Hold on!
Huh? Ult?!
What’s goin’ on here?!
Hey, quit copying me!
Same to you!
Over there!
Don’t drop your guard, Ult!
Yeah! I’ll solve this place
before you do!
Whoa!
Ult!
Ow... Why’s this place
gotta keep startling me?
Thank you, Taikaiden.
Geez...
What’s a pit doing in this place?
Look!
What the heck?!
It’s just painted on!
If you had realized sooner,
you wouldn’t have wound up falling...
But now where’re we supposed to go?
Achigator?!
Now there’s a revolving door?!
That’s incredible, Achigator!
You found the way to go!
“Found” it? Ain’t that just luck?
Stairs!
All right!
Let’s keep going, carefully.
What’s with this place...?
Up and down and up again...
They say we should be fine here.
How can you tell?
Just look at Cap and Achigator.
It’s easy to see.
Pokémon can show us things
that we’d never know as humans.
Pokémon can...?
Nah, there’s no way.
There’s a door at the other end.
Let’s check it out.
But why does this place
have all these tricks in it...?
Who’s that?
Is that a Lucario?
Lucario. Guiding Waves Pokémon.
Fighting/Steel type.
It can use Guiding Waves to see the forms of others
in places that are out of sight,
as well as to detect
what its foes are feeling.
An alternate-colored
yellow Lucario...
It’s fast!
When’d it get over there?!
Sure! I’ll take you on!
Yamirami!
We’ll battle it too, Achigator!
I’m gonna whoop ya!
Power Gem!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
It vanished?!
Not good! Yamirami, dodge it!
Achigator! Nitro Char—
Yamirami, hang in there!
Are you okay, Achigator?!
It’s so fast...
It’s like wind blasting by.
A “Yellow Blast”?!
Rush in with spirit, Yamirami!
We’ll get it this time!
Nitro Charge!
W-We lost...
U U U U You & I...
U U U U You're not dreaming...
If nothing else, at least shout! (Woo!) The hex of impatience digs in
Though boors may cloud your vision, turn aside and keep walking
Why was I given this life? (Why?) Fate tests my very body
An evening star alone, closed eyes waiting for the light
Then, everything hiding in the flames...
All the sadness and hatred, blow it away, golden wind!
U U U U You & I... For such is love? Don't give me excuses!
U U U U You're not dreaming... Who are you? Don't get in my way!
Raising the curtains... is the task entrusted to us
Next episode
Argh... That stupid Yellow Blast!
That Lucario sure was strong.
That Mayonnaise guy
smells kinda fishy,
and I can’t seem to
make Mega Evolution work...
Argh, what should I do?!
Let’s train up
and challenge Lucario again!
Just you wait,
I’m gonna get payback no matter what!
‘Cause I’m the—
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Ult—Strongest
Who’s she?
Yeah! I’m the strongest!
Ult—Strongest