What’s that?
A yacht?
A boat?
No, it’s...
The legendary hero protecting
the seas of the world!
It’s Mighty G!
Our journey seeking
Entei of the Six Heroes continues.
Mr. Mamoru from the fishing boat rental shop
told us about a customer who saw Entei,
so we went to visit him straight away.
Oh, yeah! I saw it.
Went by like “whoosh”!
It was unreal.
It felt like good luck,
couldn’t help but stare in awe.
Think you could pin down
where that was on this map?
Hmm... ‘Round there, I guess?
Vanished right away, though.
Thanks a lot!
I reckon you’ll run across it too, hmm?
I know other folks’ve also seen it.
Really?!
Yep!
And so, we gathered reports
of Entei sightings.
No doubt about it at this point.
Just like Sodayo told us...
They even reach the archipelago
off the Asagi City coastline.
With them spread out so far,
searching’s gonna be rough.
Right.
I tried grouping
the sighting reports by date.
The more recent they are,
the more they clump up around the islands.
So Entei’s moving around?
Probably.
Then maybe Entei’s
right around here now!
All right,
let’s start by checking there.
It could be a volcanic island.
A volcanic island?
Entei is a Pokémon that’s
deeply connected to volcanoes, after all.
More than likely,
it’ll be nearby a volcano.
With that outta the way...
...let’s get ourselves ready!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
A Fierce Fight With Entei! A War Cry of Fire!!
Think Entei’s here?
Either way, the place
has a heck of an atmosphere...
What’s with this island...?
Huh?
You noticed it too?
There aren’t any Pokémon.
Maybe they all left ‘cause
the volcano’s about to erupt or something?
Huh?!
Er, I mean,
that’s only one possibility...
Okay!
Gimme a hand, Cap.
Perfect.
Hmm...
No need to worry
about an eruption, I think.
What makes you say that?
If this was a volcanic island,
we’d see signs of it in the rocks and sediment layers,
thanks to all the ash and lava.
But I don’t see a thing.
So there’s no volcano?
Then Entei isn’t here either?
Hmm...
Guess this won’t be that easy.
Friede!
What is it?
Come here a sec!
Gramps found a rare Pokémon!
Is that a Huntail?!
Mm-hmm.
Even I’ve never seen
a beached Huntail before.
Huntail. Deep Sea Pokémon.
Water type.
The deep sea is its habitat.
According to one legend,
a beached Huntail serves as a bad omen.
A bad omen?!
Should we be worried?!
It’s just a legend.
Fortune and misfortune
are two sides of the same coin.
Something abnormal is happening,
that much is certain.
We can never be too careful.
Don’t worry!
I’ve got the Brave Asagi
ready to fly at a moment’s notice.
Appreciate it.
Everything looks fine.
Get Huntail back into the sea for me.
Don’t get yourself beached again, okay?
Why would a Pokémon
that lives on the seabed be up here?
Maybe it was looking for food?
Or maybe it was
running away from something?
So that’s it!
Hmm? You figure something out?
Yup.
Everyone aboard the Brave Asagi!
We’re taking off!
Okay!
Over there.
See it?
The sea’s darker there...
That spot’s deeper
than anywhere else.
Maybe that’s where
the Huntail came from?
We’re right around the area
with the archipelago where Entei was spotted.
Wonder what’s in the sea
down there...
A volcano!
Huh?!
A volcano? In the sea?
It’s what’s called
a submarine volcano.
If we wait here,
Entei’s bound to come by.
Then let’s keep watch in shifts.
We finally get to meet Entei!
I can’t wait!
Brought some refreshments.
Awful quiet, eh?
Just gotta have patience.
Wh-What?!
Friede!
It’s close!
The sea is...!
Something’s happening!
Hard to port!
Terrifying, yet beautiful.
So that’s what it’s like
when a submarine volcano erupts...
Did Entei cause that eruption,
or did the eruption draw it here?
This means Entei has to be close by!
Let’s find it quick!
Murdock, can you fly us
to an island near the crater?
Leave it to me!
Let’s all prepare for landing!
Right!
Lizardon...
You stay here and
guard the ship, just in case.
Huh?
Is that...?
The birth of a new island...
We finally found it!
Entei!
Whoa!
No warm welcome for us, I guess.
Entei! We need your help,
as one of the Six Heroes!
Come to Rakua with—
Guess it’s not eager to listen...
But if we show it our strength...!
Yeah. That’s all we can do!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Entei is a Fire-type Pokémon.
Welcamo’s Water moves
will do the trick!
So will Achigator’s Ground move!
Still, blindly throwing out attacks
isn’t going to cut it against Entei...
Then we’ll make an opening for them!
Nyarote!
Cap! We’re gonna distract Entei, too!
Huh?
Nyarote!
That pressure’s nuts...
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Cap! Sacred Fire incoming!
That’s Cap for ya!
We’re sitting ducks for those flames
if we stick together.
Split up and attack!
Nyarote! Get behind it
and use Magical Leaf!
Now’s our chance!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Welcamo! Water Gun!
How ‘bout that?
No, wait!
It dodged!
That’s not all we’ve got!
Thunder Punch!
Its strength is on a whole other level...
You guys, follow my lead!
Shadow Clones!
Aqua Break!
Lightning Speed!
All right!
Huh?
Tch!
It took both those attacks head-on,
like they were nothing...
Entei!
Over here!
Achigator, use Stomping Tantrum!
Achigator?!
Is that Entei’s Supernatural Power?!
Achigator!
Not good! Cap, need you here!
Cap!
He got burned...
Let’s finish this quick!
Shadow Clones!
Nyarote!
Protect Nyarote! Aqua Break!
Cap...
You’re not outta juice yet, are ya?
All right! Voltteccer!
You’re using Voltteccer? Now?
A whole lot of Magical Leaves!
Water Gun!
You’ve got real grit, Cap.
That just leaves...
Let’s do this, Achigator!
You can do it, Achigator!
Go!
Just hit it...
...with all you’ve got!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Watch out! It’s Supernatural Power!
Don’t give up, Achigator!
All right, looking good!
Keep up the Stomping Tantrums!
The frustration of missing
gave the Stomping Tantrums a boost.
Awesome stuff, Achigator!
Did we get its approval?
Huh?
Pagogo?
Entei!
We’re seeking Rakua with Pagogo.
We have the other Six Heroes with us.
Come with us, Entei.
We’d like you to help Pagogo.
Entei?
It doesn’t want to listen to us?
Pagogo isn’t resonating.
No response from Oliva
or the others, either.
But why...?
Is it not interested in Pagogo...?
Wha...?
Whoa!
Wh-What’s that?!
Raikou?!
What?
An aurora!
Is that...?
Suikun...
Entei...
Entei, Raikou, Suikun...
A legendary trio,
gathered together in one place!
Dawn...
They’re gone...
Good work, Cap.
You okay?
The Six Heroes on the belt
didn’t react to it.
Pagogo wasn’t resonating, either.
That Entei wasn’t
one of the Six Heroes, then?
But we sure saw
something amazing, huh?!
Yeah, it was unbelievable
to see firsthand!
Yeah, it really was!
Once the lava cools and solidifies,
Pokémon will flock here...
And this island, too, will flourish.
Maybe Entei and the others came here
to celebrate the birth of a new island.
Please, tell me all about Rakurium.
I was unable to access
crucial portions of the data.
I implore you, please tell me.
Chairman Gibeon
possesses all of the data.
Understood.
What is it?
Excuse me.
Oh, it’s you, Spinel.
Director... Your son’s
at a difficult age, I gather.
You can say that again.
Hey! It’s me.
Ms. Briar!
Ooh! Terapagos!
It’s glowing as bright as ever!
Um... Is something up?
Ahem! I’ve got promising info.
An Entei is in
the Great Crater of Paldea!
Huh?!
It might be one of
the Six Heroes you’re looking for!
So that’s why you contacted us?
Thank you!
I did give you my promise.
Besides which...
The Six Heroes, as Pokémon able to draw special reactions
out of Terapagos, are most intriguing to me!
Is there any more you can tell us?
First, take a look at this.
It’s a page from the Scarlet Book...
...containing a rendition of a Pokémon
purportedly sighted in Area Zero.
Doesn’t it look like Entei?
Now that you mention it,
there are parts that resemble one...
And that’s not all!
Recently, what may well
have been an Entei was spotted...
...on footage recorded
by Area Zero observation cameras.
That definitely sounds
worth investigating!
Yeah!
Professor Friede... With you on board,
Ms. Omodaka’s bound to approve an investigation!
Well then, see you in Paldea!
Oh, hold on!
She sure hasn’t changed...
And that’s about the gist of it.
I see.
So we’ve got a new lead!
Maybe this is a divine blessing
from that Entei.
Those bold enough to forge their own paths
find themselves oft blessed with assistance.
Okay! We’re headed for Paldea!
To the Great Crater!
Area Zero!
Entei of the Six Heroes!
Yeah!
Entei...
The black Rekkuuza...
The Six Heroes...
And then, with them...
To Rakua!
The Rising Voltteccers...
...set off!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Volcano Pokémon, Entei.
Entei
Volcano Pokémon
Type: Fire
Entei
Volcano Pokémon
Type: Fire
A Pokémon that races across the land,
with the passion of magma dwelling inside it.
Height
2.1m
Weight
198.0kg
Whenever Entei roars,
do you know what is said to occur?
What occurs when Entei roars?
An eruption
A lightning strike
Torrential rain
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What occurs when Entei roars?
A: An eruption
The answer is A: An eruption!
Various places have legends
stating that whenever Entei roars...
...a volcano erupts
somewhere in the world!
Next episode
Um...
When we went to get permission
to look for Entei in the Great Crater...
No one told us about this!
We have to battle Ms. Omodaka?!
But it’s a chance to battle
the Top Champion! That’s incredible!
Yeah, you’re right.
We have to show her what we’re made of
if we want to keep moving forward!
Let’s do it!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Over the Top