All right! Now, you give it a go.
Okay.
I’m feeling nervous...
Keep your body loose.
I’m really steering the ship...
You’ll get used to it over time.
You’re the ones who choose
where the Brave Asagi goes now.
We’re the ones at the helm...
The reason we reunited...
...is to rid the world of Rakurium!
That’s what we promised Lucius.
But the Explorers are attempting to
spread Strong Spheres, which use Rakurium.
We’ve got to stop them,
no matter what!
All right! Let’s track down every last guy usin’ one
and hand ‘em a beatdown! Mega-piece of cake!
We can’t stop them just like that.
Hmph! The bigger the foe,
the more fired up I get!
This isn’t something
we can solve with battling.
We need to make the people at Exceed
realize that Strong Spheres are dangerous!
Ugh, this is such a pain!
Meaning we need to investigate
the dangers of Strong Spheres further...
As well as the relationship
between Rakurium and Pokémon.
Still, we’ve been totally made out to seem like
some dangerous adventurer gang...
To think the Explorers
have come to be seen as “heroes”...
How very fragile justice can be.
Let’s go to Orange Academy!
Botan will believe us!
About what the Explorers
are really like!
Principal Clavel and Ms. Omodaka...
They know that we battled the Explorers
when they invaded Orange Academy, too!
Besides, I can’t think of any better place
to seek out advice about Rakurium!
Sounds like it’s settled, eh, Cap?
Right!
I’ll put together some material
for when we arrive!
So, where’s this
Orange Whatsit place?
The Paldea Region.
It’s the school where
the three of us studied Terastal.
“School”...?
And so, we find ourselves on our way
to Orange Academy in the Paldea Region.
His room’s all ready for him, but...
Where is Ult?
Only his Yamirami’s here.
Could you tell me where he is?
Can’t handle this...
My head’s spinning...
I thought... I’d do okay flying...
Yamirami... Just leave me be...
Don’t do that, Masquernya!
Gah! Liko!
Hey, Ult. Your room’s all ready!
It’s right across from Dot—
Meh, don’t need one.
Huh? But if you’re going to be
living aboard the ship...
Guh... A room that just rocks back ‘n’ forth
and makes me all dizzy. I can’t handle...
I-I mean, uh,
sounds way too cramped for me!
If you don’t like it,
we can get another—
I want that one!
I mega-like this.
There was someone else who used
this spot instead of a room, too...
But how come?
From here...
Look! You can see the sky!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Fight! Terastal Versus Mega Evolution!!
Whoa!
So this is the Orange Whatsit.
It’s mega-huge!
It’s sort of nostalgic being back here!
“Rakurium” is the name of the crystals
which were discovered on Mt. Kumuri...
Yeah!
Dot? What’s wrong?
Nothing. I’m just a bit worried about being able to
explain the material on Rakurium to the staff properly...
It was all really easy to understand!
You sure about that...?
It totally was!
Just explain it as if
you were making a Gurumin vid!
A Gurumin...!
Right.
Think they’ll be okay on their own?
Weren’t you the one who encouraged them
to go do it on their own?
They say “The Pinpuku we cherish
must be made to face the world,” do they not?
Besides, they are the ones
most suited to tell all about Rakurium.
Got that right!
Then we’ll protect the ship!
Yep. I’ve gotta get
the Brave Asagi ready for take off!
You go out shopping!
It has been quite some time
since I’ve seen you all.
Could that be a new friend of yours?
I’m Ult!
This is the mega-strongest Yamirami!
A pleasure to meet you.
I am Orange Academy’s principal, Clavel.
And I’m the board chairwoman, Omodaka.
S-Sure...
Ms. Omodaka’s also a representative
of the Pokémon League, and the Top Champion.
Wait, so you mean she’s the strongest?!
Ms. Liko...
I see she’s evolved into Masquernya.
And Mr. Roy has gained a Lucario.
You have all grown into
much stronger-looking people.
We’ve heard the rumors surrounding
the Rising Voltteccers.
Those are...
All the rumors Exceed is spreading
are made-up nonsense!
We are well aware.
They haven’t shaken our trust in you.
Thank you so much!
Well then, please present
the matter you have at hand.
Right.
It started with sightings of Pokémon
acting abnormally in various regions.
They were shrouded in a pink haze,
and became extremely aggressive.
These effects were caused by Rakurium,
the crystals that were discovered at Rakua on Mt. Kumuri.
And we believe Rakurium
is being used by Exceed...
...in the development of tools
to enhance the strength of Pokémon.
They’re called Strong Spheres.
Strong Spheres...
Yes.
While clearly effective
at imparting power,
they seem to cause great strain to Pokémon,
making them tire out quickly.
In addition, there have been cases
where they stop listening to their trainers’ orders.
I see.
Understood.
I trust in you all.
However...
I’d like to have a more thorough
understanding, wouldn’t you?
Yes. We will consider what measures to pursue
once we’ve seen more detailed data and video proof.
We need more data...
In addition,
you would need to investigate...
...the relationship between
Rakurium and Pokémon.
But, how would we...?
Let me introduce you
to the right person to ask.
Rakurium, you say...?
That is highly intriguing
research material...
Ms. Dot, you collated all of this?
That’s some brilliant work!
S-Sure.
But there’s still so much
we don’t know...
The principal said we should
come speak with you, Mr. Zinnia...
I used to be
a Pokémon biology researcher.
Back then, Mr. Clavel wasn’t in education either...
He was researching alongside me at the same facility.
The principal was a researcher...
So that’s why he knew so much about the relationship
between Pokémon, Area Zero, and Terapagos!
It was so much fun...
Researching Pokémon with him, day in and day out!
I got yelled at all the time, though.
Huh? Where’d those guys go?
I’m hungry...
It’s that way.
As you can see,
Pagogo calmed the aggressive Pokémon down.
Purification via Terapagos, huh...?
This looks mega-tasty!
Osu!
You’re not a student here, are you?!
Uh-oh!
Let’s go, Yamirami!
Stop that boy!
Huh?!
Gotta run!
So you all believe
that the effects of Rakurium...
...are what caused these Pokémon
to turn aggressive.
Yes. But we don’t believe
that’s the full extent of what it does.
For example,
it strengthens their life force, and such...
I see, a material that stimulates
the activation of life force...
Quite interesting!
Many crystals found in various regions
are new and unknown.
Hey, wait!
Even Paldea’s Terastal
is still undergoing further research.
Don’t let him get away!
There could be some connection
to Rakua being a Pokémon paradise, too...
Rakua... That’s where
these crystals originated, yes?
I’d like to investigate there,
if possible...
Exceed’s taken control of it
and made it off limits.
Unfortunate.
I’ve got it!
I’ll look into the effects
of Rakurium on Pokémon, too!
Oh! Thank you very much!
Let’s keep one another updated
on the findings of our investigations!
Right! We look forward
to working with you!
Huh? That reminds me...
Where’s Ult?
I wonder if he got lost...
Nemo!
Roy!
Long time no see!
Ms. Kihada!
Let! Me! Go!
Roy! You’ve grown!
And on your wrist... Is that...?
It’s a Mega Ring.
I’ve been training in the Kalos Region.
Mm-hmm! You are bearing fruit!
That guy over there, Ult,
was training alongside me.
I see. So you’re also a member
of the Rising Voltteccers...
Told ya! I’m not shady or nothin’!
Ah, sorry about that. Let ‘em go.
Hey, Roy! I haven’t seen you in ages,
so we should battle!
Sure! I’ll introduce you
to my new friend!
A battle to commemorate
your reunion, huh?
I shall oversee it!
Okay!
Let’s have us a fruitful battle!
Osu! You will each battle
with two Pokémon!
Whichever trainer takes down
one Pokémon first will be the victor!
Let’s do it, Achigator!
And... Lucario!
A Lucario?!
And it’s an alternate-color one?!
Great stuff!
Well then, here I go!
Time to begin
our greatest battle of all, Roy!
Yeah!
Everybody ready?!
Let the battle begin!
Let’s go, Lucario! Infight!
Parmot! Mach Punch!
Their power and speed
are evenly matched...
That’s a battle between
Fighting types for you!
That Nemo ain’t half bad.
Yeah, naturally!
She’s a League Champion!
Huh?!
Aburibbon!
Give Parmot a Pollen Dumpling!
Give Parmot another—!
Not gonna let you heal any more!
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
Aburibbon!
Use Pollen Dumpling on Achigator!
Are you okay, Achigator?!
Pollen Dumpling
is a move that heals allies,
but will change up
to attack enemies...
Dot. You’re at the school, right?
I, uh, should talk with you
about something.
Botan... Uh, right now,
I’m out on the grounds—
Somewhere less noisy. Come here.
She’s still so pushy...
Now! Use this chance
to build up power, Parmot!
Lucario, Luster Cannon!
Achigator, you hit Parmot with Flamethrower!
Aburibbon! Light Screen!
Ugh... It got blocked!
All right! Let’s end this, Parmot!
Use Focus Punch!
Achigator! Lucario!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
C-Come in...
Pardon the intrusion...
This is kinda cozy...
This is my heaven,
surrounded by merch and Veevees...
They’re all so cute.
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
Oh, yeah. What was it
you wanted to talk about?
Right. What I’ve been investigating.
A map of the Paldea Region...
Huh? What’s this?
I checked the observation cameras.
And organized the Rakurium Sign sighting points.
You could use it for your vids,
so copy it. It’ll help.
Th-Thanks.
Even if Roy lands attack after attack,
Aburibbon’s Pollen Dumpling will just heal the damage!
That ain’t all!
How’s he gonna beat that mega-speedy,
mega-powerful Parmot’s Fighting moves?!
We’ve got to stop him!
Lucario! Achigator!
Not if I can help it!
Aburibbon! Sticky Net!
Achigator!
Break through it with Nitro Charge!
Parmot!
You’re up, Aburibbon!
Use Pollen Dumpling on Parmot!
Now’s our chance, Achigator!
Good job, Achigator!
He did it!
They’re still at it!
Dot? Where did you go?
I was getting some info from Botan about
the Rakurium Sign sightings in the Paldea Region!
It’s been a while.
Hey.
Here it comes!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Whoa, he Mega Evolved!
That’s amazing, Roy!
You are bearing fruit!
All right!
I’ll hit you with my full strength!
Parmot!
Shine bright!
My greatest treasure!
It’s a head-to-head battle
between their trump cards!
Lucario, use Infight!
Parmot! Mach Punch!
He’s powered up with Terastal!
So this is the power
of Mega Evolution!
Achigator!
Help out with Stomping Tantrum!
Aburibbon! Energy Ball!
Let’s end this! Parmot!
Lucario, stop Parmot!
Aburibbon!
Use tons of Pollen Dumplings!
Achigator! Time to dig in!
Lucario!
Let’s finish this, Lucario! Metal Claw!
Give it everything we’ve got!
Parmot! Focus Punch!
Parmot is unable to battle!
The winner is Roy!
We did it! Achigator! Lucario!
That was amazing, Roy!
I was fighting
with all my strength, too...
It’s my loss today!
You did it, Roy!
You did it!
Osu! That heated battle between friends
had my heart leaping with joy!
Good work out there. Return!
Parmot, Aburibbon... Thank you.
Ahh, now that was fun!
Yeah. You almost had me!
I never thought Parmot
would be a Fighting Terastype!
I could sense the potential
within Parmot’s Focus Punch, you see.
You keep on striving even though
you’re already a Champion. That’s amazing!
This is my passion,
so it’s only natural!
Now, Roy, let’s have a quick break
and then go again!
Do a battle with me this time!
Sure thing!
Now, who should I use this time...?
That Terastal versus Mega Evolution battle
was amazing, Welcamo!
Dot...
Huh?
Wanna battle with me?
Botan?! Battling?!
But why now, outta nowhere...?
I saw a gleam in your eye,
so I thought you were gearing up for some carnage.
Carnage?!
H-Huh?!
Master Amethio... Though we’ve searched so much,
we haven’t found a single trace of you...
Where could you have gone?
Even without any clues,
keeping up the search is all we can do!
Zygarde... Please...
Guide us!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Mega Evolving today is
the Seed Pokémon, Fushigibana!
Seed Pokémon
Poison
Fushigibana
Seed Pokémon
Grass
Poison
Fresh Greenery
Fushigibana
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Seed Pokémon
Fresh Greenery
Fushigibana
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Seed Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
To support the flower on its back,
which has grown even larger,
Mega Fushigibana
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Seed Pokémon
Grass
Poison
Thick Fat
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
its legs have become even sturdier!
Even if oodles of Bug Pokémon show up,
lured in by its scent, it doesn’t mind at all.
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Now that’s Mega Evolution for ya.
Even if a hundred Pokémon were to ride on it—
Next episode
Dot! Go for it!
Huh? What’s wrong, Welcamo?
He’s acting kinda weird...
Hee-hee-hee,
my battles have a unique twist.
Okay then, about time I finish this!
Pull yourself together, Welcamo!
Wh-What do we do?!
She’s in real trouble! Roy!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
The Knight Met at the Ruins
Huh?! Ruins?! Knight?!
Look forward to it.