Our Terastal Course basics tests are over,
and our friendly matches have begun.
In a surprising turn, our opponents are
the Paldea League’s Elite Four!
Dot and Roy had heated battles;
all-out clashes with their opponents!
And now, it’s finally my turn.
With Kaede-san backing me up,
I’ll be facing Chili-san!
This is starting to
make me feel nervous!
Her opponent’s Pokémon
are both Ground types,
so Liko has the type advantage, right?
Do'oh is also a Poison type,
so I don’t think it’s that simple...
Liko should be fine!
It’s gonna be an awesome battle!
That troublemaker!
Liko! Go for it!
Show ‘em your stuff!
Exleg-chan is all fired up, too!
Well, he is facing off with Chili-san
of the Elite Four, I suppose!
Even my heart is beating faster!
I’ll... do my best, too...
Liko-san... Remember,
you should enjoy your battles.
Y-Yes...
Right... I need to show
what I learned in my basics test...
But what else? What else?
Osu! Competitors, are you ready?
Hold up a sec!
What’s wrong?
Huh?! Huh?!
You’re stiff as a board!
You’re in no shape to battle.
Well... I s’pose it’s natural to be nervous,
on account of Chili-chan being so good-looking.
There she goes,
talking herself up...
Ooh! Thanks for playing the foil!
Really though,
what’s got ya so frazzled?
I-I’m sorry!
Still so tense!
Wanna give my Do'oh a rub
to try and relax?
Aww, there’s a good boy!
So doughy! So soothing!
Whoa!
He’s poisonous, so you can’t
touch him barehanded!
Huh?!
See these gloves
Chili-chan’s wearing?
Please stop teasing me!
So? Feelin’ a bit less tense now?
I... do feel better now,
somehow...
Let’s get to it, then!
Yeah!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Liko VS Chili! At the End of the Battle
Let the battle begin!
Here we come!
Dugtrio, use Dig!
Do'oh, use Sludge Wave!
Some big moves right off the bat!
Sludge Wave is powerful,
but it hits your allies too.
So that’s why she used Dig!
It was waiting
right where she was gonna land!
Yeah.
It’s not very effective on Nyarote,
but repeated hits could still sting.
Dugtrio! Dig!
Do'oh, gimme another Sludge Wave!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Nyarote, dodge!
Oh, no!
It’ll be just like last time!
That was amazing, Nyarote!
You’re good!
But this ain’t over yet!
Dugtrio! Rock Slide!
Nyarote!
Hell Thrust!
Guess it couldn’t be that easy.
You saved us, Kaede-san!
Getting to help others is
what makes Tag Battles so wonderful.
But you shouldn’t fixate on just
Do'oh-chan, don’t you think?
Have a good look
at your surroundings.
My surroundings...?
Ya sure take things at face value, huh?
Huh?!
That what makes Liko-san so charming!
However...
Your mind’s on all sorts of other stuff.
It’s a real mess.
Am I wrong?
Well...
You shouldn’t think about anything else
when you’re battling.
Trainers and Pokémon having
all-out clashes to try and win!
That’s what a Pokémon battle is!
Your face is saying
“I know that already,” yeah?
If the goal of a battle is winning it,
what do ya think I battle for?
T-To win!
You really do
take things at face value, eh?
You’re not wrong,
but there’s more to it.
Um...
I’m willing to bet...
...you’ll understand what she means
by the end of this battle.
Well, I’ve rambled a whole bunch,
but for now...
Just stay focused on winning and come at me!
That’s all I’m tryin’ to say.
Let us accept her kind offer
and give this our all.
I can feel Nyarote’s
enthusiasm and excitement!
Okay! I’ll keep my mind on winning this!
I dig that look on your face.
Let’s get back to it, then!
If I... can’t find it soon...
Huh? Hold up, Kuwassu!
Aw, geez...
I need a breather...
Wait, seriously?! They’ve got tons of
issues of Monthly Occulture!
“Ancient Pokémon Feature”...
I’ve been wanting to read this one!
Oops. I’ll borrow it later.
Up there?
Hi.
Oh, u-uh...
That bag...
An Eevee...
Wait, no!
I meant that one...
That’s my friend’s bag.
Bag?
A Pokémon’s inside...
Um... Please don’t tell anyone about it.
Got something going on? Okay.
Wai— Give it back!
Shh! Don’t yell. Um...
Dot.
Huh?! How do you know my name?!
Man, what is even going on anymore?!
Do'oh, use Sludge Wave!
Dugtrio, use Dig!
Nyarote, use a sharp Magical Leaf!
All right!
Impressive!
But don’t go thinkin’ you’re home free!
Nyarote, here he comes!
Magical Leaf!
She did it!
It’s super effective!
So that’s her approach
to using moves...
It’s rare that someone
piques your interest, Grusha-san.
Is it?
Good going!
You’re fighting admirably, Liko-san!
Right!
Now you’ve got the rhythm!
Meaning Chili-chan
oughta kick it into high gear, too!
Do'oh, use Mud Shot!
Dugtrio, use Rock Slide!
So many projectiles...
If she keeps this up...
I’ll create an opening.
Exleg-chan! Lunge!
Smack him down!
Liko-san! Now!
Nyarote, use Lightning Speed!
Thought so!
Poison Jab!
Nyarote!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Nyarote!
Exleg-chan!
Nyarote’s safe, but look at Exleg!
That may have been on purpose.
What do you mean?
We’ll get to see Kaede-san like that...
Huh? What?!
The ability Bugout!
It powers up Bug-type moves
when you’re driven into a corner!
Cool!
Liko-san... I apologize.
I don’t think
I can hold back any longer!
Huh?!
I’ll show you the real me,
if you don’t mind!
Exleg-chan, use Bug Struggle!
Lemme see what you can
really do, Kaede-san!
Mud Shot! Rock Slide!
Incredible...
You gotta stick it out,
Do'oh and Dugtrio!
With the tremendous power
of a small bug,
twist them into knots
‘til they’re black and blue all over!
Lunge!
And then... Bounce!
Exleg is unable to battle!
That’s it for me.
He finally succumbed to
Poison Jab’s poison.
Good job sticking it out,
Do'oh and Dugtrio...
It feels so nice
to go all out in a battle!
Kaede-san... You were amazing!
Liko-san... Dugtrio will be
out of commission for a while.
I leave the rest up to you.
Right! I’ll have an all-out clash
with my opponent, too!
Let’s do this, Nyarote!
It’s so peculiar...
I can tell just how Nyarote is feeling!
You want to leap around
like Exleg did, don’t you?
Poison-type moves are
super effective on Grass types.
Is she gonna be okay?
Even so, Exleg’s Bug Struggle
has lowered the power of Do'oh’s moves.
This should be a good match.
How do you know my name?
The Terastal Course registration system...
I do maintenance for it.
Huh?
I’m an engineer for the Pokémon League...
I handle the school’s systems, too.
That’s amazing!
Shh!
Sorry...
As for me... I make apps for my team,
so I’m interested in that kind of stuff...
What is it?
Good. Agesen didn’t hear us.
Agesen?
Ms. Agepan...
That’s why she’s Agesen?
Agepan-sensei
Agesen’s data
appeared from nowhere one day...
Something’s off.
Just a bug, maybe?
I can only hope...
If you’re curious,
why not talk to her?
I’m... no good at that.
How about...?
Wha—?!
I-I’m no good at that, either!
Sheesh...
Don’t run off on your own!
Oh?
You’re one of the course students.
H-Hi...
What has you so flustered?
Oh, uh...
Ah! Ma’am, are you a fan of Occulture?
“A Prehistoric Ulgamoth, Revived”...
“A Billion-Year-Old Purin”...
They’re all absurd.
Well... Yeah, but...
Every rumor has a kernel of truth.
They could be connected
to some genuine mysteries...
I can certainly agree with that.
However...
Some truths are best left unlearned,
and some truths
must never be revealed...
Well, who’s to say?
See you around.
I really feel like I’ve seen her
somewhere before...
“The Scarlet Book”...
What’s it about?
You’re interested in that drawing?
Wonder what it is...
That book was written by
a natural historian named Heather.
Huh... I think Agesen was reading it.
Who is Agesen, exactly?
I’d like to know, too...
Sorry, but I gotta go!
Let me know if you learn anything about Agesen.
Sure.
So your name’s Botan...
Oh right, I never said.
Ah! Okay, see you!
Use a sharp Magical Leaf!
Mud Shot!
Lightning Speed!
Keep her away with Mud Shot!
You ain’t got Exleg anymore!
Poison Jab!
Nyarote!
Dodge it with your vine again!
What was that?!
A nimble dodge and attack...
Superb Acrobatics!
Acrobatics...
You did it, Nyarote!
That was a new move!
She keeps getting stronger this battle!
What’d I miss?
Hoo, boy!
I can’t get enough of this!
They’re Do'oh’s most charming feature,
but he won’t be showing his spikes off again!
Do'oh! Mud Shot!
Nyarote!
Chili-san’s so strong...
Someone this strong
is going all out against me?
Earlier, I asked why ya think
I do Pokémon battles, right?
What are ya thinkin’ now, Liko?!
To immerse yourself in the battle!
When I get immersed in a battle,
I can sense how Nyarote feels!
I become one with Nyarote!
It’s so much fun!
Nyarote always takes battles seriously...
Ever since she was a Nyahoja...
So I should treat them seriously, too!
That’s just the kinda face
I wanted to see!
Lemme treat ya to all I’ve got!
Nyarote!
Shine in full bloom!
Do'oh! Raise the earth!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Do'oh! Earth Power!
Nyarote is unable to battle!
The winner is Chili!
Chili-chan bringing it home!
Thank you, Nyarote.
Huh? Why am I...?
You took the fight seriously.
Bitter tears like these
are something to cherish.
Liko! You were so close!
That was a fierce battle!
I know you’re gonna get even stronger!
You were super awesome!
Yeah! We were all amazing!
Liko never says stuff like that...
Pretty surprising...
But Chili-chan was
just a cut above in the end, eh?
Thank you very much, Chili-san.
Now I like battles a whole lot more
than I ever have before!
You’re the Nyarote trainer, right?
I saw your match.
Huh? Who’s this?
Grusha-san! Sorry for the wait.
If that’s enough to raise your spirits,
you’re pretty frigid.
Excuse us.
Huh...?
Who was that?!
Did you just set up a battle?!
Huh?! No way!
Huh? Oh, well...
I wanna face someone strong again...
I... I’d like to do that, too!
Next time, I’m gonna be much stronger,
and have them battle way more seriously!
Right!
Sorry for the wait!
Have you seen this book before?
I borrowed it from the library.
Terapagos seems interested
in this drawing for some reason...
That’s a weird drawing...
It looks kind of like Terapagos.
I don’t know anything about it...
But it looks interesting, right?
Yeah! Not knowing makes it better!
This feels like the start of an adventure!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Spiky Fish Pokémon, Do'oh.
Do'oh
Spiky Fish Pokémon
Type: Poison/Ground
Do'oh
Spiky Fish Pokémon
Type: Poison/Ground
It may seem carefree
and completely careless,
Height
1.8m
but it has certain hidden weapons
it uses to protect itself.
Weight
223.0kg
Do you know what those weapons are?
What are Do oh's hidden weapons?
`
Spikes
Throwing stars
Hammers
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What are Do oh's hidden weapons?
A: Spikes
`
The answer is A: Spikes!
When attacked by an opponent,
it counters by extending poisonous spikes from its back.
A wise Do'oh hides its spikes!
Next episode
A message from Friede and the crew!
They wanna celebrate
us passing our basics tests!
All right! We get to see everyone!
I wanna eat something tasty!
After the meal, we’ll go to
the principal’s office at the academy.
Why? Did he call us?
And then on to some
treasure-hunting fieldwork.
Treasure? That sounds fun!
We might figure out Terapagos’s secrets!
I’m so curious!
I wanna know!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters:
A Terapagos I Had Never Known
Make sure to watch!