We, the Rising Voltteccers,
have come to the Kitakami hamlet.
We’re climbing Oni Mountain to visit Ms. Briar,
who knows a lot about Terapagos.
Along the way, in Hell Valley, Dot’s Kanuchan
evolved into Nakanuchan. It was such a surprise!
And now, we’re finally closing in
on our destination: the Shining Pond.
The Shining Pond is at the summit here!
Keep it up, everyone!
Looks like even your egg
is full of energy, Achigator!
Just a little farther...
Dot, are you doing okay?
Y-Yeah...
They’ve got so much energy...
Come quick, everyone!
This is unreal!
Wow... So this is the Shining Pond!
“Shining Pond:
“Long ago, crystalline material was brought
from elsewhere and dissolved into this pond.
“Its water has a faint glow, but it is safe to drink
and even serves as the village’s water source.”
Crystals from long ago, huh?
Think it has anything to do with Terastal?
It may have some connection to the wild Pokémon
being able to Terastallize outside of Paldea.
“One legend states that gazing upon the light of
the pond can allow you to meet with the dead,” it says.
Do they come out of the light?!
That’s awesome!
Where’s Ms. Briar?
I don’t see her anywhere.
I’ll search the area with Cap.
You guys stay here and rest.
It’s so pretty!
It said we can meet with the dead...
Think that’s for real?
It’s really mysterious...
I think I can understand
why they have that legend.
What’s that?!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Meeting at the Shining Pond
What Pokémon is that?
It— It’s mad...
Milokallos. Affection Pokémon.
Water type.
It lives at the bottom of clear lakes.
In times of war, it shows itself
to soothe people’s hearts.
Soothe people’s hearts?
She’s nothing like the Index says!
Terastal?!
A Ghost Terastal!
Yeah. Nyarote!
Welcamo...? I gotcha.
Yeah. We’ll just have to
handle this ourselves!
Normal moves won’t work
on a Ghost Terastal, so be careful!
Right.
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Welcamo! Water Gun!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Man... She’s so fast.
We can’t hit her like this!
Nyarote!
Next time she surfaces,
latch onto her with your bud!
That’s when we’ll attack, Achigator!
Welcamo, I’m counting on you!
All right!
Now! Flamethrower!
Nyarote!
Are you okay?!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
She got away again.
If we just knew when she was
going to pop up, we could hit her...
What if we lure her out?
I know! Let’s do some yo-yo fishing,
like back at the festival!
Yo-yo fishing?
We can use Nyarote’s bud!
All right, then let’s have Nyarote
and Welcamo team up for that.
Right!
When she pops up,
I’ll attack with Achigator!
Let’s get this plan rolling!
Nyarote! Grab Welcamo!
Welcamo! Taunt Milokallos
with that dance you did earlier!
Achigator!
When she comes up, hit her!
There she is!
Nyarote, pull!
Nice!
Roy!
Right!
Achigator! Charm Voice!
They’re both using Charm Voice!
Nice work, Achigator!
It’s like they’re communicating
through song.
The plan went off
without a hitch, Achigator!
Marvelous!
You three are positively gleaming!
What happened?
A Milokallos attacked us
out of nowhere.
Milokallos are usually docile...
You’re saying it attacked you unprovoked?
That’s strange...
The Shining Pond’s composition
must have affected that Milokallos somehow.
You must be...
Briar.
Ms. Raifort told me all about you.
You’re the Rising Voltteccers’...
I’m Liko.
This is my partner, Nyarote.
I’m Roy!
This is Achigator.
Dot...
This is my Welcamo.
Nice to meet you all.
I hear there’s something
you’d like to ask me about.
Ooh!
That’s Terapagos, is it not?!
Let me take a good, close look!
S-Sure...
Oh! Hold on!
Wait!
Please!
She’s quite an... eccentric teacher, huh?
Forgive me.
I didn’t expect you to
have one with you.
Ms. Raifort didn’t mention
that particular detail.
I couldn’t help but get excited.
So you’ve seen a Terapagos before?
Yes. An awakened specimen
similar to this one, at that.
Really? That’s amazing!
I’m in the process of compiling
my research up to this point into a book.
I aim to get it published,
and it’s nearly ready to go.
The crystals submerged in the Shining Pond
have a similar composition to the ones in Paldea.
Then... Is that why wild Pokémon
can Terastallize in the Kitakami hamlet?
Researching Terastal is essential
to the study of Terapagos.
Um...
Please, tell us more!
Of course.
I’d like to hear more
about your Terapagos, as well.
My tent is right nearby.
Let me show you the way.
You’re good kids, you know that?
Where’s your partner, miss?
I get so wrapped up in studying Pokémon
that I’ve never quite found a partner of my own.
That so?
I think I get what you mean.
I also love Pokémon, and my head’s
stuffed to the brim from studying them.
But I have someone
to watch over me, and...
That would be Welcamo, right?
Yeah.
I see...
So, it was originally a pendant
your grandmother gave you...
Terapagos really do take
the form of jewels to hibernate, then.
How intriguing...
In addition, you’re attempting to
trace an adventurer named Lucius,
who traveled with Pokémon
called the Six Heroes.
Lucius was headed for
a Pokémon paradise known as Rakua.
Rakua the Pokémon paradise, huh?
Unfortunately, I don’t know anything about it
beyond recalling the name from an old history book.
Not a thing?
I’m sorry.
Still... This adventurer, Lucius...
He must have met that Terapagos somewhere.
Just like Heather did.
Heather? That’s...
Heather was the first researcher
to record the name “Terapagos.”
He’s also an ancestor of mine.
Huh?! You’re descended from
Mr. Heather, miss?
Yes.
It’s my dream to solve
the mysteries of Terapagos...
...and prove that Heather was right!
Ooh!
All right!
Let me show you
a little treasure of mine.
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Heather’s own writing:
The Scarlet Book!
That book... It’s the same one I found
in the Orange Academy library!
This one is the original tome.
Look here! The pages that are
illegible in the published copies...
...are fully intact!
You’re right!
You can read all of it!
“A Disk Pokémon?”
Yes. It details the first time
he encountered Terapagos.
So that’s Mr. Heather...
Heather was a novelist,
as well as a natural history researcher.
He was selected to participate
in the Area Zero Expedition,
which delved into
the Paldea Region’s Great Crater.
And after a prolonged journey,
they eventually reached its depths.
There they found a cave
full of shining jewels.
He met a strange Pokémon,
which he would later dub “Terapagos.”
He encountered numerous other
mysterious Pokémon in Area Zero, as well.
That space was filled with
Terastal waves.
Perhaps Heather thought
those waves guided them there.
But Heather’s book was regarded as a mere
occult story, and hardly anyone believes it.
That’s why I intend to solve
the mysteries of Terapagos...
...and prove that Heather was right!
It’s the same for me.
Lucius, who I learned about from my grandma...
And Rakua, the place he sought...
I’m traveling because
I want to uncover them.
We’re kindred spirits.
Um...
This is her adventure log.
A log of your grandmother’s investigations
into Lucius and the Six Heroes, huh?
An impressive effort...
These are Lucius’s memoirs,
which she found in her attic along with the pendant.
Mm.
I bet Lucius must’ve read
that Scarlet Book somewhere, too.
And that’s why he used the name
“Terapagos” in his memoirs.
Indeed, this is a Terastal Forme Terapagos.
So that’s called the Terastal Forme, then...
We’ve only seen it for a short while.
Changing from Normal Forme to Terastal Forme
requires a special impetus or power of some kind...
Or so I theorize.
Special... Of course!
It was when we met
the black Rekkuuza from the Six Heroes!
Interesting...
Maybe the Six Heroes
and that Terapagos...
...have some special connection
that I’ve never observed.
And back then...
By the way, miss...
Have you heard of a substance
called Rakurium?
Rakurium?
It’s a substance that we believe
can have unusual effects on Pokémon.
Such a thing exists?
How intriguing...
But I’m afraid I haven’t.
That so?
Goodness me, there are so many things
I’ve never even heard of!
Miss, are you okay?
Oh, I am gleaming!
By speaking with you, I’ve learned more about
Terapagos’s mysteries, and just how deep they run!
What a marvelous day this is!
Back to the Shining Pond, you mean?
Yes.
Your Terapagos must have memories
of being with Lucius.
And those memories
might be able to show us something.
Yes.
Besides, the Shining Pond is even more
mysterious and beautiful at night.
Let’s go find out if the legend is true!
A place where people can meet with
the dead they desire to see again...
That’s what the Shining Pond is.
So then...
Maybe we can meet with Lucius.
We prayed to meet with Lucius...
Though nothing happened.
But gazing upon Terapagos and
the Shining Pond, gleaming in the night...
It reminded me
once again of my desire...
...to find the Six Heroes and discover
the way to Rakua, which Lucius himself reached.
The next morning, we bid Ms. Briar farewell,
promising we’d meet again.
As for her, she stayed behind
to continue her research.
I’ll contact you if I learn anything
from my research at Area Zero.
Well then, ‘til next time.
So no leads, eh?
But still, Ms. Briar and Mr. Heather...
It was a thrill to hear from others
pursuing the mysteries of Pokémon.
I was happy to find more people
like us and my grandma.
So, what’s the next move
for the Rising Voltteccers?
Naturally, we’ll be tracking down
the remaining three of the Six Heroes.
Easy enough to say,
but where do we start?
Basagiri, Entei, and Rekkuuza, huh...?
They’ll all be tough.
Hmm... Long road ahead of us.
By the way, where’s Dot?
When she headed out, she said she was going to get
footage of Suiryoku Town’s signs and stuff for her videos.
Nice!
Huh? Welcamo?
Where’d you go?
That’s a Guardie...
But its fur is kinda weird...
Huh?! Hisui?!
That’s the old name
for the Sinnoh Region, right?!
Schoolkid...
My Guardie catch your eye?
No, uh, it’s a Hisuian...
Th-That’s impossible, err, I mean...
S-Since that’s impossible, maybe you can tell me
about something that could actually be possible!
Perfect attitude!
Not afraid to be nosy!
You’re absolutely right. I come from the ancient land
once known as Hisui—the Sinnoh Region.
Huh?! Then...
Um... Do you happen to
know anything about Basagiri?
Basagiri...
You know something?
I could tell you...
But I have some conditions.
Conditions?
Sorry to drop this on you,
but can I snap a quick photo?
H-Huh? Th-That’s...
Uh... I’m used to recording videos,
but having my photo taken...
That’s a good attitude!
Can’t just blindly trust
strangers, after all.
Okay. That’s that, then.
Wait!
G-Go ahead!
That’s a good expression!
Don’t worry!
I won’t put it up online.
That just leaves...
Leaves what?
I wanna see how strong you are.
I’m not that strong,
but don’t hold back!
I’m just gonna snap a few shots
while we’re at it!
Hah!
A Leafia?
Not a great type match-up for us...
But still, let’s do this!
Leafia, use Leaf Cutter!
Dodge it, Welcamo!
Kick Down!
Leafia, use Leaf Blade!
Rushing in headfirst is too risky.
Leafia, go for a Swords Dance!
Welcamo?
Leafia, use Leaf Blade!
Welcamo, use Pound!
Welcamo, are you okay?!
Leaf Blade!
Are you onto something?
That wasn’t Pound...
It was Air Cutter!
Okay, Welcamo! Air Cutter!
Leafia! Leaf Cutter!
Don’t expect us to give up, either!
Lightning Speed!
Good work, Welcamo! Kick Down!
Not too shabby, schoolkid!
Well, a deal’s a deal...
That’s—?!
But still, we can’t just
stick around here forever.
But still, you’d rather my ship take off
with nowhere to go?
What to do...?
Guys!
This girl says she’s seen Basagiri!
Huh?
Good expressions, y’all!
Who’s this?
The name’s Sazare.
A traveler with a bit of a thing for
photography.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Affection Pokémon, Milokallos.
Milokallos
Affection Pokémon
Type: Water
Milokallos
Affection Pokémon
Type: Water
A Pokémon with scales
that can turn a variety of colors.
Height
6.2m
Something about it is said to be
the best in the world,
Weight
162.0kg
but do you know what that thing is?
What about it is the best in the world?
Its beauty
Its fearsomeness
Its length
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What about it is the best in the world?
A: Its beauty
The answer is A: Its beauty!
It’s said that looking upon Milokallos
can even heal warped hearts.
It has the power to quell
anger and hatred.
Next episode
So I hear Basagiri’s on this mountain!
More mountain hiking?!
You’re kidding...
Hey...
Does this place feel... off, somehow?
Apparently it’s dangerous
and packed with crazy Pokémon!
Pokémon?!
Sounds like we’re in for some battling!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Ready, and...
Track It Down! Find Basagiri!!
We’re sure to find it, right?