Liko. Here are the results of
your Terastal Course implementation test.
You failed.
Thank you very much...
If we head down here,
it should lead to the base of Mt. Nappé.
Oh... Already time to
say goodbye to the snow...
I wanna have another snowball fight!
The Terastal Course ended
in the blink of an eye...
Oh no... Nyarote!
Roy and Dot passed
their implementation tests,
but I failed mine...
I can’t use Terastal anymore...
Found them.
Your intel was good, Agate-san.
They’re bound to return to
Orange Academy.
You’d do well to intercept them
before they descend.
Indeed. All is prepared.
Additionally... Amethio seems to have spotted you.
He’s headed our way.
So, he did follow me.
I suppose he’s quite curious
what I was up to at Exceed.
Perfect.
Let’s use this opportunity
to our advantage.
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Mt. Nappé and the Creeping Shadows
Paldea’s Highest Peak?
Mt. Nappé’s summit.
Apparently, the highest point in Paldea.
It’s even listed as one of
the Ten Sights of Paldea.
Liko, you’ve been there?!
No, but those spots
are famous around here.
I bet it’s got an incredible view!
Let’s check it out before we head back!
Huh?!
That’d be such a pain.
It’ll be even colder there, y’know.
We’re already so close by!
Plus, it’ll be a nice memory.
Right, Liko?!
Ah... Y-Yeah.
No, no! Sometimes you’re just
not in the right mood for stuff. Right, Liko?
Uh... Y-Yeah.
You know, this could lift the mood!
But you’ve also gotta
take it easy now and then!
What should I do?
I think it’s my fault they’re going so far
out of their way to cheer me up...
Okay.
Let’s do it!
To Paldea’s Highest Peak we go!
That’s what I’m talkin’ about!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Can’t... keep... going...
This place sure is amazing...
Still a long way off!
There’s a cabin over there!
That’ll be a good place for a rest!
I need some water, and fast...
I made Roy and Dot worry about me
with all my moping...
I’ve got to thank them properly later.
Well done, Charem.
Stop.
Spinel... Just what are you planning?
Armorgaw, take us down slowly.
What could he be doing out here?
Hey! Liko!
Where is she?
Did we go too far on ahead?
We were focused on
getting up the mountain.
The path is a straight shot,
so she can’t have gotten lost...
She might be resting along the way.
Let’s try a bit farther down.
Where did you go?
You won’t escape!
We don’t seem to be catching up...
And it doesn’t feel like
we’re getting any higher.
Did I... go the wrong way?!
A-Amethio!
Why are you here?
There’s something off about this...
I didn’t think you’d follow me this far.
Is that Terapagos?
Terapagos, don’t!
Seems it despises me.
But...
Since we’ve crossed paths...
I must seize this opportunity.
Soublades!
Wait!
I told you...
Next time,
I would have that Pokémon.
I won’t just hand it over to you!
Nyarote...
Terapagos...
It’ll be okay.
Just stay in the bag.
Let’s go, Nyarote!
Terapagos...
I’ll protect you!
I haven’t faced Soublades
since that time on Roy’s island...
I didn’t stand a chance back then,
but now, with Nyarote...
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Nyarote!
Dodge it using Lightning Speed!
Good!
Meet it with Shadow Claw!
Acrobatics!
Behind you, Soublades!
Now! Magical Leaf!
We can do this...
We can do it, Nyarote!
So you’ve evolved,
and you can actually put up a fight now...
In that case... Sword of Regrets!
Nyarote, dodge it!
Incessantly wriggling around...
Sword of Regrets!
Magical Leaf!
Blow it away, Soublades!
Looking good, Nyarote!
She’s dodging my Fire moves
and attacking from outside my range...
So she can actually strategize now, too.
Nyarote! One more Magical Leaf!
However...
Follow your own path!
Soublades!
Terastal...
Ghost Dive!
Nyarote, behind you!
Nyarote!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
You’ve been running away
for far too long.
One more time, Soublades!
Nyarote, watch out!
It’s no use! You can’t block
Terastallized Soublades’s Ghost Dive!
Floundering already?
Soublades! Ghost Dive!
This battle is over.
Sword of Regrets!
Blacky?!
You’re...!
What are you doing, Spinel?
Oh? What brings you here?
I haven’t gotten word
of any new operations or the like.
You’re a terrible liar.
So you wanted us to
wear each other down with a battle?
I’m sure I have no idea
what you mean.
As for my goal, well...
You’re after Terapagos, too?!
Allow me to show you...
...the Eternal Blessing.
Blacky, rampage to your heart’s content.
Soublades! Shadow Claw!
Soublades!
It took out my Terastallized Soublades
like it was nothing!
What’s happening?
This isn’t normal...
So...
What will you do?
Terapagos...
Ooh...
How intriguing.
Fine work. Take a rest, Blacky.
I have achieved my goal.
I appreciate your cooperation, Liko-san.
Wait! What was that?!
Answer me, Spinel!
What did you just do?!
Ready to go, Soublades?
Nyarote, are you okay?
Let’s go!
Where is he hiding?
It’s like a maze in here!
Don’t follow me! Leave!
I want to know what that was earlier!
If you know something about Terapagos...
Yeah!
Was that him?!
He’s gone...
Impossible...
Was this all part of his—?
The way out!
Seems like everything is
proceeding as planned.
Yes. The experiment went well, too.
You lost it?!
Terapagos’s power caused it to vanish.
Seems as if it doesn’t resonate
with Rakurium.
By my guess, I’d say Terapagos and Rakurium
are opposed to one another.
Interesting.
That info alone...
...is quite a discovery!
Incidentally...
What’s the status on the other end?
Sango and Onyx
are attending to it now.
So help won’t be coming any time soon.
Then Amethio-kun is done for, too.
He must have been
quite the eyesore to you.
Gibeon-sama held him in special regard.
He was bound to
get in our way eventually.
Blood ties can lead
to hardship now and then.
For the future of the Explorers...
We shall allow his grandson...
to disappear.
You can’t find Liko?
We were together
most of the way up...
But we looked back where we came from
and didn’t see her.
We couldn’t reach her Smartphone Rotom either.
Bad reception I guess.
Understood.
I’ll go straight there on Lizardon.
Thank you!
Cap. We’re leaving.
Mt. Nappé, huh?
Didn’t the Gym there have...?
I’m worried...
Roy! We should look for her
until Friede gets here!
Yeah!
Me and Hogator will search
from the skies with Taikaiden.
Good. Meanwhile,
we’ll search from the ground.
Let’s go, Welcamo!
We’re not strong enough.
Rest for a while, Soublades.
Looks like we’re
not getting out that easily.
I can’t get through at all...
We could be in big trouble
if we don’t get out of here...
Thank goodness!
You’re awake!
Easy!
Right now,
catching you is hardly my...
C-Calm down, Terapagos!
Sandwich and...
Onigiri?!
Hmph... What a total drag!
Why do I gotta
help that dork out, anyhow?
For now, just simmer down
and lend your aid.
It never hurts to make your comrades
owe you a favor.
Well, guess it’s a nice little distraction.
We’ve got an emergency,
so get outta the way!
We’ve played student long enough!
Onigohri, come on out!
Let’s go, Kyojiohn!
The Explorers are here to play!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Land Whale Pokémon, Hulkujira.
While normally slow-moving,
Hulkujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Hulkujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Height
4.5m
it can move extremely fast
when using a certain body part.
Weight
700.0kg
But do you know which body part that is?
What part of its body lets it move faster?
Its stomach
Its back
Its tail fin
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What part of its body lets it move faster?
A: Its stomach
The answer is A: Its stomach.
By spreading ice around on its stomach,
it can slide on the ice like a sled
and spin at high speeds.
Next episode
Oh, no!
We got trapped inside a cave!
I wonder what Roy and Dot
are up to right now...
If I don’t find them soon,
they’re bound to be worried!
Terapagos?
Yeah... You’re right!
Fretting won’t help at all.
I need to calm down and think...
Right now,
all that I have to rely on is...
Ah, but he’s...
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Liko and Amethio