To uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we, the Rising Voltteccers,
have arrived in the Paldea Region.
We stopped by a beautiful beach,
where I experienced lots of surprises
and fun encounters.
And now, I’m out shopping
with everyone at a seaside town.
One, two...
Hup...
It’s a bit heavy.
Think you can handle it, Metagross?
That’s all the shopping done.
Yup.
What a relief.
This is a nice town.
The food’s cheap. Fresh, too.
Well, you’re in a good mood!
All thanks to the bargains I found.
What is it, Nyahoja?
What’s this line for?
Liko!
Roy! Friede!
Hey, what’s the line for?
Some legendary, famous sweets:
Digda Manjuu!
Digda sweets?
You can find those
at any old tourist spot.
I wouldn’t expect a line for them.
These are no ordinary Digda Manjuu.
These are Sea Digda Manjuu!
You can only get ‘em here,
and they only make thirty boxes a day!
They’re special Digda Manjuu!
But what’s so special about them?
Um...
You don’t even know
and you still lined up?
I dunno,
but they’ve gotta be super tasty!
Seems like they’re not
opening anytime soon.
I can wait!
The anticipation
will only enhance their flavor.
As long as you’ve done
all your shopping, knock yourselves out.
You have done it, right?
Uh, well...
Once we’re done here...
Hmm?
Actually, I’ll go do it right now!
Me, too!
Let’s split up and get it done quick!
I’ll go this way.
Roy, you handle the other end!
Got it!
Liko, stick with Roy
to make sure he doesn’t waste money.
Sure...
I’ll be fine! Right, Hogator?
Uh... Hogator?
Ooh, those look tasty!
I’m not sure I like
where this is going...
Are you certain there’s something
that important in this town?
That’d be news to me.
Sango has very reliable sources.
I don’t mind you going in solo,
just don’t make yourself stand out.
Yeah, I know!
See? Now nobody can tell
I’m from the Explorers.
You still stand out.
Really?
Sango’s just too totally cute to hide!
How ‘bout now?
I didn’t mean...
Then you shoulda said so!
Return, Onigohri.
Well then, here we go!
I’m not sure I like
where this is going...
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
A Letter of Challenge From the Explorers
We’ve got soap, toothbrushes...
Is that everything?
Did something happen to him?
He’s got a scowl on his face...
Um...
Sorry to bother you!
What should I do?
Mister, did you hurt your back?
Thought so!
My gramps back home and old man Landau
both get like this when they hurt their backs.
Oh, of course! Um...
M-My bags...
Please...
Got it!
Ah... That feels good...
It’s helping ease the pain.
Nyahoja’s aromatic massages
are amazing.
Thank you, Nyahoja.
And thank you for noticing
something was wrong, Mibrim.
I thought you were running late...
Did you throw out your back again?
I told you I should’ve gone instead.
Who knows what’d go wrong
if I didn’t do the shopping?
Good grief...
I’m sorry about our manager.
But thank you!
Now we can open the shop.
Great news, huh?
Yeah.
It’s not much,
but take a box of our sweets as thanks.
S-Sea Digda Manjuu!
You’re from that shop?
Ooh, you’ve heard of us?
You bet!
Our exclusive white Digda Manjuu!
A favorite of people and Pokémon alike!
Coated with white chocolate imported
all the way from the Kalos Region!
They’re white like Umidigda...
So that’s why they’re Sea Digda Manjuu!
umi
And that’s not all!
Our sea salt, made from seawater
with our time-tested process,
draws out the sweetness
of the chocolate and red bean paste!
Are you sure we can have this?
I thought they were limited supply...
Don’t worry, that one’s a spare
just for emergencies.
Thank you!
You helped us out big time.
Thank you both!
What are the odds of that?
It sure was a surprise.
Just hang on a bit longer.
Good, good...
You sure were hungry, huh?
Such a good pup!
Kanuchan? Where’re you going?
Thank you for waiting!
Welcome.
This is it, this is it!
This is so totally what I’ve been waiting for!
Only one per person!
Limited to thirty boxes total!
When they’re gone, they’re gone!
Limited to thirty...
And Sango’s the 30th person in line!
No way I can miss out now!
Here you are. Thank you.
Glad I made it!
All right!
Always nice to see you
running errands.
I’m very sorry.
That was the last one,
our stock for today—
Huh?! What’s the deal?!
Why didn’t anybody tell me?!
Hey! Places like this
always keep an extra in the back, right?
Gimme! Gimme!
W-We’re all out!
Sea... Digda-gda... Manjuu...
We got them without even lining up.
Be kind to others
and they’ll be kind to you!
Those two...
They got some...
...without even lining up?!
Rargh! I’m totally gonna make ‘em pay!
Don’t be shy.
Kindness is never wasted.
Kanuchan?
What is it?
You brought food for Kuwassu, too?
Thanks, Kanuchan.
Huh? Where’s Hogator?
Hogator.
Huh? What’s that?
A letter?
Um...
“You stole something very important”?
Stole?
I can barely read it.
“Meet me at Kabigon Rock,” it says.
Kabigon Rock...
Does it mean that rock?
My gramps told me about these.
It’s gotta be a letter of challenge!
A letter of challenge?
A battle request!
They used to send them as letters!
Let’s check it out, Hogator!
Maybe you shouldn’t...
We’ll be fine!
Wait!
You’re late!
Totally kept me waiting, y’know?
Was this from you?
‘Course it was.
C’mon.
U-Uh...
You brought ‘em, right?
The totally rare limited Sea Digda Manjuu!
You mean these?
Yes, exactly!
I was really raging
after you stole them,
but I’ll forgive you
if you give ‘em back.
“Stole them”?
They were given to us.
Well how do you think I feel?!
Do you know how long I waited?!
That’s not our fault...
Um, if you want them that much...
You can have one.
Go ahead.
Why’d you open it?!
Huh?
W-Well, you have to open it to eat them...
That’s a limited item. Now I’m not just
totally annoyed, I’m totally mad!
Huh?
Onigohri!
That Pokémon...
Wait a sec, are you—?!
Took you long enough!
A total cinch!
The Explorers!
It’s Sango-chan!
You think I’m gonna let you get away with
ruining those Digda Manjuu?!
You’re not making any sense!
I’ll call Friede.
There’s no time. I’ll battle her.
She’s using an Ice type,
so Hogator’s got the advantage.
Onigohri, let’s have some fun.
Wh-What should I do?
What now?!
That Pokémon...!
Kyojiohn. Rock Salt Pokémon.
Rock type.
Many Pokémon gather around Kyojiohn,
hoping to lick at its mineral-rich salt.
I wondered what was taking so long.
Hmph. Mr. No-Fun is here.
Two of the Explorers!
I see. The kids from
the Rising Voltteccers.
A chance we cannot miss.
Sango’ll handle that guy.
Then, miss, would you be my opponent?
Opponent?!
I never could’ve imagined that Digda Manjuu
would lead to a battle with the Explorers...
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Let us fight with honor.
Grudges over food
can get real ugly, y’know.
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
Lightning Speed!
So feeble.
Is that all you can do?
Hogator, use Flamethrower!
Gonna have to
do better than that!
Onigohri, use Blizzard!
Hogator!
Do not get distracted!
Salt Pickling!
Dodge it!
Go for a big Magical Leaf!
Such flimsy attacks
cannot harm my Kyojiohn.
Now, it’s my turn.
Kyojiohn, use Salt Pickling.
Nyahoja!
Onigohri...
Crunch it to pieces!
Hogator!
Hogator?
Amazing!
It thawed itself out?! Seriously?!
That totally cracks me up!
Flamethrower!
Too slow, too slow!
Ice Spinner!
Hogator!
What do I do now?
You’re trapped.
This attack will not miss.
Kyojiohn, use Salt Pickling!
Lightning Speed!
We got behind it!
Nyahoja, use Magical Leaf!
All right!
That made for a good smokescreen.
Run for it, Nyahoja!
You won’t get away.
Salt Pickling!
Nyahoja!
Finish her off.
You’re not ready to give up?
Got it!
Futile.
Kyojiohn, use Stone Edge!
Nyahoja!
Magical Leaf!
Bolstered by the ability
Budding Greenery, huh?
That’s it!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
Huh?
Onigohri!
Liko!
Roy!
So, you managed to
land a hit on Kyojiohn...
Guess you actually
know a trick or two.
However...
Now...
Playtime is over.
‘Bout time for us to get serious.
The way things are headed...
We need a plan.
Return, Kyojiohn.
That’s enough.
We’re pulling out, Sango.
Huh? You could totes just ignore it!
We were just getting to the good part!
It’s about our top-priority mission.
There’s nothing on that island!
I hate it there!
It is our top priority.
We can just summon Rekkuuza later!
What did she say?
Summon Rekkuuza...
Sango!
That black Rekkuuza’s gonna be ours!
But first, Onigohri’s gonna
beat the stuffing outta you!
Grab her.
Huh?!
Hey! What’re you doing?! Stop it!
Lemme go!
Don’t lemme go like that!
Agh! Fine! I’ll totally
crush you two later!
Yeah. Everything’s okay now.
They said they were going to
summon Rekkuuza.
Yeah.
I’ve got to tell Friede.
Liko! Roy!
You okay?
Yeah.
Which way did the Explorers go?
They flew that way,
out over the sea.
Did they leave any other clues?
They mentioned an island...
An island with nothing on it.
I see...
Oh yeah, Roy...
You still have those
Irukaman photos, right?
These?
Swim Trunks Guy called the people
who built that tower a “suspicious bunch.”
This can’t be a coincidence.
You two head back to the ship.
I’ll go check out that island.
Hold on!
Cap! Lizardon!
The Explorers are targeting Rekkuuza...
What could they be up to?
I can’t shake this uneasy feeling
in my chest...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Face Pokémon, Onigohri.
Onigohri
Face Pokémon
Type: Ice
Onigohri
Face Pokémon
Type: Ice
Onigohri can instantaneously
freeze moisture in the air.
Height
1.5m
Weight
256.5kg
It uses a certain thing to protect itself,
but do you know what that thing is?
What does Onigohri protect itself with?
A sword
A shield
Armor
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that end in "-s"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Orio here! You can leave machines and rap to me!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What does Onigohri protect itself with?
C: Armor
The answer is C: Armor.
Onigohri’s body is
the black part made of rock.
And the white part is its armor,
made of ice.
Did you know that, guys?
Cap... Cut it out.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
The Explorers are plotting
something sinister?!
Liko and friends found ‘em,
but... something’s off?
Wait, Friede got caught in their trap?!
I’m begging you! Liko! Roy!
You’ve gotta thwart their plans!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters:
The Plan to Capture Rekkuuza
The girl behind the costume
is gonna fight, too!