A Metamon joined us aboard the ship!
It’s a strange little critter
who can transform.
Masquernya seems happy
to have found a new friend!
I hope all the rest of us
can get along with it, too!
Yo-ssu! Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
Today I’ve got a livestream for ya!
I’ll be responding to all y’all’s requests,
so bring on the comments!
Huh...?
Let’s take a min to get jammin’! Woo-hoo!
Huh? I can’t get it off...
Dekanuchan, just sit still for a sec!
All right!
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Bread, Bread, Bread! Mini Gurumin!!
This one’s rusty...
Maybe we should
swap it for a new one.
Nicely spotted, there.
Good stuff!
A new bolt, a new bolt...
Huh? That’s odd,
I was sure I put one in here...
Oh... Is that it?
Right you are. There it is.
Wait, it’s huge!
No need to fret. I’ll apply a little cream to it,
and you’ll be better in no time.
Let’s see...
There.
Mawhip whipped cream!
Oh.
Give it a good whisk...
Gettin’ pranked by Metamon!
That’s so lame!
Hoo... I laughed so hard,
my mouth’s all dry! Water, water...
Metamon!
You shouldn’t play too many pranks!
I wonder why Metamon’s playing pranks.
It’ll take some time
for us to understand its feelings.
Dot? What’s wrong?
Ugh... I accidentally
put a black mark on Gurumin’s legacy...
Dot!
That was the best!
Miniguru!
Miniguru...?
The Mini Gurumin
that was on your stream!
Everyone’s calling it Miniguru
and getting really excited!
“Miniguru’s cute”...
“I wanna see more Miniguru”...
Huh?
Don’t tell me...
Were you Miniguru, Metamon?
S... So ca-yute!
Ooh, it really is cute!
It looks like doughy bread!
How, exactly?
Bread!
Dot! Wouldn’t this be great for
that bread festival I told you about before?
Oh, the Bread Fest.
Bread Fest?
What’s that?
A bread festival
where all sorts of bakers get together.
Apparently a bakery named Bakery Tongri-La uploaded
a Gurumin bread to social media, and it went viral.
And you got a request for Gurumin
to come liven the Fest up.
A request, as in... a job?
There’s gonna be a huge crowd,
so I was planning to turn it down, but...
If you appear with Miniguru,
you’ll really liven things up and bring joy to Gurumin fans!
Dot should be in charge
of what jobs Gurumin takes!
Gurumin and Miniguru
appearing in a Bread Fest would be...
I’m not really...
Gurumin and Miniguru
at a Bread Fest... Bread!
Gurubread! Minbread! Ahh...!
You’re right.
If it’d bring joy to even a single fan,
maybe I should do it.
Bread? Huh? Huh?!
Yo-ssu!
Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
Metamon, c’mon!
Ya gotta turn into Miniguru, just like before!
I was hoping to rehearse it together,
but if you won’t turn into Miniguru,
maybe I should turn down the Bread Fest...
Wha—?!
Huh?
What are you doing down there?
I simply couldn’t dare to watch
Gurumin and Miniguru’s rehearsal up close...
But if Metamon doesn’t want
to transform into Miniguru,
then about that, there is nothing
to be done which we may do...
NyahojaSuperfan!
Thanks for always supporting me!
Gurumin!
I’ll be relying
on your continued support, y’hear!
Miniguru!
That’s one incredible move,
letting it transform like that...
Hmph! Ain’t nothin’ special!
I’ll show ya an awesome one we know!
Can you move like this?!
Deadly... Shadow Cross!
Nyoom, nyoom, nyoom, nyoom...!
Ahh! It turned back!
Let’s eat some tasty Gurumin bread,
and all Gurumin together, y’hear?!
We’re gonna perform
a Miniguru Dance for all my fans!
Let’s get practicing!
A Miniguru Dance?! I wanna watch!
But I don’t wanna spoil
my anticipation for the real show...
Miniguru, Miniguru, Minigur—!
Ooh! Great stuff, great stuff!
Now you’ve started jammin’-min’!
Gotta see it!
Spinny-spinny! Mini-mini!
Mini-mini! Spinny-spinny!
Huh? Huh?
What? What?!
I can’t see!
Good work today, everyone!
Feels like this Mini Gurumin stuff
is starting to take shape.
Nyoom-nyoom-nyoom-nyoom...
But if it laughs, the transformation wears off
and it turns back to Metamon, eh?
Ult! Don’t you even think about
doing that during the real show!
In the end, I didn’t get to
see the Miniguru Dance...
Huh? What?
Masquernya, what’s wrong?
Before the event begins...
...I’ve gotta go say hi to Bakery Tongri-La’s manager,
who put in the request for me to attend!
Gurumin’s surprisingly
on top of things... I love it!
Huh?
Grabbing hold of your heart!
There’s no bread I can’t grip!
Hey! Manager Tong
of Bakery Tongri-La here!
Are you all tong-ing?
Uhh...
So this is the requester...
I’m so happy that you came,
Ms. Gurumin, tong!
Ooh! Those’re some real
bread-lookin’ Pokémon, ain’t they?
This is Puppymocchi!
The same as my father’s partner!
Uhh, and this little one...
That’s Bowtzel with
its Well-Baked Body, y’hear?
Always on point!
When I announced on social media that Ms. Gurumin
and Miniguru were coming, the replies went wild!
Huh? And where is Miniguru today?
Oh... Uh... It’ll be here later!
Well then, the Gurumin baking event
will be at three o’clock,
so go and enjoy
the Bread Fest ‘til then, tong!
That manager was quite the character...
Is this event really going to go okay...?
That smells good!
Let’s get something to eat
while we’re here!
They’ve got Pupurin bread!
It says this is
Mitsuhoney Honeymitsu bread!
And these are Mimiroll ear-rolls!
Cherrimbo!
Ooh! Denjimushi!
They’ve even got Fuwante!
Harimarron sandwiches!
They all look so good!
Look!
It’s Pikachu!
Wow! They’re like real Pikachu cheeks!
Ooh! A Pikachu!
He’s doing a cheek pose!
How cute!
It says these are
Sadaija chocolate cornets.
What a line! They’re popular.
We should line up, too.
I’m sorry, I just sold the last one.
Huh?
Aww... What a shame.
Then let’s get something else...
I wanted... Sadaija...
I’m sorry.
After you came all this way...
They’re sold out. There’s nothing they can do.
Let’s get something else.
I wanted this!
What a pickle...
Huh? Is that...?
So I did have one more!
Okay, here you go!
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
Isn’t that great?
Yeah!
Ooh! The Denjimushi bread is steamed bread!
mushi
Whoa! The Pupurin bread’s
got jiggly pudding inside!
This Biriridama pizza’s so spicy,
it’s zapping my tongue!
I can’t wait to meet Miniguru!
Right? I even made some cheering gear!
Ooh!
Dot?
Maybe we should
head over early and prepare.
Got it!
Let’s go, Wanival, Metamon.
Huh? Metamon?
Huh?
Metamon’s not here?!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
Metamon!
Where could it have gotten...?
Dot, you go on ahead!
But...
Don’t worry!
We’ll bring Metamon over by three o’clock!
Okay, got it!
Time to dig in!
Metamon!
Trash can, trash can...
Ah, here!
Metamon!
Huh? What’s going on?
There’s so many Metamon!
Metamon bread?!
Gah... That’s going to make
looking for Metamon even harder!
Seen it?
No. How could it get lost
right when we need it...?
Is it really lost?
Huh?
Metamon only recently
came aboard the Brave Asagi...
Maybe it found someplace better,
and went off somewhere...
Eek!
What happened?!
Oh, it’s... The pizza oven wasn’t working properly,
and I didn’t know what to do...
Huh? There’s another oven
right out here...
What a relief!
Now I can cook more Biriridama pizzas!
It was a Metamon!
It gave me such a scare!
Metamon? Where is it?
I couldn’t say.
It all happened so suddenly...
I wonder... Why would Metamon
want to transform into that...?
Gotta be for a prank.
Never mind that. If it’s transformed
into something, we’ll never find it!
If we want to find
a transformed Metamon...
That’s the only way!
Yamirami! Shadow Cross!
Nyoom-nyoom-nyoom-nyoom...
Loudbone! Nose Lantern!
Masquernya! Eye Flowers!
Nyoom-nyoom-nyoom-nyoom...
Whoa! What the...?!
That’s it! Over there!
We’ve been looking for you!
There’s no time!
Bakery Tongri-La presents...!
To commemorate the baking of Gurumin bread...!
A Gurumin and Miniguru With Friends Showtime!
Starting now, tong!
Yo-ssu! Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you bread superfans out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
Eek! It’s Gurumin!
Gurumin!
Huh? Where’s Miniguru?
Minmin!
Yay! Minmin!
Ack! They’ve already started!
Is Miniguru not coming...?
Even though I brought Miniguru
cheering gear and everything...
Where’s Miniguru?
Isn’t it here yet?
Th-The Gurumin bread
will be done any moment now!
Where’s Miniguru?
Whoa!
Y’all take a min to start jammin’
with a countdown! Here we go!
The Gurumin bread will be baked
and ready in five seconds!
Four!
Two!
One!
Ta-dough!
The Gurumin bread’s finished!
Ack!
Whoa! Miniguru!
Miniguru!
Huh? Miniguru?
So cute!
Ta-dough!
Time to perform the Miniguru Dance!
Miniguru! Guru-Gurumin!
Eek! So cute!
Miniguru! Miniguru! Guru-Gurumin!
So this is the Miniguru Dance!
I’ve got it!
Got what?
Metamon wasn’t transforming
in order to play pranks...
I think it just wanted to bring joy to people
who were sad or troubled!
Yeah! You’re right!
Manager Tong gave me some souvenirs!
They look good!
There’s even Miniguru bread in there!
Ooh, they’re well made!
Time to dig in!
Mmm, delish!
The event was a huge success!
Great work out there, Dot!
I owe it all to Metamon!
Thank you, Metamon!
And I’m so glad
all of you were there, too!
Surfugo!
Dekanuchan!
Wanival!
Thank you, everyone!
Aren’t you going to eat yours, Liko?
I mean...
Look at how cute it is!
It’d be such a waste!
I can’t possibly eat it!
I can eat it for ya, then!
No!
Huh? Wha...?! Masquernya!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Bowtzel!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Bowtzel
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Dog Pokémon
Fairy
Well-Baked Body
The pleasant aroma that emanates
from its body has a certain effect.
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
But do you know what that effect is?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
It makes skin smooth
It makes wheat grow
It makes more money
B: It makes wheat grow!
It makes wheat grow
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Farming villages have treasured
this Pokémon since the days of yore!
What a nice smell, just like bread...
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Whoa!
Next episode
So this is a Unite Battle...
Yeah, they’re heated battles where
Pokémon and trainers fight as one!
That means teamwork’s important.
Next episode
Isn’t the other team too strong?!
I’ll turn the tables on ya!
Everyone, let’s do our best!
Yeah!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Next episode
Ready, and...
READY GO! Unite Battle!!
Huh? Isn’t that Pokémon...?