The Kitakami hamlet?
Yeah.
It’s a mountain hamlet that Orange Academy
uses for school trips into the forest.
But at the moment, there’s a teacher named Briar
over there who’s studying all things Terapagos.
Maybe you can
learn something from her.
Try paying her a visit.
Thank you so much!
No thanks needed.
This little fella intrigues me, too.
Hey, look!
An airship?!
Looks like they’re here to pick you up.
The Brave Asagi!
Completely restored!
They all seem happy!
It’s been forever, huh?
Yeah.
Great work, all of you.
Friede!
Liko, Roy, Dot...
Congrats on passing your Terastal course!
Thanks!
Cap! We’re back!
We’re back!
Welcome back!
Nice to see you again.
Mm-hmm.
All right!
All together, shall we?
The evolved Brave Asagi...
...sets off now!
Yeah!
Our adventures together,
as the Rising Voltteccers...
...can now start again!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
To a New Sky! The Brave Asagi!!
Wake up, everyone.
Morning’s here.
Good morning.
We sure slept well, huh?
The breeze feels great!
A! Ga! A! Ga! Ga!
A! Ga! A! Ga!
A! Ga! Ga!
A! Ga—
Whoa! Did you see that?!
Over there!
What’s going on?
It might still be there!
Aw... Now it’s hiding...
If it appears again—
Is it over there?!
Good morning.
Oh, Liko! Morning.
Morning.
Something happening?
Yeah, it’s awesome!
Look!
Here it comes!
A Kairyu!
We got to see
a super cool Pokémon!
And I forgot to record it again!
Getting to soar through the sky
really is lovely...
Yeah! I’m really glad
the ship’s all fixed.
But... Friede said
it had evolved, right?
What changed?
You’re right...
It doesn’t look all that different.
Why don’t we go
peek around the ship?
Looking around to see
what’s changed? Good idea!
Agreed!
The Brave Asagi Indoors Tour...
starts now!
Yeah!
Nothing much here...
You sure about that?
Ooh, what’s that?
What’s this button do?
Ahh! Don’t push that!
That’s the ace up our sleeve.
Ace up our sleeve?
That button is a little secret
that’ll be handy in an emergency.
Understand? Don’t press it, ever!
I-I really wanna know...
I just gotta press it...!
Look forward to it!
Generally speaking, you don’t
“look forward” to emergencies...
All right! Next!
Yeah!
See? Look at this!
I put in new bearings,
greatly increasing its rotation rate!
It’s more comfortable
for Toroggon, too!
Amazing!
Whoa! It’s blazing hot!
We’re flying faster and higher now,
just how I like it!
Too hot...
And look over here, too!
I’ve tuned up the engine area
a whole bunch, too!
Th-Thank you, Orio...
First, the shaft was
a custom-ordered—
What’s changed?
Well, now that you ask...
I’ve got a new set
of examination tools,
and some extra shelves
packed with everyday medicines...
But if you’re feeling bad,
just tell me.
My job here is to look after everyone’s health,
Pokémon and people alike.
Right!
We’re glad to be
in your care again!
Huh?!
Welcome to the new kitchen!
It’s turned all classy now...
Awesome!
It’s like a restaurant!
Nice, huh?
It’s a good place to fix up
a quick snack and have a quick bite.
And oh, good timing! Ms. Kaede taught me
some superb sweet recipes. You interested?
Achigator?!
Wh-What?!
Hey, cut that out! He’s a friend!
Sushi.
They’re Pokémon?
Sharitatsu. Mimicry Pokémon.
Dragon/Water type.
Its colors and patterns have changed
to suit the tastes of the prey it lures in.
It is small and weak,
but it uses its wits to survive.
Three Sharitatsu...
Are they your Pokémon, Murdock?
Nope. It’s a lot more complicated
with these guys.
It’s a pretty long story,
but it all goes back
to the time when—
Wait!
Phew! Tour of the indoors complete!
That was fun!
We sure found a whole lot of changes.
Ah, there you are.
Friede!
I figured I oughta
return this to you, Liko.
Lucius’s belt!
Thanks for looking after it.
The search for the Six Heroes
can start again, too.
I’m gonna use Terastal
and battle the black Rekkuuza!
I can help a bit, too!
Huh?
What’s going on?
Are they...
...trying to say “Battle us”?
I get it.
They want to
put your skills to the test.
Huh?!
Huh?! We can’t!
Not against Lucius’s Pokémon!
No way, no how!
We don’t stand a chance!
That’s a great idea!
They’re offering to throw down,
so hit ‘em with all you got!
Nyarote’s raring for a battle.
So’s Achigator!
Welcamo...
You’re up for it, right?
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
I can’t wait to
see how these battles go!
Go for broke, everyone!
Let’s go, Nyarote!
Lightning Speed!
Magical Leaf!
The same exact move?!
A Grass type showdown...
This’ll be a real tough battle.
One more time! Magical Leaf!
Achigator, don’t worry!
You and me can hold our own
against it now!
It went straight for Blazing Rage?
Achigator! Hang in there
with Stomping Tantrum!
Oho... He worked up his own rage to
prevent his strength being sapped.
Hit it head-on with Flamethrower!
It’s a clash of rage against rage,
power against power!
Welcamo! Be graceful! Be clever!
Use your steps to dodge it!
Dot...
Nyarote! Use Acrobatics!
Good going!
It’s super effective. Solid pick!
Grass Field...
You’re telling me to hit harder.
Flex that fighting spirit, Achigator!
Now! Use Charm Voice!
That’s super effective, too!
Good thinking, Roy!
Yeah! Let’s keep it up, Achigator!
Is Dot gonna be all right?
She’s having trouble
finding an opening.
No, she’s just getting started!
We’re good to go!
Welcamo! Run toward Laplace!
Go! Kick Down!
Direct hit!
Ooh!
That battle style is just so her!
All of them are amazing!
They’re giving the Six Heroes
a darn good fight!
Mm-hmm! Impressive progress,
truly great strides.
Nyarote, shine in full bloom!
Achigator! Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Welcamo! Glitz it up,
go viral, and shine!
Ooh!
Magical Leaf!
Nitro Charge!
Aqua Break!
That’s the Six Heroes for you...
They’re strong...
But... We’re still
standing our ground!
Thank you very much!
Nyarote,
you were amazing!
You were so cool,
Achigator!
Welcamo,
you were perfect out there!
Liko, Roy, Dot...
You’ve changed so much!
You’ve become
much tougher trainers.
Your partners aren’t
the only ones who evolved.
You have as well.
See? You’ve got Cap’s approval, too.
We’re evolving, too...
Bit by bit.
If they’re giving you
some battle practice,
maybe Oliva and the others
are trying to guide you...
Towards the other Six Heroes.
Towards Rakua!
Huh?
Next we’re gonna go to
the Kitakami hamlet to research Terapagos,
and we’re gonna find the rest of the Six Heroes:
Basagiri, Entei, and the black Rekkuuza!
And if we do all that,
I just know that Rakua...
...will be in reach!
Yeah!
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
It’s my first livestream in a while!
And today, like I told ya last time,
I’ve a huge announcement to make!
Wh-Wh... Wh-Wh-Whoa!
Gurumin’s partner, Kuwassu...
...has evolved into Welcamo!
His steps are more graceful than before,
his dancing more nimble than ever!
When your partner evolves,
you can just feel how much they’ve grown!
Huh?
“But Gurumin,
you haven’t changed a bit”?
Non, non, non!
Even if I look the same as ever...
I’m gonna be making
even more astounding vids now,
so look forward to ‘em, okay?!
So he evolved...
And I didn’t even know...
Got your head in the clouds again.
My head’s not in the clouds!
I was studying
how to become even stronger!
What are you watching, anyway?!
Th-This is, uh, y’know...
Recon on the enemy!
Master Amethio!
Um...
Don’t make me repeat myself.
I’ve been dismissed
from all missions.
But...!
That’s enough.
You should stay away from me.
Even without missions,
there must be something you can do!
Exactly! Don’t lose hope!
You have no shot at promotion
if you stay with me.
That’s besides the point!
We’re comrades, aren’t we?
We vowed to follow you,
Master Amethio!
Understood.
To figure out what I...
No, what we can do now...
Lend me... your strength.
Yes, sir!
I’m in your debt.
The Brave Asagi really has evolved!
We made it to
the Kitakami hamlet in one flight.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Transport Pokémon, Laplace.
Laplace
Transport Pokémon
Type: Water/Ice
Laplace
Transport Pokémon
Type: Water/Ice
They are very kind
and intelligent Pokémon.
Height
2.5m
They love doing a certain thing
to people and Pokémon.
Weight
220.0kg
But do you know what that thing is?
What do Laplace love doing?
Cuddling
Giving rides
Slapping
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What do Laplace love doing?
B: Giving rides
The answer is B: Giving rides!
They love swimming,
with people and Pokémon riding on their backs.
They’re an important part of life in the Alola Region,
which is surrounded by ocean.
Next episode
We finally made it
to the Kitakami hamlet!
Achi!
hot
It’s hot? You really think so...?
Roy, why not take off your coat?
Geta?
No, not your geta, your coat...
Wait, geta?!
A-chi, a-chigee!
wrong
I have it wrong?
H-Huh? I feel like
we’re talking past each other...
And so, next time
on Pocket Monsters:
I’m a Pokémon, and You’re Me?!
Achi!
I'm a Pokémon, and You're Me?!
What happened to you, Roy?!