The black Rekkuuza
was immensely powerful,
and the mystery surrounding
Lucius’s Pokémon grows ever deeper.
Despite that, we keep on
moving forward, one step at a time.
We’re slowly getting stronger...
Slowly getting closer to the answer.
Thanks to that,
life’s a total thrill right now!
This journey still has plenty
more adventures in store for us!
I was so worried.
Thank goodness Terapagos is fine.
Well, then... Now it’s my turn to fight.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Going Their Own Ways
Is that all your luggage?
Adventurers have to travel light.
That hurts to hear...
The Brave Asagi is impossible to keep tidy.
Just goes to show how many
responsibilities you have to keep up with.
Oh, that’s not...
Look after Terapagos for me.
We’re heading for Paldea.
Paldea?
There are ancient records
of Terapagos sightings there.
Besides...
It’s the land of Terastal.
The gleam Terapagos gives off,
and the gleam of Terastal...
There’s a hint to
solving the mystery in there.
At least, my gut says so.
I like where your head’s at.
I’ll leave all of that to you.
Drop me off at the next port.
Grandma’s getting off at
the next port, apparently.
Won’t you miss her?
Yeah, but that’s just
how she’s always been.
I see.
Then why don’t we
hold a goodbye party for her?
With curry and a show!
Make it real fun!
Great idea!
Time to get started!
We’ll ask the others for help, too!
The Pokémon, too!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
I’m a whole new Gurumin today!
Check this out! Isn’t it the coolest?!
A certain shop was kind enough
to provide us with this Terastal Cap!
That said... Ta-daah!
Don’t you Pokémon wanna
sparkle all cool to power up, too?
Then you should use
the energy of the Terastal Orb...
...to unleash Terastal,
the miracle of Paldea!
You look so cool, Kuwassu!
Lookie here and you’ll see
what Terastype Kuwassu just became!
This is the Water Terastype!
Thus, Kuwassu’s Water-type moves are powered up!
There are some Pokémon whose Terastal
changes them to different types!
Your Pokémon’s type changing
will mess up your opponent’s plans!
A perfect chance
to turn the tables on ‘em!
...And that’s just one use for it!
Terastallize when it matters most!
Hmm... Maybe I should’ve gone a bit flashier.
You gave it everything you had.
Guess it just won’t hit right
unless we actually Terastallize.
What now?!
Yo-ssu, Madam Gurumin outta the suit!
Nanjamo?!
Thanks a ton for taking me up
on the whole Terastal Cap deal!
There was just no way I could do it.
No way? Why?
I mean, look at me!
How the heck was I supposed to
put that over my headgear?
That’s why you asked me?!
Couldn’t you just take them off?
Oh, she hits us with
a real bombshell of a question!
A Nanjamo without these li’l cuties
ain’t no Nanjamo, no how!
I’d just be any ol’ cute and trendy gal!
Wait, so, you are your accessories?
Got me some extra income,
though. Thanks for that.
Okey-dokey!
Say, when’s our next collab?
Now that you’re a trainer,
we gotta stream us battlin’ it up!
Uh...
Well, I’ll think about it.
Gotcha! I’ll wait with my head
held high as a Kirinriki’s!
So, how’s it been? Travelin’ and all,
now that you’re a trainer?
Nothing’s changed, really...
Hmm?
I knew about trainer stuff
before I actually became one.
But, uh...
But...?
Dot, you there?
We’d like to ask you something.
Hogator!
Uh... Um... Err...
Hey!
Aw, geez... Do something!
Sorry! Hogator, calm down!
It’s just been so excited
since we started party planning.
Party? Not sure I follow.
Readin’ you like a book!
Your IRL pals wantcha, yeah?
Nanjamo?!
For real?!
Uh, um... Thank you
very much for the other day!
Ooh, Madam NyahojaSuperfan!
Don’tcha worry about that!
Hate to ask ya for a favor back, but...
You look after Madam Gurumin
sans the suit for me, ‘kay?
All right!
Of course!
You got that backwards!
I’m looking after them!
Well? Still waiting for an answer.
You glad you became a trainer or not?
Eh?
Uh...
Hmm?
Okay, I gotcha! Right, y’all!
You enjoy your party, now... now... now...!
Sheesh...
What do you mean, “gotcha?!”
J-Just so we’re clear, I can’t stand
parties or other noisy stuff like that!
Master Gibeon is awake.
Amethio. So it was you
who reached the black Rekkuuza first.
But I let it slip away.
What did you feel upon engaging it?
Rekkuuza was not
taking the fight seriously.
It felt as if it was merely testing me.
Testing you... or toying with you?
It is a Pokémon beyond our comprehension.
Next time, I will seize Rekkuuza!
The path to my paradise, Rakua...
Terapagos and Rekkuuza are the keys.
It is imperative that you obtain them.
Master Amethio.
Thus concludes your audience.
Hamber, will you train me?
I have taught you all I can.
Don’t dodge the question!
I’m talking about what comes after that!
I need power.
I understand.
Yonoir.
It seems we needn’t hold back.
Let’s go, Soublades!
We are ready whenever you are.
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Yonoir. Shadow Ball!
He concealed himself in the smoke...
Crossroad Kill!
Behind you. Shadow Punch!
Breaking Armor...
Keep up the pressure!
Use Sword of Regrets!
What?!
Yonoir... Shadow Ball!
Use Ghost Dive!
Yonoir!
Yonoir is the Grasping Pokémon.
It has you in the palm of its hand.
Shadow Ball!
Dodge it!
It has no blind spots...
Do you concede defeat?
Not yet! Psycho Cutter!
Shoot it down! Shadow Ball!
Now, corner them with Shadow Punch!
End this with Shadow Punch!
Don’t let them! Grab hold!
Hang in there, Soublades!
This fighting style is most unlike you...
Shake it off!
Ghost Dive!
Well done, Soublades!
To think that you would
elect to fight in such a manner...
Are you mocking me?
Far from it. I am most impressed.
Your desire for strength is indeed genuine.
I decided to get stronger.
By whatever means necessary!
Then I myself...
...must respond in kind,
and hold nothing back.
You’re finally going all out, Hamber!
Wander the abyss, Yonoir!
Shadow Ball.
Cut it to shreds!
Sword of Regrets!
Shadow Punch!
Soublades!
I do believe that concludes our battle.
Return, Soublades.
So the Shadow Ball was just a decoy.
Are you satisfied?
Hamber... I want a rematch.
Tonight’ll be my last night
on board this ship.
What is it?
What’s all this?
Thank you, Grandma!
It’s a farewell party!
We made curry, too!
We all pitched in to prepare it!
Oh, my! All this for me?
You’ve done so much for us, after all.
It’ll be sad to part ways.
But for now, let’s party ‘til we drop!
Oh, my!
Diana! Diana!
Thank you all for that lovely song!
We’ve got a special dessert for you, too!
A special cake, just for this occasion!
What’s so “special” about it?
Just wait and see!
Mawhip! You’re up!
My, how lovely!
I suppose I ought to fetch my best tea leaves
so we can have some with the cake for dessert!
This really is splendid!
You should drink up before it gets cold!
Well, then...
Don’t mind if I do!
Meetings and partings
are two sides of the same coin.
Here’s to our journey ahead!
So this is your best tea...
It’s delicious!
I guess I’ll have some, too!
Yabacha?!
What are you doing?
Can’t even tell them apart?
What’s up, Iwanko?
Simply sublime...
Hey, Murdock, that’s...!
Potdeath...
M-Murdock?!
Drinking too much of
Potdeath’s tea is dangerous, but...
But...?
The amount he drank
should be fine. He’ll recover.
Windie, carry him to bed.
Thangs fer th’ dring...
And now, time for tonight’s main event!
Dot put together a video of
the memories we’ve made!
My!
Where’s that?
Sorry! I didn’t have any pics of the castle,
so I used something royalty-free!
Diana and the Rising Voltteccers
met one another in an old castle in Galar!
They made a desperate escape
from the pursuing Explorers!
It exploded?!
The super spicy curry
we shared with Grandma!
Curry is an explosion!
We visited a shady antique shop, too!
What wild antics!
Because it’s an antique shop.
So... antics.
Get it?
And then we trained and got stronger!
Thank you, Grandma!
The training doesn’t explode?
I mean, ideally it shouldn’t...
Neither should any of the other stuff.
Thank you for everything, Grandma!
Grandma?
You didn’t like it?
That was fantastic!
It’s a big hit! We did it, Dot!
We all made it together!
Though, Dot did most of the work...
So many precious memories!
Thank you, everyone!
Your growth is impressive.
No... I’m nowhere near strong enough.
I want to beat Rekkuuza!
That wish will propel you
to greater and greater heights.
Much like it has Master Gibeon.
Take this.
A Terastal Orb...
Are you sure?!
Whether you can draw out
the full power of Terastal...
...ultimately falls to you.
So you’re telling me to master it?
Very well.
By learning Terastal,
I will gain the power
needed to rival Rekkuuza!
Just you wait!
Hamber seems to have
taken quite a shine to Amethio.
Let’s leave them to it.
We have the data on Terapagos’s
resonance reaction up our sleeve.
Yes.
We will be the ones to seize
the black Rekkuuza.
Don’t worry about that.
I’ll handle the rest.
Where are the others?
They went to bed.
Guess they partied too hard.
I hardly recognize you...
You say that all the time, though.
Thank you, Grandma.
For entrusting me with the pendant.
Hmm?
It was just like you said.
The first step is the only scary part.
I moved forward one step at a time,
learned to speak my mind,
and kept discovering new horizons!
There was loads of stuff that scared me,
but I was okay,
because my friends were by my side.
It’s been non-stop excitement!
You really have found
some wonderful friends.
Yeah!
Oh, I know, Liko! Come with me.
Huh?
I’m the one who should be thanking you.
Watching you is what reignited
my yearning for adventure.
Take this with you.
I’m sure it’ll come in handy.
Is this... Your adventure log?
I’m setting off on new adventures.
So I’m leaving it with you.
Grandma...
All right. Then I’ve got
something for you, too.
It’s lovely!
A friend from school taught me
how to make them.
Since you gave me the pendant,
I figured I’d give you a charm of your own.
Thank you. I’ll treasure it.
Terapagos is in your hands now.
You can count on me.
See you later, Windie.
Look after Grandma for me.
Liko! Liko!
We’d best give it our all, too.
Liko...
No time to stand around and mope!
Off we go!
We will find the Six Heroes.
The black Rekkuuza!
Oliva! Galarian Fire! Laplace!
Basagiri and Entei, too!
The Pokémon who traveled with
the Ancient Adventurer, Lucius!
You were there with Lucius too,
weren’t you?
Let us walk this path together.
When we meet all Six Heroes...
Terapagos will reclaim its true power...
And the path to Rakua will open!
I will take you to Rakua!
So mysterious!
This really gets my heart racing!
We only need three more!
We’ll continue investigating
the Six Heroes...
...as we head for Paldea
to investigate Terapagos!
Rising Voltteccers... Set off!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
this Pokémon here: Terapagos!
A Pokémon steeped in mystery,
who awakened from Liko’s pendant.
Terapagos
Classification: ???
Type: ???
Terapagos
Classification: ???
Type: ???
Height
???m
Symbols resembling something
appeared on its shell during battle...
Weight
???kg
But do you know what?
What do the symbols on its back resemble?
A map
Ancient writing
Types
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
Exciting and thrilling
An adventure is starting
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that end in "-s"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Orio here! You can leave machines and rap to me!
Pokémon that end in "-s"
Kentauros, Kaiross, Heracross,
Regigigas, Terapagos, Metagross!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What do the symbols
on its back resemble?
C: Types
What do the symbols
on its back resemble?
C: Types
The answer is C: Types!
Symbols that bring Pokémon types to mind
appeared on Terapagos’s shell.
What could these symbols mean?
A power that rivals the legends!
I can’t wait to investigate further!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Low on funds, the Rising Voltteccers
take on a job. Namely...
Searching for lost Pokémon!
They head off for
the desert in high spirits!
Hmm? Sinister hunters?
Could this be a kidnapping?!
That duo’s rage will finally explode!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters:
Friede and Cap: The Duo in the Wilderness
Wait, that’s Cap’s weakness...?