Please, Ms. Rystal, tell us...
...all about you and the other Explorers...
...and about Rakua.
Those days are still with us,
as vivid as ever...
The Explorers’ adventure to seek Rakua.
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Entrusted Future, the Gleam of This World
You take that way!
Hold it!
Got nowhere to run now!
Give up and hand it over already!
Don’t worry.
I’ll protect you.
I’ll never let you have it!
Lessee if we can’t change yer mind!
How very troubling.
Wha—?
Huh?!
What’s yer problem?!
Stay outta this!
Hasn’t anybody told you that taking
someone else’s Pokémon makes you a thief?
Stuff it!
Sic ‘em, boys!
I see.
I’ll play along!
Wh-What is that?!
We ain’t got a chance!
Hmm? You didn’t want to battle, then?
Rekkuuza... The Legendary...
Ooh! Isn’t that a Terapagos?!
Tera...? You know about Pagogo here?
It’s my first time seeing one.
Where did you get it?
It took a liking to me on a trip through
the Paldea Region’s Great Crater...
That little one’s quite rare,
so folks like them are always after it...
But you’ve kept it safe.
First time I’ve seen someone
not be scared of Rekkuuza.
That was how I met Lucius.
At some point, a fellow named Heather
made record of Terapagos.
Terapagos...
You’ll always be Pagogo to me.
Most people dismiss that book as mere nonsense,
but I believed in Heather’s words.
I believed that Terapagos
really do exist.
And then, you actually met one.
Yes.
I’m glad to have believed him.
Lucius, what are you adventuring for?
I want to find...
...the beauty of this world.
Its gleam...
I want to see a world
nobody’s seen before.
Meet Pokémon nobody’s met before.
That’s why I’m seeking Rakua.
Rakua... Like the Pokémon paradise
from fairy tales?
Rakua definitely exists.
You really believe it...
Naturally.
Terapagos really do exist.
So Rakua must, as well!
Hey! I wanna go to Rakua, too!
Huh?
I also want to find it...!
The gleam of this world!
As we traveled the world together,
Lucius met...
...Oliva...
...Fire...
...Laplace...
...Basagiri...
...and Entei;
bonding with each of them.
He loved Pokémon
from the bottom of his heart.
Rakua?!
Yes.
If you know anything,
please do tell me.
Hey, mister!
You actually believe in Rakua?
Naturally!
Oh, he must be kidding.
A grown man still believing in Rakua?
What’s so strange about that?
We mean business, y’know!
Now, now, Rystal...
We’re free to believe in
whatever we want, aren’t we?!
Just so.
Here is every record
I’ve examined pertaining to Rakua,
plus verification of data points
derived from the legend,
as well as numerous theories.
Educate yourselves
before you stoop to mockery.
So you’re seeking Rakua, too?
Indeed.
I’ve no doubt that so-called “mythical paradise”
is home to something monumental.
Then why don’t you come with us?
If we work together,
we’re bound to find Rakua!
That man gave his name as Gibeon.
Traveling the world
with a white Zygarde as his partner...
He was similar to Lucius
in many respects.
They won each other’s approval,
the three of us became friends,
and our adventure continued together.
How about “The Explorers”?!
Suggesting “those who pursue,” hmm...?
Not a bad fit.
It’s great! Sounds cool!
Then it’s decided!
We, the Explorers,
would have Pokémon lend us their aid...
...and at the end of our long adventure,
we reached Rakua.
So cool!
You managed to reach Rakua together!
My heart was racing
just listening to that!
Ms. Rystal?
By reaching Rakua,
we’d made our dreams come true.
But we never imagined
what it would lead to...
A Latias and Latios!
And look over there!
A Terrakion... Simply incredible.
So many Legendary Pokémon,
and all so relaxed...
It truly is wonderful...
But what could have created
such a bountiful environment?
Let’s head deeper in!
Right.
This area seems a lot rougher.
Do the nutrients in the soil
vary from place to place?
No...
Every tree here looks to have been
larger at some point in the past.
What do you mean?
This area once flourished just as much.
But it seems to have then
suddenly withered away.
Something’s strange about this...
What is that?
Some sort of... crystal?
Pagogo... You don’t like it?
It holds an astounding amount of energy.
Entirely beyond the capability
of any known ore...
I understand...
These crystals caused the plants
around it to grow.
So, it’s the special boon
that makes Rakua so bountiful?
Or special burden, perhaps.
We should leave.
Meddling with energy beyond
the laws of nature is too dangerous.
I think it would be best
for us to leave Rakua.
And pretend we never saw this?
Gibeon... Surely you can understand.
If we stay, there’s no telling
what effect it will have on us.
You’re right. Let’s go.
Let’s head back to base camp for now.
Oh...
Rystal!
Have you seen Gibeon?
Huh?
Now that you mention it...
What was that?!
That came from
where we found the crystals!
Rekkuuza!
We should go too, Pagogo!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Gibeon!
I urge you to reconsider!
Ask me as many times as you please...
You will not change my mind.
This isn’t something
humans were meant to control!
Don’t you understand, Lucius?!
This blessing of energy
beyond human comprehension...
...has eternal possibilities!
Zygarde! Dig up even more!
Gibeon!
It truly is paradise...
Rakua!
And I...
I’ve found it!
This is bad!
Rekkuuza!
Thank you, Pagogo.
What even is this stuff?!
If it keeps spreading,
it won’t stop at just Rakua.
It could well cover the entire world!
If that happens...
...the whole world will perish.
Guys...
Fire...
We will make sure that Rakua...
Let’s go, everyone!
Then... Rekkuuza!
All right!
Magnificent!
Power that renews without end!
What’s wrong, Zygarde?
What are you doing, Zygarde?!
Stop it!
You would betray me?!
It stopped?
No!
Wh-Whoa!
Gibeon!
This isn’t over!
Lucius hasn’t given up.
I want to...
I want to protect everyone, too!
Pagogo!
Lucius!
Thank you, everyone.
Leave this to me.
I won’t die.
I promise you!
I will live on with Rakua,
and we will meet again!
Lucius, no!
Get away from here, Rystal.
I want to help!
I want to believe in the future.
I want you to protect... our future.
I left Rakua.
To protect this little one
inside of me.
I expected to simply forget it all.
If anyone ever knew
of our adventure,
there would be
more tragedies at Rakua.
Which is why...
I don’t intend to tell
this little one about Lucius!
I don’t need to be remembered.
If Layla can grow up healthy...
If she can be a link to the future,
to prove that Lucius and I lived... That’s all I need.
I’m sorry.
I did want to go looking
for all of you...
But I see you ended up
finding them instead.
The Kanto Region, the Paldea Region,
the Galar Region, the Kitakami hamlet...
We found them in
a lot of different places.
All of them cherishing the Monster Balls
Lucius caught them in.
I see...
You still hope to
keep your promise to Lucius...
Every time I’ve seen Lucius...
Those must have been things Terapagos saw,
back when it was with Ms. Rystal.
Pagogo... I had worried
you might never turn back.
I’m so happy you did.
Ms. Rystal, please tell us...
Where exactly is Rakua?
Well... We had been adrift at sea
for several days...
...and Rekkuuza and the others
lent us their aid so we could reach it.
So I don’t know exactly where it was.
And partway through the journey back,
I was rescued by a big ship...
Guess we’ll just have to
find it ourselves, then.
Gibeon might know...
But... I don’t know what
became of him after that...
Um, about Gibeon...
Sadly, it seems this is goodbye.
Wait! I still...
Liko... Diana...
And all of your friends...
Thank you.
I’m glad I got to
see Pagogo one last time.
You’re all part of the future
that Lucius protected.
I’m glad I got to see this.
Liko, look after Pagogo for me.
Huh?
I can tell just by looking at you!
Pagogo’s partner, Liko...
That’s you, now.
Thank you, Pagogo...
Lucius...
Don’t cry, Terapagos.
I’ll take you to Rakua.
I’ll grant your wish.
Terapagos?
Terapagos...
Liko.
Ms. Rystal... Lucius...
Grandma, too... and Mother...
Thank you...
For giving me the chance
to meet Terapagos.
I hope we’ll stay good friends, Pagogo!
You’re really leaving?
You could stay with us again...
Nah. My adventure
with the pendant is over now.
I can’t believe Lucius and Rystal
were my grandpa and grandma...
What an astounding tale
I stumbled upon!
You really didn’t know, Grandma?
Of course I didn’t know.
My mother, Layla, told me that
her own mother died young.
So I’d never even heard
the name “Rystal” before.
I leave the rest to you
and the Rising Voltteccers.
I’ll keep on adventuring,
going wherever my heart takes me.
That’s just like you...
But I’ll be racing right over
if you’re ever in a bind!
Well then, I’m off!
Grandma!
Take care!
That pink crystal Ms. Rystal mentioned...
That has to be the Rakurium.
As for how Rakua’s doing these days...
Guess we’ll just have to see
with our own eyes!
Which is why we need
to find the rest of the Six Heroes!
Entei and the black Rekkuuza!
But where do we start
on either of them?
Sodayo!
That’s right!
Figure something out?
Nope, not a thing.
But when you don’t know something,
it’s best to ask someone.
That’s right! Sodayo!
We can ask him!
You’re quite the zealous one.
Please, do take care not to allow
Hamber to sniff us out.
I will not slip.
Though, one thing does concern me.
Amethio?
He hasn’t been seen since
he was taken off missions.
He’s most likely pursuing his own goals.
He just doesn’t know when to give up.
The one to reach Rakua
with Master Gibeon...
...will be me.
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Next episode
Roy...
We’re really meeting someone
in the savanna?
That’s right!
sou dayo
I hear one of this ship’s old crewmates
might know something about Entei!
Is that right?
sou nano
That’s right!
sou dayo
But I hear he’s
a real strange kinda guy...
Is that right?
sou nano
That’s right!
sou dayo
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Sonano?
Is that right?
Sodayo!
That’s right!
Wait, that’s the title?!
Sonano? Sodayo!