Having finished our
Terastal Course basics tests,
we challenged the Paldea Elite Four
in friendly matches!
Dot with Ms. Nanjamo,
Roy with Mr. Colza,
and me with Ms. Kaede...
We teamed up to create
the greatest battles!
This tastes great, too!
Don’t be shy, have some more!
This party’s for you!
Yeah!
Liko, Roy, Dot...
Congrats again for passing your basics tests!
Congrats!
Thank you, everyone!
We worked real hard,
right, Hogator?
Dot standing valiantly in battle...
Just thinking about it...
...makes me so emotional!
Don’t get so worked up about it...
The course isn’t even over.
You’re right...
You’re right!
We can’t let up now.
You’re right...
But you have to relax sometimes, too.
Yeah, gotta have balance in your life!
Excuse me! Gimme an orange juice!
What is it, Liko?
It just makes me happy
to see you all again after so long.
By the time you get back,
the ship should be airworthy again!
Right!
When we come back,
we’ll all have passed the Terastal Course!
Once you’re done eating,
I’ll head over to Orange Academy with you.
Huh?
But the implementation tests
don’t start ‘til tomorrow.
Didn’t I tell you?
I made an appointment for us to see
Principal Clavel and Board Chair Omodaka.
Huh?!
Every human bears a history.
Every object bears imbued emotion.
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
A Terapagos I Had Never Known
Is that right?
You go on adventures
with Professor Friede?
Thank you for taking the time
to meet with us today.
You are welcome anytime.
I myself am familiar with
your work as a Pokémon Professor.
I hear you wanted to ask us
about Terapagos, of all things?
It couldn’t be!
A real live Terapagos!
Yes...
This is my first time ever seeing one.
Their habitat is
currently unknown, after all!
Where ever did you
find that Terapagos?
A pendant I got from my grandmother
turned into this little one.
How peculiar...
Ms. Liko... Are you saying
you were responsible for reviving it?
Yes.
I’ve heard there are old records
of Terapagos sightings in Paldea.
Given that you’re Pokémon League Chairwoman,
Ms. Omodaka...
I was hoping you’d
know something about them.
Mm.
Records show that
it usually took this form,
but it is thought that it transformed
into this one during battle.
So that’s why, back then...
No detailed data survives,
but it seems to be a Pokémon
with a deep connection to Terastal.
With Terastal?
At the center of the continent lies the Great Crater of Paldea.
The site is under our management.
That’s...!
And at its deepest point,
designated “Area Zero”...
...a Pokémon resembling Terapagos
was once sighted,
and was recorded in the Scarlet Book.
The Scarlet Book...
Isn’t that...?!
This thing!
I found this in the library.
Oh, perfect!
Look here.
Is that...?
It’s thought to be a third form
Terapagos can take.
Cool!
That’s why it was so interested?
In any case,
this is extremely interesting.
What could have caused it
to return now?
This little one wants to go
to a place called Rakua.
Rakua...
This is the first I’ve heard of it.
It’s a place the Ancient Adventurer reached
with Terapagos a hundred years ago.
We’re on this journey because
we want to take Terapagos to Rakua.
And solving the mysteries of Terapagos
will lead to you solving the mysteries of Rakua...
Do I have it right?
Yeah.
I know! Let’s go to Area Zero!
We might find something!
I bet you’re right!
Yeah!
There was an accident recently.
Entering will be difficult at the moment.
No way...
I shall guide you there someday.
You wish to shed light on
the mysteries of Terapagos,
and so do we.
Thank you very much!
Now, for things from
one hundred years past...
There’s someone
who may know more than us.
Ah, that’s right.
Allow me to introduce you.
I wish I could hold onto it, but...
Great job finding it though, Dot!
Even though there’re so many books...
Well, I suppose you should
thank Terapagos for that.
The mysteries only lead us deeper...
Feels like there’s even more secrets
we still need to uncover.
Yeah, it’s so intriguing.
Liko, what’s wrong?
Huh?
You don’t look happy.
Well... I just realized that I don’t really
know anything about Terapagos...
No way! You’ve learned
a bunch from observing it!
It likes berries,
it wants to climb up to high places,
and what else, uh...
Sorry for the wait,
ancient mystery solvers!
I’m Raifort. I teach history here.
Nice to meet you. I’m—
Wh-Why do you have a Terapagos?!
Whoops...
Putting on an Illusion again, are we?
Excuse her.
My Zoroark is a bit of a prankster.
Zoroark?
Zoroark. Transforming Fox Pokémon.
Evil type.
It has the ability to fool
large groups of people simultaneously.
It protects its lair with illusions.
That’s an impressive power...
Huh?
She looks just like him!
Liko, Roy, Dot...
You’re Terastal Course students, right?
Yes!
I’m Friede, a friend who’s been
traveling with them.
Yeah. The principal told me.
I hear you’re following an intriguing lead?
Yes. We—
I’m heading out to do some fieldwork
right now. Care to join me?
We can chat out there.
Fieldwork?
What’re you gonna do?!
Find some ancient treasure!
Treasure?
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
I see... The Ancient Adventurer Lucius
and his Six Heroes...
The mythical paradise Rakua...
And Terapagos,
revived in the present day...
Aw yeah!
The lot of you,
adventuring in pursuit of antiquities...
Now my curiosity is really piqued!
What do you think?
Have any ideas?
Rakua...
It was mentioned
in a pretty niche history book.
Huh?!
What was it...?
Keep quiet.
Listen closely.
The treasure we’re after is active nearby.
“Active”?
Is the treasure a Pokémon?!
I don’t see anything, though...
Over there!
I’ve never seen that Pokémon before!
Collecurei. Walking Forme.
Treasure Hunter Pokémon. Ghost type.
It was born from human emotion
that seeped into a coin.
It wanders around,
carrying an old coin on its back.
It was born from human emotion?!
They’re rare.
Nobody’s ever managed to catch that Forme
in the Paldea Region before.
Really?! Then I’ll do it!
Hogator!
Wh—! It vanished...
See? They’re small and run away quick.
Huh?
A coin?
Looks pretty old.
Must’ve dropped it in its panic.
Better take it.
All right! I got a new treasure!
Ah, there it is!
Oh, that’s...
Zoroark again?
Good work as always, Zoroark.
The coin wasn’t an illusion!
Keep your eyes peeled for the old coins
that Collecurei like to hoard.
We can finish our chat later.
There might be others nearby.
Let’s go find even more!
All right!
Let’s try to find some, Nyarote!
Hmm... They’re not easy to find, huh?
Huh?!
What is it, Terapagos?
What’s that?
The ruins of a fort built by humans.
Let’s check it out.
Right!
Even here...
That’s Carbou; a Pokémon said to have
accompanied nobility and knights in ancient times.
It’s riding on Terapagos!
Ooh, you’re cute!
It’s not scared of humans,
even though it’s wild...
Kojio apparently helped humans perform rituals such as
evil-warding and exorcisms for hundreds of years.
Hundreds of years?!
They’re that old?!
Carbou and Kojio have lived in this land
since ancient times,
forming connections with humans.
And when the humans left,
the Pokémon moved in, huh?
Isn’t that interesting?
Yeah!
Hey!
Roy! How far did you...?
Huh?
Huh?!
A whole lotta treasure!
There’s so much...
How come only you found ‘em?
I’m a natural treasure hunter!
You think this means...?
I see it!
There’s our goal!
A watchtower.
Back when Paldea was divided
into multiple countries,
the emperor built them to
keep watch on neighboring countries.
Does that look familiar, Taikaiden?
There was one where you used to live, right?
Artifacts once built by another,
now forming part of your own story...
Story?
The past... History is the story
that leads to the present day.
The ages of our forebears...
...led the way to the today
in which we live.
Go, Taikaiden!
Fly straight to the watchtower!
I’ll head there with Zoroark.
See you at the top.
Time for us to go too, Lizardon!
There’s something interesting
back there.
A treasure chest?
It looks so, uh... stereotypical.
Could that be...?
A Collecurei?!
Are you sure about that, Roy?
Huh? About what?
After all that work collecting them...
He fell right into Collecurei’s clutches.
Huh?
They control humans to make them collect coins,
only to steal every last one.
Control them?
Then, that means Roy is...!
See ya!
There really are all kinds of Pokémon, huh...?
Yeah...
That was fun!
By hunting for old coins,
we were able to meet modern-day Pokémon.
All thanks to the lot of you.
I had fun, too!
Me, too!
I never finished my thought
regarding Rakua, did I?
The history book described it thus:
“Once upon a time, far beyond Paldea,
“a hundred days and nights away,
there was a Pokémon paradise.
“The shining pink of Rakua.”
Pink!
So Rakua really is
connected to the Rakurium!
People dismissed it as a fairy tale,
and nowadays, there’s nobody left
who knows the name “Rakua.”
However...
I’ll choose to trust your story.
Ms. Raifort...
Before the Orange Academy was even founded,
this land was once part of the Paldean Empire.
And even before that,
another kingdom entirely...
Just imagine it.
What the Paldea lying before you
may once have looked like.
Even without seeing it for yourself...
If you learn about the past, you can imagine it!
The story of our forebears,
leading up to today...
The story of the one named Lucius...
You lot... Learning the past
is an adventure of its own.
If you believe in it, you can find it!
Give it your best!
Right!
Thank you, Ms. Raifort.
I just wanted to show
the children of the future...
...how much fun
learning about the past can be.
Good morning.
You all look full of energy today.
Those of you who have passed
your Terastal Course basics tests...
...will finally be moving on
to their implementation tests.
Osu! Listen carefully as I explain!
Just like with the basics tests,
you’ll each go to a specified town...
...and battle the Gym Leaders!
That’s the exact same thing...
What a total drag.
Silence, San...
...dwich.
Yeah, yeah, got it, “Onigiri.”
The implementation tests
will be much harder!
Each side will use two Pokémon!
You must have both of them
take part in the battle!
Two Pokémon...
Hogator and Taikaiden
both get to battle!
Are you gonna be okay, Kanuchan?
Battle tactically
as you switch out Pokémon.
The key to passing will be whether or not
you can make good use of Terastal!
I wish you good luck!
Once the implementation tests are over...
We’ll finally get to Terastallize!
And if we learn about Terastal,
we’ll find out more about Terapagos, right?
I want to learn,
because there are things I don’t know.
So please teach me
a lot more about yourself!
You can check your assignments
from the app.
Someone called Rhyme in Fridge Town!
Aoki from Champuru Town...
That guy, huh...?
Mt. Nappé Gym... Grusha...
Mr. Grusha! Sorry for the wait.
If that’s enough to raise your spirits,
you’re pretty frigid.
What route should we take this time?
Hmm...
Champuru Town seems to be the closest.
Let’s go!
I’m not about to get cold feet now!
Yeah!
All right! Let’s go!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Walking Forme of Collecurei.
A Pokémon said to have been born
around 1,500 years ago.
Collecurei (Walking Forme)
Treasure Hunter Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Collecurei (Walking Forme)
Treasure Hunter Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Height
0.1m
It walks around seeking a certain thing,
Weight
0.1kg
but do you know what that thing is?
What does Collecurei seek?
Keys
Food
Treasure chests
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does Collecurei seek?
C: Treasure chests
The answer is C: Treasure chests!
Collecurei is said to have been born
in a treasure chest.
So it walks around
looking for treasure chests!
Next episode
What is it, Hogator?
He doesn’t look too happy...
That kinda sigh is...
I’ve got it!
He’s saying, “I’m hungry so I wanna go
to a restaurant for a tasty meal!”
Did he really fit all that
in that little sigh?!
Then... Let’s go to that restaurant!
The Anything Eatery...
It looks kinda deserted... And who’s that
hanging around the entrance in a bad mood?
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
The Mascot Pokémon is Dodogezan?!