We will eliminate the Rising Voltteccers,
for the future of people and Pokémon.
We will retrieve the parts
manufactured for the Strong Spheres.
If that’s how you’re gonna be,
I’ll mega-take you on!
Yamirami!
Masquernya!
Achigator!
Welcamo, us too!
You guys better not
hold me back, y’hear?!
And you better not
rush off on your own, Ult!
This is a team battle.
I know!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
We Are the Rising Voltteccers!
Kentauros, attack.
Avoid it!
Dodge!
Masquernya!
Achigator!
It’s super effective...
They both used Raging Bull
with a type advantage, but...
...those guys didn’t order any moves!
Come to think of it...
It was the same with Maggyo.
Quit daydreamin’!
Yamirami! Hell Thrust!
Welcamo! Aqua Break!
What the—?!
Is that because of
the Rakurium, too...?
Mm-hmm!
Masquernya! Magical Leaf!
Achigator! Nitro Charge!
Stop, Achigator!
Masquernya!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Welcamo! Aqua Cutter!
Thank you, both of you.
W-Well, it is a team battle, y’know!
Let’s get back
in formation for now.
Right.
Everyone, pull back!
They’re strong...
They’ve got power
and solid defenses.
They’re under the effects
of Rakurium, but...
It isn’t like before.
They seem like they’re able to
coordinate their attacks...
Kentauros!
Keep attacking!
Dodge!
This really is strange!
They’re each attacking the same target again and again,
without any orders from their trainers...
Don’t you dare ignore me!
Yamirami!
Eerie Light!
Kentauros!
Don’t look at the lights!
Masquernya!
Dodge it!
They’re not listening
to their trainers’ orders...
That’s it!
Did you work something out?
Right now, the Kentauros
are fighting on instinct.
The power of the Rakurium most likely
heightened their fighting instincts.
But in exchange, they can no longer respond
to complex orders from their trainers.
So that’s why he didn’t
dodge out of the way just now...
Now that you mention it...
Even when they attacked...
Kentauros, attack!
...they didn’t
call out any move name.
The same thing happened
in our battle with Sango and Onyx.
So that’s how it’s able to
make anyone stronger so easily...
The heck’s with that?!
That makes the trainer totally pointless!
So, even when
they looked coordinated...
They were just instinctively targeting
the most advantageous opponent.
Then that means...
The Water Kentauros
will target Achigator...
...and the Fire Kentauros
will target Masquernya yet again.
Yeah. And we’ll use that
to snatch victory!
Kentauros, attack!
Look out!
Dodge!
Now! Welcamo, use Air Cutter!
Masquernya! Magical Leaf!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
All right!
It’s super effective!
Good going, everyone!
How...?
Even with the power
of Strong Spheres, we lost...?
‘Course you did!
If a Pokémon and trainer’s feelings
aren’t united as one,
they’re not gonna be
any good at battling!
Even if you use Strong Spheres,
you can never beat us!
Liko... Roy...
Wh-What should we do...?
Return.
The Rising Voltteccers...
Let’s head back and report in.
I’ll take responsibility for disposing of these,
so don’t you worry.
Thank you very much.
Still... They even commissioned
a tiny place like ours to make them.
They’re bound to have placed orders
at other factories, too.
So this alone won’t put a stop
to them launching Strong Spheres...
If anything,
it may not even affect the launch.
If these things are spread worldwide,
it’ll be even worse than before!
We have to stop them somehow...
Let me help, too.
I saw full well how frightening
Strong Spheres are in that battle earlier.
Those things...
They don’t help Pokémon or trainers.
I’ve been at a standstill
ever since we lost Friede...
But now I remember.
He...
...would never stand still.
I’ve got stuff left to finish and things I oughta do
laid right out in front of me.
I want to help out...
as one of the Rising Voltteccers!
Liko... Roy... Dot... and Ult...
When I was watching all of you...
That’s what I was thinking, and it lit a fire in me!
I want us...
...to fly together
on the Brave Asagi once again!
Thank you!
Let’s go together!
So we finally get to ride the airship!
Gimme four... No, three days.
If we’re taking off,
I want the ship in peak condition!
Sure!
Thanks!
I’m gonna knuckle down hard,
you hear?
I want to help, too!
Me too!
Yep, it’s perfect!
And the shopping’s all done!
The ship’s systems
are in order, too.
We’re all set to leave!
Let’s board already!
All right!
Ah, one sec!
Actually...
We’ve got some good news,
don’t we?!
Hey.
‘Sup...
Molly!
And Murdock!
But why...?
Well, you see...
After I saw you again, it sorta rekindled
my spirit of adventure... Or, I should say...
I just couldn’t bear sitting still.
Orio... Sorry to call you...
But... the airship... Could you...?
I see... So those kids...!
Orio?!
The ship?
Sorry to drop this on you
all of a sudden.
Come, now...
I’m fully in favor, you know.
Treasure the way you feel in this moment,
and stay true to that.
I’ll finish that new cake recipe for sure!
Yes!
And once you do,
be sure to pay Soapberry a visit with everyone!
I’ve finally got another chance to fly!
But still, though...
I want to travel the world, and use my own means
in order to help troubled Pokémon!
My feelings on that
haven’t changed one bit!
You never were comfortable
settling down, I suppose...
Thank you for all your support!
Thank you!
And that’s how we ended up
getting back together.
Last time I boarded the ship,
I was practically running away from home...
But this time,
I’ve got my family’s approval!
I’m so glad to hear!
We would have liked to tell
old man Landau, if we could’ve...
But he just doesn’t have
his own smartphone.
I hope we see him again!
It’s him!
It has been quite some time,
has it not, everyone?
How did you get here?!
This was originally my ship,
you know.
The waves told me
it was eager to set sail.
Wow, right on brand...
Awesome!
I can’t believe you all found us!
You’ve got it the wrong way ‘round.
You’re the ones who gathered us here.
And this time, it’s our turn to ask
if we can join your Rising Voltteccers.
That step I took...
...led to me meeting
my irreplaceable friends once again...
Sure!
Of course!
We’ll be counting on you,
just like before!
All right, I’ve made up my mind!
I’ll do you the honor
of joining your Rising Voltteccers!
“Do us the honor,” he says...
How come he’s talking down to us...?
Wait, who even is that?
Once I catch the black Rekkuuza,
I’ll hafta fly around atop its back, after all.
So getting used to flying
ain’t a bad idea.
With my almighty self along,
you got nothin’ to fear, y’see?
Right, Yamirami?
I-It’ll be okay, Pagogo.
And oh yeah, as for my position...
How about captain?
Huh?
Ult... The ship’s captain is
Captain Pikachu here.
Wait, really?!
Didn’t you know?
Well, having a new
merry face aboard...
...is fine with me!
Uh-huh!
All right! I’m gonna fill everyone’s bellies
with tasty treats, just like before!
I really do feel comfortable here.
Sorry about all the idle time.
I’ll be countin’ on you again!
If fate would have it,
even those a thousand leagues apart...
...shall meet again.
All right!
I got the Rising Voltteccers app’s
server back up and running.
Now we can all use the app again!
What’s this?
A voice message?
Yeah.
It was sent to the app’s address,
but the sender’s unknown,
and it’s encrypted.
I think I’ve just about
cracked it, though...
Sounds fishy.
When was it received?
It’s dated to about a month ago...
Got it to open!
Friede here.
Huh?!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Friede?!
What’s going on?!
Hold it, hold it!
I can’t hear the message!
Sorry. Play it again from the start.
Right.
Friede here.
And I’ve got Lizardon here with me.
My bad for not keeping in touch.
Some Explorers have been
keeping an eye on me.
There’ll be trouble
if my movements get discovered,
so I couldn’t send you a message
until I was out of their reach.
Everything I’m doing is to solve
the mysteries of Rakurium.
So, with that said...
Look after yourselves
until I get back, everybody!
That was really him... Wasn’t it?
Yeah... No doubt about it!
He’s... alive...
No clue what he’s been up to, though.
Seriously...
He could’ve at least told us where he is.
He really...
...never stands still...
Let us take comfort
in knowing he is safe.
Yeah! If you ask me,
this is such a Friede thing to do!
Yup. At any rate,
Friede’ll be coming back someday!
All right!
To celebrate our reunion, and Friede’s safety,
we’re throwing a party today!
A party?!
Nice!
We’re ready to take off anytime!
Let’s make it a sky-high party!
Good idea!
With that settled,
let’s get straight to meal prep!
I’ll help you get ready.
Betcha can’t wait, huh, Achigator?!
Thanks to us
coming together again...
...we got to receive
a message from Friede.
This is the best!
Phew... That took ages.
I always knew a day like this
would come, though.
Karna...
Thank you... for all your help.
Don’t mention it.
I enjoyed having you.
I enjoyed being here, too.
I needed this time.
Is this...?
I thought I’d try and make one, too.
It’s nowhere near
as good as yours, though.
It’s great!
It’s got passion,
and particularities...
And most of all,
it fits you to a tee.
It’s a one-of-a-kind Monster Ball.
I’ll cherish it.
I’m riding the heart-pound-racing currents
I bet
Something you can’t quite put into words...
Something that makes your heart beat a bit faster...
Something that seems to brighten up your day...
“I found some flowers I like!”
With white mist clinging onto every day
This flag really is cool, huh?
I can’t even look for what I wanna find, ooh
My diary makes it all look so exciting
Hey, why don’t we do that,
like old times?
“I threw it out, pretending it wasn’t mine” ...strike that
Good idea!
I’m in!
You lia-ia-ia-iar...
Huh?
Hey, whaddaya mean by “that”?
My inconsolable heart
A proof of our bond.
Whoa-oh whoa-oh-o-oh
Just follow our lead.
Rewrite “But”/“Yet” into “I bet”/“It could be true”
Okay! Well then, Liko...
If only I could walk on air, on a fair breeze
Take it away!
Greatly, smoothly, slightly, nearly, someday...
Right!
I wanna fly!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents!
So smile! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
We are the Rising Voltteccers!
No time to waste hiding away
I wanna discover myself!
Yeah!
The day I manage to say “I’m heading out on my own”
Ya!
Maybe I’ll grow up a little bit
Is that so...?
Understood.
Our sincerest apologies.
Everyone meets with failure
on occasion.
Please remain ever devoted to your missions,
for sake of the Explorers.
Sir.
So they’ve assembled, have they?
If only they could have
behaved themselves...
Your fur’s as beautiful as ever, Blacky.
Unsightly flying nuisances...
...will simply be swatted
once more.
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Flame Pokémon, Lizardon!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Flame Pokémon
Flying
Lizardon
Flame Pokémon
Fire
Flying
Blaze
Lizardon
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Flame Pokémon
Blaze
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Lizardon
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Flame Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Incredibly, Lizardon has
two Mega Evolved forms!
Mega Lizardon Y
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Flame Pokémon
Fire
Flying
Drought
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
This one is Mega Lizardon Y!
Its wings grow larger,
and its flying prowess increases!
It can fly at heights of
ten thousand meters without a care— Urk!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Even at speeds
that can outpace a jet!
Next episode
The Brave Asagi sets sail!
All right! From today on,
I leave the helm to you, Roy.
He looks so dependable...
I’m gonna cry again...
This feels just like old times...
So, where’re we goin’?
No idea!
Blargh!
Hey, I do have one idea...
Where? Where?
Well, as for that...
Find out next time!
And so,
to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Fight! Terastal Versus Mega Evolution!!
Huh?! “Terastal Versus Mega Evolution”?!