My name’s Liko.
I’m taking a Terastal Course
with Roy and Dot.
We all passed our basics tests!
Next, we’ll be trying to finish our
wild Pokémon reports while going camping!
There’s so many wild Pokémon!
The forest over there and that river
probably have even more.
I think I’ll be able to
write a nice report!
Mr. Zinnia said we should take
photos and videos, right?
Yeah.
How about we use this
as research material?
Is that...?
Professor Actually-Doing-Research Friede’s...
Professor Doing-His-Job-For-Once Friede’s...
Yeah. Professor Friede’s
Pokémon distribution map.
It’s been presented at a conference,
and has proper sources...
If we can find any Pokémon
that aren’t on this map,
our reports should turn out
really glitzy.
Plus, then we can
tell the whole ship about them!
I wanna get some
Pokémon Battles in, too...
Good idea!
Why not do your report on them?
Heck yeah!
Well then, I guess our campsite
for the night will be...
Right here!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
(Take a step out, go!)
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Let’s challenge
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
A Thorny Nyarote?!
The Mysterious Flower Pillar
All right! My tent’s all good!
Huh?! Already?!
I’m used to this kinda stuff!
Oh, right.
Liko!
Are you okay?!
Goodness, now I’ll have to
start all over.
Won’t that rock get in your way?
Nope, it’ll make for a perfect workstation.
I see!
Maybe I should also—
Huh?
What is it, Nyarote?
I’ve never seen that Pokémon before.
Kunugidama. Bagworm Pokémon.
Bug type.
It likes to make its shell thicker
by adding layers of tree bark.
The extra weight is not a burden.
Hey, what’s that?
Ow!
I’ve almost got you all nice and clean.
Just a sec.
It’ll be your turn next, Nyarote.
I looked it up earlier,
and apparently Kunugidama
can explode when they’re surprised.
So that was that boom I heard.
Was that a splash?
So cool!
You mind if we go after it?
I wanna write my report
on that Pokémon!
Absolutely!
Be careful!
Sure! Let’s go, Hogator! Kaiden!
We better not fall behind, either.
Let’s head back to the tent
and research the local Pokémon!
We’ll stay here a while longer.
Okay.
Terapagos can roam free here, too.
Don’t wander too far, okay?
Sorry for the wait, Nyarote.
I’ll wipe you off.
Are you okay?!
Sorry Nyarote, just a little longer.
You got yourself dirty again...
Terapagos!
I told you not to go too far!
Sorry about that...
What was it, Nyarote?
Nyarote?
Ow!
Nyarote’s fur is all prickly,
like spines...
Huh?
Ah...
Nyarote...
If I’m writing a report,
I want it to be on a really impressive Pokémon...
Are there any good candidates
around here?
Ooh, this looks interesting!
Hmm?
Huh?
Liko... Did something happen?
Huh?!
Um...
Have a fight with Nyarote?
N-Not a fight, really...
It’s just... She’s in a bad mood.
I see...
Decided on a report topic yet?
No.
Then let’s share info.
Check this out.
Apparently, something called a “flower pillar”
can happen near here.
A flower pillar?
It says a huge amount of flower petals
are whipped up into the air,
making a pillar of flowers
linking together the land and sky.
But as for what causes it,
or when it’ll happen next...
Or what plant the petals come from...
It’s a mysterious phenomenon
with a lot of unknowns.
Plus, there’s a rumor floating around
about this flower pillar.
A rumor?
It’s said that anyone who sees the flower pillar
is sure to find happiness.
Really?
Well, it’s a story with
a lot of fuzzy details.
But it sounds really impressive and glitzy,
and a local Pokémon might be behind it all,
so I think I’m gonna go
look for it later.
I-I want to look, too!
If I can see it with Nyarote...
Yeah.
Nyarote... Um, I just heard about
something wonderful.
Dot told me about this
“flower pillar” thing that happens nearby—
Uh... Huh?!
Terapagos is gone!
It wandered off alone again?!
Over there!
Sorry, Nyarote! I’ll tell you later!
Let’s get Terapagos first, Nyarote!
Okay, we should get going too.
Huh? Will that take long?
Ack! Don’t tell me...!
H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-Hold it!
Stop! Stop!
If you break this, our dinner plans
are down the drain, you hear me?!
Kanuchan!
Terapagos! Where are you?!
I was sure it went this way...
Terapagos!
Hey, Nyarote, help me look.
What is it, Mibrim?
You want to play?
Not here, either...
Are those...?
Nyarote, look after Mibrim!
Yeah, these are
Terapagos’s footprints...
It came through here.
There’s more over here.
Huh? These don’t seem like
Terapagos prints, though...
Was that noise a Kunugidama?
Terapagos!
Ow, ow, ow...
Nyarote... Mibrim...
Nyarote! Mibrim!
H-Huh? Nyarote...
Did I get...
...separated from them?
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
What do I do? I can’t climb out...
Not to mention... it’s so hot...
Wh-What?!
Pokémon...
Nonokurage. Wood Ear Pokémon.
Ground/Grass type.
It lives in muggy forests.
Its legs may be thin, but when it gets going,
it can run at a speed of fifty kilometers per hour.
Nonokurage?
What are they doing?
There’s so many vines...
Wait, are they...?
Nyarote!
Terapagos and Mibrim, too!
Nyarote is trying to protect me!
But...
Nyarote, wait!
Don’t!
Don’t attack them.
You’re trying to protect me, right?
They haven’t done anything to me.
I’m fine!
Thank you, Nyarote.
You just need those vines gone, right?
Let’s go, Nyarote!
Magical Leaf!
Are they waiting for something?
The wind’s blowing through
where the vines just were!
Is this... the flower pillar?!
You know, I heard that anyone who sees
this flower pillar linking the land and sky...
...will be able to find happiness.
I’m glad everyone’s here to see this...
Especially you, Nyarote.
So soft...
You saw the flower pillar?!
The flower petals turned out to be
Nonokurage flaps.
Really?!
Sounds like that’ll make
an awesome report!
Yeah!
I see...
So the strong wind blowing over
the hot ground caused a tornado...
And the Nonokurage around here are in the habit
of using that wind to get their flaps to peel off...
By the way...
You got it on video, right?
Huh? H-How about photos...?
Sorry... I forgot...
Wh-What a waste...
I think I’ll draw
an illustration for my report.
I got a good look at it,
so it’s clear in my mind!
Lemme see it when you’re done!
Sure!
Learning about a new Pokémon
through the flower pillar was nice and all,
but getting to learn
a bit more about Nyarote...
I can certainly say I’m happy.
How about you, Nyarote?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Wood Ear Pokémon, Nonokurage.
It looks like Menokurage,
but it’s a different Pokémon.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Nonokurage
Wood Ear Pokémon
Type: Ground/Grass
Nonokurage
Wood Ear Pokémon
Type: Ground/Grass
Height   0.9m
Menokurage
It’s said to excel at something,
Weight   33.0kg
Nonokurage
Wood Ear Pokémon
Type: Ground/Grass
Nonokurage
Wood Ear Pokémon
Type: Ground/Grass
but do you know what that thing is?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
What does Nonokurage excel at?
Running away
Leaping eagerly
Stepping sneakily
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does Nonokurage excel at?
A: Running away
The answer is A: Running away!
It’s cowardly, and will run away
immediately if enemies draw near.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What does Nonokurage excel at?
A: Running away
It’s said to be able to flee
at fifty kilometers per hour!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Next episode
Question!
What is the Habanero Pokémon
of the Paldea Region?
U-Um...
Next episode
Capsaiji!
Correct!
Amazing, Dot!
Apparently, the front teeth that Capsaiji shed
are even used in traditional super-spicy Paldean cuisine!
Next episode
Wow!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Kaiden, Strong Wind Warning!
It’s got nothing to do with Capsaiji?!