We finally met
Basagiri of the Six Heroes...
...and Nyarote, Achigator, and Welcamo
went all out battling it together.
In the end, Basagiri decided
to come with us.
Huh?
What’s that noise?
Arrived! Kamikita!
kita
Huh?!
Grandma’s Ikirinko?!
Arrived! Kitakami! Arrived!
Grandma!
Hey! Sorry to barge in.
Long time no see!
Ooh! I see she’s evolved
into a Nyarote!
My Hogator evolved, too!
So he became an Achigator!
And Kuwassu became a Welcamo!
Thanks, yeah.
You all look a lot more chipper!
But how did you know
we were in the Kitakami hamlet?
I swung by Paldea
and heard it from Lucca.
Then all it took was
a quick ride on Windie.
Awesome!
Ms. Diana, if you’re back
then that’s gotta mean...
Yes! I obtained some
new info on Lucius!
Really?!
I wanna hear! Tell us!
Now, now. No need to be hasty.
Before any of that...
Liko...
Let’s have a Pokémon battle!
Huh?!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Three Explorers
Challenging Liko to a battle
the second she got here...
Ms. Diana hasn’t changed a bit, eh?
Aw, man...
I wanna battle her, too!
Nyarote versus Windie...
The type match-up puts Liko
at an overwhelming disadvantage...
We’ll just have to wait and see
how she handles it.
This’ll be a serious 1v1 battle.
You won’t catch me
holding back today!
Last time,
it was Nyahoja and Hogator...
Even working together,
it took all we had just to land a single hit.
But now...
Nyarote and I can do this!
We’ll be going all out, Grandma!
Bring it on, Liko!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Windie, use Divine Speed!
She dodged it!
Nyarote! Take it head-on!
Good!
Ooh!
Not bad. She risked the hit to stop Windie
and make sure Magical Leaf would connect!
Your offense and defense
are both impeccable!
Now, time to really get it going!
Windie! Flamethrower!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
Nice and nimble,
but you won’t get away!
Flamethrower!
Acrobatics!
Awesome...
You’re awesome, Nyarote!
She keeps dodging the flames
and racking up damage bit by bit!
Piled high enough,
even dust can make a mountain.
Slow and steady...
That’s Liko’s style.
Yeah.
Nyarote, keep it up!
No need to rush!
Very good!
Nothing like when you were just
blindly attacking with Nyahoja.
Windie!
Diana’s coming off kinda...
...like a whole different person
right now...
There she goes...
Grandma...
Set your soul ablaze, Windie!
Flare Drive!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Dodge it!
Nyarote! Are you okay?!
Ooh, you actually managed
to endure that one.
What was that move?!
A Fire move of the highest caliber...
Flare Drive.
Ms. Diana’s relentless.
So this is what Grandma’s
really capable of...
One more time, Windie!
But we’re not giving in!
Flare Drive!
If that attack hits...
Hurry up and dodge it!
Surprise Attack!
Right on target!
We did it, Nyarote!
She reserved Surprise Attack
for this very moment!
Think she’s got this in the bag?
No...
I’m very pleased, Liko.
I had hoped you’d make it this far.
Windie...
...powered up?
Windie has an ability that raises
its attack when hit by an Evil-type move.
It’s called...
Heart of Justice!
Y-You’re kiddin’ me!
Even when Liko tried to outfox her,
Ms. Diana was ready and waiting.
Grandma really is strong...
But...
We can get stronger, too!
Nyarote...
Shine in full bloom!
I’m eager to face your Terastal!
Windie!
Time for one last Flare Drive!
If we just fire off Magical Leaf,
it’ll only burn up like last time...
Somewhere...
There has to be an opening somewhere!
Nyarote! Use Magical Leaf
on Windie’s paws!
Give me a big Magical Leaf!
That’s that.
All right!
We won... We beat Grandma!
Nyarote!
Nyarote... You are absolutely,
positively the best!
You fought well, Windie.
Take a nice, long rest.
The way you battled to make up for
the type disadvantage...
Your timing on the Terastal...
And above all, how you were
in perfect sync with Nyarote.
You were marvelous, Liko!
You got so much stronger
in such a short time!
I went traveling with Roy and Dot
as part of a Terastal Course.
Having them by my side
helped push me to do my best.
Adventures with friends are guaranteed
to strengthen both Pokémon and trainer.
Once again...
...you barely recognize me?
Now I have nothing to worry about.
Well then, about time I told you...
...the secrets about Lucius
that I discovered!
First, I want you to look at this.
Grandma? You’re so young!
Who’s the guy next to you?
An old friend of mine
by the name of Hamber.
Back then, we’d go adventuring
together from time to time.
Wow...
His Pokémon looks strong, too!
One year ago, when we met up
for the first time in ages,
he said he wanted to
aid me in my adventures.
But as it turned out,
he was after the pendant I gave to Liko.
Some sort of organization
was involved, too...
I suspected you were in danger,
and asked Lucca to keep you safe.
Yeah.
Ms. Lucca asked for my help,
and we set out
to deliver Liko home to Paldea.
And that’s how my adventures began.
I’m still getting to the important part.
When the old castle
I lived in was attacked,
Hamber and the others
called themselves the Explorers!
So he’s with the Explorers, too...
It was a real shock, hearing the name
of the Explorers after so long...
A shock...?
The truth is...
The founder of the Explorers...
...was Lucius.
Huh?!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
H-Hold on now!
How’s that possible?!
There’s no way!
Lucius was in the Explorers?
Lucius formed the Explorers
a hundred years ago.
But now, Hamber and his people
are using the name.
Wait a sec, what do you mean?!
I can’t picture the Explorers
as anything other than bad guys.
Yeah, rotten creeps who’ll
do anything to get what they want.
For what reason—and to what end—
are they using the name of Lucius’s team?
I left the Brave Asagi to investigate
the origins of the Explorers.
So that’s why...
I told Friede,
but I needed to be covert about it.
I had him keep it a secret.
I went all over the world
looking for records of the Explorers...
But only fragmentary accounts
of their endeavors survive in history books.
Same thing as when
I checked thirty years ago.
But!
I returned to the towns that Lucius
is said to have traveled through,
and visited folks who’d
lived there for a long time.
I had them fill me in on old legends,
and show me diaries kept by people living at that time.
And finally, I found them...
Records left behind by people
who met the adventurer, Lucius.
And they even spoke of Lucius’s friends.
Lucius’s friends?
The Explorers initially had
three members.
Trainers by the names of
Lucius, Rystal, and Gibeon, I discovered.
Terapagos!
Isn’t Rystal...?
You’ve heard of her?!
Yeah.
Basagiri showed us...
It’s time we leave.
Let’s go, Rystal.
So Rystal really did
travel alongside Lucius...
That just leaves Gibeon, then.
Never heard of him.
I have.
Huh?!
Amethio mentioned him while we were
trapped in that cave on Mt. Nappé.
Amethio said his grandfather’s name is Gibeon,
and that he leads the Explorers.
Is that so?
You never told us that, Liko!
Yeah!
U-Uh, erm...
D-Did I neglect to mention?
She’s picked up Friede’s bad habit!
Sure has.
Huh?
The info that I found corroborates
Gibeon being the current head of the Explorers.
So he’s been with them
for a hundred years?
Such longevity.
I’d do well to learn from his example.
I feel like he’d be too old to be
Amethio’s grandfather, though.
Yeah.
Whether he is still alive,
or if it’s someone else using the name “Gibeon”...
We can be certain that someone
going by that name...
...has taken over the Explorers,
which was originally formed by Lucius.
I found one more
piece of info about him.
Apparently, that same Gibeon is also
the board chair of the company Exceed.
Exceed?!
Wait, wasn’t Exceed...?
A company developing
useful products for Pokémon, it seems?
Friede, do you know
something about them?
I worked as a researcher
for Exceed in the past.
Really?!
You never told us.
Guess I never mentioned...
And there he goes again...
I went there to investigate
during the ship’s repairs.
At one point, Exceed was secretly researching
the Eternal Blessing—Rakurium.
Rakurium?
What’s that?
Rakurium is a mysterious substance
that can cause strange effects in Pokémon.
You never met that Gibeon guy
while you were at Exceed, then?
Before now, I never even knew
they had a board chair.
The director was a guy called Mr. Crave.
But come to think of it,
he did mention someone higher up...
I couldn’t find a single person at Exceed
who’d actually met him.
I see...
So then, Gibeon was secretly
conducting research on Rakurium at Exceed,
while using the Explorers
to try and reach Rakua.
And that’s why they want Terapagos...
Rakurium and Rakua...
Those sound pretty similar.
They do, yeah...
Maybe Rakurium comes from Rakua?
Of course! The Explorers are after...
Rakua’s Rakurium!
A-Achigator...
It’s time we take a brief rest.
Mm! This is great!
Nothing tops sweets
when you’ve been thinking real hard!
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
We’ve learned a lot
thanks to you, Grandma.
I could say the same thing.
Putting it together with what you and Friede gathered,
I can safely say my info’s good now.
Why is Gibeon still around today?
What is he planning on doing
with the Rakurium?
We still don’t know everything,
but it feels like we’re just one step away.
Yeah. I’m curious about
this “Rystal” person, too.
What is it, Liko?
I want to go back
to the Shining Pond!
The Shining Pond?
A legend says that gazing on the light
of the pond lets you meet with the dead.
Ooh! How intriguing!
It seems like Terapagos knew her, too...
So maybe Rystal would answer our call.
Of course... Last time,
we didn’t know about Rystal.
Definitely worth a shot, I’d say!
All right!
If there’s a chance,
we’ve gotta go for it!
Yeah!
Rystal...
Let’s do it, too.
Please, Rystal...
Let Terapagos’s feelings reach you...
Aww... There, there...
Huh? Huh?!
Pagogo?!
Why are you here, Pagogo...?
Who are you?
Where... am I?
U-Um...!
Are you Rystal?
Yes...
Have we met somewhere before?
My name is Liko.
Um...
Everyone! So you’re all okay!
But why do you have Lucius’s Pokémon?
Uh... Well...
Where should I even start?
Please, allow me to explain.
I’m Friede, a Pokémon Professor.
We are the Rising Voltteccers.
Terapagos awoke from a pendant,
and in order to recover its powers,
we’re trying to go to Rakua
along with the Six Heroes.
Rakua!
Through the power of the Shining Pond here,
you’ve been brought to the future to meet us.
That about sums it up, I guess.
The future...
I see... So bizarre things like that
can actually happen, huh?
I realize this is a lot to take in
and it might be hard to believe, but...
No, I believe you.
I mean, it couldn’t be wrong.
You have Lucius’s Pokémon...
...and my partner, Pagogo, with you.
Pagogo...
Terapagos was your Pokémon?
It wasn’t Lucius’s?
So you did manage to turn back...
I’m so glad to see you.
Oh...
Sorry about this.
What’s wrong?
Are you getting hungry, Layla?
Is that girl called Layla?!
Y-Yes, why?
What’s wrong, Grandma?
Layla was... my mother’s name!
Huh?!
Does that mean...
you’re my granddaughter?
Huh?! Wh-What...?!
Th-Then...
Rystal is Diana’s grandma...
...and Diana is
Liko’s grandma, so... Um...
H-H-Hold on, I can’t keep up!
You’re Liko’s great-great-grandma?!
Hey! Just how old do you think I am?!
Ahh! Sorry, sorry...
She does kinda resemble
Mother and Grandma...
Ah, but...
Now I can finally understand
why you have Pagogo with you.
Diana... And Liko.
You two are my and Lucius’s...
...descendants.
Huh?!
H-Hold on...
Hold on, hold on!
So Lucius...
...is my...
...great-great-grandpa?!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Mimicry Pokémon, Sharitatsu.
A Dragon Pokémon found with
various different colorations and patterns.
Sharitatsu
Mimicry Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Water
Sharitatsu
Mimicry Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Water
Height
0.3m
They may be small and weak,
but they excel at a certain skill.
Weight
8.0kg
What do they excel in?
Speed
Kindness
Cleverness
But do you know what skill that is?
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What do they excel in?
C: Cleverness
The answer is C: Cleverness!
Sharitatsu are exceptionally crafty.
Knowing how weak they are,
they put their heads together
and cooperate when battling!
Next episode
I want you to find...
...the beauty of this world.
...adventures...
...as you live alongside
the Pokémon of this world.
And...
...your futures.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters!
The Entrusted Future, the Gleam of This World