At the Shining Pond, we met
my great-great-grandmother Rystal-san,
who told us about how she met Lucius,
and what happened at Rakua.
With Terapagos—Pagogo, that is—
now entrusted to me by Rystal-san,
we set out for our next destination
in the search for the Six Heroes.
So, I realized who the best person to ask
about Entei’s whereabouts is...
We should ask Sodayo.
Huh?
Mm...
Sodayo, huh...?
Sodayo, right...
Sodayo...
Sodayo was...
...someone’s name?
I’m against it!
Asking him anything is a waste of time!
Aw, c’mon now...
He did use to be one of us.
“One of us”...
He was in the Rising Voltteccers?
I’ve never heard of
this Sodayo guy before, though...
That’s ‘cause he left the ship
before you came aboard, Dot.
He was technically Molly’s senior.
By two measly days!
He up and left the crew
right outta nowhere, huh?
Reject not those who arrive,
pursue not those who depart.
But he might know something
about Entei.
He’s well-informed,
no doubt ab—
No doubt, my foot!
If you’re so much as thinking about asking him,
we might as well just search all on our own!
I hear you...
I already arranged to meet him, though.
Didn’t I mention?
No, you freaking didn’t!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Sonano? Sodayo!
So, this is where Sodayo’s headed?
Doesn’t look like he’s here yet.
Molly said she doesn’t wanna see him.
Like oil and water, those two...
We’re going out for a bit!
We heard there might be
rare Pokémon out in the savanna!
Take care.
Yeah. Be back later!
Easy enough on paper, but...
...there’s no Pokémon anywhere.
Apparently, the Pokémon around here
are pretty wary, so they might be tough to find.
What’s this...?
There’s barely any water.
Did this place use to be an oasis?
Huh?
It looks kinda... mad?
Whoa!
Rikikirin. Long Neck Pokémon.
Normal/Psychic type.
While protecting its main head
with its hardened tail-head,
it swings its long neck around
to Headbutt enemies.
Achigator!
Nyarote!
Close-range attacks are too risky!
Welcamo!
Get some distance and use Water Gun!
No good?
What should we do?
Ooh, now this is a scoop!
“What Provoked Rikikirin’s
Burning Rage?!
“Was It the Savanna’s Curse?!”
Sonano?
Is that right?
Welcamo! Aim for the head
and use Water Gun!
Roy! Attack from the other side!
You got it!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Now! Liko!
Nyarote! Surprise Attack!
All right!
It worked!
But why was it so mad?
Whoo!
That was some splendid teamwork,
youngsters!
You managed to break its curse.
Who’s that?
I get the drift...
You’re that rumored secret society
that goes all over the place fighting Pokémon!
What?
Huh?
Sonano?
That’s right!
Founded in sworn secrecy, the youngsters vigilantly
await their chance to conquer the entire world!
Now this is a scoop!
What the heck?
That’s definitely not us...
Tsk, tsk.
The truth is what you make it!
Please, give me an interview.
The name’s—
Sodayo!
Oh! Friede!
I can see you’re as stylish as ever, Cap!
Huh?
Let me introduce you guys.
This guy’s our old pal...
Sotim da Yotim.
Call me Sodayo.
And this is my partner, Sonano.
Sonano!
Hey, hey, hey!
So you youngsters joined
the Rising Voltteccers!
Murdock! Orio! Old man Landau!
It’s been an age!
You seem well.
Just as peppy as I remember you.
I hear you’re a Pokémon Journalist now?
Tsk, tsk...
I’m a truth-seeking Pokémon Journalist.
I travel the world tracking down
Pokémon-related mysteries.
Wow, that’s awesome!
A “truth-seeking Pokémon Journalist”?!
Orio! I can’t get my bed to fold up...
Gah! Sodayo!
Wow, Molly! What happened to you?!
Look at that hair! And those clothes!
Huh?
Molly...
...used to look different?
She’s way cooler now!
She used to be a lot more—
One more word and I’ll have Lucky
launch you to the stars with Pound!
Hey, hey...
Awful harsh for
our first meeting in ages.
Are you the top Pokémon Doctor yet?
None of your business.
C-C’mon, ease off the scowl.
Let’s have some fun swapping stories, like old times!
Oh, spare me.
I never liked that
sweet-talking attitude of yours.
That any way to treat your senior?
By two days!
Anyway! Friede...
You wanted to ask me something?
Yeah. Actually, we—
Say no more!
I get the drift...
You want to know what I’ve been up to
since way back when.
Sonano?
Huh? Not exac—
Okay!
I’ll regale you with the long and turbulent tale
of my thousands of hardships.
Bragging much?
He hasn’t changed.
Nostalgia lies in that which
does not change.
Liko, go hide Pagogo.
If he finds it,
it’ll be an endless headache.
S-Sure...
Look at this.
“Monthly Occulture”?
The number one long-running
indie occult mag in stores!
Here, check out this article!
“The Truth-Seeking Pokémon Journalist Sodayo
Reveals Confidential Info!”?
“Unfabricated True News”...
Sodayo-san wrote this article!
I thought I’d seen
his name somewhere!
“The Hundred Faces of Pikachu”?
An article called
“Tracking Down Legendary Pokémon!”
Maybe he does know
something about Entei?
Exactly!
But even so, this is still
an occult mag, so the truth—
...is what you make it!
Huh?
Whoa!
Oh, that’s one of my articles!
I get the drift, you guys.
You’re fans of mine!
Sonano?
That’s right!
Sodayo-san...
I read all of your
Unfabricated True News articles!
Your unique angle when digging deep
into mysteries is just so cool!
Heh! You guys sound like
you know your stuff!
Maybe I should write
about you next time.
Ooh!
Really?!
B-B-But...
Reading news is way different
from being news...
I bet it’s a real pain...
Hey, Sodayo-san!
I’ve got a question!
Oh, what is it?
I’ll answer anything.
We’re actually after En—
Say no more!
I get the drift!
You wanna hear about old times
with the Rising Voltteccers?
Huh? Not exac...
But...
...now that you’ve brought it up...
Yeah, tell us!
All right!
Allow me to regale you
with the unfabricated truth.
“The legendary dessert”?
We heard you once made a dessert
called the Canetozzo that exploded in popularity!
And that you’ve never told
a single soul how to make it!
And how pâtissiers the world over
come after you for the recipe!
Huh?
I mean, I did make that... But its “popularity”
was temporary, and limited to here on the ship.
Have you been listening to
Sodayo’s tall tales?
Huh?
I made a super-fast ship
that circumnavigated the globe?
Drawing out the power
of Pokémon to the fullest!
And it was so fast,
nobody could even see it!
Even the sound it made
couldn’t keep up with it!
If I could make a ship like that,
we’d be on it right now.
Sodayo came up with that,
I imagine?
Huh?
Hmm? That aura...
You’re the Pokémon secretly commanding
this ship from the shadows, are you not?
And you have the aroma
of sorcery from a far-off land...
That tea must truly have
bewitching effects!
Um...
Old man Landau is secretly hiding
a tempered body of steel beneath his clothes.
He’s actually a superhero, I tell ya!
There’s just no way...
Sodayo-san!
All of that was fake, wasn’t it?
Was it, though?!
The truth is what you make it!
Sonano?
And lastly, there’s Molly! She—
That’s enough out of you.
If you mess with them
one more time,
I’ll have Lucky launch you
to the stars with Tackle.
Ooh, scary stuff!
Just to think, you used to hang on
my every word, crying out “Senpai!”...
Sodayo! How dare y—
Ack!
Is that...?
What?
Could that be...
...Molly?!
That’s crazy...
Ain’t it? She was the perfect picture
of a demure gal, right?
That’s the unfabricated truth.
Sonano!
Lucky!
And this time, stay gone!
I think now I understand...
...why Molly didn’t like him.
What’s that?
My junior’s in a bad mood...
Sonano?
Honestly...
You out here gathering info, too?
I’m concerned about the Rikikirin
that attacked Liko and her friends.
The savanna’s curse?
Sodayo-san!
You okay?
Yeah, no sweat!
I’m always getting roughed up
when looking for news.
Just the other day, I even went
toe to toe with a Groudon!
Sonano?
Sodayo-san, we have
something important to ask you.
We’re looki—
Shh!
I can hear Rikikirin.
And more than just one.
Sonano!
There he goes again...
They actually are coming!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Yet another huge scoop!
“The Rikikirin Pack Attacks!
“What Lies Behind Their Rage?!”
They’re headed for us again?
But why?!
Thunder Punch!
Ooh! A fierce battle between
Cap and the Rikikirin!
Now there’s a scoop!
What’s that?
Cuespatra. Ostrich Pokémon.
Psychic type.
It emits psycho-power from the gaps
between its multicolored frills...
...and sprints at speeds
reaching 200 km/h.
They’re trying to keep the Cuespatra
from coming any closer?
I get it! This oasis...
It’s the Rikikirin’s turf.
Yeah. They must be fighting a turf war
against Cuespatra over this spot.
And then we entered
their turf, too...
It’s Psychokinesis!
What’s happening?!
Amazing...
Could this be?
“Extraordinary Paranormal
Phenomenon Ravages the Savanna?!
“Is It the Harbinger
of Unprecedented Catastrophe?!”
Sonano?
The Psychic moves collided...
...and created some
enigmatic power, perhaps?
What the...?!
Stop it, all of you!
Look out!
Lucky! Tackle!
Everyone okay?
Thank you, Molly.
You saved us.
Preventive care is part of
a doctor’s job too, you know.
Hey, hey, Molly!
You sure do make a good Pokémon Doctor!
I wasn’t trying to save you.
The staredown’s still going...
What should we do?
Liko! Roy!
Does this mean...?
What is that?
Roy, can you break that rock?
Huh?
Yeah.
Achigator, use Stomping Tantrum!
The water...
The oasis must’ve been
this size originally.
I see...
The water’s flow must’ve gotten blocked
by a landslide or something, causing it to dry up.
Guess that solves the turf war, too.
Good to see they’re getting along now!
Hey, hey, hey!
I just got the biggest scoop
of the century!
Yet again,
the unfabricated truth comes to light!
Sonano?
You helped me get
some great material for Occulture!
Thanks, guys!
So, Sodayo-san...
We’ve got something
we want to ask you!
Tell us...
...about Entei!
Huh?
If it’s Entei you’re after, I heard something about
a sighting at Asagi City in Johto recently...
Sonano!
Huh?
Wait, so...
Was that all you wanted to ask me?
That’s right!
Having him mess with you
must’ve been tiring.
Fatigue is a hotbed for illness.
It’ll be a while ‘til we touch down in Johto,
so make sure to get some rest.
Yeah. You should, too.
Oh, I’m used to it.
Hey, Molly... Do you think Sodayo-san
was telling us the truth about Entei?
Yeah, no need to worry about that.
When Sonano eagerly cries “Sonano!”,
you know Sodayo’s telling the truth.
That’s right!
Huh?
Sonano!
They’ve been together so long
that Sonano can always tell.
On the flipside, if you hear it asking “Sonano?”,
you can’t be sure if it’s true or not.
Is that right?
I see...
Then we can relax?
Well, he did wind up
with some good material,
so maybe that was his way
of saying thanks.
Obnoxious or not,
he is still a journalist.
Oh, so that means... When Sodayo-san
was talking about how you used to be...
Sonano!
Ack...
Well...
I was pretty naïve back then...
Molly, if you grind up the medicinal herbs
growing on the cliff to the west,
you can make a salve that’ll heal
any wound a Pokémon might have!
Really?!
Where am I supposed to find
those herbs?!
Molly, the berries that Zubat gather
in the cave to the south...
...can make a panacea for Pokémon!
Really?!
Molly, if you yell a wish
to the Lunatone at the stroke of nine,
that wish will come true.
Really?
I wanna be the top Pokémon Doctor!
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Sodayo!
I can see how you might
get fed up with that...
Well, I still don’t know
if he was doing it just to tease me...
...or if he was trying to teach me stuff.
So, the truth is what you make it?
You might be right, there.
Let’s meet again somewhere,
Rising Voltteccers!
Sonano!
Liko! Roy!
Sodayo-san’s article got posted to
the web version of Occulture!
Huh? Let me see, let me see!
Think we’re in it?
No big deal
if we aren’t though, really...
“The Mystery of the Savanna’s Curse
Upon the Rikikirin!
“The True Cause Was an Encounter
With a Cuespatra!”
“When their powers collided
with one another,
“an astonishing and abstruse phenomenon
caused the oasis to expand,
“and the curse was dispelled!”...?
Dot, that’s us!
Huh?!
“Plus, a certain group of youngsters
bear a connection to said phenomenon?!
“A healer girl who can read
any Pokémon’s mind!
“A rampaging boy commanding
a Pokémon that’s proud of its power!
“An ingenious girl,
even more intelligent than an AI!
“Will their splendid teamwork
one day turn the world on its head?!”
Whoa...
Isn’t that great, Dot?
W-Would’ve been no big deal if we weren’t
in it though, really...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Long Neck Pokémon, Rikikirin.
The tail and the main head
merged into one when Kirinriki evolved.
Rikikirin
Long Neck Pokémon
Type: Normal/Psychic
Rikikirin
Long Neck Pokémon
Type: Normal/Psychic
Height  3.2m
Kirinriki
That process has dramatically improved
a certain power it has,
Weight  160.0kg
but do you know what power that is?
What power improved when it evolved?
Superpower
ESPer power
O-Power
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What power improved when it evolved?
B: ESPer power
The answer is B: ESPer power!
By synchronizing the brain waves
of its head and tail, its ESPer power improved!
It’s said it could be up to
ten times stronger than before!
Next episode
I hope we get to see Entei.
Nevertheless, we haven’t seen
Asagi City in ages, have we, Nuoh?
There was a time we were
the stars of the ocean, ever aglitter-aglimmer.
Such a long time
since we’ve been here-oh!
Maybe us and Samehada should try and
heal our weary bodies here-on the wide open sea.
And so, next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Landau Returns to His Hometown
What is a hometown?
That faraway place for which
Your heart goes Nuoh
Landau Returns to His Hometown