At last, Lucius’s Six Heroes
have reunited at last,
and we’re now headed towards Rakua.
Led by the black Rekkuuza,
we arrived at a mountain
tall enough to touch the sky.
Rakua is somewhere here...
Brr... It’s cold...
Well, we are at
a pretty darn high elevation.
Not a whole lot of people
live in this general area.
I sure hope we can find
some clues to Rakua...
And that’s exactly what we’ll be
asking around for in Kumuri Town over there.
The black Rekkuuza...
Do you really think
it’s leading us to Rakua?
It’s just gotta be!
Yeah!
Pagogo can feel something, too!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Place Where Heaven And Earth Meet
Whoa, this is cool!
What a lovely town!
Looks like they maintain a self-sufficient
community alongside Pokémon here.
I don’t see any of
the Rakurium’s effects at work here.
The black Rekkuuza has appeared!
Huh?
Disaster will follow!
It’s the black Rekkuuza
the Elderwoman spoke of!
Even my Onbat has vanished,
fearing the disaster!
Did he just say “black Rekkuuza”?
Yeah. And something about a disaster!
Disaster?
Don’t worry, Yuha.
You don’t have anything to fear.
Um... Excuse me.
Hmm?
Who might you be?
We’re travelers.
We overheard you talking about
the black Rekkuuza just now...
Yes... What about it?
Well, we came here
with the black Rekkuuza.
Huh?!
Have you heard of
a place called “Rakua”?
Rakua...?
No, never heard of it.
Get out of our town!
Disasters occur when
the black Rekkuuza appears!
And you brought it here?!
The black Rekkuuza
doesn’t cause disasters!
Like you’d know!
My Onbat has already
vanished because of it!
Yuha, stop.
I’m sure Onbat is just
off playing somewhere.
You people need to
get out of here!
Geez... What’s with him?
Please excuse him.
My son believes the things
he hears from the Elderwoman...
Who is this Elderwoman?
My great grandmother.
She is over one hundred years of age,
but claims to have seen
the black Rekkuuza when she was young.
Hey, do you think that means...?
The possibility is there...
Could I hear what
the Elderwoman has to say?
Huh? Well, sure...
But it happened so long ago,
and her memories seem pretty hazy...
That’s entirely fine.
I’ll go.
You should poke around town a bit more.
But shouldn’t we go with you?
I don’t want her to feel crowded
and get worked up.
Leave it to me!
If she saw it a hundred years ago,
it had to be Lucius’s black Rekkuuza, right?
Yeah, most likely.
This is such a peaceful town.
But what would make them think
the black Rekkuuza brings disaster?
That voice...
It was the boy from earlier!
Let’s check it out!
Thanks, Achigator!
Thank you.
Looks like it goes pretty deep...
Yeah. I heard the voice come
from this direction, but...
Now what...?
Huh?!
“Young man, what did you
wish to hear about?”, she says.
I apologize for my sudden intrusion.
In truth, I hoped to inquire
about the black Rekkuuza.
I hear that you’ve
seen it before, yes...?
He says that he wants to hear
about the black Rekkuuza!
“I saw it fly out from the mountain
when I was about three,” she says.
Please, tell me more
about what happened back then!
Mm-hmm.
Somehow...
We got away...
Cutting it close...
That was no joke...
You’ve said it...
Wait!
You’re those no-good
disaster-bringers!
I’m telling you,
there is no disaster!
We ran into this cave because
we heard a scream from inside.
Yuha-kun... That was you, wasn’t it?
Huh...?
Yeah.
My name’s Liko.
I’m Roy.
Dot.
How did you wind up here, anyway?
Well...
Vibrava. Vibration Pokemon.
Ground/Dragon type.
Rather than using its underdeveloped wings
for flight, it rubs them together,
producing ultrasonic waves
to attack its foes.
They sure look mad...
I was looking for my missing Onbat,
and finally found it deep down in this cave.
And then, those Vibrava
suddenly attacked us...
The black Rekkuuza
was behind this, too!
Like I keep saying,
no it wasn’t!
Yes it was!
No it wasn’t!
Knock it off, guys!
Right now, we need to think
about what to do next!
Is that the only exit?
Yeah. Our only way out
is to go through them.
Still, we can’t exactly just
charge on through that swarm...
But, knowing us...
...we’re bound to
come up with something!
Right?
We’ll be fine, with Nyarote
and the others by our side!
To start with,
Mt. Kumuri is no volcano!
And yet, there was a big, mysterious explosion
near its summit at that time.
A big, mysterious explosion?
It has long been known as
“the place where heaven and earth meet.”
The place where
heaven and earth meet...
That’s where you saw
the black Rekkuuza?
Indeed.
Right after the explosion,
I saw the black Rekkuuza rising up into the sky!
An ominous and terrifying disaster—
Are you all right?
“Young man...
You have sharp eyes.
“I have remembered something,
thanks to you.
“A man with long hair...
“The big explosion
blotted out the sun,
“and the sky went dark
for three days and three nights.
“Then, close to when light
finally began to shine again,
“a man appeared.
“He looked distinctly like a scholar.
“He had long hair,
and an air of eccentricity.”
A scholar with long hair...
“He must have been caught
in the explosion on the mountain.
“My mother nursed his wounds.”
I see...
Young man.
If you intend to approach
the mountain, take great care.
Thank you very much, Elderwoman.
Mm-hmm.
Vibrava! Just let us through,
and we’ll leave right away!
Guess they don’t understand...
No choice. Taikaiden!
Use Uproar!
Nakanuchan, go!
Play Rough!
Amazing!
Tebrim!
Heal Pulse!
More of ‘em showed up!
Gah... There’s no end to them!
Return for now, Nakanuchan.
Go, Welcamo!
Aqua Cutter!
Achigator! Charm Voice!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Incredible!
All right...
Almost there!
If we can put a gap
in the middle of the swarm...
Then I’ll use Aqua Cutter one more—
Huh?
Onbat!
Let’s go! Dragon Claw!
Okay!
Whoa!
Now!
Run!
We made it out...
Yuha, that attack earlier was amazing!
We’ve been training that one a little.
Training?
Yeah.
I wanted to train our killer move
deep down in the cave...
But then Onbat went missing.
Maybe while you were training,
you accidentally entered the Vibrava’s territory?
Huh?
So maybe Onbat vanished because
it was running from those Vibrava?
Then... it was all my fault?!
I did something wrong,
both to Onbat and the Vibrava...
Roy. Liko. Dot.
I’m sorry I said that
awful stuff about you, too!
It wasn’t the black Rekkuuza’s fault.
It’s fine! Don’t worry about it, Yuha.
You were all just incredible
in that battle, though!
You were so strong and cool!
It blew me away!
Strong and cool?
We were...?
Yeah!
It was exciting, and thrilling!
I wanna train with Onbat...
...‘til I can battle in sync with
my Pokémon someday, just like you!
I bet you can do it!
Yeah! W-Well, having goals
in mind is important, I suppose.
You can do it, Yuha!
You’re already in sync with your Onbat!
Your training’s bound to bear fruit!
Really? Thanks, Roy.
Friede.
You three, come back
to the ship for now.
I got some info about Rakua.
Gibeon? In this town?!
Yeah, no doubt about it.
And Rakua is most likely
at that mountain’s summit,
near the place known as
“the place where heaven and earth meet.”
The summit, huh...
And we can’t get there in the ship, yeah?
That’s right.
Elevation-wise,
it can’t go up much higher.
Mountain climbing gets pretty chilly...
All right! I’ll go prepare some grub!
We gotta go out in the cold again...?
Take care of the ship while we’re out, guys!
We’ve got it covered!
Take care!
Then let’s go!
We’re off!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
It just gets colder and colder...
Dot, are you okay?
What’s that?
This is gonna be trouble.
We have to climb that?
You serious?
Oliva?!
You’ll help us up?
Okay! Thank you!
This is...
No way we’re crossing that!
No helping it. Guess we’ll just
have to find a spot we can cross.
Laplace!
Looks like it’s telling us to hop on!
Let’s go!
Whoa, this is cool!
Look out!
Basagiri!
Thanks, Welcamo.
Thank you, Laplace and Basagiri!
Already out of signal range, huh?
Getting separated would be dire.
Be careful.
Huh?!
What the?!
Not good!
That was close...
Thank you, Gouging Inferno.
What’s that ahead?!
A Banguirus and a Nidoking, eh?
Gonna be hard to get through them.
They lost their energy!
That’s Galarian Fire for ya!
The Six Heroes are helping us
through so many things...
This is awesome!
This could be proof
we’re getting close to Rakua.
One final push, everyone!
Yeah!
Just a bit farther...
Oh, right...
I wonder if Lucius had the Six Heroes
help him out, just like us...
Huh?
The clouds are so close by...
Is this the place
where heaven and earth meet?
Do we have to go into the clouds?
I don’t know...
But there must be
something past there.
All right... Let’s move!
Yeah!
I can’t see a thing.
Be careful, guys!
We’ll be okay.
Huh?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Mouse Pokémon, Pamo.
The electric sacs on its cheeks
are underdeveloped,
Pamo
Mouse Pokémon
Type: Electric
Pamo
Mouse Pokémon
Type: Electric
Height
0.3m
which is why it uses a different
body part to generate electricity.
Weight
2.5kg
But do you know which body part that is?
What part of its body generates electicity?
Its belly
Its tail
Its forepaws
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What part of its body generates electicity?
C: Its forepaws
The answer is C: Its forepaws.
Its electricity-discharging paw pads
are located on its forepaws.
By rubbing its paw pads on its cheeks,
it can finally generate electricity.
We made it to the top of Mt. Kumuri!
Next episode
Whoa! What an amazing view!
Look! Something could’ve been
hidden behind the clouds!
Rekkuuza?!
If Rekkuuza brought us here,
then that means...
If Pagogo’s celebrating too,
then that means...!
Then that means...?
Then that means...?!
To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
We’ve Arrived! The Paradise of Rakua
We've Arrived! The Paradise of Rakua