Huh?
You didn’t lose anything important?
Anything... important...
I’ll be on my way, then.
This mission was child’s play.
My name is Liko.
I’m a Pokémon Trainer,
and my partner is Nyahoja.
I enrolled at Sekiei Academy
in the Kanto Region, but...
For some reason,
I’m in the Paldea Region.
Why did I come
all the way back to Paldea?
That’s strange...
Hey, Nyahoja...
Is this really how
Nyahoja and I got along?
I feel like I’ve lost
something important.
But I can’t remember what exactly...
So cute!
Ow!
Huh? I feel like
I’ve done this before...
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents
I bet
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Something you can’t quite put into words...
Something that makes your heart beat a bit faster...
Something that seems to brighten up your day...
“I found some flowers I like!”
With white mist clinging onto every day
I can’t even look for what I wanna find, ooh
My diary makes it all look so exciting
“I threw it out, pretending it wasn’t mine” ...strike that
You lia-ia-ia-iar...
My inconsolable heart
Whoa-oh whoa-oh-o-oh
Rewrite “But”/“Yet” into “I bet”/“It could be true”
If only I could walk on air, on a fair breeze
Greatly, smoothly, slightly, nearly, someday...
I wanna fly!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents!
I bet! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
Don’t let untold tales scare you
Dazzling daydreams make the world dance!
So smile! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
No time to waste hiding away
I wanna learn about myself!
I still don’t know anything about any-any-anything
I wanna discover myself!
The day I manage to say “I’m heading out on my own”
Maybe I’ll grow up a little bit
An Invisible Threat! Whozat?
Liko isn’t back yet?
She said she was going shopping.
From here, she’d have gone to either
Bowl Town or Hakkou City.
It shouldn’t have taken her this long.
Any contact?
I’ve been trying to reach her,
but no luck.
No location data either,
for some reason.
Did her battery die?
All right, let’s split up
and look for her.
Yeah.
Dot?
Bowl Town sounds suspicious.
I tried searching for
sightings of a girl with a Nyahoja...
...and found a ton of reports
from Bowl Town.
That’s incredible!
You can find that online?
Dot, you keep gathering info
aboard the ship.
Got it.
Roy and I will go on ahead.
We’ll meet up in Bowl Town.
Right!
I pray for your safe return.
Not everything you seek
is for the eye to see, after all.
Hmm... I can’t remember...
What... is this?
Nyahoja, do you know?
Oh, right.
You do like to play with balls.
For now, maybe I should just head home.
That might help.
Oh, wait!
It looks just like the crystal
of a Terastal Orb,
but I doubt that’s all there is to it.
Blacky, can you sense it too?
Intriguing...
Friede!
No good, she’s not there.
I didn’t see her either.
I asked around,
but nothing turned up.
How about you, Roy?
I asked Mr. Colza at his Gym,
but he didn’t know.
Liko...
Gah— Kaiden!
Wait, Kaiden!
Oh, this always happens...
Seriously, you’re so fickle.
But...
That free spirit is what makes you
so special, Nyahoja!
Huh?
Huh? This feeling...
Seeing the sunset with Nyahoja...
We’ve looked up and down
and haven’t found her.
Something’s off here.
You’re right.
We’ve looked everywhere.
Would Liko really head off
somewhere on her own?
Could she have been kidnapped?
Kidnapped?!
If so, why were there
so many sightings in Bowl Town...?
Don’t tell me...
Is this info bogus?!
The Explorers?!
Amethio and his goons
would’ve faced us head-on.
Do you have any other ideas?
Those Rarecoil gathered
above the ship...
One of them
was acting on a trainer’s orders.
What?!
That’s huge!
Why didn’t you tell us?!
Sorry, didn’t I mention?
Even in battle,
they didn’t show themselves.
But they were probably behind
the ship malfunctions and the signal issues.
Right... Our Smartphone Rotoms
had no signal in Oliva’s forest either.
A Rarecoil was hanging
overhead then, too.
The same trainer...
It looks like we’ve fallen into a trap
laid by some unknown enemy.
But who?
Someone else after the pendant?!
We’ll worry about that later.
First, we need to find Liko.
This is Hakkou City?
It’s so pretty!
Wait, I totally wandered off!
Come on! How could I have...?
I should’ve authenticated it!
Why didn’t I think this through...?
Right. This isn’t like me.
But what if
something happened to Liko...
I can’t just sit around.
I need real info.
But how to get it?
Put out a call in a Gurumin vid?
But I’d need a plan that’d go viral.
A plan that’d go viral...
Please pick up...
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Whatcha wantin’ from Nanjamo?
Nanjamo! It’s been a while!
Ooh! Madam Gurumin sans the suit!
Long time no see!
Once just a fan of mine,
now a popular streamer.
You really make me
hold my head high!
Well, you still
can’t touch my popularity.
I have a favor to ask
the ultra popular streamer!
What? What is it? Tell me, tell me!
I need your help!
I’m looking for someone.
Whaa?
Looking for someone?
Y’know, I am a Gym Leader,
so I’m a busy girl...
My IRL friend disappeared!
I have to find her!
Ooh! You made an IRL pal?
Yeah. A very precious friend.
Gotcha, gotcha!
Belly-ve I read ya!
But just “looking”
ain’t gonna hype anyone up.
Right. So I’ve got an idea.
Ooh! An idea, she says?
A collab stream?!
Seriously?!
That’s crazy cool!
Is something happening?
What a crowd...
The big city is amazing...
Everybody, are you ready?!
That’s...
Electrowebbing your eyes!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Whoa! It’s the real Nanjamo!
It’s time for “Whatchagot TV”!
As today’s guest,
I have a special surprise!
So, take it away!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s the costumed streamer Gurumin!
Gurumin... My favorite streamer...
Your attention, everybody!
I, Nanjamo, and Madam Gurumin;
a real dream team!
Wellzen...
Time to announce today’s plan!
Quiz! Find our girl on the street!
Yo-ssu!
To put it simply, it’s hide-and-seek.
And since it’s a collab today,
a friend of Madam Gurumin’s—
one of her subscribers—will be doing the hiding!
That’s so sweet!
I wish I could be part of something like that.
The girl everyone’s hunting for is...
“NyahojaSuperfan”!
Huh?!
Is... Is... Is that... me?!
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Coil your eyes wide
and get to searchin’!
Make sure you find
NyahojaSuperfan for us!
Why... Why did Gurumin choose me?
A friend? Did she mean to say that,
even though I’m just a fan?
Huh?
She has a Nyahoja...
Oh, no, I’m... uh...
Found her!
Oh?
What?!
U-Um, uh...
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
It couldn’t be!
No way!
Nyahoja?!
Wait! Why are you running?!
Oh, now that’s a surprise!
That’s no good for hide-and-seek!
This won’t go viral
if she’s found right off the bat, so...
We’re switching it up to a game of tag!
Hey, hold on a sec!
With all this excitement,
my subs will rise like a Shibirudon going upriver!
Huh? Madam Gurumin got disconnected?
But Nanjamo ain’t stopping for no one!
Sheesh...
Nanjamo just can’t help herself.
All she had to do was look for her...
At least now I know for sure.
Find anything out?
Liko is in Hakkou City.
What?!
Our enemy put out bogus info about
Liko being in Bowl Town to slow us down.
They’re craftier than I expected.
I’m in Hakkou City!
Roy!
When did you get there?!
I’ll go look for her now!
Yeah, counting on you.
We better hurry to Hakkou City, too!
Wait, Friede!
I have a favor to ask.
Take me to Hakkou City, too!
Wait!
I’m gonna catch you!
She said this was tag, right?
She chose me.
I’ve got to do my best for Gurumin!
Nyahoja, use a big Leafage!
She’s gone!
She vanished?
Huh?
I feel like I’ve fled with Nyahoja before...
Nyahoja! Lightning Speed!
So fast...
I can’t keep up!
Nice, Nyahoja! Let’s go!
I know this feeling.
Working in tandem with Nyahoja...
Wasn’t it a pain to go outside?
It is a pain, yeah. But...
I wanna look for Liko, too.
I can’t let them get away
with tricking me... and my friends!
I understand how you feel.
But we’re up against a Pokémon Trainer.
You’ll need a partner if there’s a battle.
A partner...
Kuwassu.
Looks like you’re all set.
Now, let’s go!
Huh? Didn’t we just come through here?
Argh, all the buildings look the same!
I can’t do this!
Huh? Is that...?
Sorry I’m late.
Friede!
And you’re...
Oh, uh...
Dot, right?
You came to help us!
You could tell?
Of course!
Look how friendly
Kuwassu is with you!
Hmm?
Anyway, any word on Liko?
No, I still haven’t seen her.
Okay. I’ll check online
for new sightings.
If I look hard enough,
I’m sure I’ll find her...
Okay, I’ll search from the skies.
Lizardon!
This is it!
This way!
That way!
You’re amazing, Dot!
But Liko is on the move, too.
We need to get ahead of her.
I’ve pushed forward with Nyahoja,
just like this.
I stepped out,
to follow my own desires...
This moon...
And the sunset earlier...
I’ve discovered all sorts of
sights with Nyahoja.
That’s it.
I remember everything!
And what we hold dear...
This way!
Is she up there?
Let’s go and see!
They’re catching up!
Right. We’ve jumped like this before.
I’ll be fine. With Nyahoja,
I can make this jump!
Found you!
Liko!
Roy!
Yes. And what I hold dear...
The reason I stepped out with Nyahoja...
The ones I came to meet...
Ready... and...
My friends!
We jumped it, Nyahoja!
Are you okay?!
Liko! We finally found you!
I remember everything!
Thank you, Roy!
Liko?
What a relief.
Oh, but there’s one thing
I can’t seem to recall...
Um... Who are you, exactly?
U-Uh, it’s Dot!
Huh?! You’re Dot?!
Well... I guess I never...
Hey! Hiya, hiya! Great work!
Nanjamo...
My! Our action-packed game
has thrilled everybody all ‘round the world!
What is this?
When did they get here?!
Hey you, tag champion!
Care to say a few words?
Huh? I’m not sure what you mean, but...
I’m glad I found her?
And for the girl who helped us today...
Introduce yourself to everybody!
Um...
I’m NyahojaSuperfan.
You’re very fortunate,
Madam NyahojaSuperfan.
Having friends that care so much for you.
Huh?
R-Right!
So then, Madam Gurumin!
Wrap this show up for us!
Sorry! My connection’s been spotty!
But just look at you,
whipping up all this excitement!
I can’t wait for the next time
we get to collab!
Good idea!
Do it again!
And to our assistant,
NyahojaSuperfan...
Thank you!
Gurumin and I worked together...
With everyone’s help,
we pulled it off!
When we work together,
nobody can take us down!
Take you down?
Now who’re you fighting, Madam Gurumin?
And that’s the finale!
If you felt the sparks fly today,
go smash that subscribe button!
The Electrical Streamer!
Whozat? This was Nanjamo!
So you do have some fight in you.
Welcome back, Liko.
I’m sorry for worrying you.
Don’t be.
What matters is that you’re safe.
Dot, Roy... Thank you.
We couldn’t have found you without Dot!
Thank you for coming to look for me, Dot.
Uh, well...
We’re friends.
Are you okay?
Just tired from walking.
Gah, this is why
going outside is such a pain...
Right. I have friends I hold dear.
By my side, I have Nyahoja...
...and everyone
in the Rising Voltteccers.
Let’s board the ship.
Adventure awai—
The pendant!
Huh? What’s wrong?
Did you drop it?
Um... I bumped into someone,
then my head went blank...
Bumped into someone?
Liko, did that person
have a Pokémon like this?
I think they did!
I knew it.
That’s the Ohbem I battled earlier.
Ohbem?
A Pokémon that can manipulate
its opponents’ memories.
They must’ve used its powers
to erase your memory and steal the pendant.
Huh?!
What a lowlife...
I’m sorry.
It’s my fault that the pendant...
Nah, we’re not giving up yet.
Huh?
After stealing the pendant,
they should have fled immediately.
But...
Something forced them
to stall for time?
Yeah. Meaning they’re probably
still close by.
Then that means...
Liko! We’ll get your pendant back!
Yeah!
The Rising Voltteccers’
counterattack begins!
Yeah!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Brain Pokémon, Ohbem.
Ohbem
Brain Pokémon
Type: Psychic
Ohbem
Brain Pokémon
Type: Psychic
A Pokémon shrouded in mystery,
which commands intense psychic powers.
Height
1.0m
It can use those powers
to rewrite a certain thing,
Weight
34.5kg
but do you know what that is?
What does it rewrite using its psychic powers?
Sheet music
Programs
Memories
See the answer after the commercials!
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Yo! We are the Rising Voltteccers
What Pokémon will we meet next?
I can't wait for more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Then why don't we learn about more Pokémon?
First, Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Now, can you say it with Liko?
Are you ready?
Hmm... Can I really do it? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next, Pokémon that have regional forms!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! Leave it to me!!
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode! Woo!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What does it rewrite
using its psychic powers?
C: Memories
What does it rewrite
using its psychic powers?
C: Memories
The answer is C: Memories.
Using the tricolor lights on its fingers,
it commands intense psychic powers.
It rewrites its opponents’ memories
into different ones.
Maybe all our memories
have been secretly rewritten too?
Next episode
Yo-ssu! Was that a hit?
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’? It’s huge preview time!
My collab with Nanjamo
was amazing, wasn’t it?
Now that Liko’s remembered all sorts of things,
the Rising Voltteccers go on the counterattack!
But our foe...
Whozat? Wherezze?
Liko and the crew face the mysterious foe!
What’ll happen?! What’ll they do?!
To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
With Kuwassu, I Can Do It