After I got separated
from Roy and Dot on Mt. Nappé,
I found myself face-to-face
with Amethio from the Explorers.
Spinel also showed up
in the middle of our battle...
and used a strange stone
that did something to his Blacky!
Terapagos managed to calm things down,
but I wound up trapped in a cave with Amethio!
Terapagos!
I’m not planning anything now.
Trust me.
Huh? Just like that...
Seems it understood
that I mean it no harm.
What now?
Roy, Dot...
I’m making you worry about me again...
Of all times, why now?
Shove off! We’re in a hurry!
Nuh-uh!
You’ll have to make us leave.
What did you say?!
Calm down, Roy.
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
(Take a step out, go!)
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Let’s challenge
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Liko and Amethio
We don’t have time
to deal with them.
Right.
Let’s all make a break for it.
Hogator, dash!
Welcamo, run for it too!
Kyojiohn! Stone Edge!
Whoa there!
Whatcha runnin’ away for?
Think we’d make it that easy?
Onigohri! Blizzard!
Hogator!
Hang in there, Welcamo!
Use Salt Pickling!
Oh no! Dodge it, Welcamo!
Hogator!
So, one of them
managed to slip away from me.
However...
Onigohri! Ice Spinner!
All right!
Show a bit more restraint.
There’s no gain
in defeating them right away.
Stalling for time
just ain’t Sango’s style!
Stalling for time?
They’re deliberately
trying to slow us down?
Which means...
They’re after Liko!
That’s bad! We’ve gotta move!
Roy. Let’s work together.
R-Right.
We’ll take them down,
starting with Kyojiohn.
But how?
We’ll exploit the Rock type’s weaknesses.
Gotcha. So...
Hogator! Stomping Tantrum!
Kyojiohn! Crush it with Stone Edge!
Now, Welcamo! Aqua Break!
It landed!
Now, stand back and let us—
Kyojiohn!
Self-Regenerate!
It healed...
...the damage?!
Always makes for
a nasty li’l surprise.
Now we’re right back
where we started. Bring it on!
Think, think!
It’s getting colder and colder.
If we don’t do something soon...
And I know Nyarote
doesn’t like the cold, either.
Huh? Nyarote?!
What? You want me to
keep warm with this?
Thank you, Nyarote!
Soublades...
Thank you. That helps.
Nyarote!
Let me have this grass.
Excuse me!
I have a request to make of Soublades.
If you light this grass to make a fire,
it’ll help keep all of us warm.
Soublades. Light it.
Amazing! Thank you!
It’s so warm!
Um...
During our battle earlier...
I saw you hesitate.
When faced with
my Terastallized Soublades,
why did you give in so easily?
I was taking a Terastal Course...
But I ended up failing.
I thought all my hard work
was paying off...
But now it’s gone,
out of my reach...
I thought that
if I was able to use Terastal,
I could learn more about this little one,
and do more to help it, too.
So I was really hoping to pass...
Are you going to give up?
I ask you... Is hitting one stumbling block all it takes
for you to give up and declare yourself worthless?
No way! I’m not done yet...
The search for the Six Heroes,
the adventure to Rakua...
They’re not over yet!
I’m not ready to give up!
Is that so?
I’ve been wanting to ask you...
Back in the battle with
the black Rekkuuza...
Why did you save me?
As I told you...
I wasn’t saving you.
But you did save me!
I made it, thanks to you.
What are you trying to say?
The Explorers are evildoers
pursuing Terapagos and the black Rekkuuza.
But something feels different about you.
Tell me!
Why do you need Terapagos
and the black Rekkuuza?
It is all for Gibeon-sama.
Gibeon?
My grandfather, leader of the Explorers.
He wants to reach Rakua.
Terapagos and the black Rekkuuza
are beings that lead to Rakua.
I want to fulfill my grandfather’s dream.
It’s... for your grandfather?
I want to be more than just his grandson.
I want to live up to
Gibeon-sama’s expectations!
Terapagos...
It’s okay.
I’m on an adventure I inherited
from my grandma, too.
I want to reach Rakua, for Terapagos—
the pendant my grandma gave me.
It wants to go to Rakua,
so I decided I’d take it there.
Terapagos itself wants to go to Rakua...?
So maybe the two of us
are following the same path.
I’m glad I asked.
‘Til now, I’ve only ever thought of you
as an enemy who was after Terapagos.
I’ve only ever seen you...
...as the girl with the Terapagos.
I’d never even considered
what your goal was.
Now I can see there’s stuff you’ll just never know
if you don’t hear people out.
You may be right.
What’s wrong?
Let’s get out of here...
Liko!
Right!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Get out of here, huh?
Look up.
That grass is swaying because
there’s a breeze coming through.
I can also see a dim light.
There’s a chance that it leads outside.
Meaning...!
Armorgaw can fly us up there.
But I want to widen the opening a bit.
Nyarote, help us out!
Go! Armorgaw!
Soublades, use Psycho Cutter!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Summon up all your strength, Soublades!
Psycho Cutter!
Nyarote, give me
a whole lot of Magical Leaves!
Get back!
Tebrim!
Mind Power!
Follow up with Brutal Swing!
Thank you, Tebrim!
Look!
Hogator!
C’mon! That all you got?!
What now? The way this is going...
This is a total drag!
They’ve got zero fight in ‘em!
Guess it’s time I wrap this up!
Don’t forget!
Our goal is to slow them down!
But I’m so bored!
About time for me to spice things up!
Onigohri!
Self-Destr—
Moonforce!
Onigohri!
Who did that?!
Grusha-san?!
Huh?
A Gym Leader?
That is one frigid game you’re playing.
He’s good.
Well ain’t that somethin’?
Onigohri! Get up!
Pull out.
Huh?!
Don’t you dare boss me around!
We’ve achieved our objective.
Battling a Gym Leader
would hardly be wise.
We’re leaving.
Return, Kyojiohn.
Listen up, dorks!
Next time, it’ll be total carnage!
You hear me?
Grusha-san!
Thank you very much!
You didn’t want to battle them, right?
We lost track of Liko, and they stopped us
when we went to look for her!
I’ve heard all about Liko.
Some guy named Friede called the Gym.
Let’s hurry.
Right!
We made it out...
As a warning...
Watch out for Spinel.
He’s bound to lay another
cowardly trap eventually.
Mm-hmm.
As for that “Eternal Blessing”...
He’s plotting something.
Um...
The Rising Voltteccers
and the Explorers...
They share the same goal
of reaching Rakua, don’t they?
And?
Then couldn’t we work together
instead of fighting?
Not possible.
Why?!
Our goals may be the same,
but our paths are not.
I will follow my own path.
We better get going too, Nyarote!
Look.
A mark in the snow...
It’s been moved?
Then that means...
Liko went past this rock?!
I could’ve seen that
if I had just looked closer!
You can’t always just look ahead.
The ground beneath your feet
is what’s important.
Tyltalis!
That was a shock...
Huh?!
Liko!
Roy! Dot!
Are you okay?
I’m so glad to see you!
I’m sorry...
And thank you! I’m okay!
Guess they don’t need
our help after all.
You’d better warm yourselves up.
Thank you very much.
Grusha-san!
Sorry for making you worry.
Well, all worked out in the end, right?
I may have failed
my implementation test,
but that’s not the only path
I could take.
There must be more paths!
If I keep trying
and never give up, I bet...!
If those guys showed their faces,
maybe they’re starting to ramp things up.
Liko...
What did Spinel come out here to do?
Well...
When he used this pink crystal thing
on his Blacky, it went on a rampage...
Spinel called it the Eternal Blessing.
So he has the Rakurium?!
Rakurium?
A mysterious substance
they kept at a lab I used to work at.
I never knew it could do that...
Blacky seemed to be in a lot of pain...
But when Terapagos transformed
and unleashed its power,
Blacky went back to normal
and the crystal disappeared.
What do we take from that?
Heh, guess you can’t exactly
answer me...
Okay!
Keep an eye out for more activity from them.
I’ll head back and fill everyone in.
Right.
We should head down the mountain
and back to Orange Academy.
Yeah!
Hold on. Roy, Dot...
There’s somewhere I want to go first!
We made it!
Paldea’s Highest Peak!
Amazing...
We’re as high up as anyone can go...
I’m glad we got to see this together.
Yeah!
We’ve seen so many sights already,
But every time... Every single time,
it feels like we’re seeing the best one yet!
Liko!
Let’s take a photo!
Yeah! I’m coming!
Here we go!
Three, two, one...
Why did you call for me?
What’s going on?
Spinel!
I need to ask you—
It’s such a pity.
I never dreamed
that you would betray us.
What...?!
This is what Spinel-sama reported.
What led you to collaborate with the enemy
without even notifying us?
You even let Terapagos escape
before your very eyes...
It’s beyond comprehension.
So this was your plan all along, was it?!
Hold it, Ame-pyon.
If you’ve got an excuse,
I’ll hear ya out.
I, too, have my suspicions about this.
Indeed.
May we ask for a complete explanation
of the events from your perspective?
There is no need.
Gibeon-sama...
You disappoint me, Amethio.
Please, wait!
So you were the same...
So you would
stray from the path, too...
Begone.
I wish to see your face no longer.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Humming Pokémon, Tyltalis.
A Pokémon with fluffy wings
that resemble cottony cumulus clouds.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Tyltalis
Humming Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
Tyltalis
Humming Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
Height
1.1m
They love to do a certain thing,
but do you know what that thing is?
Weight
20.6kg
Tyltalis
Humming Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
Tyltalis
Humming Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
What do Tyltalis like to do?
Sing
Dance
Sleep
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What do Tyltalis like to do?
A: Sing
The answer is A: Sing!
Tyltalis love to sing!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What do Tyltalis like to do?
A: Sing
They sing in a beautifully clear,
enrapturing soprano voice!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Next episode
I hear the final part of the Terastal Course
is a battle tournament!
All right! I can’t wait!
Are the course students
gonna be battling each other?
Next episode
Let’s all do our best!
What’s wrong, Welcamo?
Huh?! Could that be...
the Explorers?!
Next episode
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
System Breach!
A Crisis at Orange Academy!!
We’ve gotta do something!