The Rising Voltteccers, a band of adventurers
led by Friede, continue their journey.
The awoken Terapagos was a peculiar Pokémon
that wasn’t even in the Pokémon Index.
Terapagos hopes to find Rakua.
But to do that, we must find
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes...
...and recover Terapagos’s power.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we’re headed to the Paldea Region.
Kanuchan!
Don’t run off without me!
Gah, what a pain.
Going shopping for
hammer materials, huh?
Going out all on her own...
Kids sure grow up quick...
He’s still on that...
Come on, sit still.
I can’t wash you properly
if you keep wriggling.
Geez!
Should I give you a bath too, Nyahoja?
Nyahoja...
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Farewell, Nyahoja?
Liko! You all done? Let’s battle!
Yeah. Let’s go, Nyahoja.
Hogator, use Ember!
Dodge it and use Lightning Speed!
Charm Voice!
Nyahoja, get back!
Ember!
Scratch!
A big Leafage!
I knew you’d do that.
Dodge it!
Look out!
Liko! You okay?
Yeah... Just took a little fall.
I’m okay, Nyahoja.
Did you get hurt?!
When I landed on my hand,
I sort of...
Let’s have Molly look at it.
Looks like a sprain.
Try to avoid moving it around too much.
Right...
It should heal quickly
if you don’t overexert it.
Don’t use your left hand
to hold anything heavy.
Thank you.
I’m glad it wasn’t anything bad!
Yeah, I’m fine. It doesn’t hurt.
Nyahoja, don’t you worry either...
Huh?
I wonder where Nyahoja went...
Hmm?
Nyahoja went into the forest?
Mm-hmm.
In the direction of
that roof you can see there.
She seemed a touch crestfallen.
Really? Thank you.
I’ll go and look for Nyahoja.
Mibrim, can you watch Terapagos for me?
I’m counting on you.
Nyahoja!
Where are you?
Is this just her fickle side showing?
Though, I don’t think she’s ever left the ship before...
This must be it.
Could she have gone inside?
Excuse me...
Nyahoja? Are you there?
Huh?
That was...
Nyahoja!
Huh? It’s another Nyahoja?
Huh? What?
Huh?!
Hello!
Surprised to see so many Nyahoja?
Did you have business here?
Oh, um...
I’m sorry for letting myself in!
I’m...
Oh?
You were... Let’s see...
Of course,
Liko-san from Sekiei Academy!
Huh? Huh?!
A breeder specializing in cat Pokémon...
That’s right.
I’m Marnya, the caretaker here.
I look after a lot more
than just Nyahoja.
I mean, they’re all just so cute.
Don’t you agree?
Y-Yes...
Um... But how did you know
who I was?
I never forget the Pokémon
that head out into the world,
or the people who
take them as partners.
Then Nyahoja...
My Nyahoja was raised here?
Yes, that’s right.
I also help introduce trainers
to their partner Pokémon.
I’ve worked with students
from Sekiei Academy many times,
and you I remember particularly well.
That Nyahoja was quite unique.
Unique?
Nyahoja are fickle and carefree Pokémon
by nature, and she was especially so.
She had trouble fitting in
with her peers.
I had a hunch
that might be the case...
She didn’t look too happy
when I saw her earlier, so I was worried.
“Earlier”...
So Nyahoja really did come here?
Huh? She wasn’t with you?
No. Um...
She suddenly ran off,
and I had no idea where...
Oh, did you have a fight?
Ah, no, nothing like that...
I see...
It’s rare, but it does happen...
Pokémon leaving their partners
to return here by themselves.
Sad as it might be...
If they’re just not getting along,
and they have to stop being partners...
I can take them back
under my care here.
Stop being partners?!
N-No! We’re doing fine!
Nyahoja and I get along really well!
Um... I’m going to go
look for Nyahoja!
There’s no way we can
stop being partners!
I know Nyahoja
better than anyone... I think.
She’s probably somewhere sunny...
Wherever the view’s the nicest.
Just like I thought.
Nyahoja!
So that’s where you were.
Oh, this?
I’m completely fine.
It wasn’t your fault.
Nyahoja, I heard this is
where you grew up.
It’s a nice place.
Did you miss your old home?
Oh... Wait!
Are you... mad at me?
I bet you’re just feeling a bit sulky!
Isn’t that right?
Oh, I know! On the way back,
we can get some of that matcha cake you like—
Ah!
Hey, why don’t we
head back to the ship now?
We can finish our battle
with Hogator!
Or do you want some snacks first?
You must be hungry, right?
It’s filled with
the scent of Nyahoja!
Oh! Wait for me!
Nyahoja!
Hey, look at me.
What’s wrong?
Are you angry? Worried? Sad?
We’re partners, right?
We’ve gone on adventures
and battled together, right?
You wouldn’t quit being my partner, right?
Right?
Why...? Why, why?!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
She’s acting like
she used to back then...
Does Nyahoja...
not like me anymore?
Can’t find Nyahoja?
Well...
How about some tea?
Here, enjoy.
Thank you.
Matcha...
Nyahoja’s favorite flavor.
It’s bitter!
But relaxing, too...
If you like,
you can have some sweets as well.
Thank you for offering.
But... why would Nyahoja...?
Partners really do
take after one another, I see.
She often made that same face.
Huh? By “she,” you mean...
Nyahoja?
Yes.
She’d be sunbathing
in her favorite spot on the roof, and...
...I could practically hear her saying
“Oh... I’m so bored here. Take me somewhere more fun...”
Even if the others were playing,
she would go “Leave me out of it.”
I can picture it...
But then, one time
when everyone was play-battling...
I was quite surprised.
It was an amazingly powerful Leafage.
She must have a knack for battling.
So Nyahoja’s Leafage
really is something special...
And then what happened?
After that...
She came to be admired
for her astounding Leafage...
...and came down from the roof
to have fun playing with her friends.
So she made friends.
I’m relieved to hear
that she wasn’t alone.
Well...
Huh?
She was playing happily with
the others like any other day, until...
That’s...
The Trap Pokémon, Wanaider.
Now and then,
one would sneak onto the grounds...
...and use traps to cause trouble.
Dear me!
Don’t worry. You’ll be all better soon.
She was only trying to save her friends.
But her Leafage was a bit too strong.
The others became afraid of her,
and started avoiding her.
Ever since that day,
she never used Leafage again.
I never knew...
Before long, her friends found partners
for themselves and headed off,
but she just kept
sitting up on that roof...
Come to think of it,
when we first met...
Maybe she didn’t want to use Leafage
because of what she’d been through...
And then when her Leafage hurt me,
maybe she thought I’d abandon her
just like her old friends did...
Is that why she came here?
I told her that I was fine...
That’s why it was such a relief...
...when you two met at the Sekiei Academy interview.
Huh?
Interview?
You were introduced to some Pokémon
before starting school, right?
I was only spectating,
but I was sure of it.
I knew that you would be
the perfect partner for her.
I saw the look in her eyes.
She couldn’t stop gazing at you
through the screen...
She must have been thinking
“We’re meant for one another.”
So, if she made her way back here...
Nyahoja!
...I could only imagine
one reason why.
She doesn’t want to hurt
someone important to her again.
Found you!
No!
Caught you!
You’re not getting away again.
Take this!
I don’t mind if you scratch me.
You scratched me when we first met, too.
So many things started on that day...
My heart’s been pounding ever since.
Being kidnapped...
Jumping from roofs...
Running around...
Going to unfamiliar towns...
So many things that felt new and scary...
But because I had you with me,
I was always smiling in the end.
No matter how scary,
or how tough it might be...
Whenever I need to overcome something new,
I want it to be with you.
What about you?
Nyahoja...
That voice...
Mibrim! Terapagos!
What are you doing here?
Wanaider!
Don’t sweat it. You can do this!
Remember all the battles
we’ve been through!
Leafage!
You did it! Nyahoja, you did it!
Amazing! Just amazing!
That move...
That was Magical Leaf!
Magical Leaf?
Your bond caused the move to evolve!
You’re amazing, Nyahoja!
Are you okay?
Such a beautiful family
she’s found for herself.
Hogator, use Ember!
Lightning Speed!
Stomping Tantrum!
Jump and dodge it!
Here it comes.
Dodge it, Hogator!
Magical Leaf!
M-Magical Leaf?!
Hogator!
Ooh, now what was that?
She’s gotten even stronger...
Nice, Nyahoja!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, we’ll be taking a look at
the Trap Pokémon, Wanaider.
Wanaider
Trap Pokémon
Type: Bug
Wanaider
Trap Pokémon
Type: Bug
A Pokémon that clings to tree branches and ceilings,
moving without making a sound.
Height
1.0m
Weight
16.5kg
It makes use of a certain something
when catching prey in its traps,
but do you know what that thing is?
What does it use when catching prey in its traps?
Saliva
Threads
Stench
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cute & sweet Pokémon!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Varinich,
Tarpple, Mawhip!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Murdock here. Dot... Just watch this!!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Vanirich,
Tarpple, Mawhip! Yes!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What does it use when
catching prey in its traps?
B: Threads
What does it use when
catching prey in its traps?
B: Threads
The answer is B: Threads!
Wanaider uses its strong,
sticky threads to lay traps.
It lurks in the darkness, taking out foes
before they even have a chance to see it.
If it looks too tasty to be true,
it’s probably a trap!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
It’s never easy figuring out
what to tell worrywart parents, eh?
And when they act on
the slightest impulse,
and never let you get
a word in edgewise, life is tough!
O-Or... so my friend tells me!
A-And so... To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters:
The Intense Mom Appears!
Everything I said was about a friend,
you hear me? A friend!
The Intense Mom Appears!