During the Terastal Course’s
closing tournament...
...the Explorers appeared,
and we ended up battling them.
But somehow, we chased them off!
Mr. Grusha saw my battle and gave me his approval,
passing me on my implementation test.
So now I’ll officially be receiving
my own Terastal Orb, too!
Welcamo!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine!
There it is! She Terastallized!
Go!
Aqua Break!
Darumakka!
Darumakka is unable to battle!
The winner is Dot!
All right!
Dot won!
She sure knows how to Terastallize!
You’re strong!
Guess it makes sense
the savior of the school is tough!
Huh?! How do you know about—
Everyone was talking about it
over lunch break.
Huh?!
Mm.
Botan...
You told people?!
I heard you beat the living daylights outta
some bad guys sneaking into the school!
Th-That’s... a little
blown out of proportion...
Fantastic work!
Everyone here’s got their eyes on you!
No one wants to miss your battle!
Same goes for me, of course!
New faces linked by destiny!
Saviors of our academy!
Suddenly names everybody knows!
Next up is Roy and Liko!
Close friends, always together they go!
Let’s see just how far they’ve grown!
Here and now, time to trade blows!
Osu! It’s finally time for our last match!
Liko... Let’s go all out!
Absolutely!
Let’s make it a great battle!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Shine, Terastal! Liko VS Roy!!
Ms. Rhyme!
Lookin’ good!
I feel some stylish vibes
coming outta Hogator’s noggin.
Hogator’s in top form today!
Sounds like it’s gonna be
an amazing battle!
Can’t wait!
Nyarote’s really raring to go!
Me, too!
Really, I’m just plain excited!
Oh, my...
Ms. Liko, you seem quite a bit
more confident now!
This battle is going to taste great.
Anne, could you look after Terapagos?
Okay!
Give it your best!
Yeah!
Have fun, too!
Thank you!
Osu!
You two ready?
Yeah.
Let the battle... begin!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Hogator! Flamethrower!
Lightning Speed!
Nitro Charge!
One more time! Nitro Charge!
Nyarote! Lightning Speed!
Nitro Charge raises your speed
every time you use it.
Is Roy gonna rely on that
to clinch the win?
Good job, Hogator!
Nyarote!
Use your bud to grab him!
Don’t give up! Run for it!
Hang in there, Nyarote!
Yeah, just keep spinning him around!
Now!
Hogator!
Hogator, return for now.
Go! Taikaiden!
The real battle starts now!
Yeah!
Taikaiden?!
Magical Leaf
won’t work as well against it.
Nyarote!
Use your bud to grab it!
Now, just like before—
Not falling for that again!
Fly up as high as you can!
Now dive!
Use Magical Leaf at the ground!
Not bad at all, Liko!
Same to you, Roy!
Incredible!
She’s made remarkable progress!
That look on her face now
is way more suited for a battle!
Not bad, Roy-garde!
That was a outstanding usage
of Magical Leaf.
A fine battle, drawing out
their respective strengths...
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Fly up high and dodge it!
You can’t run away
from a Magical Leaf!
He’s not just running away, is he?
Correct. Its wings are catching the wind,
drawing electrical charge.
That should do it!
Taikaiden, use Spark!
Nyarote, use Scratch!
Nyarote!
Taikaiden has the upper hand
in the air!
Nyarote, are you okay?
Paralysis status?!
Return, Nyarote!
Tebrim, I’m counting on you!
Whoever strikes first wins!
Taikaiden, use Spark!
Mind Power!
Taikaiden?
In that case... Uproar!
All right! Now!
Fly up!
Spark!
Mind Power!
Tebrim!
One more time!
Spark!
Dodge!
Tebrim?
Tebrim is unable to battle!
We did it, Taikaiden!
You did your absolute best, Tebrim.
Nyarote has the paralysis status...
What’re you gonna do, Liko?!
Nyarote!
The paralysis is healed!
Healing Heart...
So that’s Tebrimmy’s ability.
Seeing how she’s battled so far, I can see why
Mr. Grusha passed her on her implementation test.
She’s got your pal Chili’s
stamp of approval, too.
Thank you for healing Nyarote, Tebrim.
Let’s go, Taikaiden! Spark!
Nyarote! Use your bud—
Wait, never mind!
It dropped its guard?!
Scratch!
Taikaiden?!
Taikaiden is unable to battle!
Yeah! We might be able to
make that into a new move!
You gave it all you got, Taikaiden.
This battle ain’t even close to over!
Hogator!
We’re good to go!
Let’s do this, Nyarote.
Let’s show ‘em
what we’re made of, Hogator!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Hogator, go all out
with Flamethrower!
Nyarote, one more time!
We did it! A Surprise Attack!
Nice one, Liko!
Do you still remember
our first battle?
Of course!
Leafage, Leafage, Leafage!
Ember, Ember, Ember!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
I’ve battled Roy time and time again,
and we’ve even trained together.
I’ve grown stronger together with Liko.
Nitro Charge!
Surprise Attack!
Hogator, stop!
Stomping Tantrum!
No matter who we were up against,
we made it through together.
We’ve even fought
the Explorers together.
Nitro Charge!
Surprise Attack!
I’ve seen Roy battle all this time...
I’ve seen Liko battle all this time...
Lightning Speed!
Nitro Charge!
If I’m with Liko...
If I’m with Roy...
...I can reach even farther!
Isn’t that right, Hogator?!
Hogator!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Ooh!
Bwuuuh-huh-hoi—
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Achigator!
He evolved!
You’re so cool!
You want to go all out against
his newly-evolved Achigator, don’t you?
I feel the same way!
Same for us!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Achigator!
Nyarote!
Shine... in full bloom!
Flamethrower!
Magical Leaf!
Give it your max, Achigator!
Lightning Speed!
Nitro Charge!
Nyarote is unable to battle!
The winner is Roy!
We did it!
We won, Achigator!
Whoa, whoa! Whoa!
Gave it your max, huh?
Nyarote...
And with that, the Course Students
Battle Tournament is concluded.
I’m gonna go back to Sekiei Academy
and work real hard!
I wanna be able to have awesome battles,
just like you guys...
So, once I’m ready...
Yeah! Let’s battle again!
You did it, Roy!
The Pokémon Trainer I had my eye on
didn’t let me down!
You shook me to my soul, too!
Yeah!
Me and Achigator’s feelings connected.
We wanted our battles together
to heat up even more!
Exceptional!
Id moved me to my bery core!
You adolescents
certainly are quick to improve.
Congrats, Roy-garde.
Thank you!
I’m glad our own strength
took us to victory, Welcamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao— Wait, what?
The tournament’s over already?
It ended a while ago.
Say what?!
So, how’d it go? How’d it go?!
Guess I don’t even gotta ask, huh?
Welcamokins!
That was a really great battle!
Ms. Poppy...
I got to have a battle
that felt satisfying to win!
So glad to hear that!
Excuse me! I’m still here!
Sorry, Nanjamo.
We’ll have a good chat later.
Ah! Wai—
You sure went all in.
That was a great battle!
For a minute there,
I worried I’d forget to breathe!
I managed somehow, though!
If you ever get the chance,
please do challenge our League as well.
Thank you!
What are they talking about?
Gurumin!
H-How do you know that?!
I’m subscribed.
And I’m looking forward to your streams.
Also...
You helped us out.
Thanks.
Ms. Liko!
Congrats on finishing the course.
Come now, Mr. Grusha.
Say a few words, too.
You lost your battle.
Come, now...
Meaning you can still get stronger.
Right! I’ll do my best!
If you don’t mind frigid temps...
Feel free to drop by again.
See ya.
Look after yourself!
I’ll see you again sometime!
Our Terastal Course is over.
Now with the power of Terastal under my belt,
there’s a sight I want to see...
Roy has a Pokémon
he wants to battle...
And Dot has things
she wants to discover.
This is the beginning
of a new adventure!
I’m totally bored, y’know.
Here.
How sweet of ya.
A sandwich, huh?
Something you’re fond of?
Not really.
How about you?
Hmph.
Hamber was asking about you.
Even if he suspects me, I am the only one
who can actually analyze the Rakurium.
The data on Terapagos has proven
highly useful, as well.
So, infiltrating Orange Academy
was worth our while.
This info...
Has Hamber learned of it?
I haven’t reported it...
Nor do I plan to.
All for the best, I say.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Fire Croc Pokémon, Achigator.
Achigator
Fire Croc Pokémon
Type: Fire
Achigator
Fire Croc Pokémon
Type: Fire
Evolution has brought
various changes to its body.
Height
1.0m
What looked like hairs on its head
now take on an egg-like shape.
Weight
30.7kg
But do you know what
that thing on its head is, exactly?
What is on top of its head?
A Gold Orb
A fireball
A berry
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What is on top of its head?
B: A fireball
The answer is B: A fireball!
It forms the overflowing power
it emits into a fireball.
It has full control over it,
and can even put it to use in battles!
Next episode
There really is no better place to relax!
Murdock’s curry is super tasty!
Orio, thanks for all your hard work.
Repairing the ship must’ve been a huge job.
Well, yeah...
But I gave it a nice boost!
Molly, Gramps...
I should thank you, too.
All the ship’s Pokémon
are happy and healthy!
Now is the time for us
to reconvene.
Well then, how about we go
pick up Liko and the others?
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters:
To a New Sky! The Brave Asagi!!