We came to Tengu Mountain
to search for Basagiri.
Although we faced plenty of trouble along the way,
we finally pinned down a clue.
Basagiri must be somewhere
deep in this mountain!
Trusting in that assumption,
we press on!
There!
No doubt about it, right?
Yeah.
I think these are the same scars.
Look.
A rock shard?
I saw one near the scars
from earlier, too.
Doesn’t it look kinda like this?
Like Basagiri?
Could just be coincidence, though.
Nah, that’s a sharp eye you’ve got there.
Basagiri chip their axes every time they battle,
which is said to increase their sharpness.
So this is a piece of an axe?!
I’d say it’s very likely.
So this is definitely the right way!
Yeah!
Let’s go!
A dead end...
Sure looks like it.
Terapagos?
Huh?! That tree just...!
Basagiri!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Lone Warrior - Basagiri
So we meet again, Basagiri-kun!
It really is Basagiri of the Six Heroes!
Laplace?
Just me, or do they look
like they’re out for blood?
Weren’t the Six Heroes
a close-knit team?
What’s wrong, Laplace?
The scars on that landmark...
I thought they looked familiar!
Look!
So Basagiri was the one
who gave it those scars?
So what you’re saying is...
Those two...
...might actually hate each other?!
Everyone, get back!
It’s a fight between
two of the Six Heroes...
Amazing...
Every battle sharpens Basagiri’s axes
by chipping the blades, huh?
The power and speed of
those sharpened axes is on another level.
No surprise for
one of the Six Heroes!
Huh? What? Why?
Over just like that?
Just a casual greeting
between friends, perhaps?
That’s an awesome greeting!
The Six Heroes are just so cool!
Liko.
Yeah.
Basagiri!
We’re searching for Rakua
alongside Terapagos.
Laplace, Oliva, and Fire
have joined us...
...on our journey to Rakua,
where you made your promise to Lucius!
I want you to come with us!
Lend Terapagos and the rest of us
your strength!
Huh?
Basagiri...
It left...
So it’s not interested in joining us?
Do you think that’s it?
We can’t say for sure yet!
Right!
We need to find out
how Basagiri really feels!
Hey...
Given how it hopped through the waterfall
and vanished, that means...
There definitely could be
something back there.
I’ll go take a look!
Looks like there’s an entrance to a cave!
So that’s where its hideout is.
Let’s check it out!
This must be a limestone cave.
I’ve never seen anything like this.
Pretty big one, too.
But where’s Basagiri?
Ah...
Are these...
...scars from Basagiri’s axes?
Huh?!
There’s some over here, too!
And here!
Think it battled someone down here?
Or maybe it got mad
and went on a rampage?
No, that wouldn’t have led to
such systematic scarring.
It probably made these while training,
to polish its moves.
Training...
All alone, for all this time...
But why, exactly?
Guardie, wait!
Ah— Friede!
Go on without us!
There’s a breeze...
There could be an exit nearby!
A bamboo grove...
Basagiri!
Do we call the others?
If we waste any time,
we might lose track of it again...
What’s it doing, anyway?
Is this more battle training?
H-Hey, look by its feet!
Huh? Is that all bamboo?!
Cut by Basagiri?!
That’s incredible...
It’s saying “Bring it on!”...
Maybe it wants to test
how strong we are.
Sure seems that way.
Nyarote.
Achigator.
Welcamo.
Let’s hit it with all we’ve got!
Yeah!
That’s our only option now!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Welcamo! Air Cutter!
It blocked all three
without taking a single step!
Let’s get in close
and attack all at once!
Yeah!
Got it.
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
Welcamo, use Aqua Break!
Nyarote, use Acrobatics!
Dodge it!
It’s so powerful...!
It’ll be bad news if it lands a hit.
We’ll just have to keep dodging
and rack up damage bit by bit.
Yeah!
Acrobatics!
Nitro Charge!
Aqua Break!
Nice! It can’t take us all at once!
It ran away again?!
After it!
Achigator and Welcamo will attack
from ground level! Nyarote from above!
Okay!
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
Welcamo, use Aqua Break!
Get behind it!
Nyarote, use Acrobatics!
Nyarote!
It dodged all of them!
I get it now!
Basagiri wasn’t running away from us...
It was luring us deeper in!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
No good!
We can’t land a single hit!
It’s using the bamboo
to its advantage!
So it’s staying extra focused
to make up for bad visibility...
...and relying on sound
to anticipate incoming attacks?
Either way,
our chances look pretty grim!
Everyone! Let’s get outta here!
It trapped us?!
Liko!
Roy! Dot!
Did they make it outside?
Aqua Break!
Acrobatics!
It dodged them again!
But all we can do is keep at it!
Achigator, show it your spirit!
Nitro Charge!
It’s hot...
Impressive heat!
What...
...just happened?
The bamboo Basagiri cut up...
I get it!
I’ve got a plan!
Huh?
Achigator, go all in on spirit
and use Nitro Charge!
Run around as fast as you can!
My gramps once told me...
...there’s air trapped
between bamboo nodes.
If you toss ‘em in a fire,
the air inside will expand, and...
Now!
Welcamo! Kick Down!
Acrobatics!
We threw off Basagiri’s focus!
Now it can’t anticipate
where we’ll attack from!
Nice idea, Roy!
Wait!
What’s that?
Huh?!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
They were battling Basagiri?!
You’re not getting away again!
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
Nyarote, use Acrobatics!
Welcamo, use Aqua Break!
What was that move?!
That move was probably
Basagiri’s Rock Axe!
Pretty crazy...
How are we supposed to fight that?!
So this is the strength
of the Six Heroes...
But... If it’s resorting to its best move,
that has to mean...
...Basagiri’s feeling cornered!
We’re holding our own in this fight!
Liko...
Nyarote...
Shine in full bloom!
Let’s go, Achigator!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Welcamo!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Aqua Break!
All right!
Nyarote!
Achigator!
Welcamo!
Thank goodness...
Basagiri!
Is it saying “Follow me”...?
Wow!
What a breathtaking view!
You can say that again!
Landscapes aren’t really my thing,
but I can’t resist!
That’s Oni Mountain, isn’t it?
Then the Shining Pond is over there!
That’s right.
An Ancient Monster Ball!
Huh? Huh?!
Lucius...
And Basagiri!
Basagiri is not
the only one at fault here.
Live your life as you see fit...
But stay away from this village,
understood?
I’m sorry, Laplace.
Haven’t finished your rampage yet, I see.
Have you ever wished to
put your strength to the test?
We are seeking
an undiscovered paradise...
On an adventure
where anything might happen.
Wouldn’t you say
that’s a far worthier cause...
...than making trouble
for these villagers?
Mm-hmm.
Basagiri...
Let us seek out Rakua together.
It’s time we leave.
Let’s go, Rystal.
What?! What was all that?!
A memory from the past...
That’s the only way I can explain it, I think.
We’ve seen fragments of them
a number of times before.
You think that was when
Basagiri and Lucius first met?
And when Laplace got those scars...
Lucius called out
someone’s name, didn’t he?
It was “Rystal,” I think.
Rystal... Who could that be?
Basagiri...
You’re coming with us?
You think maybe you won it over
by proving your strength in that battle earlier?
Basagiri may’ve been
waiting here all this time...
Waiting for someone it could trust
so that, like in the past,
it could use its well-honed strength
in service of its allies.
Huh?! You’re leaving?
Yeah.
I got loads of good photos
thanks to you!
Now I’m just brimming with motivation
to find and snap even more amazing Pokémon!
And there’s no time like the present!
Time is money, y’know!
Um! Sazare-san, I gotta ask something!
Way ahead of ya.
I won’t publish any photos of
Basagiri or Terapagos. Don’t you worry.
Liko-kun, Roy-kun, Dot-kun...
Professor Friede!
Can’t wait to see you all again, once you’ve
changed so much I can barely recognize you!
Thank you so much for everything!
‘Til next time, Guardie!
All right, we’re outta here!
See ya!
See you around!
Now then, let’s get back to the ship
and report back with the crew.
Right!
Huh? What’s that noise?
Arrived! Kamikita!
kita
Huh?!
Grandma’s Ikirinko?!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Battle-Axe Pokémon, Basagiri.
Basagiri
Battle-Axe Pokémon
Type: Bug/Rock
Basagiri
Battle-Axe Pokémon
Type: Bug/Rock
It evolves from Strike
using a special kind of ore.
Height
1.8m
You can tell how strong it is
by looking at a certain part of its body,
Weight
89.0kg
but do you know what part that is?
What shows Basagiri's strength?
Its axes
Its eyes
Its wings
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What shows Basagiri's strength?
A: Its axes
The answer is A: Its axes!
Its axes are made out of hard rock,
and often get chipped in fierce battles.
The more battles a Basagiri has been through,
the more chipped its axes are.
Next episode
Grandma Diana
is back on the Brave Asagi!
And she says she discovered
something about Lucius!
“Do you think she’ll tell us?”
The instant I wondered that,
she started a Pokémon battle with me?!
Her vitality is through the roof!
Wish I had a bit of her stamina!
But now’s our chance to show her
how much we’ve grown!
Let’s do our best, Nyarote!
Let’s defeat Grandma
and hear what she has to say!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
The Three Explorers