Rekkuuza...
Why is it here?
Now that the Six Heroes are assembled,
it decided to find us, huh?
But Liko and the others
just fought Gouging Inferno...
They’ve already used
their Terastal Orbs.
What will they do now?
Rematch time!
I’m fired up!
How ‘bout you, Achigator?!
We’re more prepared
to fight it now!
Let’s go for it, Welcamo!
Pagogo’s desire... Everyone’s desires...
Let’s pass them on together,
Nyarote!
Liko, Roy, Dot.
I’ll back you up with all I’ve got.
Lizardon!
You can leave Terapagos to me.
Now, let’s give it a wallop!
Yeah!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Crossing Beyond the Rainbow's Glow
Spread out across the battlefield!
I’ll draw Rekkuuza’s attention!
Right!
What are they planning to do?
Hey, hey!
Heya! Over here!
Lizardon!
Now!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Tebrim! Mind Power!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
Welcamo! Nakanuchan!
Aqua Break! Slam!
All right!
Perfectly in sync!
Don’t let up, guys! Let’s go!
Right!
Lizardon, fire an Air Slash barrage!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
Flamethrower!
My word... They’re taking advantage of
the bowl-shaped terrain to land hits from multiple angles.
Nice one, Nyarote!
Even when we do hit,
we barely deal damage...
Incoming! Watch out!
Dodge it, Lizardon!
Not gonna fall for
the same trick twice, I guess.
We can’t hit it all the way up there!
Roy! Change of plans!
Let’s try the soaking-wet strat
that worked in the Gouging Inferno fight!
The soaking-wet strat...
But do you think it’ll let us
soak it just like that?
We’ll use this waterfall.
If we break these rocks,
plenty of water should pour down!
That...
...just might work!
Taikaiden!
Get us high up!
Flamethrower!
We’re not through yet!
This’ll clinch it!
Flamethrower!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Welcamo! Aqua Cutter!
Counting on you, Cap!
Voltteccer!
We did it!
Dragon Tail?!
Lizardon!
Cap!
Taikaiden!
Dot!
Ah!
Oh no!
Welcamo! Nakanuchan!
Return...
I saved Cap!
Lizardon...
Thanks, Roy.
You helped us out big time.
Take a good, long rest.
Taikaiden, fly up high!
Tebrim! Brutal Swing!
Follow up with Mind Power!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Taikaiden! Spark!
So close!
Dot! He’s not done yet!
Achigator?!
Did he...?
Good work, Achigator!
Make sure it hears your soul!
Charm Voice!
It was super effective!
Nice one, Roy!
Thanks for the assist, Liko!
Amazing...
They’re fighting so well,
even up against Rekkuuza...
Another Dragon Meteor Shower...
Then, just like last time...
Tebrim, use Brutal—
Tebrim!
Taikaiden!
No way...
Pagogo!
Can’t letcha forget about us, now!
Cap!
Rising Voltteccer!
Direct hit!
Don’t tell me...
Cap!
Guess that’s that.
You put on a cool show, Cap.
Tebrim, Nyarote... Thank you.
Thanks, Taikaiden. Rest up.
All we have left is Roy’s Achigator...
Let’s go, Achigator!
We can still fight!
Flamethrower!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Roy hasn’t given up.
I don’t want to give up, either.
I still really, really, really
want to keep battling Rekkuuza!
Pagogo!
You want to fight by my side?
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
So, Pagogo’s moves are...
Okay.
Primal Power!
Ooh! It’s super effective!
Charm Voice!
Pagogo! Protect!
Primal Power!
Flamethrower!
Pagogo!
Achigator!
Liko, Roy...
You can do this!
Rekkuuza’s taking damage, too.
All the attacks we’ve been landing
are definitely adding up!
Yeah.
Both sides are nearly out of stamina.
Everything’s riding on the next hit!
Here it comes...
Draconic Masterstroke!
Pagogo! Tera Cluster!
Achigator...
...Terastallized!
What the...?
It shared its own Terastal energy
with Achigator?
This phenomenon is entirely new to me!
Terapagos is truly intriguing!
Let’s end this, Achigator!
Nitro Charge!
Now!
I-I did it!
I caught the black Rekkuuza!
I did it, Achigator!
Congrats, Roy.
Great going!
Roy... Your dream came true!
Thanks!
I owe it to all of you!
Rekkuuza...
Pagogo!
Now it’s met up with all of the Six Heroes,
and seems to have gotten its full power back.
I’m so happy...
I’m so happy for you, Pagogo!
Oh! There they are!
Don’t get separated from us now,
when we’ve come so far!
Let us welcome the fruition
of our dreams in unison.
We’ve made it, Pagogo!
It’s Rakua!
Rystal-san, Lucius... and even Gibeon.
All of them were there.
They all looked so happy together.
Rekkuuza wanted to be
reunited with all of them, too...
In that memory with Rekkuuza...
It was with Lucius
and all his companions.
I could really tell
how much it trusted them!
It’s been hoping to go to Rakua
with Pagogo and the Six Heroes...
It’s been hoping to fulfill
its promise with Lucius...
The Six Heroes have assembled.
Now, we just need to get to Rakua.
Let’s get back to the ship
and talk strategy!
Yeah!
Okay...
Return, Rekkuuza!
Huh?
It’s not listening to me...
The black Rekkuuza belongs to Lucius.
It might not feel ready to
approve of you as its partner just yet.
Huh?! You gotta be kidding...
Roy...
But still! It did go in the ball,
so I know it approves of me at least a bit!
I’m gonna really push myself, so that I can be
your real partner someday, Rekkuuza!
What happened?
Is it saying “Follow me” or something?
Maybe it’s going to guide us to Rakua?
There’s only one place Rekkuuza
would want to take us!
Let’s hurry and set sail, guys!
Don’t worry about me.
Go on ahead.
Briar-san...
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much!
You’ve shown me
such marvelous things.
I’m confident I can write
a worthy book on Terapagos now.
Stay well, everyone!
Hmph! This ain’t no fun.
Time to head back.
We need to report to Gibeon-sama.
An e-mail from Liko!
“We’re heading to Rakua right now.
“My adventure, which began with
the pendant Grandma gave me...”
I simply can’t wait to see
what we’ll discover next!
Liko...
Mother... Father...
I’m heading out!
There’s so, so much I want
to tell you about when I get back!
I finally battled the black Rekkuuza,
and got it to approve of me just a bit!
I’m gonna get even stronger,
and become a trainer worthy of Rekkuuza!
By going out, I’ve run into so many new ideas
and exciting things by being with everyone.
I dunno how to put it
into words, Mom, but...
Right now, I’m having tons of fun!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I’ll think of you
Someday, let’s shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow’s glow
I found my dream
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
this Pokémon, Terapagos.
A Pokémon still very much
shrouded in mystery.
Terapagos
Terastal Pokémon
Type: Normal
Terapagos
Terastal Pokémon
Type: Normal
Height
0.3m
Its appearance changes
when it battles!
Weight
16.0kg
But do you know
what that Forme is called?
This form is called the "what" Forme?
Terastal
Tera Type
Crystal
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
This form is called the "what" Forme?
A: Terastal
The answer is A: Terastal Forme!
It makes the distinctive shell it bears
by crystallizing Terastal energy.
Next episode
Are you ready, Zir?
Yeah. Naturally, Conia.
We’re going to sneak into Exceed,
and expose Spinel-sama’s secrets!
If anyone figures out
we’re doing something so scandalous...
Isn’t that why
we’re wearing these disguises?
But don’t you look
more suspicious in that?
Hey, your getup is just as—
What are you doing?
Hurry up and go.
Amethio-sama!
To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Truth is Revealed? Amethio’s Resolve!
Be sure not to miss it.
The Truth is Revealed? Amethio's Resolve!