The Rising Voltteccers
have obtained the black Rekkuuza,
and Terapagos has awakened.
They are currently on the move,
with all Six Heroes in tow.
Most likely, they...
...will be headed for Rakua.
The time has come.
Then we must move as well.
Yes. We will ambush them in Rakua.
Spinel.
Sir.
I will need your intellect.
I expect great things from you.
I desire nothing more than to display
my utter devotion to you, Gibeon-sama.
Everyone, I bid you to
meet up on location posthaste.
Pampered little Amethio’s
gettin’ left out again?
He could provide
more firepower, at least.
Have you forgotten?
He’s been taken off missions.
We have enough firepower
between the four of us.
Agreed.
Well, not like ya can lose
with Sango on your side, anyhow!
Enhancing your future with your Pokémon.
Leave it in Exceed’s hands.
H-Hi!
Is this it?
Yes.
This is Spinel’s lab.
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Truth is Revealed? Amethio's Resolve!
The black Rekkuuza appeared before us.
We all worked together,
and fought it using everything we’ve learned...
Until finally, Rekkuuza went into
Roy’s Ancient Monster Ball...
Pagogo recovered its powers too,
and Lucius’s Six Heroes have reunited at last!
It seems like Rekkuuza
is going to take us to Rakua!
Pagogo looks so happy!
It did seem to be good pals
with Rekkuuza, after all.
I’m so jealous!
I wanna ride it too!
Now we just have to let Rekkuuza
show us the way...
But we’ve gotta be careful
to make sure the Explorers don’t catch on.
Since they’re after the Rakurium,
we can’t let them anywhere near Rakua.
Really, though...
Rakurium draws out a Pokémon’s power,
but makes them all vicious, right?
Forcing that on them...
It makes me sick.
Yeah. Those poor Pokémon!
There’s one thing that bugs me.
I just can’t figure out why they would’ve
named Rakurium “The Eternal Blessing.”
Rystal-san mentioned that!
Gibeon said the Rakurium had
“eternal possibilities.”
Eternal... Forever...
You mean like never-ending?
Just a thought, but...
What if Rakurium
activates the cells in your body?
Huh?
What do you mean?
Well, you see, living creatures like us...
We’re made out of lots of
these invisibly tiny cells.
Every day, when you eat food and snacks,
you use those nutrients...
...to create new cells
and replace old ones.
That’s the way the body maintains itself;
through gaining and losing cells.
That’s amazing!
How strange...
For example...
Y’know how Roy and Achigator
are always getting injured?
We just get so wrapped up in training...
But even when you get scratches or cuts,
they’re all healed up in a week’s time.
That’s the same thing.
It’s because your skin cells
have been born anew.
That’s a doctor for ya!
Super informative!
Maybe Rakurium continually
gives you a strong, fresh body...
...by forcibly activating
the replacement of cells.
I get it. The plants rapidly growing
and withering in Rakua...
That must’ve been due to their cells
being reborn too fast.
People and Pokémon
wouldn’t be as susceptible as plants,
but it’s sure to be dangerous.
If Gibeon used the Rakurium
on himself, with Exceed’s tech...
Then... Gibeon’s still alive?!
A truly venerable companion
of the Ancient Adventurer, then.
Guess it’s not someone else
using the same name.
So Amethio’s grandfather
really did travel with Lucius and Rystal...
But if they’ve already got Rakurium,
they’ve got no reason to go to Rakua, right?
Since Rakurium is a material substance,
they’ll only have so much of it.
In which case, they must need
a larger amount, right...?
Do you think there’s still
Rakurium left in Rakua?
Hmm... Well, that depends on
what condition Rakua’s in...
Lucius worked together with the Six Heroes
and Pagogo to protect Rakua, right?
Pagogo gave its energy
to the Six Heroes,
and put up a barrier
by amplifying its powers.
Considering the effects of Rakurium
haven’t been seen around the world,
I suppose we can assume
they were successful in sealing it up.
On the other hand, that means
the Rakurium could still be in there.
I don’t know the specifics.
What exactly do we do if we find
something that dangerous in Rakua?
You kids aren’t scared at all.
Yep! Just think, we get to go
where Lucius and the others went: Rakua!
Alongside Pagogo,
the Six Heroes, and all of you!
It’s so exciting!
I wanna know what it’s like already!
I wanna see!
Guess we’ve been overthinking things.
The reason we’re going to Rakua is to bring
Pagogo and friends there, anyway.
Anything we’re not sure about
can wait ‘til after we get there!
Mm-hmm.
Let us return to the basics.
We adventure just for the excitement.
We try stuff just for the thrill!
Can’t lose sight of that.
We’ve got no idea what could happen...
And there’s bound to be
great dangers ahead...
But together,
we can overcome them all!
Let’s give it all we got!
Yeah!
What... is that?
Rakurium.
It draws out a Pokémon’s power
and turns them vicious.
Spinel used it on his Blacky.
That’s just cowardly!
“Beta version”...
So that wasn’t even finished?!
Why would he research
something like this?
“Rakurium Spheres”...?
Hey! What’s the meaning of this?!
Spinel... Agate...
You arrived rather quickly.
We had already been preparing
at our observation post.
How is your body doing?
It is holding up well.
Perhaps my body, too, is unable to restrain
its elation at the Rakurium I will soon possess.
For the Explorers to prosper evermore...
Gibeon-sama, it’s crucial you live
another hundred—no, two hundred years...
No, you must live eternally!
It’s taken so very long...
The seal upon Rakua
will lift in short order.
My dream will be fulfilled.
Amethio-sama!
I really think we should force our way out!
They took our Monster Balls!
What’re we supposed to do?
This won’t hold me!
Use your head a little!
What, you got a better plan?!
I’m working on one!
Don’t fret. Quiet down.
So he saw through my plans...
Locking Amethio-sama
in a place like this is shameless!
We need to bring this
straight to Director Crave!
No. My father likely
knows nothing of this.
Huh?
This has nothing to do with Exceed.
They took us all the way
to a warehouse by the port...
...because they don’t want my father
to know of our actions.
Those guards were
under Spinel’s influence...
U-Um...
Why would Spinel-sama
go so far as to—
Shh!
You took your time.
Huh?
I’ve come to retrieve you.
Welcome back!
I’m glad you’re okay!
I apologize for failing you...
Soublades, Armorgaw.
I see you’ve acted
quite recklessly once again.
And yet you came here,
expecting this could happen.
I’m sure we share the same suspicions.
About Spinel-sama, you mean.
Spinel intends to betray Grandfather.
Huh?!
Gibeon-sama?!
I see you have indeed
conducted your own research.
Tell me, Hamber!
What is this “Rakurium”
that Grandfather and Spinel seek?
What happened between
Grandfather and Lucius?
I wish to be able to help
my grandfather... to help Gibeon-sama!
To do that, I must know everything,
and I must ask myself...
Who am I?
What must I do?
Amethio-sama...
There is no point in lingering here any longer.
Let us go someplace else.
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
What’s wrong? Hurry up.
N-No!
We will wait for you right here!
I want you to hear this with me.
S-Sir!
H-Hi!
My mother.
When I was young...
she died in a traffic accident.
Ah...
Hold your condolences.
I was too young to even remember it.
Hamber was a worthy
stand-in for a parent.
Ah, thank you.
Don’t mind if I do...
Amethio-sama, I presume you are
already familiar with some of this...
...but allow me to explain
everything from the start.
Everything I tell you now
comes straight from Gibeon-sama.
One hundred years ago, Gibeon-sama formed
the Explorers alongside Lucius and Rystal.
They traveled in search of Rakua.
Gibeon-sama believed Lucius
to be his closest friend.
They both nurtured dreams of enriching
the world of Pokémon and people.
However...
At Rakua, the two of them
became divided over Rakurium.
Lucius did not understand
the value of Rakurium...
...and was opposed to its use,
even knowing of Gibeon-sama’s noble aim.
Even Zygarde made an attempt
to seal away the Rakurium.
But why?
Zygarde is Grandfather’s Pokémon.
Rekkuuza—that is to say,
Lucius—told it to.
That man betrayed Gibeon-sama.
No way...
While in Rakua, Gibeon-sama lost a friend,
as well as many of his partner Zygarde’s Cells.
Zygarde’s “Cells”?
Zygarde is a Pokémon composed of a Core,
which serves as its brain,
and a great number of
units referred to as Cells.
That’s from Grandfather’s...
Yes. One of its Cells.
For some strange reason,
it’s taken a liking to me.
So I keep it with me,
as you can see.
Perhaps it’s a sign
that Grandfather trusts you.
You are much too kind...
Lucius aligned his fate with Rakua’s...
Whereas Gibeon-sama was caught in
Rakua’s collapse, his very life endangered.
And yet he survived,
thanks to the power of Rakurium.
Rakurium...
Just what exactly is it?
It draws out the latent power of Pokémon,
and should perhaps be thought of as a source of life.
Depending on how it is applied,
Gibeon-sama discovered that it may even
maintain a person’s youth for an extended time.
And that is Grandfather’s secret.
His heart broken, Gibeon-sama retrieved
a small sample of Rakurium and fled from Rakua.
Invested in the future of Pokémon
all around the world,
he founded Exceed
and has continually researched Rakurium.
He alone carried on the name of the Explorers,
and has endured one hundred years of loneliness.
I have served the noble Gibeon-sama
in what meager ways I can.
What led you to follow
Grandfather, Hamber?
Gratitude...
...and respect.
When I was wandering blind,
and my path as an adventurer was muddled,
Gibeon-sama had the grace to guide me.
Your path, huh...?
Pokémon and people...
His noble aim, wishing eternally for their prosperity,
left a profound impression upon me.
I see.
So that’s why you took up
teaching duties in the Explorers.
Huh?
Is that true?
Amethio-sama, followed by Sango-sama,
Onyx-sama, and Agate-sama...
I coached each of them in turn.
Spinel-sama, however,
is the sole exception.
He was an Exceed researcher
who garnered special approval from Gibeon-sama.
At present, they are working
in tandem with one another.
Spinel intends to monopolize
the Rakurium.
He’s using Grandfather,
and plans to steal the Rakurium at Rakua.
This is kind of... a little...
Yeah, it’s heavier than I expected...
I won’t let Spinel have his way.
Soublades.
You’ve always been by my side,
ever since you were a Carbou.
Hamber’s strict training,
and the Explorers’ grueling missions...
You’ve helped me overcome them all.
I’m counting on you, Soublades.
I’m going to Rakua.
I will save Grandfather.
Zir, Conia...
Seems I needn’t even ask.
My Saidon’s drill will pulverize
anyone who dares get in your way!
My Golduck’s ready to rumble
for you, too!
The Rising Voltteccers will arrive
at Rakua in short order, as well.
The girl with the Terapagos, Liko...
We’ve discovered she is
a descendant of Lucius and Rystal.
Huh?!
You don’t seem surprised.
Somehow, I suspected
that might be the case.
Perhaps you could call it destiny,
reaching across a hundred years’ time...
Destiny, you say...?
I’ve decided to take up my Grandfather’s will,
but I don’t intend to fight in his stead.
As for who I am...
I am myself,
and that’s all I need to know.
I will ensure nobody
suspects our movements.
You may count on me.
Apologies for
the constant fuss, Hamber.
Forgive my recklessness,
just this once.
It is simply who you are,
Amethio-sama.
Everyone... Good luck.
Now, to Rakua!
Is that...?
Friede!
Are we there?!
Is that Rakua?!
Where?! Where?!
That place over there is Kumuri Town.
People live there, and Pokémon too.
It’d show up on any old world map.
So it’s... not Rakua?
Right. Doesn’t seem like “Rakua”
was a past name for it, either...
It just flew off...
I know! Rakua’ll be through there!
Friede! Catch up to it, quick!
Sure! Leave it to me!
Orio! We’re climbing to the top
of that mountain, full speed ahead!
Yeah!
No way! No way, no how!
What are ya, an amateur?!
If you go above the ship’s max safe altitude,
it’ll be blown to bits!
Okay... Slow and steady
does the trick.
First, let’s land at the town
in the foothills.
Then we’ll head for
what lies above those clouds!
Rakua...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Grasping Pokémon, Yonoir.
It is said to suck up wandering souls
and take them to the world beyond.
Yonoir
Grasping Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Yonoir
Grasping Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Height
2.2m
Weight
106.6kg
But do you know which body part
it uses to suck up souls?
Which body part sucks up souls?
Its eye
Its hands
Its belly
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Which body part sucks up souls?
C: Its belly
The answer is C: Its belly.
It swallows a targeted foe whole
with the mouth on its belly.
It’s said to suck out just the soul,
then spit out the leftover body before departing.
Next episode
Well, the black Rekkuuza showed us
the way here, but now what...?
Rakua’s bound to be
just beyond this place!
You think it’ll be that easy to find...?
Wha—?! The black Rekkuuza’s
a bad omen? What do you mean?!
Wild Vibrava are coming after us!
To be mind-blowingly continued!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters...
The Place Where Heaven and Earth Meet
Huh? Nobody told me
there’d be mountain hiking!
The Place Where Heaven and Earth Meet