We are the Rising Voltteccers.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos, we’ve traveled far...
...and have finally arrived
in the Paldea Region.
At the town we visited,
Roy and I came face to face with...
...a duo from the Explorers!
Why did they suddenly show up?
We’d heard that suspicious people
were seen on an uninhabited island nearby,
but all this gives me
an uneasy feeling in my chest...
Is that it?
I’m heading back to the ship.
Everyone, gather in the meeting room.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
The Plan to Capture Rekkuuza
I’ve confirmed there’s a suspicious building
on the island near the Hakkou City port.
It’s just like the Snap Kids’ photos!
And I also saw these...
That man...
He stole my pendant in Hakkou City!
So it’s the Explorers...
What’re they trying to do?
Sango said they were going to
“summon Rekkuuza”...
They must be planning to
lure it in somehow and catch it.
I’m not letting them have
the black Rekkuuza!
If they’re using a machine,
Cap’s electric attacks can destroy it.
Rushing in there is the quickest solution.
I’ll try and put together
a shutdown program, just in case.
What’s that?
Something that can take down
any system it’s thrown at.
I’ll never forgive that creep...
Got it. Go for it, Dot.
But we don’t know
when they’ll make their move.
I’m ready to charge in anytime.
But if we roll up in the airship,
they’ll probably spot us.
Even if you have
Lizardon drop you off...
They’ll know I’m coming.
Gramps, get a boat ready.
Mm-hmm.
We’ll land on the opposite coast.
I wanna go, too!
Me, too!
It’s too dangerous.
You two—
Yeah, all right.
Everyone else will wait on the ship.
But get ready to take off
at a moment’s notice.
Okay!
Careful not to make a sound.
Doesn’t look like anyone lives here.
Yeah.
Hogator! Quiet!
Seems like they’re
not used to humans.
Let’s get a move on.
Shh!
All right. There’s no lookouts.
It’s open?
That can’t be right...
You wait out here.
If anyone shows up...
Battle them, right?
Gramps,
you look after these two.
Mm-hmm.
They’re in my care.
Now, let’s get in there!
It won’t open!
Friede! Friede!
Looks like the others
missed out on your little trap.
No matter.
Mere children...
...are no threat to us once we’ve
set our minds on something.
That voice...
So you finally show your face,
Mr. Awfully Shy.
Welcome, Professor Friede.
I have been awaiting you.
I anticipated the possibility
of Sango leaking our plans.
This place was
built to imprison you.
So you also anticipated
that I’d come here.
Liko! Roy!
This is the wrong place!
Keep looking around!
Huh? Friede!
What does that mean?!
Are you okay?
Calm yourselves.
Friede’s duty is now
to save himself from his predicament.
Ours is to trust in him
and continue onward.
He said this was the wrong place.
Yeah. Let’s keep looking around!
Just where are the Explorers?
Where will they summon Rekkuuza?
Is that thing really
gonna get Rekkuuza to turn up?
This is a total drag...
And anyway,
where’s our pampered li’l Amethio?
Fashionably late?
We will execute the plan without him.
It was Spinel’s idea.
Oho! Poor guy, he’s missing out!
Spinel does hate
that pampered kid.
Totally cracks me up!
No more idle chatter.
Get back in position.
Fine, geez! You’re such a pain!
It’s close.
A resonance generator?
Yes.
I analyzed the accumulated data...
...and recreated the energy
Terapagos emits when calling to Rekkuuza.
Even if you can call it,
do you really think you can beat it?
Three skilled Explorers
are on the job.
They will bring it down.
That’s a surprise.
Didn’t peg you as the type to ask for help.
Don’t be ridiculous.
I am simply using them.
I shall acquire the black Rekkuuza
without even fighting it.
Blacky!
Not if I can help it!
In this confined space,
you cannot make use of Lizardon’s flight.
Nor a Terastallized rampage.
So you anticipated all of this, huh?
A Pikachu? You’re toying with me.
I’ve heard the same thing
from someone else before.
You’re gonna regret it.
Blacky! Bark Out!
Don’t let it faze you, Cap!
Shadow Clones!
Thunder Punch!
Reflector!
Keep it up! Shadow Clones!
Wipe them out!
Lightning Speed!
Meet it with a Thunder Punch!
Foul Play.
Cap!
Now, what to do next?
Wanna try for it?
There’s nobody here.
Maybe they’re not on the island.
If they’re close by,
maybe... Hakkou City?
Let’s check it out.
But without any clues
on where to look...
Terapagos?
What?
That way...?
Is there something...
at that lighthouse?
Liko!
Yeah. This feeling...
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Electric Netting your eyes!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
It’s time for “Whatchagot TV”!
And in store today,
we’ve got...
Huh?
What is that?
Rekkuuza...
We need to hurry!
Let’s go full speed ahead! Nuoh!
Hydro Pump!
It has let its guard down,
just as Spinel predicted.
Commence the plan.
Awright! Onigohri, use Blizzard!
Kyojiohn! Salt Pickling!
Even a Legendary Pokémon can’t defend from
surprise attacks that exploit its weaknesses.
Join in, Charem. Psyche Beam.
Rekkuuza’s...
...in trouble!
Liko, look!
They’re using that machine
to lure Rekkuuza in!
We have to tell the others!
Understood.
So if we don’t stop that device...
...Rekkuuza’s in danger.
I finished the shutdown program!
Dot!
But it can’t do anything from here.
I’d have to connect
to that machine directly.
I’m not sure if I can do it,
but if I need to...
I’ll go.
Wh—?! It— It’s too dangerous!
I can’t just let you—
Liko and Roy
are out there fighting!
I... I can do it, too!
Dot!
All right, got it!
We’ll take you there!
Everybody, get in position!
Okay!
Seems the black Rekkuuza
has shown itself.
Cap!
Blacky, use Foul Play.
We’re not done yet!
Foul Play.
Are you just stalling for time?
This battle’s going nowhere.
Correct. You are powerless here.
You cannot even hope to escape.
Don’t give up, Cap! Keep at it!
Your struggling
will amount to nothing.
That should be enough, Cap!
Voltteccer!
Blacky, use Reflector!
Sorry for wrecking the place.
My Foul Plays, meant to turn
Pikachu’s strength against it...
Yeah, I turned ‘em
right back on you.
Lizardon!
You showed some real grit, Cap.
Is that the place?
Hightail it, Lizardon!
Interesting.
Perhaps he is deserving of
further study.
The victor is clear.
Hold it!
Stop!
Huh?! Those brats...!
They sure took their time.
The black Rekkuuza will be ours.
Dot!
We’ll make sure she gets there!
Hogator! Stomping Tantrum!
So ill-behaved. Kyojiohn!
Nyahoja! Lightning Speed!
Running circles around us...
Oh no you don’t!
Go, Kaiden!
Use Spark!
Charem, use Psyche Beam.
Kaiden!
That was awesome, Kaiden! Thanks!
Rest up.
This is a total drag!
Quit getting in our way!
That jerk...
Friede!
Sorry for the wait, you guys!
We’re here!
Wh-What?
Ow...
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
Kanuchan, use Slam!
Charem, dodge it.
Where’s the connection port?
There!
Go, Rotom!
What?
All set.
How dare you?
Kuwassu! Kanuchan!
Dot!
We did it, Kuwassu! Kanuchan!
There, there.
That must’ve been scary...
Return, Kanuchan.
Dot!
You did it!
That was awesome!
This has taken a bad turn.
Charem, use Mind Headbutt!
This is crazy!
Not good!
I’m pulling us out for now!
You! Don’t even think
about screwing with us!
Stop! Don’t pursue it!
I’ll blow ya to bits!
Onigohri, Self-Destruct!
My word...
No way...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Meditation Pokémon, Charem.
Charem
Meditation Pokémon
Type: Fighting/Psychic
Charem
Meditation Pokémon
Type: Fighting/Psychic
Charem, a Pokémon that harnesses
psycho-power through its elegant movements.
Height
1.3m
Weight
31.5kg
Do you know what it does on the regular
to train its psycho-power?
What does it do to train its psychic powers?
Work out
Yoga
Battle
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! This'll be a snap!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it do to train
its psychic powers?
B: Yoga
What does it do to train
its psychic powers?
B: Yoga
The answer is... B: Yoga!
It often meditates for a whole month
without even eating.
That yoga training is what gives it
its fierce psycho-powers!
Every expert’s expertise
is the result of all their past efforts!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
What a disaster!
The Brave Asagi...!
Is everyone okay in there?!
But still... the black Rekkuuza is
right before Liko and Roy’s very eyes!
It’s now or never!
All they can do is work together and fight!
And as if they weren’t in enough trouble already,
Amethio shows up, too! Now what?!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Having Come So Far
Something’s gonna happen!
Don’t you miss it!