All okay getting here?
Yes. It’s unlikely that I was seen.
Hurry inside!
Mm-hm.
Thank you for joining in
on this operation, Amethio.
Hamber’s told me much of
what’s going on.
In order to fully employ Terapagos’s power
and erase the Rakurium Core,
you need the power
of eighteen Terastypes?
Yeah.
And that’s just one more reason
we have to rescue the Six Heroes!
So, you found out
where the Six Heroes are?
I had Zir and Conia
search from the inside.
They learned that five of the Six Heroes had been returned
to Explorers HQ, and kept under tight control since.
Explorers HQ...
Smack-dab in the middle of
our good ol’ enemy’s base, huh?
Spinel is at Exceed.
If we’re to strike, now’s the time.
Plus, we’ve no idea when or if
they’ll be moved to another facility...
Then we have no time to waste.
There’s one thing we learned
when we fought the Six Heroes before.
Even under the effect of the Super Strong Spheres,
the Six Heroes never fought amongst themselves.
One would expect them
to attack indiscriminately...
Maybe it’s because deep down, they all still share
the bond they formed as Lucius’s friends?
Meaning we can still save them!
But... If they end up losing that bond
due to continued use of the Strong Spheres...
This might be our last chance, then!
We cannot afford to hesitate.
Are you prepared to do this?
Yeah!
Let’s start with a strategy meeting!
Regarding the building’s interior...
There are sentries and security cameras
placed at the entrances and along passageways,
keeping close watch site-wide.
We must proceed with caution.
I stepped out upon a question with no answer
pOCket Monsters
Rising Again
Starting a story from here, a place nobody knows, sends the message
That even if I take detours, I still took the shortest route
Tucking fear and excitement away in my pocket, I ran straight over
Let me hear about all of your tears
This adventure can’t be overcome alone
We will go beyond where the wind points
The iolite connected by meeting you
resonated in the midst of battle
Having you by my side was all I needed
To feel like I could walk anywhere
The answer is inside of me
The world has always been in my hands
Having you there for me was all I needed
To make my heart leap with joy
Storm In! Explorers HQ
If we maintain this course,
we should get there before dawn.
We can put the plan into action
before sunrise!
So just leave everything to us until then,
and get some sleep while you can.
Right.
I whipped you up some grub,
so make sure that you eat, too.
Thank you!
We’re counting on you, kids!
Right!
Yeah... This should be doable.
It’ll be okay!
What is it?
Carbou...?
Ah, you wanted to put that on?
That must be hard to move in...
You’re quite fond of it, huh?
Feel free, then.
What’s up with you,
just hangin’ around out there?
You can head in here if ya want.
No. I’m fine where I am.
‘Kay.
Back then, on that day,
a storm was raging...
But now, it’s calm.
Huh? I mean, if there’s clear days,
of course there’s gonna be rainy days, too.
So these are the sights
the Rising Voltteccers saw...
I see... You have such freedom.
I don’t really get it...
But I’ve taken a mega-liking
to those guys.
So I’m gonna trust you, too,
since they approve of you and all.
How are things on your end?
We’re good to go any time.
Let’s hurry and do this!
No issues here, either.
Okay! Everyone’s ready to go.
Let’s begin!
That’s...
Amethio?!
Address him with “-sama,”
you insolent fool!
This is the entrance!
Requesting urgent backup!
We’re facing
the former Explorer, Amethio!
Psycho Cutter!
First, I’ll provide
a distraction from the front.
While security’s attention
is focused on me,
you can storm in from above.
And here we are!
Over there!
Awright!
Oh no you don’t!
So Amethio was acting
as a decoy down below!
Let’s go!
Let’s do it!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Mega Evolve!
Lucario!
Time to cut loose, Yamirami!
That’ll be the second distraction.
If one wishes to trick
the ever-strategic Spinel...
...one needs to out-scheme the schemer.
We’ve got the best odds of success.
Only admins have access to the underground floor
where the Six Heroes are being held...
With one exception: The freight elevator
in the rear goes down to that level.
However...
Seems like they’re busy elsewhere.
There it is!
He did say it was normally locked...
So far, everything’s gone as expected.
So?
I’ll need a bit of time to crack it,
but it should be doable!
What should be doable?
The Explorers!
So they even predicted this...
Bohmander!
Flamethrower!
Masquernya!
Carbou!
What is that?
An eyesore!
Strong Spheres!
Carbou alone won’t cut it!
Welcamo, let’s go!
Wait!
Amethio!
I completed my task.
Spinel’s hand-reared pets?
You traitor!
We’ll eliminate you!
Who was the real traitor here?!
I’ve always followed a single path!
All right... This is my chance!
Now where did it get
that stubbornness from, I wonder?
You want to fight alongside
Soublades, don’t you?
Let’s go!
pOCket Monsters
Rising Again
Bohmander! Attack!
Avoid it, Soublades!
Carbou, dodge!
Not yet, Bohmander! Hold on!
Hide inside the armor!
Carbou, are you okay?!
Soublades! Shadow Claw!
The Reversed Scale isn’t stopping?
Yet another of
the Strong Spheres’ powers...
We’ve got them!
Bohmander, attack!
Carbou!
Follow it up with Ember!
It can fire them that rapidly?
Yeah, thanks to its training!
But they’re not strong enough!
Soublades, hang in there!
What a weakling.
Tch... Is that its ability,
Breaking Armor?
I’ve waited for this moment!
Soublades! Shadow Claw!
Not so fast! Bohmander!
Continue attacking!
Now, while it’s confused...
Carbou! Take Down!
It used the armor
to reduce the recoil...
Fantastic!
Great thinking, Carbou!
A worthless effort...
Get up, Bohmander!
Raise your power!
Dragon Dance...
Here they come! Be ready!
Keep going!
If this continues...
Amethio... Together, now!
Carbou, together with Soublades...
Soublades, alongside Carbou...
Combine your strength!
Ember!
Psycho Cutter!
They make a good team!
Yes. But...
They’re already nearing their limits.
In that case... Carbou!
Use Fire Vortex on the both of you!
What?!
You’re using Fire Vortex
for defense?!
That’s some incredible stuff...
But...
Yeah! Right now,
I’ve gotta stay focused on my job...
Now, if we can wait for the Bohmander
to tire themselves out...
An insipid plan.
Bohmander! Take flight!
You’re defenseless!
Bohmander!
Attack!
Now you have nowhere to run!
We have nowhere to run...
...and neither do you!
You mean that you lured us in...
...in order to nullify our speed?!
Carbou!
Put all your strength into it!
Muster all you have!
Soublades!
What’s going on in there?!
It doesn’t matter!
Keep giving orders!
Bohmander! Attack!
Ember!
Psycho Cutter!
Carbou...
...has evolved into Guren'arma?
Amazing...
You’re amazing, Guren'arma!
It decided to evolve now?!
Bohmander!
Get up!
Attack them!
Give it up! The winner is clear.
Look at the state
of your Bohmander!
As if we care!
Strong Spheres grant us
the justice that is victory!
Amethio. We need to stop
the Bohmander ourselves.
Understood.
Soublades! Ghost Dive!
Attack!
Clear Smog!
The effects of Dragon Dance...!
Follow up by finishing it off!
Sword of Regrets!
Dodge it!
You’re open!
No!
Guren'arma!
Give me your best Ember!
What was that?
Armor Cannon...
Seems it’s learned that.
Guren'arma...!
Yes. Understood.
You really gave it your all!
You were so cool!
Now you can take a nice, long rest.
Thank you, Amethio and Soublades.
It’s because of you that
Guren'arma was able to exert its strength.
It demonstrated its own skill
by utilizing Soublades’s flames.
You’ve raised it to be strong.
You did well.
Rest now, Soublades.
Liko!
Congrats on the evolution!
That was an incredible battle.
Thank you.
And I managed to unlock the door.
That’s good news.
Hey!
Everyone!
You’re okay?
‘Course!
But the amount of dudes we had to fight was nuts.
Yamirami ended up going down.
Along with Lucario and Cap.
Thank you.
You have my thanks, too.
You’ve opened up my path.
We should be thanking you, Amethio!
The plan was a success.
Yes.
Zir. Conia. We’re about to head down
to the underground floor.
Watch the back of the building,
just in case things go wrong.
Sir!
Zir-san! Conia-san!
Thanks to you guys, too!
Guru— Ack!
I’m not worthy of your praise!
Let’s go.
So this is it...
I can’t really see much...
Basagiri!
We came to rescue you!
We’ll get you out of this somehow!
Everybody!
Where are you?!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Brutal Pokémon, Samehada!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Brutal Pokémon
Evil
Samehada
Brutal Pokémon
Water
Evil
Rough Skin
Samehada
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Brutal Pokémon
Rough Skin
Samehada
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Brutal Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
The time has come
Even if I tried to count, I couldn't put a number to it
Asleep or awake
We're together forever, taratta!
How 'bout we postpone that doughnut dessert to next time?
This is the big 1, gotta make up our minds
Let's go meet up with the kids
who are walking along the railroad tracks
I simply can't wait
Even when I'm scared, my heart's still thumping from excitement
Asleep or awake
We'll be together forever!
Let's go on an adventure
I bet we'll snag 1st place
Just 1 more time, yeah, in 1 great, big
"What if?" story
Where I'm just a caterpillar
and you Fly high above
Just 1 more time, just 1 more time, and
we can become friends
Let's go on an adventure
I bet we'll snag 1st place
Just 1 more time, yeah, with 1 great, big
squeeze of kindness
The best kind of things
I bet aren't listed in the Index
I wanna see them with you, yeah, time and time again
break 'em down and remake 'em
OK!
Welcome back future, come on back soon
Let's do a super cool Encore
C'mon, sing it with me
Forever until the end, taratta!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
The spikes sprouting from its head
are transformed fangs!
Mega Samehada
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Brutal Pokémon
Water
Evil
Speed Boost
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Even if they’re injured or broken off,
they’ll grow back again and again!
The yellow pattern on its body
shows all the scars it’s received in battle!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It’sh got exploshive propulsion power
that letsh it momentarily exceed 200 km/h—
Waah!
Next episode
What do we do?
We’ve all been separated...
All of those guys were waitin’ for us!
And now we have to battle
the Six Heroes again?!
That wretched Spinel...
He planned all this?!
It’ll be okay!
Liko...
Even if we can’t see each other, we’re still together.
We’ve all come here for one goal!
Right! Let’s show ‘em
the fruits of our training!
This is our last chance!
Yeah! We’ll accomplish this together!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Get Back the Six Heroes!
Let’s go!
Yeah!