The Rising Voltteccers, a band of adventurers
led by Friede, continue their journey.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we set off for Paldea.
H-H-Hold on, Kanuchan!
Where are you going?
What’s wrong, Kanuchan?
Who’s that? Gah, I’ll look later!
Kanuchan, don’t cry!
Ooh, it says she read it!
But she’s ignoring me?!
“What’s wrong?!”
“You there?!”
“You just read my message!”
H-H-H-Hey! Don’t you dare
make a hammer out of that!
Were you just setting up a joke?
I’m not kidding around!
Wait!
Ahh, wait!
“Where’s my regular report?!”
He’s not even reading them?!
Hold on, Kanuchan!
Gimme that pan back!
Where’d she go?
Look!
Over there!
Just popping in!
Blanca?!
Mom...
“Mom”?!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
The Intense Mom Appears!
Just popping in!
Don’t just “pop in” like it’s nothing!
You should tell me when you’re coming!
I did tell you, though.
You two just left me
on read and unread!
Big Bro, your reports
have been so brief lately,
I figured I oughta swing by in person,
and Friede came right on by
to pick me up!
Ooh, did you know how smooth
a flight on a Lizardon feels?
You just gotta try it!
Right, Friede?
That quick trip
through the skies was great!
And you know what else?
Oops, got carried away.
Ah, this is Lugarugan. Midnight Form.
My partner Pokémon.
Huh? What was I talking about?
Um...
That’s one heck of a mom, huh?
Oh, I remember now!
C’mon, Dot. I think your trial period’s
gone on long enough,
so I came to pick you up.
Trial period?
Pick up?
Yeah!
My daughter’s only here as a trial!
Huh?!
Right, Dot?
Oh, she’s gone.
Well, whatever.
We can catch up when we’re home.
H-Hey!
Hold on a minute!
Oh, sorry about her.
My younger sister Blanca is...
Well... Quite the character.
“Quite the character”?
What kinda character?!
I always wonder
what you mean by that.
Oh! You know what else
I’ve always wondered?
I got carried away again.
Anyway...
Blanca’s never been able to
keep from worrying about Dot.
She’s ten times the worrywart Murdock is.
That’s why she’s so excitable.
But Dot can’t really match
Blanca’s level of energy.
Really?
When she’s streaming,
she seems just about as excitable...
Streaming?
Is that the thing Dot was always doing
when she was cooped up in her room?
Even at home?!
You bet!
When I barged into her room
‘cause she wouldn’t come out,
she went “Mom alert!”
and got super mad at me.
Huh?
So you mean...
Gurumin was in the middle of a livestream?
Gurumin?
W-Wait!
I think I caught that stream live!
Huh?!
Wow! So you’re the mom
she was talking about!
Whoa, I’m blown away!
What’s a Gurumin?
Oh, wait a sec. I’ll just look it up.
Streamer... Popular...
What? This is news to me!
I gotta ask her about it!
Blanca...
Don’t try to stop me!
There’s too much I need
to hear straight from Dot!
No, I won’t stop you.
But if she has some doughnuts,
she might open up more.
You want to carry them again?
Go for it.
What’s that about?
That’s the Ikkanezumi’s
way of paying us back.
Since we saved them, they’ve been doing
all kinds of things to show their gratitude.
What?! I gotta ask her
about that, too!
Ms. Blanca!
Hmm?
Um... Would you mind
if we talked to Dot for you?
Huh?
We’ll ask her
anything you want to know.
Then I guess I’ll leave it to you.
Sure!
Let’s go, Roy.
Yeah.
Aww, I feel like I could cry.
So Dot’s made friends
who wanna protect her like that...
Dot, can you hear me?
We want to hear your side of the story.
What this “trial period”
is exactly, and all that...
I don’t want you to just
get taken away out of the blue!
Me neither!
I don’t want you to leave the crew!
Liko... Maybe today’s no good.
Let’s head back for now.
Right...
“Go”?
Sure, but...
They already left,
and I’m not about to go running after them...
Wait, they’re still here!
The pretend-to-give-up plan worked!
Okay. I’ll tell you my side.
Dot!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
The trial period was my idea.
I felt like I’d hit a wall.
Hit a wall?
I was always in my room at home,
but I didn’t feel like
I was missing anything.
I could stream as Gurumin,
with the net as my connection to the whole world.
But I kept bumping into things
I just couldn’t get from inside my room.
I was totally stuck.
Something just doesn’t add up...
Can’t I find anything
more interesting...?
Oh, there’s a new thesis.
This professor’s so amazing...
He goes all over the world,
meets all sorts of Pokémon...
He even made a distribution map!
All right, this’ll be the topic of my next vid!
The net’s full to the brim
with interesting info.
But... the reason it’s interesting is that it comes
from people speaking from actual experience.
At first, before I’d realized that...
I tried to research stuff and
gather lots of info to share as Gurumin,
trying not to be overshadowed.
But it just didn’t feel right,
and I couldn’t keep it up.
Nanjamo’s got a livestream today!
I’ll grab something to eat
before it starts.
Wh-Wh-Who are you?!
I’m Friede.
I’m friends with your uncle Murdock.
This is my partner, Captain Pikachu.
Friede?
I was passing through,
so I thought I’d say hi.
Nice to finally meet you, Dot.
Hey, I know we only just met, but...
Could you fix this for me?
Huh?
It just won’t work right.
Why ask me?
You’re good with this stuff, right?
Did you hear that from Murdock?
Something like that.
Here’s the issue I’m running into.
If I can’t get this program working,
I won’t be able to do
what I like doing most.
Hmm...
That was in the thesis I saw earlier!
Professor... Friede...
Oh...
N-N-Never mind!
So? Think you can fix it?
Easily.
That’s reassuring!
Thanks!
And all the data’s still there!
Of course.
It’d be really bad
if you lost such important data...
Hey, Dot.
While we’re at it, could you make
an app for the Rising Voltteccers?
What do you mean
“while we’re at it”?
Wait, what? An app?!
Yeah.
I want an app that stands
as a testament to our friendship.
Well? Think you could do it?
Easily...
Well, maybe not easily, but...
Give me some time and
I can put a program together.
You’re amazing!
It’s nothing special.
Just something I taught myself
‘cause I liked it...
That is absolutely special!
What you like and what I like
have crossed paths.
It must be fate! Right, Cap?
Dot, wanna join us aboard our ship?
Huh?
Wh-What?
None of this makes any sense...
O-On second thought, forget it.
I can’t make you an app.
What a weirdo.
Oh no, Nanjamo’s stream started!
Keep up the questions, queries, and Pokémon “Q”s!
I’m waiting on all of your comments!
Questions, queries...
Yeah, right.
Ooh! I spy a curious comment
a-comin’-trekkin’-Kentauros!
It’s a question from Homebody!
Huh? No way! This can’t be...!
Th-Th-Th-That’s my comment...!
“I’m a streamer as well.
“Nanjamo, have you ever felt
like you’ve hit a wall before?”
That’s what it says!
Well, of course I have!
You have?
But just sitting and waiting won’t get you
over that wall! You gotta get moving!
Get moving...
Oh, but I wouldn’t wanna
stop streaming... Oh, I know!
I’d have my studio grow wings,
so I could fly all over!
Did that help you out?
If not, just laugh it off
as some Nanjamo nonsense!
Dot! When are you gonna wake up?!
Big Bro and Friede left ages ago!
Not like that matters to me...
I’d grow wings,
so I could fly all over!
That is absolutely special!
What you like and what I like
have crossed paths.
Wanna join us aboard our ship?
I had no idea...
So then what happened?
I made the app
and came aboard the ship.
I convinced my mom
by telling her it would be a trial period.
And she said I could stay here
until she came to pick me up.
So that’s how it is...
Oh! Dot, you’re out of your room!
What a coincidence!
I thought I’d swing by the kitchen since I was
feeling peckish, and here I end up bumping into you!
So? Liko, Roy...
Did she tell you anything?
Um...
She told us about the trial period,
and you coming to pick her up.
Then you get it now, right?
I popped in ‘cause I figure
the trial period’s gone on long enough,
but I’m curious
how Dot feels about it.
I’d have liked to ask her myself,
but Dot never tells me anything.
So annoying...
Annoying?!
‘Course I’m annoying!
I know I’m annoying!
But I’m—
Um!
Ms. Blanca...
Dot just needs to find
the right moment to talk about this... I think.
Liko...
I see.
Right... But then... What do I do?
What should we do, Lugarugan?
Huh?
Don’t tell me, Dot...
You became a Pokémon Trainer?
So what if I did?
Okay.
Then there’s only one thing to do!
Battle me!
Why?!
Um...
What brought this on?
Well, don’t look at me.
Battles speak as loud as words!
That’s a common saying among trainers.
In other words, during a battle...
...though Dot’s at that age where
talking to her parents is embarrassing,
she’ll be able to say
what she really feels!
Really?
I’ve never heard that saying before.
But there may be some truth to it.
Really?!
I just don’t get it.
Battling my mom...
This is absurd.
Wait, you want to battle?
This battle seems so pointless.
But...
Somehow, I just...
Feel like I shouldn’t run away.
Self switch, on!
Mom switch...
On!
The first strike seizes victory!
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
I thought you’d do that.
Lugarugan!
Don’t stop! Keep it going!
You know, Dot,
Big Bro’s regular reports
keep me well-informed.
Even on the ship,
you just stay cooped up in your room.
Maybe so...
But I’ve also made friends, and started to
think the outside world is pretty fun, too!
Why did you become a Pokémon Trainer?
You never seemed interested before!
Back then, I wasn’t!
But since meeting Kuwassu...
Things have been
so much more exciting!
And I thought I’d have fun
with Kanuchan by my side, too!
That’s why!
You caught them, right?
Yeah, I did!
Use Pound, Kuwassu!
Counter!
Kuwassu!
Even if I’m backed into a corner,
I can learn from it and try
something different next time...
Everything that was
out of reach in my room...
I feel like I could do it all now!
And that excites me!
Okay! Well then, dazzle me
with what you can do now!
Water Gun!
Lugarugan, use Rock Throw!
In that case... Pound!
Counter!
Everything keeps getting hit back...
Was this hopeless from the start?
Right! We can’t give up!
I shouldn’t be thinking about
what I can do, but what we can do!
The legs!
Aim for the legs, Kuwassu!
Pound!
Go!
Counter!
Huh?! Was that...?
Whoa! Big Bro!
Right!
Good job, Kuwassu!
You learned Kick Down!
Dot.
Mom, listen to me!
Oh?
I don’t want the trial period
to go on any longer.
From now on, I want to be
a proper part of the crew.
I want to stay here!
So...
Please let me!
That’s just what
I was hoping you’d say...
Dot! You’ve really grown!
Living out wonderful days on this
wonderful ship... What an amazing thing!
Thanks.
Here.
So? What’s your answer?
Well... Of course it’s okay!
No mother could deny
such a heartfelt wish from her daughter!
What a relief!
All right!
You want this?
No way!
H-H-Hey...
You’re supposed to
just accept it, you know?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
Lugarugan: Midnight Form.
Lugarugan (Midnight Form)
Wolf Pokémon
Type: Rock
Lugarugan (Midnight Form)
Wolf Pokémon
Type: Rock
It’s a Pokémon that lives alone
rather than forming packs.
Height
1.1m
Do you know what battle style
this Lugarugan excels at?
Weight
25.0kg
What battle style does it excel at?
Hit and run
Feints
Countering
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cheerful bird Pokémon!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Y'all been groovin'? It's Gurumin!!
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What battle style does it excel at?
C: Countering
The answer is C: Countering!
It uses Taunt on its opponents, and when they rush in
to strike, it launches its Counter attack.
It sends back double the damage it takes!
Taking cuts to let it shatter bones...
It’s a true battle maniac!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
It’s the ocean!
Beloved by everyone, it’s Irukaman!
Irukaman transforms from
Naïve Forme to Mighty Forme...
...to save anyone
who’s in trouble!
But I hear nobody’s seen
the moment it transforms.
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Transform! The Hero of the Ocean, Irukaman
Transform!