Sorry to keep you waiting.
The Pokémon you left in my care
should be all better now.
Thanks!
Come on out!
Let’s go!
Thank you for your hard work.
It’s time for my shift,
so feel free to call it a day, Molly-san.
Okay.
Thanks for your hard work!
How’d it go today?
Nothing special. Same old.
Is that so?
Well, Mommy’s really happy
to see you back home.
You really are
all grown up now, Molly.
All grown up, huh...?
Pokémon in the Forest Park were...?!
I’m heading out!
What, right now?
But if you don’t get your rest...
At least let me do what I want
on my own free time.
Let’s go, Lucky!
Just hang on!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
The Pokémon Center Lady
Delicious!
Here you go! Time for dessert!
We’ve been on the move a lot lately,
so let’s make sure to rest up today.
Yeah! Time to eat lots, sleep lots,
and recover our energy!
Sorry I’m late!
Ohh, my Pokémon just
started feeling sick in the forest...
Sounds like you had a tough time.
I had the Pokémon Center heal it right up,
so there’s no need to worry.
Oh, the same happened to me.
Forest Park, right?
I was out on a hike there,
and this little one suddenly ran out of energy.
The Pokémon Center
sure was crowded, wasn’t it...?
It sure was...
They kept me waiting.
Forest Park is on the outskirts
of Uirou City here, right?
Yeah... Wonder what’s going on.
Let’s check it out!
It’s pitch black...
Is this as far as we go?
Thanks, Cap!
Let’s move.
“A hiking trail
that even beginners can enjoy.”
Doesn’t look like there’re
any aggressive Pokémon here.
Yeah.
It didn’t sound like the hotel guests’ Pokémon
were attacked by anything, either...
They just simply lost their energy.
Don’t tell me it’s some kinda ghost
that sucks out your life force...
Huh?! Don’t say scary stuff like that!
Was that all...?
It’s just an ordinary tree.
Don’t scare us like that, Achigator.
Now what?!
Ghosts!
Shadows?
Just seeing things again...
O-Of course there aren’t
actually any ghosts!
Wh-What now...?
Acting spooked won’t get us anywhere!
Let’s check it out!
Right!
Molly!
Roy! And Liko!
Long time no see!
What happened to that Ootachi?
Seems like it got poisoned.
Most cases will
alleviate naturally in time,
but a strong poison’s been
cropping up around this area lately.
A strong poison...?
Yeah. So that’s the cause...
Administering medicine
helps them get better faster.
There, you’re all good now.
What have you been doing
since then, Molly?
I’ve been working
at my family’s Pokémon Center,
as well as heading out to treat
any injured wild Pokémon I catch wind of.
That so?
I’m putting my experience
from back then to good use.
How about you?
What are you up to?
Liko, Dot, and me
reformed the Rising Voltteccers.
Right now, Pokémon suffering from
the effects of Rakurium are turning up all over the place.
Rakurium?!
We’re traveling around
to investigate the cause behind it.
So, it’s still not over...
But knock it off with calling yourselves
the Rising Voltteccers.
Wh-Why?
We decided on that already, right?
It’s not going to help you!
If we can solve the Rakurium problem,
I bet it’ll clear up the whole misunderstanding!
Don’t be reckless!
The Rising Voltteccers... were disbanded.
No way...
I don’t wanna!
It’d be hard for us to keep traveling,
given how we can’t find Friede.
The engine’s damaged too,
so we won’t be able to fly smoothly.
But... if we just repair it,
then we can—!
We went on this journey
to take Pagogo to Rakua.
We’ve achieved that, and gotten rid
of the Rakurium like Lucius wished.
Isn’t that right?
The end of an era.
I don’t want to keep you
stuck here any longer.
You should leave the ship and go back to school,
or continue your journey...
Do whatever calls to you.
What gives?!
You’re not gonna ask what we think?!
Dot... Please, try to understand...
I wanna stay with everyone!
Me, too!
I understand.
Liko?!
You sure about this?!
Murdock...
Orio...
Molly...
Gramps...
You all made this decision
with our best interests in mind...
From this moment onward,
the Rising Voltteccers are disbanded!
I know, but...
Believe me, they were all my dear friends,
and that was my place to call home, too...
With the ship, I could treat even
faraway Pokémon in need of help...
But things are different now.
Our ship can’t fly, and the Explorers
are even spreading nasty rumors about us.
You can keep traveling without having to
chain yourselves to the Rising Voltteccers.
If you wanted, you could even pick out
your own name. One just for the three of—
No!
This year apart from everyone
made me realize...
I’m Roy of the Rising Voltteccers!
No matter what anyone says, or how much trouble
they give us, that’s not gonna change!
A bit ago, we met someone who thought
the Rising Voltteccers were bad guys.
But she understood us.
She said she’d support us!
And that’s why I want to keep adventuring
as Liko of the Rising Voltteccers!
I see...
Follow your heart, then.
Right!
What was that...?
Lucky, Ikkanezumi! Let’s go!
We should go too!
Return, Tebrim!
Oh, no!
Molly!
They’re all suffering
from a strong poison...
Just like the Ootachi
from earlier.
Marill, you too?
Pollen... That means...
Huh? What?
A Rafflesia?!
The allergenic poison pollen!
Why are you doing this?!
Molly...
Do you know that Pokémon?
He’s lived in this forest a long time.
He’s well-behaved, and gets along fine
with the other Pokémon...
He’s not the kind of Pokémon
to spread poison around for no reason...
A Rakurium Sign!
That has to be why...!
Watch out!
Masquernya!
Achigator, you go too!
Be careful, you two!
Masquernya!
Achigator!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
They got poisoned...
Masquernya!
What a powerful Toxic...
And that Poison Powder, too...
If we get in close,
we’ll be hit by the poison pollen...
Attack from a distance!
Achigator, use Flamethrower!
Masquernya, use Magical Leaf!
Return, Masquernya!
Achigator, you rest up, too!
Liko, leave this to me!
Lucario!
Poison doesn’t affect Steel types!
Let’s wrap this up nice and quick!
Metal Claw!
Molly, watch out!
Lucky!
Thanks, Cap!
Let’s cure this poison, fast!
Thank goodness.
This time, we’ve gotta make sure
not to spread the pollen...
Lucario! Luster Cannon!
Lucario!
When did it get paralyzed?!
It’s Rafflesia’s ability, Spore.
So when it touched him earlier...
Cap’s attacks
will spread the pollen, too.
What should we do...?
Tebrim!
Keep your distance
and use Mind Power!
All right!
Plus, it’s super effective!
This could work!
Tebrim!
Tebrim’s not strong enough...
Rafflesia will heal up with Giga Drain
before she can beat him!
Put all your strength into it!
One more Mind Power!
Protect Tebrim!
Ikkanezumi?
You want to protect Tebrim,
don’t you?
Okay! Use Tidy Up!
Ikkanezumi!
Great! We’ll help out, too!
Taikaiden!
Fan it with your wings!
Nice one, Cap!
Taikaiden!
Don’t let him show you up!
Tebrim!
You can do this!
Believe in yourself!
Everyone worked together
to give us this chance!
Tebrim, shine in full bloom!
Tebrim Terastallized!
Mind Power!
Again...
Ikkanezumi, use Follow My Finger!
It landed!
Okay! If we can land
just one more hit...
Tebrim?
She picked up Rafflesia’s feelings...
Roy. Molly.
I don’t want to attack Rafflesia any more!
Liko...
Tebrim feels the same way!
Rafflesia hurt his own friends,
and his heart is wounded!
She wants to help heal it!
I want to let Tebrim
fulfill her desires!
She’s going to calm
Rafflesia’s feelings with Healing Pulse?
She’ll heal up the damage
we finally managed to deal to him, but...
Don’t worry.
I bet we’ll get through to him!
We understand, Tebrim!
Not good! She got poisoned!
Tebrim... Hang in there!
Is that...?
Healing... Wish!
Tebrim!
You really gave it your all!
Take a nice, long rest!
Pagogo! I’m counting on you!
Even though his stamina should’ve been restored,
he’s still pretty weak.
Could be the effects of Rakurium...
With how much he exerted himself,
it’s only natural he’d be feeling sore.
Ikkanezumi! I’m counting on you!
We’re better off taking him to the Pokémon Center
than treating him right here.
Let’s hurry!
Monjara’s perked up quite a bit!
It’s a lot better now!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
So this is where Molly works
to help Pokémon every day...
Yeah!
Hey, have you heard of
those whatsit-Spheres?
What are they?
I hear they’re real handy in a battle!
And they’re coming out soon!
Wow... What’s so great about ‘em?
Sorry for the wait.
Everyone!
Glad to see you’re all better!
Rafflesia is, too.
Take him back to the forest for me.
Yeah, you got it.
What about you, Molly?
They seem to be short-handed here.
I’ll help out for a while.
Um... Molly.
If you’d like to...
You could come adventure with us again!
Great idea!
You can treat hurt wild Pokémon
along the way, too!
Right...
I think I’ll try
sticking it out here for now.
I do learn a lot
working here, after all.
I see...
But...
If, say... I was offered another chance
to fly around the world on a big ship, or something...
When that time comes...
Mm-hmm!
Miss!
Welcome to the Pokémon Center!
U-Um...
Don’t you worry.
Leave this little one to me.
Okay!
Molly’s really cool, isn’t she?
Yup!
What’s wrong?
Look!
Maybe he thinks
they all hate him now...
What a relief.
We can relax now.
Roy?
Let’s check it out.
Right, of course...
This wouldn’t have happened all on its own.
There’s gotta be some clue
left behind around here!
What... is that?
Exceed?
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Light Pokémon, Denryuu!
Light Pokémon
Denryuu
Electric
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Light Pokémon
Static
Denryuu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then always
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Denryuu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Light Pokémon
Electric
Dragon
Mold Breaker
It’s said that Mega Evolving
stimulated its genes,
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
causing it to regrow the wool
it lost to evolution!
It’s so soft and fluffy!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It also gained the Dragon type,
and has powered up...
Next episode
Hey, Roy... About Ult...
Ult? I’m not really the guy
to ask about him.
But aren’t you friends?
He just won’t leave me alone.
What do you wanna ask, though?
Over there...
Do you think that’s Ult?
Where?
Y-You mean that guy?
But he’s got this
dead serious look on his face...
Can’t be Ult, then.
But he has a Yamirami with him.
Then it is Ult?
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Strong Spheres
Is it Ult? Isn’t it Ult?
Which is it?!