While the Brave Asagi is under repairs,
Roy, Dot, and I are going to
Orange Academy to learn about Terastal.
Our Paldea-spanning
Terastal Course has finally begun.
And the first to take the basics test
from their Gym Leader...
...will be me.
I can’t go another step!
You need some more exercise.
Gotta build that stamina!
As if! My battles are about cleverness!
Using my head!
There it is!
Cercle Town...
It’s so far!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Liko and Nyarote, Put Your Hearts Into It
Over there!
There’s a ton of Bug Pokémon!
This town’s Gym Leader is a Bug-type expert,
so maybe they feel at home here.
Whoa...
Liko... Are you nervous?
Huh?
Y-Yeah, a little.
You’ll be fine!
You’ve battled Rekkuuza!
You’re right.
I told myself I’d give it my all,
but I’m really not feeling confident...
How about we start with the gym?
All of a sudden, I have to Terastallize
for the first time in a battle...
From here, it should be...
Something smells good!
It’s that way!
H-Hey! Don’t run off on your own!
Hold on!
“Pâtisserie Soapberry”...
That reminds me...
The Gym Leader’s a pâtissière...
If she’s a pâtissière...
Maybe she’s here! Let’s ask!
Huh? Where’s Hogator?
And Nyarote!
I guess it’s snack time first.
Please relax and enjoy.
So this is...
Soapberry’s famous...
Tamantu-la-Torte!
Time to dig in!
It tastes amazing!
A powerful sweet flavor,
with a slightly bitter aftertaste...
This tastes like nothing I’ve ever had.
You finished yours already?!
That was delicious!
Was everything to your satisfaction,
dear guests?
Just messing around!
Murdock!
But why...?
Looks like you’re all doing well!
Dot! Those clothes look good on you!
Oh, shush. Molly picked these out for me.
She’s the one with the fashion sense...
Wait, never mind about me!
Shouldn’t you be on the ship, Murdock?
I left the ship repairs to Orio
and came here to earn some money.
I’m working part-time at Soapberry.
Working part-time...
But Soapberry’s sweets are so popular
that every day is crazy busy!
And the owner’s just lovely, too!
She even makes extra cakes
for the staff as a treat.
Sounds like...
...you’re having fun.
Yeah! The owner’s an outstanding
pâtissière named Kae—
Hey, what’s the big idea?!
What’s going on?
Let’s go look.
This is a total drag.
I came all the way here to have some of
your limited cake, you understand me?!
Oh dear...
So don’t you tell me it’s “sold out”!
I am the customer!
You should just go and make some for me!
Oh dear, what to do?
Hurry up and make it!
Make it, make it!
Make it, make it, make it!
Make it! Make! It!
A textbook whiny customer.
Hey! Stop it!
You’re bothering the employees.
Huh? Wuzzat?!
Oh. You’re...
San...
...dwich.
Why are you here?
Why else?
I’m in Paldea,
so I gotta try the Tamantu-la-Torte!
Oh, it was delici—
Hold on now...
Isn’t she with the Explorers?
I don’t know why,
but she showed up to do the Terastal Course.
Is she watching Liko and...?
Better not let your guard down...
Ms. Kaede, I’ll handle this.
Now... I’m sorry,
but we’re all out for today.
Ms. Kaede?
Yep! Meet the owner of Soapberry
and the Gym Leader...
Pleased to meet you.
I’m Kaede.
Welcome to Cercle Town.
N-Nice to meet you!
My name’s Liko.
I’m Roy.
Dot.
Of course.
I was told you’d be coming, Ms. Liko.
Shall we get started, then?
Hey! Hold it!
If you’re down to battle,
then Sandwich wants in too!
Huh?
I came all the way out here.
It’s gonna bug me like crazy
if I don’t cut loose big time!
Oh dear... And I have the shop to run
for the rest of the day...
I only have the time
to face one of you.
Then I’ll battle her first!
Then you can battle whoever wins!
Hey now, try to be reasonable.
Shut up!
Just can it, old man.
If you want to battle...
I accept!
Liko?
Ms. Kaede...
Can I Terastallize in this battle?
That isn’t permitted between students.
May I ask why you wanted to?
I’ve... never used a Terastal Orb before,
so I was hoping to try it before my test...
Huh?!
You want me to be your practice dummy?
Well do your worst, punk!
Now, now, calm yourself.
Ms. Liko.
Y-Yes?
Practice is important.
But practice is different
from a real battle.
Oh!
How about this?
Rather than battling,
I’ll have the two of you make cakes!
Huh?
Cakes?!
Never thought they’d be
facing off in a cake contest.
Go for it, Liko!
Does Liko know how to make a cake?
I’ve shown her how before.
She’ll be fine.
Liko! Keep your cool and don’t rush!
Yeah!
This’ll be my first time
making a cake by myself.
But I’ll just have to do my best!
Nyarote, let’s both give it our all!
Okay then... Begin!
All done!
I see Ms. Liko has finished.
Now, how is Ms. Sandwich doing?
Yeah... What kind of cake
has she made?
Gah, I give up!
I don’t know what the heck I’m doin’!
She’s nowhere near done.
Shut it!
Onigohri!
This is ‘cause you were no help!
That’s it! I’m doin’ it my way!
Blizzard! Turn it into shaved ice!
S-So c-cold...
How ‘bout that?!
Ms. Sandwich...
Sweets are much like Bug Pokémon...
They may be small,
but they hold tremendous power.
It takes great care to plump them up
with the joyous thing we call deliciousness.
Come again another day.
I...
I’m leavin’!
Wh-Whoa...
She can be a harsh judge
when it comes to making sweets.
Now then...
We have a winner.
Ms. Liko,
I will administer your basics test.
Okay!
But while we’re here,
why don’t you two try the cake you made?
It came out yummy!
You worked hard on your cake
without worrying about practicing first.
Huh?
Right...
The stronger your feelings are while making a cake,
the nicer and plumper it will turn out.
Battles are much the same.
If you and your partner
really put your hearts into it,
you can create the most delicious, one-of-a-kind battles possible!
Maybe I was overthinking it.
Every battle is a real battle.
It doesn’t matter if it’s my first time.
I’ll try out Terastal during my test!
It seems you’re eager to begin.
Well then, let’s adjourn to the proper place.
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Now then, Ms. Liko.
Let me treat you to a sweet battle.
I’ll do my best!
A sweet battle?
Is she gonna go easy on her?
Don’t let Ms. Kaede’s
sweet demeanor fool you.
There’s a hint of bitterness
beneath her sweetness.
If she uses Bug types,
Nyarote’s at a disadvantage!
Off you go, Beary.
Himeguma. Little Bear Pokémon.
Normal type.
Its paws are soaked
with lots of honey.
When nervous,
it will lick its paws in order to soothe itself.
Normal type?
Liko can handle
a cute little Pokémon like that!
Terastallizing is like
emerging from a cocoon.
It lets you draw out tremendous power
within your Pokémon.
But can you put that power
to good use?
Terastal Course battle, start!
Let’s go, Nyarote!
Lightning Speed!
She made the first move.
All right!
Beary, use Fawn!
Nyarote?!
Huh?!
She really held back...
My sweet little Himeguma’s
fawning is irresistible!
But...
Slash!
She also has a bitter side.
Nyarote, get back!
Then, if I attack from a distance...
Beary...
Flap those wings!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf
from over here!
Nyarote! What’s wrong?
I smell something nice nearby...
Is that...?
Sweet Scent.
Does it not fill you
with happiness?
Nyarote, watch out!
Beary! Slash!
That Himeguma won’t go down easy.
Get close and its sweet fawning
makes you pull your punches,
but keep your distance
and its Sweet Scent clouds your focus...
Then it takes you out with a Slash...
That’s...
Ms. Kaede’s “sweet” battle...
What should I do?
Are we nearly done, I wonder?
Beary, fill the air
with your Sweet Scent!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
She can’t focus on the battle.
Slash.
Nyarote!
The way this is going...
She won’t even get to Terastallize!
Battles are much the same.
If you and your partner
really put your hearts into it...
Nyarote!
Look at me! Battle with me!
Let’s pour everything we have...
...into enjoying this battle!
Yeah!
Beary, use Sweet Scent again!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf
towards the ground!
She’s blocking Sweet Scent
with the leaves?
But...
Beary can fix that with a Slash!
More and more! Magical Leaf!
Nyarote! Shine in full bloom!
Use a big Magical Leaf!
Oh...
Oh dear...
We did it!
Good, good!
She did it!
It seems I added
a bit too much sugar.
Break free of your cocoon
and grow big and strong!
She Terastallized, too!
She’s Bug type now!
Not good, Liko!
Let’s finish this, Nyarote!
Magical Leaf!
Huh?
Beary, use Consecutive Cut!
This battle is over!
Nyarote!
Are you okay?
I’m sorry we lost...
And after you tried so hard...
Ms. Kaede?
Okay! You pass.
Huh?
It doesn’t matter whether
you win or lose Terastal Course battles.
What I wanted to see was...
...whether you could put your hearts
into the here and now.
Our hearts...
You were in perfect sync
with your partner,
and you put
your heart into the battle.
And you were able to Terastallize
at the absolute perfect moment.
To be honest,
I should have ended the battle there,
yet I couldn’t help but
want a little taste...
Through fine artistry,
you baked a nice and plump battle.
Thank you very much!
Ms. Kaede,
I’m going to try even harder from here!
I can’t wait to see
how you and Nyarote turn out!
You did it, Liko!
Congrats!
You did great
for being up against Ms. Kaede!
Everyone... Thank you!
And that concludes your basics test.
Now, what do you say to teatime?
Go enjoy the best sweets
Paldea has to offer!
Yeah!
Ms. Liko, be sure to always enjoy
the here and now.
Please don’t ever forget that.
Right!
I got so fired up when I saw
Nyarote’s Terastallized Magical Leaf!
How many more times
are you going to say that?
But it really was exciting.
So exciting
I don’t think I’ll be able to sleep.
Yeah.
Thank you, Nyarote.
Terastal is amazing.
It drew so much power out of Nyarote.
I hope I can learn to use it better.
Next up, my turn.
I’ll do my best!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Little Bear Pokémon, Himeguma.
Himeguma have the tendency
to lick their own paws.
Himeguma
Little Bear Pokémon
Type: Normal
Himeguma
Little Bear Pokémon
Type: Normal
Height
0.6m
They do that because of
a certain thing soaked into their paws,
Weight
8.8kg
but do you know what that thing is?
What is soaked into their paws?
Honey
Miso
Water
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What is soaked into their paws?
A: Honey
The answer is A: Honey!
They soak their paws
in the honey they love.
They especially enjoy
Mitsuhoney’s Sweet Honey!
Next episode
Next up is me and Hogator’s basics test.
Let’s make sure we pass!
Huh? Something seems odd
about this town...
“Art Festival”...?
There’s all sorts of art
on display around town!
Ooh, that sounds fun!
Let’s check it out!
Huh?! But what about my test?!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Shine! The Sparkling of Fire and Art