We’re currently heading
through Galar,
following a black Rekkuuza
sighting that Dot got wind of.
Dot! Let’s do some battle practice!
You look fired up, Kuwassu!
Dot!
I’m busy right now!
I need to dig up more info.
Aw...
See you later, Kuwassu.
Dot has holed herself up
in her room again,
and won’t even show her face.
I realize she’s focused
on collecting info about Rekkuuza,
but I can’t help missing her...
Why not say that
to Dot instead of me?
Now, say “Ahh...”
But I don’t want to be a bother...
Everything looks fine.
Check-up all done.
I should take a look at Mibrim, too.
Another time.
Considering how others feel
is all well and good, but...
But?
If you overthink things, trying to anticipate
every outcome, you may end up doing nothing.
Trying to tackle things head-on
is important, too.
You mean...?
I’m saying that sometimes
you have to be “reckless.”
We’re nearly at our destination.
Get ready to disembark.
Now, off with you.
I’ll look after the ship
with Ms. Diana and Gramps.
Right!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
With My Friends
So many Pokémon!
The Wild Area’s home to more species
than anywhere else in Galar.
Something’s over there!
Something big!
Hey, Roy!
It might be Rekkuuza!
That’s one heck of an Iwark.
It’s huge.
Watch out.
Some of the wild Pokémon here
are crazy strong.
Don’t follow it!
Oh, yeah! You think Terapagos can tell
whether or not Rekkuuza’s nearby?
Good question.
Can you?
I guess not.
Too bad...
Then I’ll ask Dot
if she’s found any clues.
Hey, Dot!
Huh?
Dot, can you hear me?
I can hear you.
You were here?!
Just got here.
I’m glad you joined us.
No point if I don’t, is there?
This is where we’re meeting the guy
who had some info on Rekkuuza.
Out here?
There’s no one around.
This is definitely the place.
But I can’t reach him...
Looks like there’s no trace
of anyone coming through here.
Fake info?
Man, I got tricked again...
That’s just how adventures go, Dot.
Sometimes you strike out.
There’s value in seeing that for yourself.
All right!
Since we’re in the Wild Area,
let’s relax and have some fun!
Sounds good.
You all fine with that?
All right!
Count me in!
Dot?
I’m going back to the ship.
Hold on!
I need to plan our next move.
You don’t need to rush...
Yes, I do!
My ineptitude already
put you in danger once before...
If only I’d done a better job,
they wouldn’t have outwitted me...
Gah! I’m so mad at myself!
Mibrim!
Sorry! I scared her again!
Let’s go after her together!
You too, Nyahoja!
I’ll go, too!
I’m glad we found her quickly.
Yeah.
Wh-What’s that Pokémon?
Kajirigame. Bite Pokémon.
Water/Rock type.
It has an extremely vicious disposition.
It lurks along the shoreline, and chomps down
on prey when they come to drink water.
Maybe we should keep our distance.
Huh? Where’s Terapagos?
It was here a second ago...
Oh, no!
When did it get over there?!
Hogator, go help!
It was just a yawn?
Hey, Kuwassu!
Looks like it’s surprisingly friendly.
They all seem happy
to have found another friend.
What now?!
Now that’s a surprise.
That should be my line.
I came over to warn you
that wild Kajirigame can be violent,
but you seem to be just fine.
Good for you, customers!
Customers?
Is that the guy with the info?
No.
Um...
I’m an Ingredient Merchant. And I’ve got
the finest ingredients in stock, as always!
Totally bored!
Someone play with me!
Charem.
Learn to control yourself, Sango.
Your behavior continues to degrade
the reputation of the Explorers.
But anything goes in the Explorers, right?
You can talk like that
after you show some results.
Isn’t that for the best?
With notoriety preceding us,
fewer will try to oppose us.
Totally well put.
For you at least, Spinel.
Spinel. How is the disinformation
campaign going?
It went off without a hitch.
The Rising Voltteccers should be tangled up
in our web of misinformation as we speak.
Thank you for waiting.
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Ooh!
Sure was lucky you bumped into
an Ingredient Merchant.
Now we can make some tasty curry!
All right! Curry!
I don’t need any.
I have my usual stuff.
You don’t like curry, Dot?
Never had it.
Seriously?!
Never?!
Is it that surprising?
Absolutely! Curry’s really tasty!
You’re missing out!
Th-That’s right!
The next best thing in this world
after Pokémon is curry!
I-It’s that good?
Yes! So let me make you
your first curry!
I’ll help out!
That’s a great idea.
I wanna try Liko’s curry!
Eating curry in the great outdoors
makes it even better!
Ah... I’m already getting hungry...
Now I’m really craving some curry!
The Wild Area’s
the perfect place for curry!
I’ll run back to the ship now...
Huh?
I’d better invite Molly and the others.
Oh, of course. Right, yeah!
Then let’s prep the ingredients!
Yeah!
You cut it that small?
I’m gonna fry it ‘til it turns black!
Huh... I always used to have
chunky vegetable curry.
Different families,
different tastes, huh?
Oh! What do you prefer, Dot?
Huh? What?
Creamy or chunky?
Well, then...
How about we make
Roy’s curry and Liko’s curry?
Ooh! Nice idea!
It’s a curry battle!
Yeah, got it!
Then I’ll go gather
some secret ingredients!
Me, too. Come with me, Dot!
Huh? Me?
Take care!
We can boil the rice.
Roger.
Putting Kurabo Berries in curry
makes it taste a lot better.
I bet you’ll like it too, Hogator.
Don’t eat that yet!
Next one incoming!
Here goes!
And more to come!
What’s wrong, Hogator?
Hey, you!
Those eyes won’t work on me!
Give them back!
There’s a lot of Momon Berries here.
Wow.
Let’s pick some.
Yeah.
H-Hogator!
How’d you like Kuwassu’s Water Gun?!
We didn’t do so well...
That sounds rough.
You can have some of ours.
Huh?
You’re a glutton too, huh?
You can use these.
I picked them with Kuwassu.
Thanks.
But I’m looking for Kurabo Berries.
Momon Berries taste good, too.
I gotta use Kurabo Berries.
I’ll go gather some more!
Now he’s being picky...
Curry is a total mystery...
We got our berries!
Now, time to make some tasty curry!
Yeah!
Y-Yeah.
Go for it!
Looking forward to it!
I can’t wait!
There’s five important steps in cooking curry!
One: The ingredients!
Two: The berries!
Three: The heating!
Four!
Th-The stirring...
And lastly?
Huh?! Um...
The size of the vegetables?
Wrong!
It is...
It is...?
Your heart!
My... heart?
Yes! Do it!
Like this!
What... is that?
Our hearts!
L-Like this?
Well done!
Curry... really is a total mystery...
Time to dig in!
I-It’s good...
Yeah. I can taste your heart in it!
Seriously?!
My curry really is the best!
Now this is good.
Yeah, it’s tasty.
Roy Curry and Liko Curry...
They’re both good!
Delish!
Tasty!
You too, Cap.
Here’s Liko’s.
And this is Roy’s.
Cap gives them a perfect score!
All right!
We did it, Dot!
Y-Yeah...
Time for seconds!
Me, too!
How about you, Dot?
Yeah, I think I will.
Sure!
As long as I got enough nutrients,
I never cared what I ate...
...but meals really do
taste good with company.
There are so many things
I thought I understood...
...when I really didn’t know
the first thing about them.
And thinking about that scares me...
Don’t stress. There’s a lot of
fun stuff out there.
Together, we’ll discover
so many things all over the world!
Yeah.
My special curry is tasty, right?
Too spicy...
Falling rain strengthens the ground.
Eating curry strengthens bonds.
I even breathe fire!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers
out there! Y’all been groovin’?
Gurumin here!
There’s more to Pokémon battles
than just one-on-ones!
There’s also Multi Battles, where trainers
face off two-on-two, or in even bigger groups!
I even battled in a team
of three trainers recently!
Battles with loads of Pokémon
trading blows are intense!
But some moves can end up
hurting your allies, so be careful...
Yeah! Like Explosion!
But the best part of Multi Battles
is having friends by your side!
Friends by your side
can really reassure you!
Friends, huh?
Huh? What was that?
Just talking to myself.
You seem carefree.
You realize the higher-ups
are in a meeting, right?
I wonder if Amethio is okay...
The pendant Diana passed
to her granddaughter...
...escaped our grasp, and made contact
with a black Rekkuuza in the Kanto Region.
Then, after contacting Oliva in Paldea,
and Galarian Fire in Galar...
The pendant has now
awoken as Terapagos.
But they’ve got that
Tera-thingy with them, right?
Cause some people here
let it get away...
Then we should have a showdown
with the Rising Voltteccers...
...and claim Terapagos.
Let’s do it!
Sango totally loves that kinda stuff!
Isn’t resorting to force
quite the risky proposition?
Huh?!
You seem awfully pessimistic.
Do you know something?
No.
Fortunately, they do not understand
the value of Terapagos.
In which case, we would be wise
to simply monitor them for now.
He has a point.
Would you care to explain
your reasoning?
Oliva and Galarian Fire
were not awoken by the pendant....
...but by the black Rekkuuza.
Awoken by contact with Rekkuuza...
Pursuing Terapagos
will keep us one step behind.
If we are to get ahead of them,
we must pursue the black Rekkuuza.
Putting action before perfection.
Very well.
I concur that it is our best option.
A fine proposal. You’ve just barely
managed to scrape by, Amethio.
So that means...
we’re all going after it?
You can do as you wish.
I will be the first
to reach Rekkuuza.
What was up with you today?
Huh? What do you mean?
You’re pushing yourself.
Huh?! You think so?
Yeah. A whole lot.
I had to stop you!
Huh?
Well, if you went back to your room...
You’d have just been left with
the bitter memory of defeat...
...so I thought we could eat curry together,
and give you some fun memories!
Where’d you get that idea?
Thanks.
Sure. I’m glad I pushed myself!
I was worrying about being tricked
again and again, and nothing working out...
I wanted to be
more helpful to everyone.
That’s a surprise.
What’s a surprise about that?
Well, you’re helping us out
so much already!
With the ship, Gurumin, and more...
You’re amazing.
You think so?
I do!
Today was nice.
Yeah.
We got to enjoy the Wild Area!
I got to eat curry,
and got to... talk with you.
We should talk more often in the future.
When I’m not busy!
We didn’t find Rekkuuza,
but we sure had fun!
I’ll keep looking into
Rekkuuza’s whereabouts,
but looking over
all the info again will take time.
Got it. We’ll leave it to you.
I wonder if there’s
anything we can do, too.
Liko, why don’t we go
ask around about the balls?
If only we could find
someone who recognizes them...
Funny you should say that...
I happen to know someone
who runs an antique shop.
He may have some idea.
Antique?
An old item that isn’t used anymore,
or an old work of art.
That sounds interesting!
I wanna go!
We might learn something
I can’t find online.
It’s settled.
Let’s set off for
the antique shop!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, we’ll be taking a look at
the Rock Salt Pokémon, Kyojiohn.
Parts of this Pokémon
are made out of salt.
Kyojiohn
Rock Salt Pokémon
Type: Rock
Kyojiohn
Rock Salt Pokémon
Type: Rock
Height
2.3m
New salt is constantly
being created inside its body.
Weight
240.0kg
Do you know what that salt is used for?
What is Kyojiohn's salt used for?
Battling
Cooking
Healing
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cute & sweet Pokémon!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Varinich,
Tarpple, Mawhip!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Murdock here. Dot... Just watch this!!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Vanirich,
Tarpple, Mawhip! Yes!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, for the correct answer!
What is Kyojiohn's salt used for?
A: Battling
B: Cooking
C: Healing
What is Kyojiohn's salt used for?
A: Battling
B: Cooking
C: Healing
The answer is... all of them!
Kyojiohn’s salt has a healing effect.
In battle, it uses Salt Pickling
to attack its foes,
but that same salt
can also be used for healing.
Of course, it’s also great
when used for cooking.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers
out there! Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Seeking clues to the Six Heroes,
they arrived at an antique shop!
It’s full of suspicious artifacts...
Whoa, what?! Roy’s Ancient
Monster Ball disappeared?!
Who could’ve taken it?
The suspect’d have to be...
that shopkeep?!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
The Stolen Treasure
After that man, wherever he goes!