I’m Liko.
Hoping to become a Pokémon Trainer,
I enrolled at Sekiei Academy in the Kanto Region.
I met Nyahoja,
and our new life began.
Or so I thought...
Until a mysterious group came after
the pendant my grandma gave me,
and I was in serious trouble!
Found you!
Friede came to our rescue,
riding his Lizardon.
Apparently he’d been tasked
by my mother to come pick me up.
They were from a group of adventurers who
chase after the world’s Pokémon-related mysteries...
The Rising Voltteccers.
Whatever brought us here...
I hope we can get along, Liko.
That was how my adventure
with Nyahoja began.
Being a trainer is my dream!
Along the way, we picked up Roy,
who befriended Hogator...
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
And I met the livestreamer who streams
with Kuwassu from inside the ship, Gurum—
Err, Dot.
I was happy to have
some crewmates my own age.
While we were en route
to my grandma in Galar,
we encountered
some mysterious Pokémon.
A black Rekkuuza that emerged from
the Ancient Monster Ball Roy had...
Oliva, who was protecting
the Pokémon’s forest...
And Galarian Fire,
whom we met in the Galar Mine.
It seems they were part of
the Six Heroes, a group of Pokémon...
...who once traveled with
the Ancient Adventurer, Lucius.
And my pendant resonated when we met them,
shocking us all by transforming into a Pokémon!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
Terapagos's Adventure
Another helping, please!
Please!
You got it!
Grandma...
Talk about a huge morning appetite...
More for me too, please!
You got it!
I like that! Energy and stamina
are the foundation of all adventures!
Eat well!
Sure!
Grandma amazes me...
She’s already right at home
with the crew.
Cap and Windie have become friends!
Looks like they see eye to eye.
The strong are drawn
to one another, I see.
I’m gonna want some pointers from you
on how to raise Pokémon, Ms. Diana.
Really, I’m not as special
as you’re making me out to be.
I hope Terapagos will get along well
with Nyahoja and the others, too...
Huh?!
Liko?
What’s up?
It-It-It—
It’s gone!
Not here!
Not here...!
Where’d it go?
It can’t have gone outside, can it?
Don’t worry about that,
the ship’s in the air.
Perhaps, but I’m still worried...
Oh, no!
It can’t get back on its feet!
It wanted to eat berries?
Come to think of it...
It didn’t eat any Pokémon food, did it?
Maybe it’s got its own preferences.
I see.
I really don’t know anything
about this Pokémon.
I’ll need to observe it some more.
It doesn’t flinch when yelled at.
It retains its composure!
Is it good?
It’s surprisingly fond of sweets!
Terapagos never seems to get bored,
no matter where it goes on the ship.
Its sparkling eyes are so cute!
Must be rough,
running all over like that.
A little.
But seeing Terapagos having
so much fun makes me excited, too!
A-Ah, it happened again...
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Gurumin here!
There’s more to Pokémon battles
than just one-on-ones!
You’ve got Multi Battles, where trainers
face off two-on-two, or in even bigger groups!
Uh... Cut! Cut!
Liko!
Huh?
Dot?
Don’t tell me...?!
Huh?
Wait—
Gurumin?!
Sorry about earlier...
We interrupted your filming.
Terapagos just seems curious
about so many things.
It’s been asleep for decades, right?
Yeah.
The ship must be full of stuff
it’s never seen before.
I see...
Of course.
It’s only just woken up.
The reason it wouldn’t eat the Pokémon food
was that it didn’t know it was delicious food...
Everything is new to it.
It might have trouble
adjusting to life in our day.
If so... then I need to teach it.
Liko?
I was just thinking I wanted to
get to know it a little... better...?
Again?!
Geez! It keeps wandering off!
Nyahoja!
Bad news!
Terapagos disappeared again!
Do you know where Terapagos went?
Can you help me find it?
Nyahoja...
She’s in a bad mood...
But right now,
I need to find Terapagos.
Wait, Mibrim!
What is it, Mibrim?
Terapagos!
What are you doing out there?!
Be careful!
Mibrim!
Go back inside your Monster Ball!
Mibrim...
...could sense
Terapagos’s strong emotions...
It seems to be calling for somebody.
Terapagos!
I have to tell Friede right away...
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Nyahoja?
What’s the matter?
What?
Liko!
Terapagos!
You’re going to be okay!
Liko!
I’m so glad you’re safe.
Yeah...
I’m sorry for doing
something so dangerous.
You just acted on instinct.
Nothing to fault you for.
Good thing Nyahoja
let me know, though.
Thank you, Nyahoja.
Maybe Nyahoja is mad at me
for being so reckless all the time.
Your “reckless” behavior is rooted in
how much you care for Pokémon, isn’t it?
That is what we call courage.
I’m sure it’s because of you
that this little one awoke.
Nothing happened with the pendant
while it was in my care.
Grandma...
That one step I took on my adventure
ended up paving the way for you, Liko.
And you’re already so far ahead of me.
What you said to me...
I keep thinking about it.
If you believe in it...
Right.
Seek out the Six Heroes.
What will happen
if I meet the Six Heroes?
I suppose it’s time
I give you the full picture.
Lucius’s memoirs.
The Pokémon he met over the course of
his adventures are described here.
Is that...?
Terapagos.
The Pokémon Lucius bonded with.
But...
Yeah.
Perhaps it doesn’t have
enough energy yet.
Come to think of it...
When we met Oliva and Galarian Fire,
we were engulfed in a strange light,
and saw a man within it...
What?
That man...
Was it him?
Yes, that’s him!
I see...
Resonating with Oliva and the others...
...awakened Terapagos’s memories,
and caused it to return to Pokémon form.
If you meet the remaining Six Heroes,
I’m certain it will regain its original power.
Its original power...
That is when the path
to Rakua will open.
Much like how Lucius
was once led there!
Terapagos?
What’s the matter?
It looks like it reacted to
the mention of Lucius and Rakua...
Grandma...
Don’t you think Terapagos
wants to see Lucius?
And that’s why it’s crying?
Maybe it thinks we’ll meet him
if we go to this Rakua place.
Unfortunately, his memoirs don’t say
anything about where Rakua is located.
Not to mention, Lucius is a trainer
from a hundred years ago.
So, even if it wants to see him...
Even so...
I want to grant this little one’s wish.
Liko...
Even if it can’t meet Lucius,
there might still be something there...
At the place where it made those
treasured memories with Lucius... Rakua!
I’ll take it there!
The road may be harsh, but...
Oh, right!
With Pokémon by my side,
I’ll do just fine!
With Pokémon—
This was Lucius’s belt.
It’s made for
the Six Heroes’ Monster Balls.
It only makes sense
that you should bear it.
Please, accept this
from your old grandma.
This is Lucius’s...
Yes!
Do you know why that little one
responded to you?
Huh?
Because you’re in tune with
the feelings of Pokémon.
Meeting your partner
and taking that first step forward...
...allowed your best traits to blossom.
My partner...
Nyahoja...
Grandma,
look after Terapagos for me!
Found you.
I never have trouble finding you.
Hup.
I’m so sorry, Nyahoja.
You’re always looking after me, while I...
I was only able to take the first step
thanks to you. I remember that now.
I’m not sure if you understand
what I’m saying...
But, um...
Nyahoja...
Please, stay by my side.
Nyahoja!
Geez...
Pokémon are such
strange, strange creatures.
Even if words can’t
reach them, feelings can.
Grandma...
Now...
Yeah!
Getting happy... Getting angry...
Getting sad... Having fun...
We can understand each other’s feelings,
whatever they may be...
That’s how we can
live together with Pokémon.
I’ll tell everyone about Rakua.
Another adventure begins!
Be safe.
Of course!
Nyahoja!
I see.
Never would’ve guessed
it wanted to go to Rakua.
What kind of place is it?
An amazing place unlike anything
anyone’s ever seen, I’m sure.
An idyllic paradise?
Paradise, huh?
There’s gotta be tons of berries there!
I want to take this little one there...
And to do that, I’ve decided
I need to meet the rest of the Six Heroes!
I realize it’ll be extremely difficult...
And that I’m still
nowhere near strong enough...
So that’s why...
That’s why I’m asking all of you...
Please, help me!
U-Um...
Of course we’ll help!
We’re friends!
When one of us truly wants something,
we’ll lend all the support we can!
We all feel the same way!
Yeah!
Thank you...
Besides...
After what Ms. Diana told me,
I want to follow
the mystery of Lucius, too!
Is that...?
The remaining Six Heroes.
Laplace,
Basagiri,
Entei, and...
...the black Rekkuuza.
They all look so tough!
Entei’s a Legendary Pokémon, isn’t it?
I hear it’s always racing about
some place or other.
Yeah... The odds that
we’ll run into it are incredibly low.
What about this “Basagiri”?
It’s a Pokémon that used to
live in a region called Hisui.
It hasn’t been seen in ages.
Then how are we
supposed to look for it?
Good question...
Which leaves Laplace, but...
We don’t have any clues
for that one, either.
Huh?! Come on, let’s start by
finding the black Rekkuuza!
Now, look...
We need a solid plan and an order of—
Good news, Roy.
Dot!
There have been sightings of
the black Rekkuuza all over the Galar Region.
There’s a good chance it’s still in Galar.
Then we can catch up to Rekkuuza!
Things are heating up now,
huh, Hogator?
Guess sitting around thinking
won’t get us anywhere.
Right, Cap?
All right, let’s get to it!
Rising Voltteccers,
together through thick and thin!
To Rekkuuza we...
Go!
Hard to actually talk to him right now...
What could he be thinking about?
Whatever the case,
we will simply follow Amethio’s lead.
Yeah.
Soublades...
I...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Legend Pokémon, Windie!
This Pokémon turns the blazing fires
inside its body into energy,
Windie
Legend Pokémon
Type: Fire
Windie
Legend Pokémon
Type: Fire
Height
1.9m
and races across the land,
lightly and gracefully.
Weight
155.0kg
Do you know how far
it can run in a single day?
About how far can it run in one day?
100 km
1,000 km
10,000 km
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! This'll be a snap!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, announcing the right answer!
About how far can it run in one day?
C: 10,000 km
The answer is C: 10,000 kilometers!
Racing around the world,
the Legend Pokémon is the subject of many folktales.
Its proud and regal appearance
has entranced the hearts of the people!
Pokémon legends sure are exciting!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Liko has inherited Lucius’s belt!
Lookin’ sharp!
The adventure to gather
the Six Heroes begins!
This time, you will find
the black Rekkuuza!
The gang arrives in
the Galar Region’s Wild Area.
Ah...
Th-There’s a super delicious
scent in the air!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
With My Friends