My name is Roy.
I’m a Pokémon Trainer on an adventure
to meet strange Pokémon and solve their mysteries.
With Achigator, Taikaiden,
my new companion Lucario...
...and Cap, my journey goes on.
One day,
I got some info from Dot about
sightings of a Pokémon behaving abnormally,
and went to investigate.
What I found was a Kekking
enveloped in pink mist.
Together with Ult, who was chasing after me,
and his Yamirami, we managed to subdue it in battle...
But there’s no mistaking it...
That was the effect of Rakurium.
To tell her of these events,
I went to visit
my former companion, Liko.
Liko is continuing her Pokémon Trainer studies
at Sekiei Academy in the Kanto Region.
I have to let Liko know, quick!
What if the Rakurium,
which should have been destroyed, is actually...?
We have to do something about it!
I can see Sekiei Academy!
Here we go, Taikaiden!
Found you!
Liko!
Roy?!
Cap!
Have you guys been doing okay?
Yeah! But what brings you here?
I just had to see you, Liko.
I’ve got something important
to tell you.
Hey, who’s that?
Huh? Who could it be?
Look!
Uh... Hang on a second.
Looks like Liko-senpai knows him!
A transfer student?
He’s kinda cool!
It’s not what it looks like!
What’s up?
So cute!
Roy?!
It is you, isn’t it?
Anne! Long time, no see!
You got taller, didn’t you?
You look so cool!
Thanks!
But what brings you
to Sekiei Academy?
Liko. I have to tell you something.
Come with me, and...
Wait, stop!
Just hold on a moment...
We have today off,
so everyone’s doing stuff like battle practice
with their Pokémon, or going out into town.
Amazing!
There’s even a Lizardon here!
Everyone’s doing their best
to grow as trainers.
What a great place!
Hey, what’s that?
That’s the student dorm we live in.
It’s got a terrace and a cafeteria, too.
A cafeteria?!
You look like you’re doing well, Roy.
Glad to see you guys are, too.
It really has been a long time...
We haven’t talked since
we left the Brave Asagi, have we?
Oh, right! It did seem like you hadn’t been
keeping in touch with anyone...
The thing is...
The Rising Voltteccers disbanded.
Huh? What do you mean?
When we were escaping from Rakua,
which had been our journey’s destination...
...we got separated
from one of our crew members.
We looked around for a long time,
but we never could find him.
Exceed made the entire area around Mt. Kumuri,
where Rakua’s located, off-limits...
So we couldn’t even
continue our search.
We all discussed it...
...and decided to go our own ways.
I see... I had a hunch that
something must’ve happened, but...
Sounds like things
were rough for you guys.
I’m sorry I never told you.
Don’t be.
Thank you for telling me now.
So, Roy, what’ve you been up to?
I’ve been in the Kalos Region, doing some awesome training
just like when I was in the Rising Voltteccers—
Anne-senpai!
Excuse me,
could we borrow you a sec?
We’ve got some questions
about battling.
Oh, sure.
Let’s talk over there, okay?
See ya ‘round!
Okay.
That reminds me.
Just recently...
...Dot contacted me
for the first time in a while.
Huh? Dot did?
She said there was something
she wanted me to investigate.
There was a sighting of a Pokémon
enveloped in an eerie pink mist,
which got reported to Gurumin.
A pink mist...
Then, when I went to look into
the Kekking that was in the area...
The way it was acting totally lined up
with the effects of Rakurium.
Rakurium?! But back then, in Rakua...
Yeah. We thought we destroyed it.
But if this really is Rakurium...
No way...
It just can’t be...
We don’t know anything for sure yet.
But something is going on.
Is that what you wanted to tell me?
I need you guys’ help!
Dot said Pagogo might be able to tell
if it really is Rakurium!
Pagogo...
Liko?
Actually...
It hasn’t left its Monster Ball
even once since then.
Huh?
I see. Maybe it’s tired.
I’m sorry, Roy.
Huh?
I can’t help you.
Gotcha.
There’s still a lot we don’t know...
...so I’ll try investigating
a bit more with Dot.
Sorry.
Don’t sweat it!
Sorry ‘bout that!
Uhh... Huh? What happened?
Oh, well...
Hmm...
I’m thinking you two
need a good battle!
Anne?
Great idea! Let’s do it!
I actually got
a new partner in Kalos!
Huh? Masquernya?
Sorry, I’m gonna go look for her.
Okay... We’ll be in the courtyard.
Wanna battle while we wait for her?
I’ve been working real hard
as part of the school’s select team!
Right?
Okay! In that case...
Whoa! A yellow Lucario!
Awesome!
Now I’m really raring to go!
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Let the battle...
...begin!
Lucario! Luster Cannon!
Daikenki! Hydro Pump!
Keep it up and push through!
Dodge it, Lucario!
Man, you’re fast!
Now! Metal Claw!
Shell Blade!
Two-sword style?!
Good work, Lucario!
We’re not done yet!
Drill Liner!
Daikenki’s really tough!
There it is!
Daikenki’s three-sword style!
Lucario’s trainer is strong, too!
Hey, her opponent...
Huh? Isn’t he from
the Rising Voltteccers...?
Quick! Anne’s battling!
For reals?! Who’s she fighting?
Someone from the select team?
No idea.
Some boy I’ve never seen before.
Masquernya...
Where did you go?
This scent...
I know what that means!
That’s right. Let’s go, Tebrim!
I knew it... Masquernya!
Anne and Roy...
Roy’s Pokémon...
Lucario. Guiding Waves Pokémon.
Fighting/Steel type.
It’s said that it can even see invisible opponents,
through the detection of Guiding Waves.
That’s Roy’s new partner...?
Anne... Roy... Dot...
Everyone’s moving forward.
But I’m just...
I’m just not sure
that I’m doing enough.
Masquernya?
What’s wrong, Masquernya?
Amazing!
Neither side’s giving any ground!
So, just who is that guy
Anne’s fighting?
He’s not from Sekiei, is he?
Senpai...
You see, that boy is...
Huh?! He’s from
the Rising Voltteccers?!
Aren’t the Rising Voltteccers
that dangerous adventurer group?!
What’s one of those guys
doing with Anne?
Lucario! Focus your mind!
Let’s finish this now, Daikenki!
Drill Liner!
Sense the Guiding Waves, Lucario!
Lucario! Infight!
There!
Daikenki!
Great job, Lucario!
That was fun, Anne.
Yeah! You sure have
gotten strong, Roy!
Daikenki and I have gotta
keep working even harder!
Sorry I’m late, Roy.
Let’s battle, Liko!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
This’ll be our first fight
against her as a Masquernya.
Achigator, let’s show ‘em
the results of our training!
My first battle
against Achigator in so long...
Okay.
All right...
Both of you ready?
Let the battle begin!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Dodge it, Masquernya!
Masquernya!
Now it’s our turn!
Trick Flower!
Watch out, Achigator!
Achigator!
Masquernya...
You really are incredible!
Whoa! She’s not called
the Magician Pokémon for nothing!
Concentrate, Achigator!
Nitro Charge!
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Another Nitro Charge!
It’s super effective, Achigator!
Are you all right, Masquernya?
Got it.
Trick Flower!
If we try to track them by sight,
they’ll just misdirect us... In which case...
Achigator!
Use Charm Voice towards the sky!
Sing out with all you got!
Achigator’s song
has powered up, too...
Yup, thanks to
all the training we did!
We can’t let them outdo us!
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Give them
a full force Flamethrower!
Dodge it!
Wow! That blinding veil’s
a whole new way to battle!
Yeah. I can sense your feelings!
I can understand them now!
Achigator! We can’t let ‘em
outdo us, either!
Nitro Charge!
Masquernya! Tangle him up!
Bust out with Stomping Tantrum,
Achigator!
Huh? What?!
Achigator’s levitating!
Not exactly... Masquernya’s
got him tangled up in invisible vines!
Let’s give it a try!
We can’t move! In that case...
Achigator! Use Flamethrower!
Well done!
Masquernya’s flower is gone!
Where’d it go?
Trick Flower!
When did she...?!
Achigator!
I shoulda known...
You two have also gotten stronger!
You two are incredible, too!
Guess we’ve both powered up!
I see... So I haven’t
just been standing still.
Masquernya just proved that to me!
Masquernya! Shine in full bloom!
Achigator! Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
That’s Terastal!
Nitro Charge!
Magical Leaf!
Throw them off with Trick Flower!
We’re not done yet!
Achigator, use Nitro Charge!
Masquernya!
It’s over!
The winners are Roy and Achigator!
Masquernya...
Thank you, Masquernya.
You were both amazing!
Absolutely top-notch!
Um... Do you have a moment?
Huh? Me?
Are you... a member of
the Rising Voltteccers, by any chance?
I heard he was! You too, right?
Yeah. He said so himself.
He’s one of the Rising Voltteccers.
Yeah, I am. Right, Cap?
Anne-senpai... Should we really allow
someone like that onto school grounds?
Uh, well, you see...
What’s the meaning of this, Liko-senpai?
Explain yourself!
All right. I’ll explain.
Liko?
I never told you, but I’m...
...a member of
the Rising Voltteccers!
Let’s go, Pagogo.
So the rest of the school didn’t know
about the Rising Voltteccers, huh?
Yeah. But it’s better this way, don’tcha think?
Usually, Liko keeps her worries all bottled up.
Got that right.
I’ve gotten the feeling she’s had some kinda
cloud hanging over her this past year.
Here I am!
Now, let’s go, Roy!
Yeah!
We’re going to get it back!
What was stolen from us by the Explorers...
The truth of the Rising Voltteccers!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Whenever I want...
At any moment...
If I have Pokémon by my side,
I can start moving forward.
Let’s go, once again...
To the Skies Once More, Part Two
To our sky!
The world will be
kneeling before us in short order...
Just as they are.
Next episode
Man, this is a mega drag...
Where’d Roy run off to?
Hmm?
Oh, there he is!
Great work, Yamirami!
Huh? Who’s there?
Wha—?! Why’s he got a girl with him?!
What’s up, Liko?
I thought I heard a voice...
Anyway, I heard a Pokémon enveloped
in pink mist was sighted up ahead here.
What? Is that true?!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Follow the Rakurium Signs