After parting ways with Ms. Briar
at the Shining Pond,
we returned to Suiryoku Town.
There we met Ms. Sazare,
who gave us some information on Basagiri.
Now, we’ve arrived at Tengu Mountain.
More mountain hiking?
This can’t be happening!
Grumbling will just
tire you out even more!
Huh...? Where’s Nakanuchan?
Are you all right?
Let’s take a break, okay?
Basagiri is somewhere
on this mountain...
I hope we find it soon!
Yeah.
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Track It Down! Find Basagiri!!
So this is the photo Ms. Sazare took...
She really got a nice, clear shot!
Total pro photographer!
Right?
I’m just brimming with talent!
When I was little, people said
I was a total whiz kid at photography!
So you’ve been doing this
since you were a kid!
That’s amazing!
Ain’t it just?
Well, these days I like traveling all over,
meeting and snapping shots of all kindsa Pokémon.
The big draw of travel
is seeing stuff you never imagined!
Traveling to meet Pokémon
you never imagined, huh?
Sounds like fun!
And to help find them, I’ve got...
Professor Friede’s
Pokémon Distribution Map!
Huh?
I cannot believe I got to meet
the guy who made this!
This map’s accuracy
and ease of use is second to none!
You totally get it!
I’m planning on adding
a map of the Kitakami hamlet next!
Ooh, can’t wait!
Hey...
Huh?
Where on Tengu Mountain
did you see Basagiri?
Hmm...
Well to tell the truth, I dunno.
Huh?!
My memories after I got to this place
are kinda fuzzy, y’know?
First thing I recall...
I found myself deep in some forest...
...and Basagiri suddenly appeared,
so I engrossed myself
in hitting my shutter.
And then it raised up
a big axe to attack me.
I frantically ran all the way
down the mountain.
Honestly, I don’t even remember
which direction I fled.
It attacked you...
Sounds like it could be
pretty vicious.
Why are your memories so fuzzy?
Well, partway through it all started feeling
like I was in some kinda dream.
If you don’t remember
where you took that photo, then...
...for now, we’ll just need to look around
to try and find the spot.
Yeah.
Okay! Then we’ve got
no time to waste!
Let’s get moving!
Right!
Time is money!
All right! Let’s go, Achigator!
Ah! Hold on, Roy!
Do you have to run?
So, “The Six Heroes,” was it?
I asked you why
you were looking for Basagiri,
but ain’t this a little bit dangerous
for those schoolkids?
You think so?
They may seem like they’re just kids,
but they’re evolving every day.
Well, just wait and you’ll see.
Pay attention to your surroundings
as you head up!
You might find some clues!
Right!
Huh?
Achigator!
Whoa!
Roy! Achigator!
Oww...
Are you okay?!
Can you climb out?
I’m coming!
Whoa!
Ow!
No good...
Huh? A cave?
Looks like it goes pretty deep, too.
Roy! What’s going on?!
This leads into a cave!
We’re gonna try following it!
We might find Basagiri!
Got it. But be careful!
If anything happens,
tell me right away!
Roger!
We should get back to climbing.
Pokémon!
Whoa!
There’s all kinds of them
down here...
Hellgar!
Everyone, be careful!
There’s Delvil, too!
We’re surrounded.
We might’ve strayed
into their territory.
Over there!
Lizardon!
We’ll keep Hellgar
and the pack occupied.
Run into that forest
when you get the chance.
What about you guys?!
We’ll catch up later.
For now, just run
and don’t look back!
Lizardon, use Air Slash!
Cap, you use Thunder Punch!
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Now! Go!
Right!
Cap! Shadow Clones!
Nyarote! Lightning Speed!
Liko!
I’m fine! Go on ahead!
Got it!
Magical Leaf!
Now, then...
All we gotta do is let loose!
I don’t see an exit anywhere...
Umm...
Huh?
Which way did we come from?!
Achi?
That way?
Liko’s still not here.
I... think I’ve been here before.
Huh? You mean...
When you met Basagiri?
Probably.
I was walking through
this forest, and then...
Where are Dot and Ms. Sazare?
Did we get separated?
No answer...
Should we try doubling back,
Nyarote?
Huh?
What is it?
These scars...
It’s like it was slashed with a big axe.
Could Basagiri have done this?
Wh-Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Huh? What was I...?
Huh?
What were we just doing?
I think I saw an odd light
just before...
A light...
Now I remember!
It’s just like that day
in the forest...!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
What’s that?
Ohrot.
A Ghost/Grass-type Pokémon.
I’ve heard it attacks
anyone who harms its forest.
So we were tricked
by one of Ohrot’s moves.
Must’ve been Eerie Light.
Falling for the same trick twice...
I never learn, do I?
Guess it doesn’t plan on
letting us escape, eh?
We’ll have to battle it!
Counting on that strength
you showed in yesterday’s battle, schoolkid!
It’s Eerie Light!
Everyone, shut your eyes!
That’s gonna be a big hurdle...
We can’t even battle
if we don’t get around that.
When I give the signal,
could you use Ember?
Oh, got a plan?
Guardie!
Right.
Okay!
Welcamo, use Water Gun!
Now!
Guardie, use Ember!
Ooh!
Air Cutter!
Phew...
We did it!
You were so cool too, Guardie!
I’m starving...
Huh?
A river?
Berries?
But berries don’t grow in caves...
Maybe they’re coming from outside?
Which means...!
We made it out!
Doesn’t look like
we can go any further.
In that case...
All right...
Achigator, let’s climb up here!
Phew...
Took ‘em long enough to clear off.
Lizardon! Your time to shine!
Time to track them down from the sky!
Look!
A third set of scars...
They’re fresher than the others.
Which means we’re
getting closer to Basagiri.
It almost feels like these scars
are guiding me some place...
Is Basagiri purposefully
leaving signs behind?
But Ms. Sazare said it attacked her
out of the blue...
So... Could these be warning signs,
rather than guiding the way?
Telling me not to come any closer?
If it doesn’t want anyone
to find it, then...
I know!
Tebrim, do you sense anything
from this mountain?
Like anger, or hatred, or fear...
Any kind of awful feeling like that?
She’s relaxed...
If the mountain is at peace,
then Basagiri must be, too...
Thank you, Tebrim.
Let’s keep heading this way!
We drove that Ohrot off...
But we still got nothing
for clues, don’t we?
Ms. Sazare, can you show me
that photo of Basagiri one more time?
Huh? Oh, sure...
It’s just a close-up shot of Basagiri...
And I really dunno where I took it.
Import the photo...
...then zoom in...
Ah, I see.
Huh?
This plant that you can just make out
behind Basagiri is pretty distinctive.
There aren’t any of them around here...
So if we can find those trees, we might find the place.
Its habitat is...
Wetlands.
We should be looking
near ponds or swamps.
Plus...
This rock shaped like a Dugtrio.
That’ll be a nice, big
landmark to look for.
Ooh! You’re right.
I’d better let everyone know.
Liko?
Dot! Glad to hear from you!
Listen, I found a clue to Basagiri!
Scars used as signs, huh?
Interesting.
I have some info to share, too...
A Dugtrio-shaped rock, right?
Got it!
I made it out of the cave,
and I’m climbing the cliff now.
Scars caused by an axe
and a Dugtrio-shaped rock, huh?
We’ll try to find them
from the sky, too.
Okay, info sharing all wrapped up.
So, how about we get going?
What’s wrong?
“Time is money,” right?
Yeah, sure is.
“Evolving every day,” eh?
Huh?
All right!
Lemme get a snap of that face!
I’ll pull you up now, Achigator!
Looks like we’re about halfway up.
Whoa!
What?!
What’s with them?!
They’re angry!
Maybe this cliff is their territory?
Gah...
We’ve got nowhere to run!
Then...
Achigator,
get on Taikaiden’s back!
Go, Taikaiden!
We can battle as a team, too!
Dodge it!
That’s it!
Rush straight in, Taikaiden!
Follow it up with Spark!
Good job! One more time!
Huh?
Oh, no!
Circle around them, Taikaiden!
Achigator! Charm Voice!
We did it!
These are the same leaves!
No doubt about it!
Meaning that rock
should be nearby, too...
Hey, schoolkid.
You take pride in
all your wild adventures and stuff?
Me...? No way.
For the longest time,
I was cooped up in my room.
If I hadn’t met Friede,
I’d never have gotten to board his ship.
When I did go outside, so many things were
new to me, and I had so many shortcomings...
So now I’m getting as much experience as I can;
to catch up with everyone else!
Y’know, I was in a slump
until just recently.
Huh?
I was stressing about
not being able to snap good photos.
But then, I realized something.
If I simply chase the Pokémon I love,
and engross myself in getting them on camera...
In time, the results will come naturally.
What I’m saying is...
Looking at you,
engrossed in your daily struggles...
You’re already on a grand adventure,
in my book!
T-Time is money, right?
Ah!
Another sign!
They’re definitely not warning signs!
All kinds of Pokémon are enjoying
their lives here on the mountain.
Basagiri hasn’t shut everyone else out...
So maybe it’s waiting
for someone to arrive?
Huh? The shape of these scars...
I feel like I’ve seen it before...
Oh, there she is!
Dot! Ms. Sazare!
I’m so glad to see you!
So you found the rock, too.
Huh? Rock?
So this is the Dugtrio rock?
Grab on!
Nearly there...
And heave!
Roy!
Oh! You’re all here, too!
Hey!
So you’re all together.
Yeah!
Ooh, that’s a fine expression!
Lemme snap that!
If we combine
all the clues we’ve found...
It really narrows down
the area Basagiri could be hiding in.
Yeah. We’re really
getting close now.
They’ve got a lot of promise.
Earlier, you said
those kids were “evolving”...
I think I get it now.
Each of them forged a path in their own way,
and all arrived at the same place.
How fast they’re evolving
never fails to blow us away.
All right, everyone!
We better get going!
We’re only one step away
from Basagiri!
And the signs to look for...
...are these scars!
Yeah!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Scout Pokémon, Hisuian Guardie.
Guardie (Hisuian Form)
Scout Pokémon
Type: Fire/Rock
Guardie (Hisuian Form)
Scout Pokémon
Type: Fire/Rock
A Pokémon once discovered
in the Hisui Region.
Height   0.8m
Form seen in other regions
Its distinctive fur is longer
than that of other Guardie.
Weight   22.7kg
But do you know why its fur is so long?
Why does it have longer fur than other Guardie?
To keep out sound
To keep out the cold
To keep out smells
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Why does it have longer fur
than other Guardie?
B: To keep out the cold
Why does it have longer fur
than other Guardie?
B: To keep out the cold
The answer is B: To keep out the cold!
Thick fur retains heat better,
s-so even in the c-cold of H-Hisui...
...it can frolic around without a care!
Next episode
Basagiri really was here!
It looks really strong...
Has it been training all this time?!
Looks like it’s raring for a battle...
The others aren’t here.
What do we do?
We’ll just have to
take it on ourselves!
Yeah!
Let’s all do our best!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters...
Ready, and...
The Lone Warrior - Basagiri
Let’s hit it with all we’ve got!