pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
I want you to find...
...the world’s true beauty.
...adventures...
...as you live alongside
the Pokémon of this world.
And...
...your futures!
Found it!
Route 22...
Yep, no mistake.
Hey!
Sorry I kept you waiting!
You been well?
Yeah!
Someone you know?
I don’t know her.
Ack... I messed up.
So awkward...
“Don’t know,” huh...?
I’ve heard that one before.
“I just don’t know what you’re thinking”...
Well, don’t look at me.
I don’t know either.
But...
Oh, thank you...
I want to learn things I don’t know.
That’s what brought me
all this way... I think.
Welcome, all you Pokémon Trainers
out there!
Y’all been groovin-vin’?
It’s a vid from Gurumin!
She said Yo-ssu Kuwa-ssu...
That’s Gurumin! I know her!
Actually, I’m a fan too...
And... I’d like to tell them that...
But I wouldn’t know
how to put it...
...so I’d better not.
It’s always like this.
I get so caught up in what might happen,
I totally freeze.
My first time in the Kanto Region...
There are so many Pokémon
I’ve never seen before! I’m amazed!
The Pendant of Beginnings, Part One
I hope I find
what I’m looking for here.
It was incredible,
bet it tasted great—
Found it!
Room 303... This is the place!
Aw, man...
Where’d I leave my toothbrush?
Hmm?
Oh...
Err... my mistake.
There was... someone in there.
Wasn’t there?
Yes, there was!
Did I get the wrong room?
It’s the right room...
Nope, no mistake!
Room 303, yeah?
U-Uh... Y-Yes.
C-Could she... hear my thoughts?
I’m Anne, your roommate!
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you.
I’m Liko.
I’m a bit messy!
She’s pretty intense...
I’ve never met anyone quite like her before.
Huh, you’re from the Paldea Region?
I’ve never been.
Is it nice there?
Um... Let’s see...
Yeah, it’s nice enough.
Hey, you ever seen a Pamo?
Yeah.
But it ran off right away.
I’m jealous...
I’ve never been outside Kanto.
Same for me.
I haven’t been outside Paldea until now.
Really? Then how’d you end up
coming to school here?
Well...
When I asked my mother
and father about school,
they told me about this place;
how they both went here.
Huh... That’s so nice!
Honestly, I feel like
there’s so much I just don’t know...
Then I’ll show you around
Tokiwa City sometime!
You’d do that, Anne-san?
Oh, just call me Anne!
You’re fine with just Liko, right?
Huh? Yeah.
Anne...
Goriky! Explosive Punch!
Reflector!
Follow up with Psychokinesis!
Wasn’t that move amazing?!
Yeah.
Will I get to have battles
like that too, someday?
So hey... After the entrance ceremony,
it’ll finally be time, y’know?
Time? For what?
What else?
Our partner Pokémon!
Right! A partner...
My own partner Pokémon...
My heart’s been racing so much,
I’ve avoided thinking about that.
No! I can’t! If I do that...!
Liko, how’d your interviews
and stuff go?
My interviews...
Right after I was accepted here,
I had several online interviews;
discussing teachers, Pokémon, and more.
They said I should rest assured
I’d find a perfect partner for myself here.
But I’m so used to hearing
“I just don’t know what you’re thinking”...
...that I’m worried
they may not have really understood me.
They were tense, I guess.
Just how it goes.
No, you can’t just run off like that!
I’m sorry!
I bet you can’t wait!
Y-Yeah...
My partner...
I’m nervous.
It was a day filled with new experiences.
Leaving home,
living on my own at school...
I...
...c-can’t sleep.
One thing led to another,
and tomorrow’s the entrance ceremony.
The day I finally meet
my partner Pokémon.
Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
This planet’s strange, strange creatures.
You can find Pokémon in the sea, the sky,
forests, cities... most everywhere.
People and Pokémon forge all manner of bonds,
living together in this world.
And so, here at Sekiei Academy,
I hope that you will bond
with your Pokémon and find your dreams.
Are you all with me so far?
All right then.
Everyone, please restart
your Smartphone Rotoms.
After that, you’ll be able to
use your Pokémon Indexes.
My Pokémon Index...
Next up is the meetup
we’ve been waiting for!
My partner Pokémon...
What will it be like?
My heart’s pounding.
Next, Anne-san.
Here! Here I am!
Go ahead.
Sure!
Next, Hiro-san.
Mijumaru!
All right!
Nice to meet you!
Mijumaru’s data
was added to the Index.
Next, Liko-san.
H-Here!
Go ahead.
When meeting someone,
your first impression is really important.
My... partner...
Nyahoja’s data
was added to the Index.
Nyahoja...
S—
So cute!
Ow!
Okay everyone,
that will be all for today.
Right!
Rotom, tell me about Nyahoja.
Nyahoja. Grass Cat Pokémon.
Grass type.
When Nyahoja kneads and rubs
with its forepaws,
a sweet aroma is released
that can mesmerize those around it.
E-Excuse me.
Why? Why? Why?! No! No!
I never expected a twist like this!
Oh, right!
My best lead is
Nyahoja’s Sweet Scent.
If I follow this scent...
Did she... go up there?
The scent is stronger here, but...
Found her!
Being up there is dangerous!
Why did you go up there?
What were you thinking?
Wait! I didn’t mean—
Stop! Stop! Stop!
No way!
I thought I was done for...
I-I’m sorry!
Ah! Wait!
Jeez... Why?
Wasn’t I supposed to find
my perfect partner?
Nyahoja!
What a relief!
What a nice scent...
Ow!
Why...?
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’? It’s a vid from Gurumin!
What? “What’s a Pokémon Trainer?”, you ask?
Well, when someone raises Pokémon to compete
in Pokémon battles, we call that someone a Pokémon Trainer!
And all of those Pokémon Trainers
have their eyes on the same prize...
To be a Champion!
One thing led to another,
and my partnership with Nyahoja began, but...
I’m nervous.
My first battle
went about how I expected...
Um...
Nyahoja, use Leaf—
Mijumaru! Water Gun!
I’m sorry, Nyahoja!
Not much of a battle
if you go and do that.
You’re always so reckless...
I just don’t know what you’re thinking.
Oh. Now that sounds familiar.
Does that mean Nyahoja and I...
have something in common?
Also, you gotta coordinate strategy
and attack as a team...
Hey, are you listening?
Sorry.
Yeah, I’ll try my best.
Yo-ssu!
In Pokémon battles,
trainers command Pokémon to use the moves
they’ve mastered in clashes of strength!
All sortsa things can affect a battle,
but top of the list is type match-ups.
For example,
Fire types’re strong against Grass types,
and Grass types’re strong
against Water types, and so on!
Understanding the 18 types
when you challenge someone is the key to victory!
This spot became our own
little secret training ground.
Nyahoja! Leafage!
But...
Leafage!
No good, huh...?
The moon feels so far away...
Even if I stretch out my hand,
I can’t possibly reach it...
Nyaho—
Shh!
What’s up?
D-Did I wake you?
What’s that?
Uh, um...
A good-luck charm...?
A good-luck charm?
I got it from my grandma.
It’s meant to keep me safe.
Ooh...
Can I touch it?
Yeah.
Why hide it away?
It’d look great on you!
Yeah...
I feel like it’s just not time yet...
That so?
I came here hoping
I could find something for myself...
but maybe I won’t find anything...
even here...
Mijumaru’s in a good mood.
What’s Nyahoja up to?
Hmm... Probably napping.
Oh, look! It’s an airship!
That’s a rare sight, Liko!
What’s up?
Something bugging you?
I really envy you and Mijumaru...
Nyahoja on your mind?
Isn’t it nice that she’s so free-spirited?
I’m not so sure...
You have a tough time
getting others to understand you, right?
Maybe Nyahoja has
the same problem.
You’ve gotta really show her
who you are!
What does that even mean?
It sounds tough.
Nyahoja?
I... When I want to do something...
Even if I want to tell someone...
I can’t find the words.
What about you?
What do you want to do?
You can tell me.
I want to learn more about Nyahoja.
If I do that, I can work out
what both I and Nyahoja want to do... hopefully.
I haven’t found it yet.
But I have to look for it myself!
So that’s it.
See you!
See ya!
It’s hopeless!
All their faces look the same!
Not all of them, surely.
Keep at it.
We can’t find her.
Nyahoja has several
favorite sunbathing spots.
I found you.
Nyahoja!
Wait!
Please! Stop being so reckless!
Oh... If you’re going to do that...
I’ll squeeze your paw pads!
What a nice scent...
Ugh... And we need to
find her fast, too...
Any luck?
Not one bit.
We can’t find her.
All right!
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Wait...
Huh?
Seriously... You’re so fickle.
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Is this it?
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Been a while
since I’ve gone home!
Time to kick back!
And I need to show everyone Mijumaru!
This is our first long break.
Aren’t you going back to Paldea?
I’m fine here.
My mother and father
will be busy, anyway.
That so? Well then, I’ll leave you
and Nyahoja to look after the place!
Right!
Have a nice trip!
See you!
Should we head back?
We’re off!
Excuse me.
Yes?
I’m here looking for someone.
I have written permission here.
Sure. If you’d excuse me for a minute.
Oh, Liko-san, someone’s here to see you.
Pleased to meet you.
Liko-san, correct?
Y-Yes...
And who might you be?
I am here on behalf of your grandmother.
I have this letter from her.
A letter?
Huh? A letter from
my grandma? What?
Never mind that, this man...
Um, what is thi—?
All will be explained in time.
In essence, she urges you to bring her
your cherished pendant without fail.
Nyahoja, that’s rude.
I’ll go and get ready.
Just wait right here.
No! No, no, no, no, no!
Who is that man?!
A letter from
my grandma, that’s...!
Something’s weird about this!
And...
“Bring her the pendant”?
That’s so suspicious!
Pardon me.
Why couldn’t she just behave
and come with me...?
She ran. Secure the area.
Have you found her?
No. I suspect she is hiding somewhere.
What a nuisance.
There she is!
Y-Yikes!
There you are!
Go, Saidon!
Saidon?!
Huh? Wait, Nyahoja wants to fight!
Guess we’ve got to...
Nyahoja, Leafage!
Hah! You really think you can
beat us with that pitiful Leafage?!
Right...
We don’t need to beat them...
Nyahoja!
Once more, Leafage!
W-We did it, Nyahoja!
Oh right, no time for that!
Wh-What...
What have I gotten into?!
But anyway, we pulled off a move!
Or, well, did that really count...?
What?! What is even going on?!
Where did she go?
She fled up there.
Stop right there!
Be good and hand over the pendant,
or I’ll have to use force.
As if that’s going to
change my mind...!
Found you!
What?! Someone else showed up!
Who are you?!
I could ask you the same question.
I have business with that girl.
As do we.
Well then, let’s decide this
with a Pokémon battle.
Soublades!
Just what I was hoping for!
Stay out of this.
Sword of Regrets!
Flamethrower!
Soublades! Crossroad Kill!
Lizardon! Dragon Claw!
Wh-Wh-What is this...?
What’s going on?
I can’t process any of this!
The school’s in danger,
caught in the crossfire like this!
We can’t let them
do any more damage...
Hey, wait! Hey!
Wait... I’d have to jump this gap...
I-I know!
If I don’t step forward...
I won’t find anything!
Huh? What’s she going to—?!
Psycho Cutter!
Ready... and...
Huge preview time!
All you trainers out there!
Liko and Nyahoja’s huge adventure
has finally begun!
Just as these guys after Liko’s precious pendant
show up and things are lookin’ real, real bad...
...another guy shows up!
A mysterious trainer with a Lizardon!
This “Hey! Where do ya think yer takin’
Liko and Nyahoja! Hold it!” twist...
...has my heart pounding non-stop too!
And so!
To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
The Pendant of Beginnings, Part Two