We heard stories of a Laplace that used its song
to rescue ships lost in the white mist.
Could it be Laplace of the Six Heroes?
The Brave Asagi
hurried off to investigate,
but something strange
happened out at sea.
Upon clearing the fog, we saw a group
of Pokémon approaching the ship...
...and we saw Laplace.
You are the Hero Laplace!
What?!
Lucky!
Iwanko!
Hold it!
We’ll take you on!
Us too, Nyahoja!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Laplace's Feelings For Its Friends
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Hogator! Ember!
What do we do?
There are just too many!
Divine Speed!
Windie!
Are you all okay?
Grandma!
We’ll back you up!
Friede! You, too!
You two did great.
Now, then...
Please refrain from boarding
the ship unless permitted to do so!
Stop!
Laplace!
After them!
All right!
They got us good...
What do you mean?
“A kindhearted Laplace who
guides ships lost in the mist”...
Or so we assumed.
Huh?
But then fog rolled in out of the blue.
Almost as if it was done on purpose.
And it was one of Laplace’s moves.
Exactly.
It shrouds passing ships in White Mist
to make them get lost.
Oh, no...
But it saved us with its song!
That, too, was part of Laplace’s plan.
And this silhouette...
...means it had company.
That was Whaleoh.
Yep.
Thanks to Cap clearing the mist,
we’ve got the full picture.
You don’t mean...?
That’s right.
While Laplace was distracting us
with its song in the mist,
its companions—
meaning Whaleoh and the rest—
would sneak on board
to steal our supplies.
That was the truth behind
the song in the white mist?
They were just after our food?!
The captain of that freight ship
was totally duped by Laplace,
never realizing that it was the culprit
behind his missing cargo.
Can’t believe you figured all that out.
The non-native Pokémon were a crucial hint,
especially considering how they’re unable to swim.
They’d need an ally
to ferry them across the sea.
And that ally was Whaleoh?
The ship shaking
just before Laplace appeared...
...was likely caused by
Whaleoh’s approach.
Laplace may have traveled to a variety of regions
to gather all those companions.
I suppose we could call them
the Laplace Pirates!
P-Pirates?!
It actually formed its own team...?
Yeah...
I’ve heard Laplace are highly intelligent,
but I didn’t expect this...
I had the two of you confirm
that they really were coming to swipe our food.
You should’ve told us!
We were freaking out back there, you know!
Sorry about that.
Good grief...
Why would Laplace
and the others do that?
Yeah, for real!
Stealing people’s food and berries...
Do you think
what they’re doing is wrong?
Huh?
Y-Yeah...
From our perspective, it might be...
But how does Laplace feel, I wonder?
How Laplace feels?
Whaleoh! We caught up!
You’re amazing, Gramps!
This was his ship once.
He’s second to none when it comes to sailing!
Like a Gyarados in water, no?
Orio! Time to bring it home!
Give it all we’ve got!
Okay!
If you would, Lizardon!
Go, go!
All right!
We’ve got ‘em trapped now!
It looks to me like
they’ve trapped us.
Well, they’re raring to go...
Oh, no!
Worry not!
Huh?
Gramps?
Have faith in my Nuoh!
Nuoh?!
When did you...?
Hold on tight!
Nuoh’s Surf can be a little rough!
Hard to starboard!
To port!
Fine waves, Nuoh!
You’re awesome, Gramps!
A trifle.
They stopped attacking?
All right!
Now to cut past Whaleoh
and get to Laplace...
Laplace!
Trying to help its friends escape, huh?
Oh, no! Everybody get down!
T-Talk about intense!
I don’t believe it!
It’s got guts!
We’ve been had...
An Ice Beam!
And...
A crazy strong one, too!
Th-The ship’s...
...completely stuck!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Wait, Laplace!
It’s gone...
It wasn’t worried for even a second.
Hrmm... It won’t budge...
As elusive as mist...
Can’t lay hold of it,
no matter how hard you try.
I doubt it’ll show itself again.
Oh, no...
Come on! What do we do now?
Are we just giving up?!
Hardly.
Laplace is out on the ocean.
We’ll find it for sure!
“Out on the ocean”...
How are we supposed to
search something that big?!
Laplace...
It seemed to hesitate for a moment
when it saw Terapagos.
Hesitate?
I think Laplace has
something on its mind...
So... I want to
get to know Laplace, too!
All the more reason
we have to see it again.
But how do we...?
Liko, look!
That’s... an empty berry box, right?
Yeah. There was one just like it
floating by when we first got here, too.
That must be the cargo belonging
to the captain we met at the port.
It must’ve drifted over here
after Laplace tossed it out...
Drifted...
Oh! Then that means...
What’s up, Liko?
If we can’t chase it,
then we should just wait for Laplace!
Oh?
Wait for it?
Yeah. It’ll be fine.
I will get through to it.
Hey there, Laplace!
We’ve been waiting for you.
H-Hope we aren’t a bother!
You surprised?
Once Liko deduced where your base was,
we flew straight here on this guy.
The empty berry boxes!
There were a lot of them nearby,
so I figured it’d be here!
Wait! I wanted you to see Terapagos!
This sure is impressive.
It befriended them in no time at all.
Yup.
Impressive is a pretty good word for it.
Yeah.
Laplace, I need you to listen!
Terapagos wants to go to Rakua!
The paradise you all found
alongside Lucius...
I still don’t know where it is,
or what kind of place it is...
...but I want to grant Terapagos’s wish!
That’s why I came to see you, Laplace...
Because you used to be
one of Lucius’s companions!
Please, Laplace!
Help this little one!
This is...
Lucius!
Thank you, everyone.
Leave this to me.
I won’t die.
I promise you.
I will live on with Rakua,
and we will meet again!
Did it get some power from that?
That’s good.
They made a promise with Lucius, huh?
And that’s why Terapagos
wants to go to Rakua.
A promise... So that’s why Oliva and
Galarian Fire came with Terapagos...
Why they came with us!
You mean we can eat this?!
Seems they’re giving us a warm welcome.
Ah, there’s the ship!
Hey!
Looks like it worked out!
What happened to the ice?
That stuff was no match for Windie!
Hey, guys! I’ve got tasty doughnuts,
fresh from the oven!
Let’s all dig in!
Is this how Laplace and the others
have been living all this time?
Working together to obtain food,
then sharing that food with friends...
Our ideas of good and bad
don’t apply here.
That is just how they live.
One way of living in nature.
Grandma...
Pokémon and people...
...find many different ways
to coexist in this world.
They don’t always stand side by side.
But what bridges the divide
between Pokémon and people...
...are Pokémon Trainers, Liko!
Yes.
Ah, I’m stuffed!
Laplace.
I need to ask something.
Will you keep your promise to Lucius
and accompany us to Rakua?
An Ancient Monster Ball!
They’ve been keeping it safe!
White Mist...
Whaleoh could use it, too?
They’ll be able to keep living their way!
They’re gone...
They’ll be fine.
They’ve got the strength to live on!
Now we have half of the Six Heroes!
Which means we’ve gotten closer
to the black Rekkuuza, right?
Rekkuuza?!
Y-You’re kidding!
To think that it came to us!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cute & sweet Pokémon!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Varinich,
Tarpple, Mawhip!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Murdock here. Dot... Just watch this!!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Vanirich,
Tarpple, Mawhip! Yes!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
So much happened, but it’s great how
you finally got through to Laplace, Liko!
But, uh... Wait! Rekkuuza?!
That’s outta nowhere!
I get how you feel...
But for now, deep breaths...
All right!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters:
The Bellowing Black Rekkuuza
Huh? What’s up with you, Terapagos?!
Another day bursting with energy!
Terapagos’s Sparkly Exploration Diary!
Terapagos's Sparkly Exploration Diary
This is where you’ve been?