My name is Liko.
The drive to discover, the drive to learn...
These are the feelings
that set us on our journey.
Terapagos, who awoke from
my mysterious pendant,
was a peculiar Pokémon
that wasn’t even in the Pokémon Index.
Terapagos hopes to find Rakua.
But to do that, we must find
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes...
...and recover Terapagos’s power.
We are the Rising Voltteccers...
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we’re headed to the Paldea Region.
A job?!
Yeah.
A request came in from
an archaeologist friend.
What’s the job?
He wants us to move a rock that’s getting
in the way of some ruin excavation work.
A rock?
Do we have to take it far?
No, apparently we just
need to get it away from the ruins.
A rock, huh?
But if that’s all, the pay can’t be
anything to write home about, right?
This is what we’ll make.
That much?!
Just for moving a rock?!
You in?
How could we turn down
such a lucrative offer?
A new job!
And so, to help move the rock,
we headed to the excavation site.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Hogator Turns Bad?!
The sunlight in the desert
is harsh and blinding.
But Terapagos seems to enjoy
basking in the sun.
And as for Roy...
Rekkuuza appeared!
Skreek!
Whoa! Rekkuuza attacked!
Skree!
Bam-bam-bam-bam-bam-bam!
Hogator!
Attack Rekkuuza back with a new move!
Go! Hogator!
Hogator!
You okay?
I guess pulling off
a new move isn’t that easy...
But...
If we battled Rekkuuza right now,
we wouldn’t stand a chance.
We gotta train, Hogator!
Ooh, juice from Tsubotsubo!
Thanks, Yukiwarashi!
Time for a drink!
Ice-cold Berry Juice!
That was great!
Thank you, Tsubotsubo.
Thanks, Liko.
Don’t mention it.
Huh? Roy...
Are you angry?
Huh? No, not at all.
Oh, it was the blinding sun.
Your face was so scrunched up,
I thought you were mad about something.
The sunshine is really harsh in the desert.
What you need are sunglasses.
Here, Roy.
Ooh!
Don’t I...
...look cool?!
Mm-hmm!
Liko.
Huh?
Personally, I don’t find it
all that bright...
Hogator?
Do you want to
try on these sunglasses?
Hogator! You look so cool!
You look like you’re could totally
pull off a new move!
So...
When are we supposed
to be moving this rock?
Apparently,
things have been rough on-site.
We’re waiting on a call from him
to give us the go-ahead.
Of course.
No such thing as easy money...
The machines are running!
That means work’s underway, right?
We can finally move that rock.
Gah! They’re back! Run for it!
Did something happen?
I’ll go check it out.
Cap.
Oh, Friede.
Hey.
I thought I’d see how things were going.
Right...
Is this the rock
you need us to move, Professor?
Yeah. We were making preparations...
...when those savage Pokémon
attacked us again.
Savage Pokémon?
Pokémon did this?
Yeah.
We’ve seen Waruvial
and Waruvile for certain.
So far, we haven’t had any injuries...
But regardless, we can’t work
under these conditions.
Next time they come ‘round to be a nuisance,
we’ll have these Pokémon exterminate them.
We’ll resume work as soon as
our machines are repaired.
Sorry, but you’ll have to
wait until then.
Exterminate them?!
That’s horrible!
Even so, keep in mind
they’ve been attacked several times.
For now, I’m going to investigate
what’s going on inside the ruins.
I wanna go too!
Me too!
No! Waruvial and the other Pokémon
behind the attacks are down there.
I’m going with Cap.
But we wanna help everyone out, too!
We won’t do anything dangerous!
Please, Friede!
Please, Cap!
No taking matters into
your own hands, you hear me?
Right!
Whoa... Amazing!
First, we’re going to look for signs of
Waruvial and company.
Right!
What is it, Cap?
Hogator?!
You okay?
What’s that?
Meguroco. Desert Croc Pokémon.
Ground/Evil type.
It submerges itself in sand
and moves as if swimming.
It evolves into Waruvile,
then Waruvial.
Is that one of the nuisance Pokémon
Friede was talking about?
Hogator!
It burrowed to get away...
We gotta tell Friede, quick!
Wh-What?!
Waruvial, Waruvile,
and Meguroco tracks.
Quite a few of them, at that.
Do you think it’s a big group?
Yeah.
Seems like Waruvial and its friends
make their nest near here.
Liko. Roy. Don’t leave my side.
Right.
Roy?!
That’s...
Waruvial and Waruvile!
Newly-hatched Meguroco!
They kinda look like a mom and dad.
This must be where the little one
we saw before came from.
This kinda feels like...
Yeah, no doubt about it!
Hogator, you got the beat?
All right, let’s go!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Roy! Hogator!
Where are you?!
I can’t believe him...
What is it, Cap?
Cap?
What is it?
Wh-What?
“Follow me”?!
Wh-What’s going on?!
Liko!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Roy?
What?
Sing out nice and loud!
Meguroco! Waruvile! Waruvial!
Raise up your voices!
Sing out nice and loud!
Meguroco! Waruvile! Waruvial!
Raise up your voices!
What is he doing?
Meguroco! Waruvile! Waruvial!
Roy is such an enigma...
Break out into dance!
Raise up your voices!
But... could they really be the “savage” Pokémon
behind the attacks at the dig site?
Meguroco! Waruvile! Waruvial!
What was that move just now?
That move is called Round.
Friede!
Excellent work, Roy! You managed to
make friends with Waruvial and the others!
Nah, that was all
thanks to Hogator’s singing!
You know, Friede...
I could tell they were
having a lot of fun singing with me.
There’s no way Waruvial and her family
deserve to be called “savage” Pokémon!
What?!
The excavation team
is starting up again!
The noise and vibrations
are reaching all the way down here...
Then maybe Waruvial and her family
weren’t trying to hurt anyone...
...but instead trying to
stop all this noise?
Not good! He said they’d be exterminated
next time they showed up!
Then...
Roy!
I gotta stop Waruvial and the others!
We better go, too!
Yeah!
Seems like Waruvial and company
are back to cause trouble.
We’ve got no choice.
Take care of them.
Right!
Chillarmy! Magical Shine!
Waruvile!
All right! Horudo! Arm Hammer!
Wait!
Waruvial and her friends
aren’t troublemakers!
Chillarmy!
Horudo!
Waruvial! Waruvile! Stop!
Waruvial and the others...
They’re all in a blind rage...
Hogator, stop them with Tackle!
Hogator!
What now? I’ve gotta do something
to calm them all down!
Hogator?
Hogator...
Roy!
Liko! Friede!
Hogator, you...
Hogator! Go for it!
Seems like they’ve calmed down.
What a relief.
That move... Was that...?
It was Charm Voice.
Charm Voice?
Amazing, Hogator!
You got a new move!
Hogator was incredible, wasn’t he?
I see...
So the noise from the excavation
was disturbing their nest.
I understand. I’ll think this over.
That’d be a big help.
However...
That does mean we’ll have to
wait on moving that rock.
Gotcha.
Though we do need it moved soon...
Move...
...this?
...or it’ll just continue to
delay our excavation work.
I know!
You were taking forever,
so we came to check on you...
...but what are you getting up to now?
They did it!
Ooh! Marvelous!
Now we don’t even need your ship
to move the rock!
Which means...
...after all that...
...our pay...
...was also obliterated?
Though they obliterated our pay,
Roy and Hogator...
See you again!
Waruvial! Waruvile! Meguroco!
...seem to have gained something
even more valuable.
Apparently, the excavation team is going to
take breaks during Meguroco nap time.
And the Rising Voltteccers’
travels continue!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, we’ll be taking a look at
the Intimidation Pokémon, Waruvial.
Waruvial
Intimidation Pokémon
Type: Ground/Evil
Waruvial
Intimidation Pokémon
Type: Ground/Evil
A savage Pokémon, also known as
the gangster of the sands.
Height
1.5m
There’s a secret to those eyes
that look like sunglasses,
Weight
96.3kg
but do you know what it is?
What special thing can Waruvial's eyes do?
Repel water
Block light
See far away
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
Exciting and thrilling
An adventure is starting
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cheerful bird Pokémon!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Cheerful bird Pokémon
Y'all been groovin'? It's Gurumin!!
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What special thing can Waruvial's eyes do?
C: See far away
The answer is C: See far away!
Waruvial’s eyes are able to
act as binoculars.
They let it spot prey, even at a distance.
Letting your guard down for an instant
can cost you your life in the desert.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Mibrim picks up all kinds of feelings
from everyone, right?
Exciting feelings!
Sad feelings...
But this time, Mibrim has picked up...?
Yeah! An SOS!
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters:
An SOS From a Wakkanezumi?