On the road to our Terastal Course
implementation tests,
we’ve arrived at Champuru Town.
An unexpected turn of events led to
us needing to chip in at the Anything Eatery...
...but it all worked out in the end.
And now, it’s finally time for
Dot’s implementation test.
Huh?!
Gym Leader Aoki-san isn’t here?!
I do apologize.
Aoki’s out making the rounds right now.
Making the rounds?
He’s gone out to meet with Gym clients.
He should still be
somewhere in town, though.
Such a pain...
I wanna get to passing my
implementation test already!
You’re quite confident...
You got a plan for the test?
‘Course I do!
I’ve studied every last one of
Aoki-san’s battle vids...
And since we have to use
two Pokémon in our implementation tests,
I’ve come up with strategies
for both Kuwassu and Kanuchan!
Oh, geez... Are you okay?
They’ve got plenty of fighting spirit, huh?
There, there... There, there...
Okay, how about
we start looking for Aoki-san?
Easier said than done, though...
Yeah...
Kuwassu?
What’s going on?
Wait!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Dance, Kuwassu!
The Blue Champuru Step!!
Where’s Kuwassu?
There’s lots of people here.
Over there!
Kuwassu! You can’t just run off like that!
One last dance step!
Odoridori! Use Feather Dance!
Ooh...
Wow!
Awesome!
Do you wanna dance with us?
No way!
We can’t waste time like that!
We need to find Aoki-san, quick!
Oh, are you guys looking for
Gym Leader Aoki-san?
Do you know him?
Sure do!
He’s a big name in this town.
You wanna know where he is?
Yeah, please!
Okay! But first...
Let’s get acquainted by dancing together.
Huh?
Yay!
Gah, guess I’ve got no choice.
Kuwassu, show your stuff!
He’s doing Kick Down dance steps!
So cool!
Not half bad.
Now, we oughta turn it up, too!
Odoridori! Come on!
Those movements...
That’s Awakening Dance!
Ooh! So pretty!
Kuwassu?
He’s doing the same dance?
Whoo! Good stuff!
Show ‘em your sizzling steps!
That was unreal!
Weaving Kick Down and Awakening Dance
into your dance routine...
You must’ve had a lot of practice!
Yeah, Kuwassu is always working hard.
So... Where’s Aoki-san?
Oh, right.
The Treasure Eatery?
This place was
the Anything Eatery’s rival, right?
Yeah. I’d heard about it,
but it sure is something...
Let’s go.
Heya! Come on in!
U-Uh... U-Umm! Ao—
Table for three?
Uh, erm, uh...
Actually, we came here to
meet with Aoki-san, the Gym Leader.
We heard he’d be here.
Oh, acquaintances of Aoki-san?
Aoki-san!
Very well.
Dot-san, isn’t it?
Here for your implementation test, yes?
Good day. My name is Aoki.
I believe we met before,
during the friendly matches.
Huh?
Hmm?
Wha—?! You’re the Aoki-san
from the Elite Four?!
A Gym Leader’s in the Elite Four?!
Wait, you didn’t notice?
Yeah...
Don’t fret. I am often told
that I don’t stand out.
But I am proud to blend into the crowd
as a simple office worker.
Anyway... My boss won’t be pleased
if I spend too much time chitchatting,
so let’s begin the test.
Ma’am, if I could ask for your assistance.
Sure thing!
Guests in the parlor!
If you wouldn’t mind...
Ooh, does that mean
what I think it means?!
Nice, it’s finally time!
Can’t wait to see this, Aoki-san!
Huh?!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Cool!
What a contraption...
I’ve just finished eating,
so let’s not strain ourselves too hard.
For your implementation test,
you’ll battle with two Pokémon.
You will be judged on how well you make use
of Terastal under those conditions.
How well we make use of it...
So I’ll have to time it just right.
Dot!
Go for it!
Now... Select your first Pokémon
for this battle, if you would.
Kanuchan has never battled before...
So I’ll start with Kuwassu!
Nokokotchi. Let’s go.
Nokokotchi. Land Snake Pokémon.
Normal type.
It uses its hard tail to make its nest
by boring holes into bedrock deep underground.
Their nests can reach
ten kilometers in length.
It’s a Normal type...
Dot... What’s your plan?
Now, we shall start the test.
Let the battle begin.
Let’s do it like we planned, Kuwassu!
Water Gun!
All right! Now, Kuwassu... Aqua Break!
Nokokotchi. Use Snake Glare.
Don’t look, Kuwassu!
He’s paralyzed!
Gotta avoid looking at that pattern!
He shut that down in no time...
Next, we will attack with Blast Waves.
Run for it, Kuwassu!
Return for now, Kuwassu.
Kanuchan, let’s go!
It’s Kanuchan’s first battle!
Go for it!
All right! Let’s go!
Already on your second Pokémon?
Well, once more...
Use Snake Glare.
I won’t fall for that again!
Kanuchan!
Use your hammer as a blindfold!
Yes! Good work!
In that case, use Hyper Drill.
Kanuchan, dodge it!
Good work!
And now...
Brutal Swing!
Oh?
Not bad.
Good! They canceled each other out!
Nice!
Let’s keep it up, Kanuchan.
Do another Brutal Swing!
Nokokotchi, return.
Mukuhawk, let’s go.
Now...
Wing Attack.
I can see Kanuchan is unable to battle.
You did your best though, Kanuchan. Return.
Will that be all?
Kuwassu!
Let’s run the plan again!
It’s gotta work this time!
Water Gun!
I see...
Next, use Pound!
Blow him away with Hurricane.
Air Slash.
Kuwassu!
Sneak around in the smoke!
Now! Aqua Break!
Use Wing Attack.
Kuwassu!
Will Kuwassu be okay?
Hang in there, Kuwassu!
No way... No matter what plan
or attack I go with...
He’s always one step ahead.
I see...
Dot-san, is a “plan” something
to be carried out all by oneself?
Huh?
Kuwassu’s... flapping his wings?
Could that mean...?
He’s trying to move like Mukuhawk?
Of course! He’s had a ton of practice
copying how others move...
In that case...
Do this, Kuwassu!
Remember?!
Blend those movements together!
Like you did
when you were dancing, right?!
Huh?
Weaving Kick Down and Awakening Dance
into your dance routine...
Go!
Suck in lots of air just like Nokokotchi,
then use Water Gun!
Ah!
Then use Kick Down
with Odoridori’s dance steps!
Follow up with
Mukuhawk flapping his wings!
Use your wings to Pound!
This is it! Use Aqua Break
while spinning like Kanuchan!
Wing Attack!
Mm... You’re strong.
Great work, Kuwassu!
Huh?
Kuwassu?
Welcamo!
He evolved!
That’s so cool!
Quite the surprise.
Now’s the time, Welcamo!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine!
Let’s make this look gorgeous, Welcamo!
Aqua Break!
Air Slash!
Now, let’s finish this!
Welcamo!
It seems like Snake Glare’s effect
has persisted.
Put in enough grunt work
and it’s bound to pay off eventually.
Perhaps I need to give this
a bit more effort.
Mind if I show you a little technique
every adult knows all too well?
Grin and bear it!
Use False Bravado!
Welcamo...
Task complete.
That’s our Aoki-san!
You did it!
You did well too, challenger!
I was so close...
Now...
Although I’ve recently
tended to forego these...
My boss has asked me to
start putting together proper reports, so...
Course attendee Dot-san.
Following an impartial examination
by Gym Leader Aoki of Champuru Town,
you have been awarded a passing grade
on your implementation test.
Huh?
I-I passed?!
The reasons are as follows:
Battling effectively using two Pokémon.
In addition...
Evolving Kuwassu into Welcamo
and Terastallizing at an appropriate time.
And lastly... Showed situational awareness
in reading your Pokémon’s intentions...
...and thereby combining their moves.
Marvelously done.
Your hard work studying the basics
has paid off in your implementation test.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
Does that mean...
...you kept throwing out emotionless attacks
in order to teach me all that?
Just a coincidence.
Congrats, Dot!
Congrats!
Oh, right!
Welcamo. Lesson Pokémon.
Water type.
A hard worker that studies
the movements of people and Pokémon...
...from various regions,
incorporating them into its own dances.
They compete with each other
to see who has the most stylish footwork.
I get it... Because Kuwassu was always
practicing dance moves...
...he evolved into Welcamo!
I thought we were both
growing together,
but you passed me right on by again.
I better catch up quick!
You were great too, Dot!
Your final plan was really cool!
Yeah!
Huh?
I knew it...
The Treasure Eatery’s secret menu item:
Onigiri à la Great Blaze with lemon!
Time to dig in!
Delicious!
That’s not bad.
Eat up until you can’t have another bite!
Here’s the bill for everyone’s onigiri.
The check...
I guess I can’t exactly split it...
Understood.
Come again!
So good!
What do you think?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Lesson Pokémon, Welcamo.
Welcamo
Lesson Pokémon
Type: Water
Welcamo
Lesson Pokémon
Type: Water
A very diligent and disciplined Pokémon.
Height
1.2m
They tend to compete
with one another in a certain field,
Weight
21.5kg
but do you know what that field is?
What do they compete on?
Hairstyles
Footwork
Swimming
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What do they compete on?
B: Footwork
The answer is B: Footwork.
Competing lets them all
learn from one another.
They mimic all sorts of moves
and even incorporate them into their own attacks!
Next episode
Dot, congrats on passing
your implementation test!
And it was a real surprise
when Kuwassu evolved!
It was a surprise for me, too!
Next, it’s finally time for
Roy’s implementation test.
To get to the Fridge Town Gym,
we’ll have to pass through Mt. Nappé.
It snows on Mt. Nappé, right?!
You gotta be looking forward to that, right, Hogator?
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Our First Snow! Ho! Hoga!!
Ho! Hoga!
Make sure to watch!
Our First Snow! Ho! Hoga!!