You can call me Ult.
Grew up in Miare City, Kalos Region.
I was trainin’ to
try and master Mega Evolution,
but now I wanna learn more about Yamirami
by gettin’ payback on Lucario in a rematch!
I’m Roy. I’m currently taking on
Mega Evolution training with Ult.
When we retried the Mayo-Maze Palace
that Master Mayonnaise told us about,
Ult and Yamirami
saw right through its tricks!
At last, we can battle Lucario!
Or so we thought...
Oy-ssu! I am Count Oyster!
This humble one
is Shouyu the Shinobi.
“Count Oyster” and...
...“Shouyu the Shinobi”...?
Oy-ssu! If you wish to
fight the Yellow Blast...
...you must first
see us vanquished!
So you’re saying if we defeat
Chevargot and Agilder, we can battle Lucario?
Precisely shou!
They’ll make for a good warm-up!
Ult... Don’t let your guard down.
Am not!
Old man Mayonnaise asked me...
Who am I to Yamirami?
I could spend forever
thinkin’ about that and not get it...
But if I battle with Yamirami
right now...
I dunno why, but...
Then I feel like I’ll get it!
Okay!
Achigator, we’ll fight too!
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
Mega Evolution—Bonds
Strike without delay!
Hell Thrust!
Chevargot! Iron Defense!
Crawling Strike!
Let’s hit ‘em both!
Flamethrower!
Hoping to land
a super effective blow?
Chevargot! Protect!
Agilder! Water Shuriken!
Achigator!
The offensive Agilder...
and the defensive Chevargot...
They’re a perfect team.
Ult! We’ve gotta cooperate, too!
You think I’ll just let ya
knock me around?!
Use Shadow Strike, Yamirami!
A trifle!
Agilder! Shadow Clones!
Chevargot! Finishing Sting!
This will end you!
Crawling Strike!
Charm Voice!
Nice, Achigator!
Thanks for the save...
They’re working as a team,
dividing up offense and defense...
If you attack them alone,
they’ll just gang up on you!
I know that!
None of my attacks are hitting...
And I’ve taken a ton of damage...
What the heck’m I supposed to do here?!
Isn’t this exciting, Achigator?
How can ya laugh at a time like this?
The stronger our opponent,
the more fired up me and Achigator get!
Achigator, let’s do this!
What’re you gonna—?
Aim at them both...
and use Charm Voice!
Oy-ssu! We must prioritize
defeating Achigator! Finishing Sting!
Precisely shou!
Water Shuriken!
Dodge it!
Flamethrower!
Protect!
We’re not done yet!
Nitro Charge!
What’s with you...?
How come you can battle like that...?
What is it I don’t got...?!
You wanna battle with me,
but I keep rushin’ ahead on my own?
Ult?
It’s so simple...
How’d I even miss it?
Yamirami feels just like I do!
It wants to become
the strongest with me!
I ain’t gonna aim
to be the strongest anymore...
I’m gonna aim
to make Yamirami the strongest!
Then, when you’re the strongest,
Yamirami...
You can make me the strongest, too!
Yeah... I hear ya, Yamirami.
Let’s give it all we’ve got...
...and rampage like the strongest!
Ult... I’m counting on you!
You’ve nowhere left to run!
Finishing Sting!
Achigator!
Drat!
Flamethrower!
All right!
Too naïve!
Smash ‘em, Yamirami!
Shadow Strike!
Whoa! You hit one!
You’re amazing, Yamirami!
That really was amazing,
Ult and Yamirami!
Hmph!
That was nothing special for us!
My bad, Yamirami! You okay?
Splendid!
We have no qualms
with your strength!
Go forth, and allow your bonds
to bloom further!
Huh? Where’d they...?
Roy!
Pick up the pace!
Right!
Lucario!
It’s payback time!
Ult, is Yamirami okay?
All good.
And I ain’t just sayin’ that.
Yamirami’s raring to go!
I can tell!
‘Sides, if we can’t handle
somethin’ like this,
Mega Evolving’s
beyond our wildest dreams!
Well said!
Master Mayonnaise!
Old man Mayonnaise?!
I shall keep a watchful eye
on your battle.
Suits me!
I’ll show ya somethin’ worth seein’!
Begin!
It vanished!
It’s just so fast!
Yamirami! Dodge!
Achigator, dodge it!
Ult, can you see where it’s moving...?
Yeah, I can just barely
keep track of it.
Back when we first came here,
this would’ve taken us out.
But in that last battle, we picked up on
how to follow our foes’ movements.
Our turn now!
Yamirami! Power—
Still, dodging’s the max
we’re able to do...
If it keeps on pushing forward...
Achigator!
How’re we supposed to
keep up with that speed?!
Speed... Of course!
Got an idea?
The moment it comes in for an attack,
we can counter it.
Drawing it in super close...?
But if we get the timing
even a little wrong and mess this up...
You and Yamirami
have it in you now!
Yamirami...
You’ve always been there,
watching over me.
This time,
I’ll be there to watch over you!
Yamirami! Hell Thrust!
It’s still tough...
Don’t get shaken up, Yamirami!
You’re not alone!
I’m here with ya!
Ult!
I’ve always been following
behind Yamirami wherever it goes.
I could tell where Yamirami is
with my eyes closed.
Yamirami’s me, and I’m Yamirami.
We’re fighting together...
I can feel it.
When Yamirami feels
Lucario’s presence closing in...
...I do too!
I’m sure of it, Yamirami...
You’ve got outrageous power!
Break past your max, Yamirami!
Now! Shadow Strike!
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
We Mega Evolved...
We did it, we did it!
Yamirami... You’re mega-cool!
That was awesome, Ult!
Your feelings aligned,
and you believed strongly in one another.
Thus, a strong bond was formed.
Awright! Let’s keep it up
and bring this home!
Something’s coming!
Yamirami!
Hmph. Now ya get serious.
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Is that thing heavy?!
It is unaccustomed
to its own Mega Evolution.
If you can’t move,
then use Eerie Light!
Great!
So, he’s stopped
relying solely on brute force.
Now, Yamirami! Hell Thrust!
Yamirami is unable to battle.
Yamirami!
Hang in there!
Don’t say that.
You were the mega-strongest.
It broke through its confusion
with fighting spirit?
Achigator!
Did Yamirami Mega Evolving
reinvigorate him?
You wanna beat Lucario, huh?
All right!
Time to sing, Achigator!
A! Ga! A-ga-ga!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Th-They’re singing?!
Don’t give up! We’ve just gotta! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Don’t give up!
We’ve just gotta! Go for it!
Dodge!
Right! Left! Now up!
Those guys’re
predicting every move...
Right! Left!
Now it’s coming from the front!
I can sense Lucario’s feelings
through Achigator.
Its movements... its thoughts...
even its next attack.
Left! More left! Now behind you!
His emotions are resonating
with Lucario in the heat of battle?
Lucario...
I can sense you’re having fun!
You wanna battle even more, right?
Then let’s battle more, Lucario!
My Key Stone
and Lucario’s Mega Stone are...
Huh?!
What the heck?!
It’s a miracle... To think it’d form a bond
with its opponent’s trainer and Mega Evolve...
That boy...
I never imagined
he could achieve this...
I’m so happy!
I get to battle you at your full strength!
Let’s go, Achigator! Full power!
Flamethrower!
Achigator!
Lucario is unable to battle!
We won! Achigator!
We did it! We did it!
Mm-hm.
That was truly a fine battle.
Master Mayonnaise.
Ult, and Roy.
You have done well to overcome
our Mega Evolution training!
“Our”?
Ta-daah!
Whoa!
The guys from...
Oy-ssu! That was marvelous.
Verily, a shining example.
We are kindred spirits,
all fascinated by Mega Evolution.
We built the Mayo-Maze Palace
to serve as a place where Pokémon and trainers...
...could undergo training
to strengthen their bonds.
Then... you’re the ones
behind the maze and the pit, too?
Precisely shou.
The heck?
You were all workin’ together?!
It turned out okay in the end.
You have attained Mega Evolution.
Mega-congratulations.
Roy, Achigator.
Congratulations on
your Mega Evolution as well.
Huh? But we didn’t...
Through a heated battle with you and Achigator,
Lucario was led to Mega Evolve.
That Mega Evolution
was made possible only by your bond.
Looks like Lucario’s
taken a liking to you.
Hmm?
Huh...?
It seems Lucario
wishes to go with you.
Huh? With us?!
I believe the reason Lucario decided
to stay at the Mayo-Maze Palace...
...was because it wished to grow stronger,
and continually strive for greater heights.
I think you are capable of
living up to Lucario’s hopes.
That it forged a bond with you—its foe in battle—
in order to gain true power is the surest proof of that.
True power...?
Lucario...
You’re going to come with me, then?
Come on out!
Let’s be good pals, Lucario.
Hmph! You got no taste
if you’re picking that guy over me.
But I s’pose you go good together.
You’ll approve of me
and Yamirami someday, won’t you?
Right, Pop?
We have done all we can for you.
From here on,
using the power of Mega Evolution...
...appropriately falls to you,
as you each walk your own paths.
Right!
Matière-san,
thanks for all your help.
What are you going to do next?
I’ll keep on traveling with everyone.
I wanna test our strength even more!
I see. Go for it!
Right!
Before I go,
I was hoping to say goodbye to Ult...
Oh... Ult already left
to go adventuring.
Huh?
Huh?!
To become the mega-strongest,
I wanna leave this city
and go adventure with Yamirami!
So... H-How should I...?
W-Well... You helped me and all...
Tanksalot, Matière!
Ult. Feel free to come back
whenever you like.
This is your home,
and we’re family.
O-Okay then! I’ll be goin’!
What’s with him?
He could’ve said something to me...
He did leave a message with me.
“Roy! The black Rekkuuza
belongs to me!”, he said.
I’m not giving up on that, either!
Roy... Thank you.
Ult finally found something he wants to do.
You really do make good buddies!
Yeah!
Oh, right.
You said you didn’t know
why Cap chose to follow you...
But I think it’s because
you’re always looking forward.
Huh?
Sometimes, I can tell things.
What people are thinking,
with Fluff’s mysterious powers...
Like, inside my head.
Ult stopped always looking down,
because you weren’t doing that.
That Friede guy used to
look forward too, didn’t he?
Maybe you two look alike,
from a certain angle.
Cap...!
Do you think
I’m a bit closer to being like Friede?
How do I look?
Cool, right?
It’s just like Friede’s!
I’ll take this!
A’ight.
Yo, kid... Lookin’ fresh!
Now, let’s set off!
Oh, he forgot this.
Geez, why’re you following me?
Huh?! You’re the one
copyin’ offa my path!
Anyway, for now...
...we’ve gotta handle that!
Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
U U U U You & I...
U U U U You're not dreaming...
If nothing else, at least shout! (Woo!) The hex of impatience digs in
Though boors may cloud your vision, turn aside and keep walking
Why was I given this life? (Why?) Fate tests my very body
An evening star alone, closed eyes waiting for the light
Then, everything hiding in the flames...
All the sadness and hatred, blow it away, golden wind!
U U U U You & I... For such is love? Don't give me excuses!
U U U U You're not dreaming... Who are you? Don't get in my way!
Raising the curtains... is the task entrusted to us