Having finished our
Terastal Course basics tests,
we’re now observing
wild Pokémon for our reports!
They’re a different color
from Grandma’s!
Ikirinko. Parrot Pokémon.
Normal/Flying type.
White ones have a strong sense of community
and survive by cooperating with allies.
Ooh...
This time, I have to
make sure to get a video...
Ah! Hold on! Umm...
Huh?!
Getting wild Pokémon
to relax around you is pretty tough...
Hey, Kanuchan!
Quit going crazy!
Capsaiji. Habanero Pokémon.
Grass type.
The more sunlight it absorbs,
the more spicy chemicals its body produces.
Some traditional Paldean cuisine is extremely spicy
due to the use of shed front teeth from Capsaiji.
Extremely spicy, eh?
A nice big Ubu Berry!
Thanks, Hogator.
Let’s give this to it.
Ooh! It’s eating! It’s eating!
It says they’re spicy,
but I wonder just how spicy...
I wanna try some
traditional Paldean cuisine!
Huh?
Kaiden!
Hogator’s really gotten
the hang of Nitro Charge!
Grilled berries seem like
a yummy idea, too!
Kaiden?
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Kaiden, Strong Wind Warning!
What am I looking at...?
Ah! Hold on! Umm...
There were these white Ikirinko...
Huh? These are Ikirinko?!
...but I couldn’t get a good video.
Huh?
Sad to admit, but it’s really bad.
What a waste!
The white ones are rare,
but you can’t exactly use this in a report...
How about you, Dot?
What wild Pokémon have you seen?
Oh, well...
Nothing to write home about.
How about you, Roy?
Look here.
That’s not a wild Pokémon...
It’s your Kaiden, right?
When you first met it...
...its fear of heights kept it from flying,
and you helped it train, right?
Yeah.
It’s gotten a lot better since then...
But it still loses control in strong winds
and gives up on flying right away.
I wish I knew how to make it
feel more confident in its wings...
What should I do?
Huh? Kaiden?
Kaiden!
Where did Kaiden get to?
Huh?
Kaiden?
What a relief!
I was worried about you.
What were you doing
all the way out...?
Hey, were you training?
Kaiden?
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Kaiden, sing along with us!
Try to forget your worries
and have some fun singing!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Don’t give up, Kaiden! Go for it!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Wh-What was that?
I-I am n-not scared...!
Don’t give up, everyone...!
Go for it!
What is this thing?!
Heel!
Who’s that?
C’mere, Hakadog.
Hakadog?
He’s my dear, sweet
Ghost Dog Pokémon.
Now that I get a good look at him,
he is really cute!
I was giving your song a listen.
I’m getting some
real passionate vibes off you.
Looks like you’re trying to
cheer that little one up.
But you... are giving off
awful jittery vibes.
Running from your fear’ll
never get you anywhere.
Yo!
Nothing wrong with some fear!
It’ll make you stronger, ya hear?
You only gotta fear the path that veers
you towards limiting your own frontiers!
So cool!
A Capsaiji!
It’s a Pokémon that loves sunlight,
but it’s running around at night...
It must be fleeing from
the one not of this world.
The one not of this world?
Yo!
The one not of this world
is this weird Pokémon!
Got all the others ‘round here
scared outta their wits!
I gotta track down the one not of this world!
This fearsome beast who dares, yeah,
to come to our world bringing the scares!
The force of my rage hit its critical point,
got me spinnin’ three times up in this joint!
Now I wanna meet it, too!
But if Capsaiji was running from it,
that Pokémon could be vicious...
Oh yeah, my report!
What report?
I’m taking a course at Orange Academy!
Maybe it’s rare to see them
running around after sundown.
Capsaiji, you might
make it into my report!
Uh... Video, video...
Hmm... Taking a course, huh?
You’ve got some real fire in you.
Keep it going!
It’s gone...
Oh yeah!
Lemme get a video of Hakadog...
Huh?
The one not of this world?
Yeah!
Apparently it’s some really strange,
fearsome Pokémon.
Nothing’s coming up when I search for it...
You sure it’s a real Pokémon?
And who told you that?
She vanished before I could ask.
Vanished?!
You sure you weren’t just dreaming?
It was all real!
Oh, I know! I recorded the Capsaiji,
so maybe I got her too!
What’s this?
It’s pitch-black...
Wha...? That’s weird...
Maybe I need to teach you two
how to take videos...
Over there! Ikirinko!
And this time...
Shh!
Sh! Shh!
Ahh! The Ikirinko!
Ooh! That’s great!
Wait... I shouldn’t be trying to
record glitzy vids right now!
I need to find some wild Pokémon!
Think the Capsaiji
from yesterday’s still around?
What are you doing?!
Don’t pick fights, Kaiden!
You okay, Hogator?
Hogator, Kaiden...
We’re all buddies here,
so we’ve got to get along...
Kaiden?
Kaiden!
Capsaiji!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
It fell down there!
What do we do?
I’ll come save you right away!
Hogator, you wait here!
Hogator!
You and water don’t mix, right?
If you fall, you’re gonna drown!
J-Just barely...
Capsaiji!
You’re okay now! Come here!
Come on!
Ouch!
My finger’s... getting really itchy!
Hey!
Spicy!
But...
It tastes great!
It’s super spicy, with a deep flavor...
Don’t mind if I do!
Spicy! Tasty!
Habanero Pokémon are awesome!
It’s got a great, spicy aftertaste!
This can go right into
my report! All right!
Capsaiji, come over here.
Don’t worry. I’m not a bad guy.
You don’t have to be scared.
Yo! Nothing wrong with some fear!
It’ll make you stronger, ya hear?
You only gotta fear the path that veers
you towards limiting your own frontiers!
All right!
But... What do I do next?
I can’t climb this one-handed.
Kaiden!
Kaiden...
Please! Help save Capsaiji!
I know you can do it!
I wonder how far Roy went...
What is it, Mibrim?
Nyarote? Where are you going?
Kaiden!
Go for it, Kaiden!
You did it, Kaiden!
What a relief.
Hogator! Kaiden! Where’s Roy?
Roy!
Oh, no!
I’m okay! I’m great at climbing trees!
What do I do?! What do I do?!
You are not okay!
That’s dangerous! Don’t move!
Roy!
Kaiden...?
Incredible!
Taikaiden. Frigatebird Pokémon.
Electric/Flying type.
It inflates its throat sac
to amplify its electricity.
By riding the wind,
it can fly 700 kilometers in a day.
You’re awesome, Taikaiden!
Hup!
See ya, Capsaiji!
It was a Kaiden just a minute ago,
and now it’s a Taikaiden...
Evolving one of your Pokémon
in the wilds of Paldea...
That sounds like
it’d make a great report!
Yeah!
Dot, did you record it evolving?
Huh?
You didn’t get it?!
Well... I just couldn’t take my eyes off it...
Then... Did you, Liko?!
Huh?! Umm...
Wha...?! Neither of you?!
No way...
Kaide— Wait, I mean...
Taikaiden!
You wanna fly too, Hogator?
Looks like fun!
Right, Nyarote?
Taikaiden flying Hogator around...
What a great shot!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Frigatebird Pokémon, Taikaiden.
Taikaiden
Frigatebird Pokémon
Type: Electric/Flying
Taikaiden
Frigatebird Pokémon
Type: Electric/Flying
Just like its pre-evolution Kaiden,
Height
1.4m
it produces electricity
when its large wings catch the wind.
Weight
38.6kg
But do you know where it stores
the electricity it produces?
Where does it store its electricity?
Its cheeks
Its beak
Its throat
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Where does it store its electricity?
C: Its throat
The answer is C: Its throat!
It can inflate its throat to store electricity.
The size of its throat sac
correlates to the strength of its electricity!
Next episode
Hey... Is it really in this forest?
It’s gotta be!
I hope I see it soon...
The one not of this world!
I wonder what sort of Pokémon it is.
A fog rolled in...
An uncanny air...
What is it, Mibrim?
Look! Out in the fog!
Could that be...?!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Mibrim and the One Not of This World
It’s here!