I’m Liko.
In hopes of discovering
more about myself,
I enrolled at Sekiei School
in the Kanto Region.
There were so many Pokémon
I’d never seen before, I was amazed!
It was my first time
living in a dorm.
My roommate...
I’m a bit messy!
...was a cheerful girl, Anne.
I hope we can get along.
And, what made me
the most nervous was...
So hey... After the entrance ceremony,
it’ll finally be time, y’know?
Time? For what?
What else?
Our partner Pokémon!
Next, Ms. Liko.
H-Here!
When meeting someone,
your first impression is really important.
Go ahead.
My first Pokémon was Nyahoja.
So cute!
But...
Ow!
...it’s very fickle, and I don’t know
what it’s thinking a lot of the time.
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Please! Stop being so reckless!
One thing led to another,
and my dizzying life went on, until one day...
Pleased to meet you.
Ms. Liko, correct?
A suspicious man came to see me.
Am I being targeted?!
Found you!
Just as soon as
this other person showed up,
they started a Pokémon battle,
and I was in big trouble!
Psycho Cutter!
Ready... and...
On top of all that,
my grandmother’s pendant started shining...
What’s going to happen to me?!
The Pendant of Beginnings, Part Two
Huh? Lizardon?!
You two! Don’t be so reckless!
That’s exactly what
I keep telling Nyahoja...
Still...
I like your spirit.
It’s weird, if you ask me.
So much weird stuff happened...
...that maybe I’m weird now, too?
Right now, I feel like...
...something has just begun.
Too bad.
We’ll have to finish our battle
some other time.
Lizardon!
Hold on tight!
The night sky stretches out endlessly
above the school rooftops.
I stepped out, leaping into that night sky
where the full moon looms large...
I think... I could do it
because Nyahoja was by my side.
You’re amazing, Nyahoja.
That shine... That pendant...
Amethio, sir.
How do we proceed?
Return, Soublades.
We follow them.
Sir!
Airm'd!
Armorgaw!
Earlier... Was I seeing things?
I feel like I got totally swept up
in everything that was happening...
...but this whole thing is crazy!
He saved me, but... who is this guy?
And where is he taking us,
for that matter?
Um, excuse me!
Could you let me go now?!
Huh? What was that?
Um... I mean,
could you drop me off some... where...?
What is that?!
Ah, that’s our ship.
The Brave Asagi.
We’re back!
Deploy the Wing Deck!
Touchdown.
Thank you, Lizardon.
Welcome back.
You gave us quite a hassle.
You must be Liko.
Y-Yes.
But... Why do you know my...?
Or rather, who are all of you?
Don’t tell me...
Hey! Did you leave her
totally in the dark?
Huh? Did I?
Man, how’d you get her
to come along, then?!
Friede!
Oh, um, well...
So his name is Friede.
It drives me nuts when you do stuff like that...
A Hogator! And a Pamo!
Whenever I see Pokémon,
I start moving on instinct.
My heart starts racing.
Why are there Pokémon
from Paldea here?
Oh, those guys.
They settled in here
during our journeys.
And it’s not just Pokémon
from Paldea.
Look.
If the Pokémon feel so at ease here,
maybe these people aren’t bad guys.
I never did introduce myself.
I’m Molly.
I’m Murdock.
And that’s my partner, Iwanko.
Huh? Nyahoja’s already
made friends with it...
They’re all so cute!
No, no, no! Focus!
I’ve got to ask them...
Um, excuse me...
Sorry, one sec.
One, two, three...
Could it be the same group?!
What’s up?
I’m going to the wheelhouse.
We’re setting sail.
Yorunozuku, keep a lookout
on our surroundings.
They haven’t given up yet.
Friede! Who are you talking about?
What happened at the school?
I’ll fill you in later.
Murdock, you check downstairs.
Molly, you look after
the Pokémon and that girl.
Got it.
Orio’s freaking out.
Says there’s a storm right in our flight path.
I’ll figure something out.
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Return, Iwanko.
I didn’t get to ask a single thing...
I can’t let myself get swept up.
I need to get some idea of what’s going on!
Orio, give it all she’s got.
I’m doing my best already!
I’ll send you some backup.
Lizardon, head to the engine room.
I’m counting on you.
Cap! I’m on my way.
Just in time!
Is that it?
There’s a storm ahead.
Are you sure about this?
We can’t back down now!
Let’s catch them!
Sir!
A blackout...
Now, of all times...
Um, excuse me...
I have no clue what’s going on...
I was at school until just a bit ago, and then those people showed up...
So, they’ve finally shown themselves!
They were really suspicious,
asking all this stuff about my pendant...
Those guys...!
They’re the Explorers!
Wait... The Explorers?!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Cap.
Lemme take over here.
Captain
Pikachu
Nosepass, which way’s north?
Thanks!
Geez... What are you up to, Friede?!
Orio, can you give us
a little more speed?
Mmh... Like I said,
I’m doing my best already!
All right. Let’s plot a course
into the thunderclouds.
Huh?! Are you serious?!
We’re not gonna shake ‘em
otherwise, right?
Honestly... I couldn’t have asked for
better weather today!
More recklessness...
Well, I guess we’re out of options.
Orio, it’s all up to you now.
You’re not hearing
a word I’m saying, are you?
Roger. Let’s do this!
Lizardon!
Thank you, Hogator.
Thanks, everyone!
Turn to starboard!
All right!
These guys are so perky...
Are they heading for the clouds?!
So reckless... Amethio, sir!
We can’t afford to lose them now.
Use the airship to shield yourselves
from the wind and close in!
On me!
Roger!
Oh, gramps. You look after it.
Piece of cake.
Um... They’re here!
Friede! The Explorers
have reached the Wing Deck!
What?!
Can you retract the Wing Deck?
The power’s out.
No choice.
All of you, stay put.
Huh? Where are you going?
To retract it manually.
Are we okay?
Murdock, take the wheel.
Sure thing.
Let’s go, Cap!
Hey! Don’t be too reckless.
We’ve got children on board.
Is this it?
Sorry, I need to head out
with Lizardon.
Huh?!
It’s too late!
Hold on...
This twist...
Getting thrown around this way and that,
all for this pendant...
Am... Am...
Am I the heroine in some story?!
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
I don’t know what’s happening...
But I do know... that these little ones
are getting caught in the crossfire.
It’s all... because of me...
and the pendant I got from my grandmother.
Why did you run?
I don’t know.
So, do you think
you can trust them?
I don’t know.
That pendant...
What was that shine?
I don’t know.
It seems you don’t know
a lot of things.
But... I do know one thing.
Oh?
I can’t trust any of you.
My, what a little brat.
Nyahoja!
Stop it! If you want the pendant
that much, I’ll give it to you.
Just... give Nyahoja back!
Drop it.
Sir.
At first, we were only after the pendant.
But it looks like that pendant
holds some kind of secret.
And you...
appear to be part to that secret.
As such, you’ll be
coming with us as well.
This all depends on me...
I can stop it.
Come along.
I understand.
Everyone, you’ll be fine now.
This is fine.
This is just fine...
Not good! Liko!
Hold it!
Hold it, hold it, hold it!
Friede!
Molly, look after the Pokémon!
Thanks!
Leave this to me.
Umm, I...!
Don’t worry. I’ll protect both of you.
Count on it.
He came to save me again...
Why?
So you’re with those notorious Explorers.
Amethio.
I’m Friede.
The leader of the Rising Voltteccers.
You’re one foolhardy crew,
flying right into a storm like that.
Big words coming from
guys who boarded us by force.
We’ll take our leave
the moment our goal is achieved.
Whoa there. I can’t let you do that.
Well then, shall we pick up
where we left off?
Just what I was hoping for.
Return, Lizardon.
What are you planning?
Isn’t it obvious?
Let’s go, Cap!
A Pikachu?
Are you toying with me?
I could ask you the same thing.
Very well. I won’t hold back.
Let’s show ‘em!
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Hmph. That’s worthless
against Soublades.
Next! Shadow Clones!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Thunder Punch!
Sword of Regrets!
Nice one, Cap!
Go! Voltteccer!
This isn’t over yet!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
This will just...
Stop! Please stop!
I don’t want to cause all of you
any more trouble.
Huh? What are you talking about?
I don’t want anyone
to be hurt any further.
Hear that?
Seems like she wants you
to back down.
I bet... even Nyahoja...
What is it?
What’s wrong, Nyahoja?
Why are you so riled up?
I get it.
I’ve been lying to myself.
You could tell.
Okay. Got it.
Let’s go, Nyahoja.
Leafage!
What?!
We did it!
Nyahoja, we did it!
No!
Nyahoja!
Amethio, sir!
We’ll be caught in the storm
if we stay here!
Retreat!
Sir!
Nyahoja!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents
I bet
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Something you can’t quite put into words...
Something that makes your heart beat a bit faster...
Something that seems to brighten up your day...
“I found some flowers I like!”
With white mist clinging onto every day
I can’t even look for what I wanna find, ooh
My diary makes it all look so exciting
“I threw it out, pretending it wasn’t mine” ...strike that
You lia-ia-ia-iar...
My inconsolable heart
Whoa-oh whoa-oh-o-oh
Rewrite “But”/“Yet” into “I bet”/“It could be true”
If only I could walk on air, on a fair breeze
Greatly, smoothly, slightly, nearly, someday...
I wanna fly!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents!
I bet! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
Don’t let untold tales scare you
Dazzling daydreams make the world dance!
So smile! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
No time to waste hiding away
I wanna learn about myself!
I still don’t know anything about any-any-anything
I wanna discover myself!
When I got the courage to say “I’m going out”
Maybe I grew up a little bit then
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Grass Cat Pokémon, Nyahoja.
Nyahoja
Grass Cat Pokémon
Type: Grass
The floral Sweet Scent that Nyahoja gives off
grows stronger if it does a certain thing.
Height: 0.4m
Weight: 4.1kg
Do you know what thing that is?
Which action
makes Sweet Scent
grow stronger?
A: Battling
B: Sunbathing
C: Eating
Which action
makes Sweet Scent
grow stronger?
A: Battling
B: Sunbathing
C: Eating
See the answer after the commercials!
Now, let’s announce the correct answer.
Which action makes
Sweet Scent stronger?
B: Sunbathing
Which action makes
Sweet Scent stronger?
B: Sunbathing
The answer is B: Sunbathing.
It may look like it’s just taking a relaxing nap,
but that’s the key.
Sunlight makes Nyahoja’s scent
grow stronger.
Taking a nap out in the warm sun
is the best, isn’t it?
Next episode
Yo-ssu! For real-ssu!
Huge preview time!
The battle for the pendant
with mysterious powers...
...on the airship headin’ for the storm
hits a boiling point!
Or so I thought, but then Nyahoja
disappeared with that freaky group!
“Hey! What are you
going to do, Liko?!”
“It’s obvious, Liko.
We have to find it.”
So we better join in
and give her a big “Go for it!”!
And so!
To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
If I’m With Nyahoja, I Bet