Fans of Unite Battles,
welcome to Remota Stadium!
The curtains are moments from lifting on
the special event battle you’ve all been waiting for!
What kinds of twists and turns
are in store for us?
Now then, let’s get straight to the intros
for our competing teams!
Taking part will be...
The number one center of attention!
Possessing popularity and skill,
they’re the idol team of Unite Battles!
The Shining Oceans!
And going up against them...
Today marks their Unite Battle debut,
but they’ve got infinite potential!
A promising new team
storms into Remota Stadium!
The Rising Voltteccers!
Whoa, they’re really hyping us up!
Give the crowd a wave, at least.
Huh?
Awright! Just you watch!
Nuh-uh. No way, no way,
no way, no way...
Umm... If you’re wondering
how we ended up here...
A Unite Battle?
What’s that?
It’s a kind of Pokémon Battle match
using a special energy, known as Aeos Energy,
which gushes forth
on an island called Aeos Island.
Teams composed of
five trainer and Pokémon pairs...
...each employ moves and strategies
in heated battle!
Aeos Energy...?
I think...
you collect that Aeos Energy in battle,
and use it to power up your Pokémon
as you compete for points... or something.
Dot, you know about them?
Well... The rules, at least.
Okay, you’ve pretty much got it.
You see,
I happen to know Professor Rin,
the one who discovered Aeos Energy
and created the Unite Battle system.
There’s a special battle scheduled
to be held on Aeos Island in three days,
but one of the teams planning to compete
ran into some trouble and had to drop out.
Would you happen to know a team
that could sub in for them?
She asked me, so I told her...
“I know the best team
you could ever ask for!
“They’re called the Rising Voltteccers!”,
is what I said.
Huh?!
Us?!
Sounds fun, right?
And so, we’re competing
in a Unite Battle!
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
READY GO! Unite Battle!!
Shining! Oceans!
Do your best!
Get another win today!
That’s some serious cheering...
The Shining Oceans are a team with
top-class popularity and skill, after all.
That’s the kind of team
we’re up against...?
Woo! I’m so excited,
I can’t stop shakin’!
The battle will begin in...
Ten...
Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Ready...
Go!
Masquernya! Right!
Shall we go, Cap?
Loudbone, rush down the middle!
Wanival, left!
Yamirami, follow his lead!
First, aim to power up!
Seek out wild Pokémon on the field
and keep on challenging them to battles!
There! Pokémon!
They’re glowing!
That’s Aeos Energy!
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Dodge and use Trick Flower!
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Loudbone! Flare Song!
Yamirami! Shadow Strike!
Wanival! Air Cutter!
They’re building up Aeos Energy
nice and smooth!
The energy keeps stacking up!
This is interesting!
Don’t let your guard down.
We’ll be closing in on the enemy.
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Now, go for the Beequeen!
Negigaknight! Brutal Swing!
Masquernya, dodge it!
What’s this? Pokémon from both teams
have made contact for the first time!
Are they here to snatch the energy?!
Whichever Pokémon lands the final hit
gets the Aeos Energy.
Meaning one potential tactic
is stealing the last hit.
I won’t let them snatch it!
Masquernya!
Use Trick Flower on Beequeen!
Guard!
Cap, support Masquernya!
Zoroark! Shadow Claw!
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Not bad. But...
Pixie! Moonlight!
It recovered?!
Negigaknight! Consecutive Cut!
Masquernya, run for it!
It appears the Shining Oceans
have won the struggle for the energy!
They got us...
But we’re not down for the count yet!
Cap! The enemy goal is wide open! Go!
Goal!
In a stunning turn of events,
the first point goes to the Rising Voltteccers!
Nice goal there, Cap!
We did it!
Awright, now me!
Go, Yamirami! Score a goal!
Hey, wait! If you just rush in—
Showers! Quick Turn!
Yamirami’s down!
It’s been sent back
to the starting zone!
Gah! All that energy I gathered...!
Bad news!
The enemies are at our goal!
Loudbone, protect the goal!
They got ahead of us!
I’ll kick them out of the way!
No, this is our time to shine.
Let’s show the stands what they’re hoping to see.
Okay!
Zoroark! Nightfall Burst!
Wanival?!
Strinder! Venom Distortion!
What were those moves?!
That’s some amazing power...
They already got powered up?
Building up Aeos Energy
makes Pokémon power up...
...and learn powerful new moves.
They’re... Unite Moves!
The Shining Oceans make a rush for the goal!
They’ve turned the tables in an instant!
They’re strong...
They’re a top team for a reason...
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
We’ve still got a chance
to turn the tables.
No giving up! Let’s keep at it!
First, we need to hurry and power up.
We need to cooperate as a team to build energy,
rather than going in solo.
Cap, cover him!
Seems like that Pikachu’s
their commander.
Then let’s disrupt their teamwork.
Everyone, attack him!
Roger!
Masquernya, use Trick Flower
on those Runpappa!
You powered up!
Pixie! Gravity!
Strinder! Overdrive!
Masquernya, support Cap!
Blooming Showtime!
Ooh, is that a Unite Move?
Not good.
Let’s retreat for now and regroup!
Now, Loudbone!
Go, Wanival!
Looking good, Yamirami!
Nice, Cap!
All the members of the Rising Voltteccers
have powered up, too!
Now we can fight on an even playing field
with their Pokémon!
We ain’t gonna lose
no energy struggles, neither!
Five minutes remaining in this battle.
Only five minutes left?
Let’s use Unite Moves
to keep up our attack and turn the tables!
No, hold on.
We’re going to
seal off our Unite Moves.
Huh?!
Seal off? Like, not use them?
But why?!
We can’t win the battle like that!
Once you use a Unite Move,
you can’t use it again for a while.
And we’ve got a chance
to really turn the tables coming up!
Showers! Aquamarine Splash!
The other team seems to be
saving their Unite Moves.
Yeah. They’ve probably got
you-know-what in mind.
In which case,
we won’t hold back on scoring plenty of goals.
Their lead is just growing bigger!
Can we actually turn the tables?
Hey, what was that just now?!
N-No way!
Just what I was waiting for!
Feast your eyes, everyone!
As if drawn here
by the rising Aeos Energy,
the Legendary Pokémon Thunder...
has just landed on the Remota Stadium Field!
Our chance to really
turn the tables is Thunder?!
Everyone,
gather in the middle of the field!
Our speed against theirs! Hurry!
Right!
Thunder’s Aeos Energy is far beyond...
...that of the other wild Pokémon.
And what’s more...
Two minutes remaining in this battle.
Entering the final stretch.
During this time,
goals will be worth twice as many points.
Twice as many points?!
I get it... If we steal Thunder’s energy
and make a goal, we’ll score big time!
Precisely!
Dodge it!
Their team’s here, too!
This is what’ll decide the match.
Now, we unseal our Unite Moves!
Cap!
Full Bolt Storm!
Leave the enemy team to me!
Go attack Thunder!
Okay! Let’s go, Loudbone!
Rousing Symphony!
Wanival! Splashing Carnival!
Zoroark! Shadow Claw!
Cap! Shadow Clones!
Their team isn’t coming
to defeat Thunder?
They’ve got a big lead, so they could be prioritizing
obstructing us over pushing for more goals.
Thunder’s up to you.
Huh?
Yamirami, head into the grass!
Hold on! Ult?!
We should concentrate on Thunder!
Got it.
Masquernya! Blooming Showtime!
It’s working!
Keep up the momentum
and land the last hit!
Sorry, but you won’t get the chance!
Over there! Negigaknight?!
Negigaknight!
Jade Lance Flash: Negiga Nova!
Jade Lance Flash
Oh, no! The last hit...!
Pop out, Yamirami!
Yamirami! Chaos Gazer!
Ult! Was that... a Unite Move?!
Its effect was to force a foe
to return to their starting zone?
So you had spotted Negigaknight...
Incredible!
Heh! Only natural.
Hey! We don’t have time for this!
Oh right, Thunder!
Wanival! Wave Tackle!
Loudbone! Flare Song!
Masquernya! Trick Flower!
All right, run for the goal!
Don’t let that happen!
Stop them!
Go!
The Rising Voltteccers
score goals one after another!
Strinder! Overdrive!
Dunk it, Cap!
And there the battle ends!
The winner is... In a stunning, stunning,
stunning turn of events...!
The Rising Voltteccers!
We... actually won...
We did it!
What do you think? Fun, right?
I got stronger yet again!
And learned an awesome move!
Unite Moves can only be used in Unite Battles...
Were you not aware?
What?! Seriously...?
They defeated us.
Let’s train even harder
and win next time!
Right!
Our first Unite Battle was
an exhilarating experience, filled with thrills!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Strinder: High Form!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Strinder
(High Form)
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Punk Pokémon
Electric
Poison
Punk Rock
Plus
When it releases strong electricity,
it makes a sound akin to a certain instrument echo out,
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
but do you know what instrument that is?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Guitar
Bass
Drums
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
Guitar
Bass
Drums
A: Guitar!
Guitar
When you see it pluck at its chest to produce sound...
It looks just like a rock star!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Are you ready?
We’re closing out with a one-night-only
special unit performing on stage!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Next episode
Everyone!
We’re about to arrive in Miare City!
It’ll be my first time,
so I’m really looking forward to it!
There’s all sorts of Pokémon
living in the city, right?
Next episode
I hear they’ve got
lots of delicious food, too!
Plus, it’s your hometown, isn’t it, Ult?
I s’pose!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Next episode
Miare City! A New Encounter
Everybody, welcome!
Huh? Who’s that?!
Miare City! A New Encounter