Amethio-sama!
It’s finally shown itself, huh?
I’ve got a reading...
It’s Rekkuuza!
Take us up.
You two remain on standby.
Sir!
Armorgaw!
Let’s go!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
The Bellowing Black Rekkuuza
The Rising Voltteccers entered an ocean enveloped
in fog, hoping to meet Laplace of the Six Heroes.
At long last, we were able to
pinpoint its location.
In the end, Laplace was moved by
Terapagos’s feelings and came with us.
Just when it seemed all was said and done,
we found ourselves face to face with...
Rekkuuza!
Y-You’re kidding!
Hey! Rekkuuza!
I’ve been looking for you for so long!
Please, battle me!
Did the Heroes call out to each other?!
I see...
You must be Lucius’s greatest partner!
We’re down here, Rekkuuza!
Please, let us get through to it...
Uh, are we... gonna be okay, here?
Mm-hmm.
It does not seem to wish to fight.
Armorgaw, face it head-on!
I’ve been looking for you...
This time, I will catch you!
Come out!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Armorgaw! Air Slash!
What was that?!
Amethio?!
How’d he find us?!
So, long-distance attacks won’t work...
Armorgaw!
Ascend together with Soublades!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Dodge it, Armorgaw!
Not good! Lizardon!
Are you okay, Roy?!
We met it first!
No! Not yet!
But Rekkuuza’s—
Don’t push yourself!
Let go of me, Friede!
Rekkuuza’s gonna—
Friede!
Get the two of them
back on the ship!
Here we go!
Rekkuuza! Let me go!
Or Rekkuuza’ll—
Liko! You stand back, too!
Grandma! We have to talk to it!
Terapagos is here, too!
I realize that!
But it’s just too riled up!
Now’s not the time.
Knock it out of the skies!
Sword of Regrets!
Soublades!
What a monster...
Armorgaw!
The Rising Voltteccers?!
Roy!
Rekkuuza! I’ll take you on!
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Windie! Let’s use Flamethrower, too!
Liko!
Watch out, Roy!
Terapagos?
What is happening?!
It’s so beautiful...
What is that?
Terapagos... That form...!
Is that the light of evolution?
No, it’s something else!
Terapagos!
Rekkuuza’s...
Talk about unwelcome interruptions...
The Explorers...
Yeah... Based on the timing,
I doubt they were tailing us this time...
Still, I don’t like this.
It’s gone...
After I finally got to see it again...
Roy.
Let’s head back to the ship.
Sure.
Grandma?
Yes... I’ll be right there.
It doesn’t seem injured.
It must be worn out
after using up all its energy like that.
You go to bed, Liko.
I’ll stay here overnight.
Okay...
I wanted to see it for so long...
But when the time came,
I couldn’t do a thing...
It barely even looked my way.
But next time, for sure...
Hogator?
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
So, Terapagos really was the Pokémon
depicted in Lucius’s journal?
Yes. The power I sensed from it
was identical to that of the Six Heroes.
But after it used that power,
it immediately reverted to its usual form.
And it seems Rekkuuza decided to leave
the moment it saw that happen.
Almost as if it had no interest whatsoever
in the untransformed Terapagos.
Rekkuuza may have been
testing Terapagos’s power.
Meeting Oliva, Galarian Fire, and Laplace
may have awakened Terapagos...
...and granted it some power.
But maybe that power
isn’t complete yet?
Aside from Rekkuuza,
two of the Six Heroes remain.
Basagiri and Entei.
All right! That gives us
a clear goal to strive for!
Let’s do this, Cap!
I must express my gratitude,
Diana-san.
Why so formal all of a sudden?
This is what I dreamed of doing
when I became a professor!
Going on an adventure with
unknown Pokémon on center stage...
Guess it just hit me all at once.
I know the feeling.
It’s just like my own desire to
pick up where I left off thirty years ago.
Now...
I entrust Liko to you!
Of course!
Wait, where’d that come from?!
I was thinking of pursuing
this adventure in my own way.
The investigation on Laplace and
the run-in with Rekkuuza helped reassure me...
...that Liko will be safe with you,
the Rising Voltteccers.
That said...
There’s still something
that worries me.
I told you about how
I reunited with an old friend, right?
He was with the Explorers.
That made me want to
look into them myself.
Well, if so, I can...
Traveling light is better
in times like these.
And traveling in packs
isn’t really my strong suit, anyway.
Diana-san...
You should focus on
finding the Six Heroes.
And then pursue Rakua.
I’ll investigate why they seek
the pendant and Terapagos.
That is my responsibility as the adventurer
who got you and Liko wrapped up in this mess.
I understand.
All right!
Ah, but I don’t want to
worry the others.
So keep this to yourself, okay?
I will. But please,
call us if anything goes wrong.
Oh, right... You don’t have
a Smartphone Rotom, do you?
What do we do?
I’m no good with machines.
If I need you,
I’ll have this one deliver the message.
Now, then...
One last thing before I go!
Liko.
Do you have a moment?
How can we get Rekkuuza to battle us?
Huh?
Roy. Mind coming along?
You want us to battle you?
The two of us, together?
That’s right.
You must have a lot on your minds
after what just happened.
But both of you
are full-fledged trainers!
And when it comes time
to dispel your doubts,
nothing beats a good battle!
Battle... you...
C’mon Liko, let’s do it!
Yeah!
Well, that settles it!
We’ll be watching!
You got this, kids!
Go wild!
Curious, are we?
I mean, yeah.
No way I could miss this match!
And if I record it, they can
use the footage for reference later!
Land a single hit
on Windie and you win!
We’re good to go!
Show us what you’ve got!
All right! Here goes!
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Windie! Use Divine Speed!
Nyahoja!
Hogator! Flamethrower!
We’ll answer with our own Flamethrower!
Hogator!
Diana-san isn’t holding back one bit.
Windie! Clear Skies!
That looks like it could be trouble!
Yeah. The real fight starts here.
Don’t count us out yet!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
That’s super effective
against Windie! Good move!
Gah, so close!
Nyahoja! Use a big Leafage!
Burn it all to ash with Flamethrower!
Clear Skies made the flames
even stronger!
What’s the matter?
I can’t even call this a warm-up!
She’s so strong...
What now?
Nyahoja?
Hogator?
Is this thanks to Clear Skies?
Hogator’s saying “I’m not done yet!”
Right!
This is no time to get cold feet.
Right, Nyahoja?
Now it’s really getting exciting!
Time to go all in, you two!
Roy! Let’s do this our way!
Our way...
I gotcha!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
We won’t give in! Go for it!
What’s up with you two?
Nyahoja! Leafage!
No use trying to distract us!
Divine Speed!
Nyahoja!
Hogator! Slide in!
Nyahoja! Leafage!
Hogator! Flamethrower!
Windie! Wipe out their attacks
with Flamethrower!
Don’t give in, Hogator!
Now, Nyahoja! Scratch!
I landed the hit, Roy!
Yeah! Mission accomplished!
Mm-hmm... You got me good.
Very well done, you two.
A tactic utilizing the gap in size, huh?
Way to use your heads!
We decided we’d handle it our way!
Hogator distracted them
to give us an opening!
On top of that...
You picked up on what Clear Skies could do.
That’s a perfect score from me!
Hogator, you were incredible!
Nyahoja, you did really great!
No matter how big or strong the foe,
there is always a way to fight back!
A trainer must remain resolute
until they find that way forward!
It seems you understand that now.
Yes!
There’s still so much we can do!
Yeah! I want to keep getting
better and better as a trainer!
Same!
Grandma has taught us so much!
Of course, there’s still a lot
I don’t understand, but...
Liko! Terapagos is awake!
There’s still a lot
I don’t understand...
About Rekkuuza. About Lucius.
About Rakua.
Nothing but unknowns!
But that’s exactly why I want to know!
Together with
the Rising Voltteccers and Nyahoja,
my journey will go on!
Welcome back, Amethio-sama.
I understand you made contact
with Rekkuuza?
Though it got away from me.
Then I take it you understand
what you now need?
Yeah...
I want more power.
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Molly here. Sounds like this'll be worth my time.
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Hmm? Liko and Roy
are sneaking about, doing...
Huh?! You’re planning a party?! Woo!
Y’all like parties?
I mean, who doesn’t like parties?
Ooh, this is so exciting!
I can’t just sit around!
And with that said...
To be continued next time,
on Pocket Monsters:
Going Their Own Ways
Let’s have some fun!
Another day bursting with energy!
Terapagos’s Sparkly Exploration Diary!
Terapagos's Sparkly Exploration Diary
Huh? The heck is all this?!