We’re right in the middle of
our Terastal Course implementation tests.
After Dot, it’s Roy’s turn next.
Our next destination is Fridge Town!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Don’t give up, don’t give up! Go for it!
Roy and Hogator
sure are in a good mood!
I can’t believe they can
sing like that when it’s this cold.
We were basically born
to partner up together, huh?
I can just feel it
when we sing together like this!
Right, Hogator?
Yeah, you’ve been singing together
since the very day you met.
Even during battles.
Y’know, it definitely seems like Hogator’s moves
get stronger when you sing during battle.
Absolutely!
It’s like... It fills us with courage!
And strength! And... all sortsa stuff!
What’s up?
The town!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Resound, My Soul! The Challenge to Rhyme
So this is Fridge Town!
There’s so many candles...
It’s really pretty!
Those candles are kept lit to help guide departing souls.
This is the town of
snow and requiems, after all.
Requiems...
A town that helps souls find peace?
Yep. There’s a legend passed down
in the mountains ‘round here.
It’s said that souls gather here once their time is over,
so that they may return to the sky.
This town has a long history of festivals
meant to ensure those souls can depart in peace.
Festivals?
Nowadays, there’re even concerts
in the town’s plaza.
Concerts? In a quiet town like this?
Sounds kinda fun.
I think there’s two concerts today, actually.
A day show and a night show.
Um, I’m here to take
my implementation test.
Where can I find the Gym?
Oh, the Gym is right over...
There it is!
Fridge Gym!
Huh? Rhyme isn’t here?
She went out earlier.
She’s probably somewhere
near the plaza stage,
so would you be all right
to look for her?
Think Ms. Rhyme’s
gonna watch the concert too?
I wonder what kind of show it’ll be.
What is it, Hogator?
Huh? Pokémon?
They’re adorable!
Looks like they’re having fun!
That tickles!
Wait...
Huh? I feel...
...kinda exhausted.
This is weird.
What’s going on?
Bochi. Ghost Dog Pokémon.
Ghost type.
This Pokémon is said to be the reincarnation of
wild dog Pokémon that die without ever meeting a human.
It slowly saps the life essence
of those nearby it.
Huh?!
It’s sapping our life essence?
Wait, does that mean...?
Roy, are you okay?
You’ve got a battle coming up and all...
I’m all good!
Eating brought my energy back!
Right, Hogator?
Huh?
Terapagos?!
Wait!
Nyarote!
Catch it!
They’re getting away!
Wait!
Liko? Roy and Dot, too!
Terapagos!
Pamot, catch it!
Nice catch!
Nemo?!
I see. So your implementation test
is with Ms. Rhyme, Roy?
Yeah!
But I guess she went to go see the concert,
so we’re going over to look for her.
Huh? No, not quite...
Ms. Rhyme is performing at the concert.
Performing?
She’s a Gym Leader and
a super-famous rapper!
Huh?! For real?!
So, Nemo...
Are you here to see the concert?
Ms. Rhyme’s concerts
have open participation segments,
and sometimes you get to see
heated Pokémon battles.
That’s why I’m going.
Ooh!
There’s a lot more people than before.
Ahem, test, test... Is the mic good?
We all set for the lighting rehearsal?
Think Ms. Rhyme’s here?
I don’t see her anywhere.
‘Scuse me!
Is Ms. Rhyme here?!
I wanna do my implementation test
battle, please!
Maybe she’s not here yet...
Then how about battling me inst—
Heya, dude in the crowd!
You wanna battle?
I’m MC Kammer
and I’ll be your host today.
We’re just about to rehearse,
and having someone on stage
would be a huge help.
So how about you come
and battle me right now?
Sounds like fun!
Let’s do it, Hogator!
Thanks for helping out!
It’s just rehearsal,
but let’s blow the roof off this place!
Yeah!
I was hoping to battle, you know...
But there’s nothing like
getting to watch Roy battle!
All right then... Light up the stage!
Bring down the hammer, Yamirami!
Let’s give it all we got, Hogator!
Let the battle begin!
Yamirami... Use Shadow Claw!
Dodge it, Hogator!
Power Gem!
Now it’s our turn!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Don’t give up, don’t give up! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Huh? He’s singing?
Roy and Hogator have won
lots of battles by singing together.
Don’t give up, don’t give up! Go for it!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Ah... So that’s how
they get in sync with each other?
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
What’s up? You singing ‘cause this is
a concert rehearsal or something, dude?
Don’t give up, don’t give up!
Nitro Charge!
Whoa! Dodge it, Yamirami!
Aw, dang... You only needed one swing
to bring the hammer down on us!
Good effort, Yamirami.
You’re strong, dude!
‘Kay. Thanks to you,
rehearsal’s all done.
Thanks!
We did it, Hogator!
We really are unbeatable
when we sing together!
So, looks like the stage is
good and warmed up now!
Everyone, give it up for
the dude from our opening battle!
That’s a big crowd!
When did they get here?
Thanks...
Perfect timing, too!
Everybody here ready?
Then lemme introduce
the star of today’s show!
Come on, Soulful Beat!
Rhyme!
Yo, yo, yo, how are you doing?
Hot dynamite! I’m Rhyme, a.k.a...
The Soulful Beat!
Hands up, looking neat.
Couldn’t sit still
in my Gym Leader seat.
This rap’s gonna teach you
all about vibes.
So it’s time for wannabes
to say bye-bye.
Living with Ghost-types
is my history.
Ghosts but they’re alive,
ain’t that a mystery?
Word is when I’ve got my Ghost types,
ain’t nobody can beat me, yeah!
Put your hands up,
‘cause I’m Rhyme, I’m hot dynamite.
H-Huh?! Y-You’re kidding me!
Thank you, baby!
Explosive vibes!
Bomb bomb check it, ghost flow.
Roy?
What’s got you so surprised?
Sh-She’s Ms. Rhyme?!
Put your hands up,
‘cause I’m Rhyme, I’m hot dynamite.
Sure is. She’s a rapper and a Gym Leader.
A Ghost-type specialist.
Thank you, baby!
Sharing soulful tunes anytime,
check it out, make it hot, ghost flow.
That was her!
You know, that mysterious trainer I told you about!
The one who told me about Konoyozaru!
Huh?! That was Ms. Rhyme?
So you really weren’t just dreaming?!
I told you so!
Rhyme! Say “Gym Leader”!
Gym Leader!
Say “Ghost type”!
Ghost type!
Say “flow and rhyme”!
Flow and rhyme!
Now raise your voice and your hands,
let’s make some noise!
Okay! Time for our show’s
signature open participation section!
So, who thinks they’re ready
to bring some heat to this stage?
Me!
Terastal Course student, Roy!
I’m here to take
your implementation test!
Ooh!
Ghost flow!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Joining us on stage...
The guy who brought down the hammer
in his battle earlier... Roy!
The academy told me
a course student was coming,
but I never thought it’d be you.
Ain’t that something?
I was surprised, too!
We did end up
running into Konoyozaru later!
Well, that’s good to hear.
Guessing your vibes
must’ve brought you together.
So. You wanna take your test, right?
Yeah!
Okay!
Well, I’d like to say “okay,” but...
This is still a concert, y’know.
I can’t let you take it just like that.
Huh?
If you want to battle me,
you’re gonna have to heat this place up
with a rap battle first!
Do your best to liven this place up, man!
Come on, music!
A rap battle?
Can Roy even do that?
All right! I’ll give it a try!
You challenge me to a battle of rap?
Crushing a kid like you should be a snap.
Get outta here
before you make yourself a fool
Let-down challenger
who’s gonna get schooled
I’ll show you a true Terastal!
Shiny and energetic, a real sparkle!
Staying true to my path is just the best!
I’m ready to pass any battle or test!
You’re pretty good!
Okay, let’s get this
implementation test going.
All right!
Whoa! Rhyme’s taking the challenge!
Time for a Pokémon battle!
Let me ask you one thing.
What does Terastal mean to you?
Terastal is...
...something I need...
...to get closer to my dream,
the black Rekkuuza!
That’s a harsh path
that’ll shake your very soul.
Lemme test you and see if
you’ve actually got the guts to go on!
Hakadog!
The implementation tests
use two Pokémon.
You know that, right?
Yeah!
Go, Taikaiden!
The Kaiden from before!
It evolved, huh?
Okay then, come at me!
Let the battle begin!
Taikaiden, use Spark!
Dodge it!
It’s even faster
than when it was Kaiden!
Looking good! Keep using Spark!
One more Spark!
You think you’re slick,
but you’re just one-trick!
Hakadog! Ghost Dive!
Taikaiden! Climb!
You’re not going anywhere! Crunch!
Taikaiden is unable to battle!
Taikaiden!
You gave it your all.
Still, you’ve given me a clue to follow.
So, finally making your appearance.
How about you show me
that potential I sensed last time?
Let’s do it just like
we did before, Hogator!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
He’s singing again?
There it is! His trick to victory!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Go for it!
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
The same tactic
you used against MC Kammer.
Get! Back! On your feet!
I’ll jump in first, then.
Hakadog, use Scary Face!
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Crunch!
Nitro Charge!
One more Nitro Charge!
Ghost Dive!
Now! Turn and use Flamethrower!
Hakadog is unable to battle!
Now it’s a 1v1!
Thanks, Hakadog.
Take a rest for now.
We won again!
We’re amazing!
Maybe we really are unbeatable!
Unbeatable, huh?
You sure are confident.
Let me ask you one more thing.
What does singing mean to you?
Huh? Singing?
Singing...? Hmm...
I’ll put it another way...
Why do you and Hogator sing?
What brings you to sing during battle?
It...
...helps us get stronger.
It helps us win!
Okay. I hear you.
Come on out, Strinder!
Strinder?!
Strinder: Low Form. Punk Pokémon.
Electric/Poison type.
It plucks at the organ on its chest to generate electricity,
which also produces sound akin to that of a bass guitar.
It’s not a Ghost type...
Your song, plus Strinder’s sound...
Let’s see how this jam session turns out.
I’ll win for sure, and pass my test!
Get! Back! On your feet!
The same tactic again...
Flamethrower!
Overdrive!
She repelled it?!
Then... Stomping Tantrum!
Overdrive!
She even blocked Stomping Tantrum?!
In that case... Nitro Charge!
Blast Waves!
Hogator!
No way...
My attacks can’t get through?!
Strinder has an ability that greatly strengthens
sound-based moves: Punk Rock!
He’s a sound move specialist.
What’s wrong?
Weren’t you singing to get stronger?
This isn’t over yet!
Let’s go, Hogator! Sing!
Get! Back! On your feet!
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Don’t give up, Hogator!
Charm Voice!
But why? That was a hit!
The ability Punk Rock doesn’t just
strengthen moves...
It reduces damage taken
from sound moves, too.
Plus, Charm Voice being a Fairy move
means it’ll struggle against Poison types.
No way...
Then what’s he even supposed to do?!
It’s about time I fought back.
Strinder! Evil Eye!
Jump and dodge it, Hogator!
Overdrive!
Hogator!
At this point...
Terastallize!
Terastallizing out of desperation...
Is that the kind of path
that’ll lead you to Rekkuuza?
You can’t beat my Strinder
with those weak vibes!
Venom Shock!
Overdrive!
Hogator!
Are you okay?!
Roy... Hogator...
I lost... How...?
A trainer who forgets their song
is a partner who has their rhythm wrong.
Do you mean... me?
You can’t put this guy’s
fiery vibes to good use.
To be blunt,
you’re a failure of a partner.
A failure... of a partner...
You’ve failed your implementation test.
Go wash your soul and come back!
Hey, man! Stick around
for the second half of the concert!
Ms. Rhyme didn’t even Terastallize...
We lost bad... I’m sorry, Hogator.
Roy...
It's my fault Hogator isn’t
living up to his full potential...
That’s what makes me
a failure of a partner...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Ghost Dog Pokémon, Hakadog.
A Pokémon that is usually found sleeping,
buried in graveyards.
Hakadog
Ghost Dog Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Hakadog
Ghost Dog Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Height
2.0m
It hates having a certain body part touched,
Weight
15.0kg
but do you know which part that is?
Where on its body does it hate being touched?
Its head
Its tail
Its back
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Where on its body does it
hate being touched?
A: Its head
Where on its body does it
hate being touched?
A: Its head
The answer is A: Its head.
Hakadog cherish the protuberance
atop their heads.
It’ll only let you touch it
if it trusts you.
Next episode
I wanna challenge Ms. Rhyme again!
In that case...
Try some Awesome Training!
Awesome Training?
That... kinda sounds awesome!
But will it really be enough to win?
Ms. Rhyme asked you
about your singing, right?
What made you like singing
in the first place?
Well...
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Me and Hogator’s Song
Fill me with your fire, you hear?
Me and Hogator's Song