There can be no doubt.
This is it.
The place where we, in time gone by...
It has been an age, Lucius.
This is where you ultimately perished,
after you stood in my way.
In a sense, I suppose this gigantic Rakurium
serves as your gravestone.
So you’ve reclaimed your prior form,
my dear partner?
Then I shall, as well...
Only a temporary reprieve,
but I’ve no choice...
Now then, Zygarde!
Dig up the Rakurium!
Grandfather!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Guidance of the Black Rekkuuza
Amethio, is it?
I believe I ordered your suspension.
Spinel is using you, Grandfather!
He intends to monopolize
the Rakurium!
He has been researching it
of his own accord!
I ordered his research
into the Rakurium.
Are you familiar with
Rakurium Spheres?
I found the proof in Spinel’s lab...
He’s plotting something
involving the Rakurium!
Spinel is taking the initiative towards
drawing out the full potential of its power.
What is so wrong with that?
Grandfather...
Is Rakurium truly a righteous thing?
While under the influence
of Rakurium, Spinel’s Blacky...
...seemed to be in great pain!
I would never want to see
my own partner writhing in pain.
Even without borrowing
the Rakurium’s power,
there must be other avenues
for us to assist people and Pokémon!
So that is the conclusion
you’ve reached in that head of yours?
Yes.
Pathetic!
That’s enough. Stand back.
Please, wait!
Zygarde! Dig up the Rakurium!
Liko...
Pagogo’s really mad...
I bet that’s the Rakurium.
It’s begun.
They’re more trouble than expected.
Get up, Kyojiohn!
Let’s have us a li’l rampage, Onigohri!
Rock Slide!
Muddy Water!
Huh?!
But why...?
Liko! Roy!
R-Right!
Taikaiden!
Hey! Don’tcha dare run away!
Tebrim!
Nakanuchan!
Brutal Swing!
I said you ain’t goin’ nowh—
Ya freak!
You little snots...
Do you know what you just did?!
You intend to obstruct us?
Depending on severity, the—
We’re prepared for any punishment
we might receive!
Our mission takes priority right now.
We will proceed
to the next stage immediately.
Do my words not reach you,
Grandfather...?
My, oh my...
Weren’t you put on leave?
I know what you’re plotting!
Using my grandfather like this...!
I haven’t the time
to deal with you right now.
Friede!
Roy!
All of you okay?
Thanks, Taikaiden.
My, my, even more visitors!
We’ve pulled quite a crowd!
Spinel...
Huh? Amethio...
Pagogo!
Terapagos.
So that’s Gibeon...
Is he really
over one hundred years old?
A white... Zygarde...
This is very bad...
The power of the Rakurium
is overflowing.
But then...
What’s gonna happen?
Judging by the tales
from a hundred years ago,
I wouldn’t be surprised
if Rakua collapsed again.
Huh?!
We have to stop him!
You are too late.
The Rakurium
will be coming with us.
They’re calling out...?
Such pests...
Zygarde! Ignore all else and dig it up!
What is that?
Gibeon...
You’re as heavy-handed as ever, I see.
I understand now...
So this was your goal...
Zygarde!
You have betrayed me once more!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Lucius...
He was alive!
I finally get to meet you, Liko.
Oliva...
Fire...
Laplace...
Basagiri...
Entei...
Rekkuuza...
Ooh! And you look well, Pagogo!
I’m glad you came to see me!
Obstruc—
Wait.
But, Master Gibeon...
Welcome to Rakua.
I’ve been waiting for you,
members of the Rising Voltteccers.
How do you know about us...?
Zygarde has shown me
what’s been going on in the outside world.
I’ve even seen Roy
obtaining one of my Monster Balls,
and eventually reaching Rekkuuza.
U-Um! I-I’ve always admired you as
the Ancient Adventurer, Lucius—Er, Mr. Lucius!
Oh, I know that well.
I’m just as familiar with all your adventures thus far.
And naturally, Gibeon...
I know of your exploits
with the current Explorers as well.
How dare you, Zygarde?!
Feigning being enchained,
and going so far as to monitor me...?!
Monitor?
What’s he mean?
For that...
...I’ll borrow some of your power, Pagogo.
One hundred years ago,
after we worked together to stop
the Rakurium reaching out into the world, I...
...was sealed inside Rakua.
I seem to have slept for a long time...
...but then one day,
I felt a voice inside my head.
It was Gibeon’s white Zygarde.
For these one hundred years,
he had used the Cells he left in Rakua—
as well as his Cells scattered throughout the world—
to monitor whether exposure to Rakurium
had affected the ecosystems of Pokémon.
Zygarde saw Rakua’s
ever-expanding Rakurium as a threat.
So then, Rakurium really is...
Rakurium does not originate
from this planet.
In the end, it can only
bring disaster upon Pokémon.
How foolish. Utter nonsense.
One hundred years have passed
since our Rakua adventure ended,
and Terapagos has now revived.
With that well in mind, Gibeon...
...you began to move once again,
seeking the Rakurium.
In order to put a stop
to your ambitions,
Zygarde sent a message to my Rekkuuza,
which had left its ball.
A message?!
“I want you to find trainers worthy of
inheriting Pagogo and the Six Heroes.”
Then, as if guided by Rekkuuza,
you assembled the Six Heroes at last,
reclaimed Pagogo’s power, and arrived at Rakua.
One heck of a surprise...
I never imagined this was all
the will of Zygarde and Rekkuuza.
But Rekkuuza did not aid you,
even once.
Which was because...
...you sought out Rakua
by your own wills, for Pagogo’s sake.
Because this was your adventure!
Our adventure...!
That is what has made you
stronger as trainers,
and you’ve grown enough to exceed
even Rekkuuza’s expectations.
In that event, Lucius...!
Why did you allow them
to unseal Rakua?
Sealing it away isn’t enough!
Please!
I want you to work together
to get rid of the Rakurium!
I know you can do it—
No...
You are the only ones who can do it!
I will not allow this!
It’s mine!
I will have it!
As I told you,
this power is dangerous!
You’re just like you were
a hundred years ago!
Rakurium is a source of life!
It lets you live longer,
and stronger than ever!
By extending the time
we’ve been given,
people and Pokémon
can enjoy even fuller lives!
So that’s what Rakurium is used for...
But...!
What I saw was...!
Why...?
Why are you alive?
Why do you interfere?
If you rely on powers
beyond the laws of this world,
perishing is all that awaits you!
By taking things one step at a time,
and walking alongside Pokémon...
...we can forge links
down to future generations!
But if you get rid of the Rakurium,
won’t that mean the end of the paradise that is Rakua?
A flourishing energy circulation cycle
has already established itself in these lands!
The Pokémon can go on
living happy lives!
I get it...
Sounds like Rakua doesn’t need
the Rakurium anymore.
And as such...
It should be of no concern if we take it, yes?
People mustn’t lay their hands
on the Rakurium!
If you dig it up by force,
you’ll end up activating it!
Activating...
Isn’t that...?
So applying an external force
would cause unforeseen reactions, huh...?
Correct.
As if to drive away human hands,
it releases a wicked energy.
Just like one hundred years ago, it will affect
the natural environment and make Pokémon go berserk.
And that’s the thing you wish to use?!
I am aware of the risks
a hundred times over.
Which is why, through extensive research
and mindful handling, we shall make use of it safely.
Rakurium will lead the world
to new evolution.
One plus one is nothing more than two,
but Rakurium can change that.
It can multiply “one” a hundred—
even a thousand times over!
People and Pokémon can make great leaps,
surpassing the limits and conventions of science!
We simply cannot
let a power like that go unused!
So much hubris!
What’s really important is—
We’ve heard enough.
You are no more than a ghost.
Master Gibeon.
His words are meaningless to us.
Master Gibeon?
You may begin.
Right.
Commence the operation.
What are those things?
Come on out, Jibacoil!
What’s he doing?
They’re activating
the underground Rakurium?!
What I seek is not the petty shards of crystal
scattered about our feet...
But rather the Core itself,
sleeping deep underground!
The Core?!
If the Core awakens,
Rakurium will be produced without end.
If the Rakurium Core activates,
it’ll be beyond human control!
Oh, but it won’t...
Thanks to the scientific prowess of Exceed.
Jibacoil!
Cap?
Lizardon?
Look at Cap!
Lizardon’s acting weird, too!
That’s due to me weakening them
in our battle earlier.
It may have made them
more susceptible.
Stop it!
Return!
Drat...
I’ll stop those machines!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Can’t letcha do that.
Why else would we
be standing guard on them?
Now then, Rakurium!
Awaken under my command!
Not good!
It’s gonna go out of control!
Stop this, Gibeon!
This time, the whole world will surely perish!
If they are to perish,
then let them perish!
Only the people and Pokémon who take up
the great power of Rakurium shall live on...
...to usher in
a new era of prosperity!
Right. There’s no other choice.
Liko!
Gather everyone’s power into Pagogo!
Pagogo...
Understood.
Six Heroes!
Lend Pagogo your strength!
You expect me to give it up?!
My whole life has been devoted
to the Rakurium!
Even after being betrayed by Lucius and Rystal,
and having my dreams quashed...
I believed in the potential of Rakurium...
Lived for one hundred years...
...and have returned to Rakua.
I had no intention of betraying you.
Neither did Rystal.
We treasured all the time we spent with you...
The days of our adventures together.
Then how?! How can you not
understand my ideals?!
Right...
We should have discussed things
so much more back then...
Gibeon...
I’m sorry.
It’s too late for mere
words of apology!
Zygarde! Lend me your aid!
Our ways of thinking may differ,
but I still believe in you
as my partner!
These hundred years since losing my friends...
You are the only one who has remained!
I beg you, Zygarde!
I want you to fight for my sake!
There’s no way
Zygarde’ll go along with—
No way...!
You’ve gotta be kidding...
Why are you helping the bad guy?!
Gibeon...
You chump!
Have you lost your mind?
Amethio...
And here I was, eyeing you as heir
to the Explorers someday...
To think you would turn your fangs against me.
I want to protect you, Grandfather!
That is why this is the path
I must now choose!
I need more strength!
Would you fight alongside me?
Liko!
Yeah!
Nyarote! Shine in full bloom!
Achigator! Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Welcamo! Glitz it up,
go viral, and shine!
Follow your own path!
Soublades!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Order Pokémon, Zygarde.
Small individuals known as Cells
assemble together, creating larger bodies.
Zygarde
Order Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ground
Zygarde
Order Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ground
Height
5.0m
Zygarde Cell
Regular color
Weight
305.0kg
But do you know what thing
Zygarde does across the world?
What does Zygarde do across the world?
Create
Destroy
Monitor
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does Zygarde do across the world?
C: Monitor
The answer is C: Monitor!
Zygarde is said to scatter its Cells
across the world,
and to constantly be monitoring
the ecosystem for any issues!
Next episode
Time to battle Zygarde!
We’re not gonna lose!
We’re up against a Legendary Pokémon...
How should we handle this fight...?
There’s no time.
We will stop my grandfather!
For Pagogo to purify the Rakurium,
we need to win this!
Nyarote...
Right. With Pokémon by my side...
With you by my side...!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Earth-Quaking White Zygarde
Nyarote?!