Rakurium, which brings
disaster upon Pokémon...
In order to stop Gibeon, who had been seeking it,
we battled the white Zygarde.
Striving to link together everyone’s desires,
Nyarote evolved into Masquernya.
Zygarde left Gibeon’s side...
...and Pagogo finally took on
its third form!
The Rakurium...
It’s disappearing!
Looks like it worked.
We did it...
We did it, Pagogo!
You really gave it your all, Pagogo.
Thank you.
Gibeon...
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
At the End of the Adventure
Gibeon-sama...
The Rakurium is lost...
My wish will never be...
Grandfather.
You founded Exceed for the advancement
of people and Pokémon.
From all I have seen...
You have gone to great lengths in pursuit of that goal.
Amethio...
As your grandson...
Rather, as a member of the Explorers...
...I vowed that I would
inherit your will.
Even without using the Rakurium,
I’ll find something we can do
for the future of Pokémon and people.
I will devote my life
to searching for it!
Zygarde abandoned me...
Deserted even by my own partner...
Meaning, I suppose, that I never had the right
to speak to the future of people and Pokémon!
That’s not true, Gibeon.
As a scientist, it was once your wholehearted wish
to bring happiness to Pokémon and people.
That is precisely why Zygarde, observer of the ecosystem,
who shared your same desires...
...chose you as his partner.
Then... Zygarde...
...understood me.
The future is not something
you can shape by your own desire.
It’s something you discover
at the end of your adventure.
Discover...
What we can do now is believe in the next generation
and entrust this world to them, don’t you think?
Amethio has bright eyes.
I bet you he’s up to the task.
Mm-hmm.
Everyone...
This is goodbye.
No way...
Not right when we finally met!
It’s all right.
Conveying Zygarde
and Rekkuuza’s desires to you...
...and having you purify
the Rakurium...
That was the final task
remaining for me.
Everyone...
Thank you for everything.
Pagogo...
I’m happy I got to see you again.
Liko...
Please keep looking after Pagogo.
Now, let us go, Gibeon.
Rystal is waiting for us.
Our adventure is not over yet.
Isn’t that right?
Grandfather!
Amethio...
Follow the path of your own beliefs;
alongside Soublades.
Gibeon-sama...
This can’t be real...
He just vanished...
Lucius...
Maybe Pagogo knew
this would be Lucius’s farewell...
...and wanted to meet with him,
one last time...
No, Pagogo’s just smiling
because it got to see him again.
The Ancient Monster Balls!
Rekkuuza’s, too!
What’s going on?
With their partner Lucius gone,
maybe the Six Heroes
have returned to being wild.
It’s finally over... All of it.
How disappointing.
Gibeon-sama
had my wholehearted respect.
Using the Rakurium to bring
an eternal blessing upon the world...
And here I assumed I would be
the one to inherit Gibeon-sama’s will.
But now that Gibeon-sama
has gone...
...I shall surpass Gibeon!
Those are Rakurium Spheres!
Rakurium... Spheres?
Don’t tell me... They’re filled with...
I have already
harnessed it for myself!
Cap!
Hey, Spinel!
Hey! What’re ya playin’ at?!
It’s fine. Just keep quiet and watch.
Huh?
From this moment forth...
The Explorers shall occupy Rakua!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Calm down, everyone!
Stop it! Weren’t you guys friends?!
It’s no good!
We can’t get through to them!
Seems to have been quite effective.
Now they’re completely useless to you.
We have to do something!
That’s too reckless!
We don’t have the strength left to fight the Six Heroes!
But...
...we can’t just leave them like this!
Pagogo...
Please! Just stop this!
No!
Rekkuuza!
It protected us?
Got it, Rekkuuza.
Roy...
You’re saying “Leave this to me,
and get going!”, yeah?
All right.
Amethio-sama!
It’s you! You’re all okay?
Never mind us! Hurry and withdraw!
Return, Soublades!
Armorgaw!
We better hurry, too!
Masquernya, Pagogo...
I’ll get you someplace safe,
so just rest up for now.
Achigator.
Welcamo.
Thank you, Rekkuuza!
Please do what you can for them!
Let’s go!
Over there!
The Pokémon are all...
This is awful...
They can’t get away with this mess!
It truly is bizarre...
Now that the Rakurium’s gone,
what’s there to gain from occupying Rakua?
The belt!
Liko!
Look out!
You guys!
You okay?
Lucius’s memoirs...
They’re irreplaceable...
All that takes form is lost in time.
But the story of the Ancient Adventurer...
will last for as long as you remember it.
Now then...
If only we could fly...
Tebrim?
Friede! Get Lizardon!
Tebrim! Healing Pulse!
Lizardon!
Thank you, Tebrim!
All right, let’s move!
Right!
Taikaiden, help me out!
Th-The wind’s so strong...!
I’m falling!
Dot! Hang in there!
Y-Yeah...
Just hold on until we make it out!
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Taikaiden, give it all you’ve got!
Lizardon, you’re incredible!
You too, Taikaiden!
Look out!
You saved us!
Thanks, Cap!
All right! Just keep that up
‘til we’re outta here!
Is everyone okay?
Yeah.
You really came through
for us, Lizardon.
You too, Taikaiden.
Great work!
Though, we’ll have to walk
the rest of the way...
Climbing down now’s too dangerous!
But we sure can’t stay here!
What do we do...?
Don’t get anxious, now.
Friede?
Can’t let ourselves forget...
...that we’ve got a home to return to...
...and friends we can depend on!
The Brave Asagi!
Amazing!
They came to get us!
Yeah, talk about perfect timing!
But... Aren’t they going above
the ship’s max altitude?
No way...
They were so close...
It’s not over yet!
Believe in our friends...
in the Rising Voltteccers!
Right.
It won’t go any further!
This is a dire emergency.
Which means...
Time to bust this thing out!
Everyone, brace for impact!
Got it. Let ‘er rip!
Ignite... our fire!
All right! Ready when you are!
Brave Asagi, fly up into infinity!
Huh?
The Brave Asagi: Infinite Rising!
Infinite Rising?!
Didn’t I tell you to look forward
to an emergency?
What’s that?
What’s this button do?
Ahh! Don’t push that!
That’s the ace up our sleeve.
Ace up our sleeve?
That button is a little secret
that’ll be handy in an emergency.
So that’s what it...
Hurry aboard!
Orio!
The jet engines are straining
the ship’s hull, and bad!
Okay, reducing speed!
Let’s hurry!
Right!
Made it in time!
Don’t relax yet! Inside, quick!
Friede!
What are you doing?! Hurry up!
Cap, look after everyone for me.
That was the final sight I saw...
at the end of my adventure.
- One year later -
Liko! You still sleeping in there?!
Class’ll start without you!
Sorry! I’ll be right out!
Masquernya, Tebrim. Let’s go.
What’s wrong?
Forget to do your homework?
No, just... spacing out.
Huh? You not getting enough sleep?
One year on from
the big incident at Mt. Kumuri...
Director Spinel, is the natural landscape
that was lost to the notorious Rising Voltteccers...
...any closer to
being restored?
Yes. Thanks to Exceed’s preservation efforts,
it is slowly but surely being reclaimed.
Do you have any comment to give regarding the rumors
of unknown effects arising in Pokémon worldwide?
It’s nothing to worry about.
Everything is being taken care of
under the guiding hands of the Explorers.
I see. Then we can all rest easy,
knowing that the Explorers are around.
Now...
Let’s go find ‘em!
Found you!
Liko!
Roy?!
The adventure heads to a new stage!
We’re going to get it back!
The truth of the Rising Voltteccers!
Now, together, we will get it back
Opening Theme: GET BACK
Song by: Yuzu
Mega-new!
Yeah, our utopia
Looks like you’re
in a mega-pinch, eh Roy?!
Lucario!
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
Mega-powered up!
Keep your mega-gaze
locked onto AniPoké!
waking up there! Get it back!
Keep your mega-gaze locked onto AniPoké!
Let’s go, once again... To our sky!
The future!
Get it back!
Pocket Monsters: Mega Voltage!
Entering a new chapter!
Don't miss it!!
Don’t miss it!