Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Reboot! To a World of Adventures!!
Friede!
Hey! It’s been a while!
Looks like you’re doing well, Cap.
Friede!
Why the surprise visit?
I thought you were busy at Exceed.
Things’ve finally quieted down,
so I got them to give me a day off.
Dropped in to invite you along
on some fieldwork.
Wanna come see
some awesome Pokémon?
Oh...
Hmm?
What’s wrong?
I thought you’d be ecstatic...
Oh, it’s just that, well...
We’ve seen plenty of awesome Pokémon already.
The Rakua adventure
was mega-awesome, too.
So we figured we’d relax for a while.
Sure, relaxation is important too, but...
I finally got some time off!
We oughta do something!
Well, I did wanna train with Roy...
But he says he ain’t got no motivation.
Oh, like you haven’t been going “Tomorrow, tomorrow”
for who knows how many days now.
Well, me and Yamirami
are already strongest, anyhow.
I’ve really got to record
some new Gurumin vids, too...
But... I’m really blanking on ideas.
Sounds like you’ve all
just been spacing out.
Liko... How about you?
Huh?
I...
All right!
Then let’s set off straight away!
Huh?
That okay, Captain?
Muscles of a Saidon...
I wonder how Mr. Zir’s doing.
There’s so many Cocoon...
There could be Spear nearby.
Be careful.
When you were a Hogator, there was
that whole mess with a Beequeen chasing you...
But don’t worry. You could take down
a whole pack of Spear now, Loudbone!
Stop!
A pack’s approaching.
Huh? It couldn’t be...!
Oh, it was just some Dodo...
That time I got chased by
a buncha Dodrio was a real nightmare.
Hey, Master... You sure there’s some kinda
mega-awesome Pokémon ‘round here?
How far do we have to go?
We’re nearly there.
As soon as we get through this...
The Pokémon I want you
to investigate is here.
What kind of Pokémon is it?
Well, you see...
It’s a Hinbass!
Hinbass?
I’d like for you to catch
the Hinbass that lives in this lake.
Hinbass. Fish Pokémon.
Water type.
It is ragged and shabby,
and is paid no attention by anyone.
It has a hardy life force,
but is slow and easy to catch.
Ragged and shabby...
Paid no attention by anyone...
What’s mega-awesome about that?!
When it evolves,
it becomes Milokallos!
Milokallos, huh...?
We battled one of those
at the Shining Pond.
That brings back memories!
Yeah. We’ve already fought a Milokallos,
so if it’s a Hinbass we’re up against...
Catching it’ll be a snap.
Oho. You sure about that?
Well then, just give it a go!
Argh! I’m not hookin’ anything!
Is it really even here?
Yo, Hinbass! Get out here!
Quit it, Ult!
You’re just gonna spook it!
There it is! The Hinbass!
I’m gonna be the one to catch it!
Awright! Easy win!
Huh?
Augh! One more time!
Now it’s my turn!
Got it!
What’s the big idea, Roy?!
I could ask you the same thing!
Just stay outta my way, you!
You’re the one getting in my way!
Wha—?!
Urk!
I’ve got it!
I-It’s heavy...
I’ll help you!
Ready, and...
A Yadoran?
Tough luck.
That Hinbass is something else.
Yeah.
Fishing it up might not be so easy.
New plan.
Wanival. Head underwater
and corner that Hinbass!
When it pops out of the water,
Masquernya...
...can hook it on her vine!
Here it comes!
Catch Hinbass with your vine!
We did it!
Aww, so close!
Grrr... Yamirami! Power Gem!
Wanival, catch it!
Loudbone! Flare Song!
Just what is that Hinbass?!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
Darn it!
How come we can’t even
get a foothold...?
Seems like you’re having trouble.
But the Index says
it’s slow and easy to catch...
The Index isn’t the final word
on Pokémon ecology.
They’ve each got their own quirks.
All stuff you’d never know without meeting them in person!
Hmph.
It’s mega-awesome, that’s for sure.
Now I’m mega-mega-fired up!
I wanna learn more about it!
I’ll catch it! Just you wait!
Let’s all work together!
Once it Flops,
it’ll be in midair and defenseless!
If we seize that moment...!
Now, Loudbone!
Stop it from moving
with Charm Voice!
Yamirami! Eerie Light!
Masquernya!
Wanival!
Wave Tackle!
Acrobatics!
Hey! Wait up, you!
Let’s go after it!
I’ll be making dinner
at sundown, y’hear?!
It’s not tiring out at all...
It’s got mega-stamina!
Almost like it has us in mind...
What’s going on?
Hmph! What a show-off!
Maybe...
...it wants us to
pay it some attention?
Huh?!
That’s why it’s doing this?!
You might be right.
I get it.
Shabby or not, its scales’re still mega-cool
once you get a good look at ‘em!
Yeah. They’re proof of
the hardy life it’s lived.
Yeah.
I was never into Hinbass before,
but now I think they’re great!
Look, it’s the Dodo from before!
Huh?! A Dodo started flying?!
It’s like it’s kicking off the air to go even higher!
Maybe it’s dreamed of getting to Fly?
Just like Cap did...
When we saw these Dodo earlier,
I didn’t realize there was one like that...
Wait, what? It’s gone!
Huh?!
It’s gotta have some crazy muscles
to Flop across dry land like that...
That’s some finesse...
They’re using their threads like ropes.
I always pictured
Cocoon being immobile...
Its guard is down.
We’ll catch it this time, Wanival!
What the...?!
A surfing Saidon?!
They can do that?!
Maybe...
...it observed how Water-type Pokémon
and people move, and copied them!
Even within the same species,
they’re all distinct!
Innerestin’!
Let’s go find some more!
Wait, Ult!
We gotta find Hinbass first!
I can look for Hinbass along the way!
I’m gonna check out
every Pokémon livin’ here!
He’s so reckless...
Welcome back.
You sure worked hard!
The Hinbass got away...
So frustrating...
We got so close a few times, though...
It was unreal.
Well, it is the Strongest Hinbass,
which no one’s ever managed to catch, after all.
Huh?!
Strongest...
Huh?
Didn’t I mention?
You did not!
Ahh, that hit the spot!
We didn’t manage to catch Hinbass,
but we had a lot of fun.
Yeah. Don’t think I’ve gotten that much exercise
in a long time. My muscles are already aching.
It really was amazing.
We got to meet
lots of interesting Pokémon.
And there’s still
loads of ‘em we ain’t met!
The world’s huge!
Pokémon’re so deep!
Adventures never end.
Even if you feel like you’re all burnt out,
you’ll end up aching for more.
Excitement never stops.
Get up!
What’s going on? It’s so early...
Shh! Just watch.
You know,
with the Rakua adventure over...
I wasn’t sure
what I wanted to do next.
But I’ve got it figured out now.
I want to keep having exciting adventures;
keep taking on heart-pounding challenges...
...alongside all of you, just like this!
With Masquernya and everyone!
And Roy, Dot, and Ult...
I want to keep having adventures...
...as the Rising Voltteccers!
I feel the same way!
I wanna travel to brand-new places
with all of you,
and I wanna sing with Loudbone
all across the world!
Same here!
I wanna learn so much more about Pokémon!
Don’t you, Wanival?
Yeah! There’s loadsa
strong Pokémon out there, after all!
We’re gonna keep aiming
for strongest, Yamirami!
Isn’t that just
the most beautiful sight, Cap?
We’ve been slacking off for a while,
but now, once more...
Please journey with us!
We’d been slacking, too.
We’ve gotta muster up some spirit again!
I’ll go all out,
and get this ship really movin’ again!
All right! Let’s get this ship
prepped to set sail!
Everyone... Thank you!
Hey! First, how about we do...
y’know, that!
The hand sign! Good idea!
Let’s do it!
That reminds me...
Where’s old man Landau?
I haven’t seen him at all lately.
Oh, Gramps said he had
other business to attend to.
Whoa! It’s Mighty G!
Grk... Surpass your potential!
Your heart is always
with your friends! Mighty G!
Rising Voltteccers...
Reboot!
Yeah!
You did a fine job rekindling them.
Huh?
You invited them out for fieldwork
knowing all this’d happen, didn’t you?
Oh did I now...? See ya.
I’ll be back to visit.
The Brave Asagi sets sail!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Hinbass!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Hinbass
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Fish Pokémon
Water
Swift Swim
Thickheaded
It’s a Pokémon
with a strong life force,
but do you know
what kind of habitat it lives in?
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
All of them!
Seas
Lakes
Rivers
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
It’ll live anywhere there’s water...
That’s how tough a Pokémon it is!
That sure was one incredible Hinbass.
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
I wonder what it’s up to now.
Next episode
The Brave Asagi sets sail!
Another adventure
with everyone begins!
We’re finally on the move!
Next episode
What’s all this...?
The Rising Voltteccers’ exploits
have made the news!
Huh? When we’ve only just set off?
What’s going on?
I don’t have a clue either...
Next episode
Let’s go and investigate.
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Fake Rising Voltteccers Appear?!
Fakes, huh?
If yer fixin’ to battle, I’ll take you on!
The Fake Rising Voltteccers Appear?!