Dot in Champuru Town,
and Roy in Fridge Town...
Each of them passed their
Terastal Course implementation tests.
Next, it’s finally my turn!
Which is why we’re headed
to the Mt. Nappé Gym, but...
It’s too cold!
I’m cold, I’m tired, I’m cold, I’m tired...
Even I’m starting to feel the chill...
Liko, are you really sure
there’s a Gym out here?
We should be nearly there, I think...
I can’t!
I can’t walk another step.
I’ll spend the last of my days
lying here in the snow...
The Gurumin Channel
is finished, too...
Thanks for all your support,
everyone...
Ahh... I’m seeing things...
Death has come for me...
Awesome!
Huh...?
What is that?!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
(Take a step out, go!)
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Let’s challenge
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
The Battle of Ice! The Cold-Eyed Grusha
Got it. Thank you for having me!
They said I’d have to wait a while
before they were ready to do my implementation test.
Then let’s go give that a try!
Yahoo!
Arukujira. Land Whale Pokémon.
Ice type.
It left the ocean and began living on land
a very long time ago.
It lives in frigid areas,
in pods of five or so individuals.
Looks like Arukujira-sledding
is booming in this area lately.
People hop on
the backs of trained Arukujira...
...and ride them like sleds
down the slopes!
That sounds super fun!
We’ve got some time to kill.
Let’s give it a try!
Yeah...
But my test will be coming up soon.
Nyarote? And even Terapagos...
They all wanna try it, too!
You never know,
it could be a good warm-up!
You’re right.
Okay, maybe just for a bit.
What do you say, Nyarote?
Yahoo!
We’re gonna crash!
Whoa! That’s my Hogator!
Thanks, Welcamo.
Whoops!
Whoops...
O-Okay!
Hah!
Wow! It’s so pretty!
Ah! Terapagos!
Th-Thank you.
It’ll be safer for you in the bag.
What was that?
Yukihami. Caterpillar Pokémon.
Ice/Bug type.
I wasn’t talking to you!
It eats snow that has accum—
Huh?!
Nyarote, look up ahead!
I can’t stop!
A cliff?!
That was a close one!
Thank you, Nyarote.
Liko!
Are you okay?
Sorry... I almost fell off this cliff.
A cliff?!
I mean, even if you did fall off here...
Huh?
Ah...
Either way, I’m glad you’re okay.
Yeah, thank goodness.
Geez, you’re such a scatterbrain.
Enjoying yourself?
If that’s enough to raise your spirits,
you’re pretty frigid.
Mr. Grusha...
Wait... That’s Liko’s...
Yeah. The Gym Leader
of Mt. Nappé Gym.
If you’re goofing off right before
your implementation test,
you must feel confident.
Huh?
You had better be prepared
to heat me up.
Arukujira. Let’s go.
We’re back!
That was so much fun, mister!
Come back for more anytime!
Mr. Grusha was just as harsh
as the rumors made him out to be...
Yeah...
Huh?
Isn’t that Mr. Grusha?
Yep!
That’s an article from after Grusha
won a pro snowboarding tournament.
So Mr. Grusha’s a snowboarder!
But... he seems so different
compared to now.
Grusha’s our pride here on Mt. Nappé!
He was a talented snowboarder,
winning many tournaments at a young age.
But then one year,
during a tournament...
Grusha’s injuries led him to
retire from snowboarding.
But that wasn’t enough to break him.
The next path he chose was
to become a Pokémon Trainer.
And now, he’s risen all the way up to serving as
Gym Leader at the Mt. Nappé Gym.
He produced impressive results
on an entirely different path.
He’s something else.
No kidding...
Mr. Grusha’s incredible.
Though...
He could have kept snowboarding.
Then why didn’t he?
I figure he couldn’t get the kind of results
he was hoping for anymore.
He puts results above all else.
And he’s harsh on everyone,
himself included.
That’s how he made it
as a Gym Leader.
Harsh...
I’ll do my best!
I’ll get Mr. Grusha to approve of me!
That’s right!
You’ve gotta do all you can!
Show him what you’re made of!
Right!
Nyarote, let’s do our best together!
Your implementation test
is ready to begin.
Liko!
Go for it!
Huh?
U-Um...
So that’s where you were.
I told you not to run ahead.
It’s frigid out here.
Right, let’s get started.
Yes! Please, let’s!
Let’s go, Nyarote!
Let me show you a reality
as icy-cold as snow.
What is that?!
Hulkujira. Land Whale Pokémon.
Ice type.
It protects its body with powerful muscles
and a thick layer of fat under its skin.
How’s she gonna deal with
that difference in bulk?
Plus, Ice-type moves are super effective
against Grass types. In other words...
I need to make sure
its attacks don’t land.
Well then, let the battle begin!
Nyarote! Lightning Speed!
I get it! She’s moving around
so her opponent can’t target her!
That’s our Liko!
No good?!
Hulkujira! Icicle Spears!
Dodge it!
Then... Try Magical Leaf!
Use Ice Spinner!
Are you okay?!
But it was so slow before!
It’s a heck of a lot faster
during that spinning attack!
Nyarote, return!
Tebrim...
Counting on you!
Trying to turn the tide, huh?
Wasted effort.
Icicle Spears!
Tebrim, use Mind Power!
Okay, we can do this!
Tebrim, use a Brutal Swing attack!
A head-on battle, huh?
Aqua Break!
Tebrim, keep it up!
Ice Spinner!
Tebrim!
Thank you, Tebrim.
Nyarote!
Now you have nothing left.
I’ve landed several attacks,
but its defenses are solid...
Ordinary attacks
might not be enough...
Hulkujira! Ice Spinner!
In that case...
Dodge it, Nyarote!
Nearly there!
Just hold on, Nyarote!
It’s time I ended this.
Hulkujira! Icicle Spears!
Now! Fire a Magical Leaf
into that big mouth!
Okay!
Huh...
Nice control!
Excellent!
It might have tough muscle all over its body,
but it can’t buff up the inside of its mouth!
Hulkujira, return.
Guess you’ve got something to offer...
Then, next I’ll use...!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Tyltalis. Humming Pokémon.
Dragon/Flying type.
It sings in a beautiful soprano.
It has a kind disposition, but if it’s provoked,
it will intimidate opponents with shrill cries...
...before attacking them
without mercy.
Not good...
Grass-type attacks barely deal any damage
to Dragon/Flying types.
It’ll be fine.
Liko will think of something.
Tyltalis is a strong foe.
But...
I fought against strong trainers
in order to make it here.
All that’s left is to do my best!
Nyarote, let’s go for it!
Lightning Speed!
It didn’t connect!
Know your place.
Tyltalis, use Moonforce!
Magical Leaf!
How long can you hold out?
Keep using Moonforce!
Nyarote, dodge it!
How can I hit a flying opponent?
That’s it!
Nyarote!
Latch your bud onto Tyltalis!
Caught you!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
Excellent!
Good work, Liko!
Now, Nyarote!
Shine... in full bloom!
Terastal!
Keep it going and bring it home!
Terastallizing now...
Battles are much like snowy mountains.
They can turn on you in an instant.
Mr. Grusha Terastallized too!
Wait, that could actually
be good for Liko...
Huh?
It becoming an Ice Terastype means that
Grass-type attacks should work now.
The type advantage has changed!
Nyarote, let’s go!
Magical Leaf!
Changing the type advantage
won’t change the skill gap.
Ice Beam!
Despair is always close at hand.
Shiver and fall into slumber.
Oh no... Nyarote!
Tough luck, huh?
Yeah...
Nyarote...
I’m sorry.
Don’t worry!
You tried really hard
and gave it all you’ve got.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
You lost the battle,
but you could still pass.
That’s right! He might look at
how well you battled, instead of the results.
That’s what happened with me.
Right.
Liko. Here are the results of
your Terastal Course implementation test.
You failed.
No way... But she tried so hard!
Please let her try again!
How hard she tried doesn’t matter.
And there are no do-overs
in real battles.
No matter what,
the results are all that matter.
He puts results above all else.
And he’s harsh on everyone,
himself included.
That’s simply how battles go.
Passing you, even though you lost?
What a frigid joke.
Thank you very much...
Bye, then.
Liko...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Land Whale Pokémon, Arukujira.
A Pokémon that forms pods
on snowy mountains.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Arukujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Arukujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Height
1.2m
But do you know what Arukujira’s
favorite food is—what it’s constantly eating?
Weight
45.0kg
Arukujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Arukujira
Land Whale Pokémon
Type: Ice
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
Onigiri
Sandwiches
Snow
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
C: Snow
The answer is C: Snow.
Arukujira love the minerals found in snow.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
What is Arukujira's favorite food?
C: Snow
They spend their days
walking and eating snow.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Next episode
Well, the Terastal Course is over.
Hey, let’s stop by somewhere
before we head back!
No way! It’s too cold!
Don’t be like that! Let’s go!
Next episode
Gah! Hey, wait!
They sound happy...
Wait, huh?
I got separated from them?
Next episode
What do I do?
I’ve got a bad feeling...
Stuff like this always leads to
some big event...
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Mt. Nappé and the Creeping Shadows
Don’t miss it!