My name is Liko.
I’m taking a Terastal Course
along with Roy and Dot.
I managed to pass my basics test.
Next is Roy’s turn.
His opponent is Mr. Colza,
the Gym Leader of Bowl Town.
Gimme a bunch of Flamethrowers!
He’s really fired up...
Yeah.
We’ve gotta win and
pass the Terastal Course, Hogator!
And after that...
Next time, we’re gonna beat
that black Rekkuuza!
All right!
Gimme a bunch of
Stomping Tantrums!
One! Two! Three! Four! Five!
He got a bit too excited...
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Shine! The Sparkling of Fire and Art
So this is Bowl Town...
Yeah!
But something’s going on...
A festival, maybe?
Easy! Easy does it!
Ooh, that’s perfect.
Mr. Hassaku!
Hmm?
Ah, it’s you three!
What’s going on?
“Welcome to the Art Festival”?
Indeed.
Every year at around this time,
Bowl Town hosts a delightful festival of the arts.
I’m here to lend any assistance I can
as an art instructor.
Ooh!
The black Rekkuuza!
Whoa...
Isn’t that Mr. Colza’s...?
Correct.
“Kimawari in the Black Dragon’s Gaze.”
It’s the centerpiece
of this year’s art festival.
He is the festival’s
artistic director, after all.
I wanna challenge him right away!
Is he at the Gym?
Challenge him?
Ah, for the Terastal Course.
Well then,
allow me to escort you.
Colz!
Oh, Hass.
Colz? Hass?
How are things coming along?
Ah, yes... I think it’s shaping up
to be something truly avant-garde.
Hmm? Aren’t you kids...?
Hello.
Um... Mr. Colza, Mr. Hassaku...
Are you two friends?
Yes. Well, we’re closely acquainted.
When I was suffering from art block,
Hass provided a sympathetic ear and sound advice.
He’s my mentor in life, really.
It’s thanks to him that my current art style
was able to take shape.
Wow...
Is that you, Liko?
Father?! Huh?
What are you doing here?
Mr. Alex’s picture books
exhibit a strong artistic flair!
I invited him in hopes of
borrowing just a touch of it.
Hi, Mr. Alex!
Hey.
Is the course going well for you?
Yeah! I passed my basics test!
That’s great news!
Oh! These are Dot and Kuwassu.
N-Nice to meet you.
Liko’s told me all about you.
My, what a surprise.
I had no idea
Mr. Alex was Liko’s father.
Mr. Colza!
I came here to battle you!
Hmm. Yes, I was informed of
your participation in the Terastal Course.
And I’m curious to see
how you’ve improved since last time.
Then—!
But unfortunately,
I haven’t the time right now.
I must finish this new piece
before the ceremony tonight.
I’m calling it “Kimawari at Dawn.”
It represents a downcast spirit
getting back up to pursue fresh hope.
As such, coursework will have to wait
until after the ceremony.
Until then, enjoy the breeze of artistry
blowing through town to your heart’s content.
I can’t wait that long!
Hmm?
We wanna get stronger right away
and challenge the black Rekkuuza again! So—
So why not battle me?
Nemo!
I was passing by
and heard your voice.
We didn’t get to fight last time,
but nothing will stop us today!
Yeah, let’s do it! I wanna battle!
All right!
Let’s have us a fruitful battle!
Parmot. Hands-On Pokémon.
Electric/Fighting type.
It is normally slow to react,
but once it enters battle, it will strike down
its enemies with lightning-fast movements.
Electric/Fighting type, huh?
You’re banned from Terastallizing
outside of course battles, right?
Then I won’t Terastallize either.
Feel free to. I don’t mind!
Feeling pretty confident, huh?
Well then... Let the battle begin!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
Dodge it and use Lightning Speed!
Charm Voice!
Parmot! Keep your distance!
You’ve got some new moves!
Your efforts are quick to bear fruit!
Flamethrower!
Nice, Roy!
Rain?
Corner him!
Stomping Tantrum!
Parmot, use Dig!
Keep your eyes peeled, Hogator!
Attack when he pops out!
Now! Flamethrower!
All-Out Lightning Attack!
Hogator! Are you okay?!
Why didn’t Flamethrower work?
The rain?!
Right, yeah...
That was fun!
That was a nice, fruitful battle!
We should—
Let’s battle again!
Huh?
I only lost ‘cause of the rain!
So—
There is no point!
You cannot win as you are now,
no matter how much you try.
Huh?
As long as you fail to understand why that is,
you will never master Terastal.
Our battle is on indefinite hold.
No way...
Roy...
Well, how does this sound?
Why not try your hands at art,
as a change of pace?
Good idea! I’m interested in seeing what
Liko and her friends will come up with, too.
This art festival accepts submissions
from anyone and everyone.
Nemo, you’re submitting
a piece as well, correct?
Yeah!
This year’s theme is
“Working With Pokémon.”
The rule is that you must
make your piece together with Pokémon.
Making art with Pokémon?
Sounds like fun!
Well, it’s something to do
while staying dry.
Never mind all that!
I wanna battle!
It’s important to
switch things up sometimes.
And hey, look at him...
Hogator... Does this interest you?
Got it. If you wanna try it...
Well then, Nemo...
Please show Roy and the others
the way, if you would.
During the art festival,
the Pokémon Gym serves as a public workspace.
You’re free to use
any materials and tools you want.
Wow!
Well, we ought to be getting back.
What should we make?
I wonder if we could paint
something nice, like my father does.
Let’s give it a try!
Art isn’t exactly my strong suit, but...
Kanuchan definitely seems to be a fan.
Lizardon, huh?
That’s it!
Hogator, let’s do it!
Now, what kind of painting
should we make?
Pawprint stamping?
I’ve got it!
Nyarote, try doing that with your bud!
That’s perfect!
Okay, I should do some!
Mibrim, Terapagos...
You want to help, too?
Thank you!
Hold on.
If I can put this and this together...
No, maybe not...
Wait, if Kuwassu helps out...
That might work!
But I want something
a little more high-tech.
Which means...
It’s starting to look like a Lizardon now!
Roy.
Huh? Dot?
I’d like to ask Kaiden for something.
I’ve got a favor to ask.
Could you help me out?
Okay, I’m borrowing Kaiden for a bit.
We’ve gotta give this
all we got too, Hogator!
Hmm...
Something just feels off...
It just doesn’t stand out.
What’s it missing?
It’s falling apart!
Whoa! The wing!
Aww, man... Why?!
Art lives or dies by the artist’s hand.
Mr. Colza!
This clay is not the only material
at your disposal.
Anything in sight,
as well as anything in reach...
...could be the clue you need
when creating your art.
Anything can be a clue?
I am so lost!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
“This clay is not
your only material,” huh?
But what else is there?
Are you okay, Hogator?!
Aww, you burned it...
Don’t sweat it!
We can start over...
Huh? Wait, it actually looks
pretty good burnt like that!
Plus, it shouldn’t fall apart now!
Oh, yeah! If we’re making art
together with Pokémon,
maybe we can use
Pokémon moves as materials, too!
That should do it!
Hogator, burn it with Flamethrower!
Looking good!
Okay, finished!
We did it!
You really can find clues
in all kinds of places!
I get it!
The same thing goes for battling!
I made a carving of Parmot
in the heat of battle!
Cool!
Hey, lemme see yours!
It’s super colorful!
I painted it with Nyarote
and my other Pokémon.
It’s titled “Oliva in Full Bloom.”
Ooh, it turned out excellent!
Such bold color choices...
Truly avant-garde!
We did it!
It’s a hammer ferris wheel.
Ferris wheel?
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
Kaiden, use Spark!
It lights up!
That’s marvelous!
Me and Hogator made this!
It really stands out!
What is the title of this piece?!
“I Wanna Get Stronger!”
It’s inspired by Hogator’s wish to be
like Lizardon, and by my feelings, too!
Okay, Hogator!
Finish it up with a Flamethrower!
Absolutely magnificent!
It just oozes strength!
Yes! We totally nailed it!
You’ve come to understand, I hope?
Art is not the only field where
clues may be found anywhere you look.
The same is true of battling.
Terastal is battling’s answer
to mixed-media artwork.
Pokémon and trainer!
Sky and land! Logic and emotion!
When they all intertwine...
That is when you create art that shines the brightest!
Right!
I’ll be waiting at the battle court.
Hah!
Are you ready to fling open
the doors to the world of art?
Let’s go! Usokki!
So, he’s going with Usokki...
My Usokki is normally Rock-type,
but becomes a Grass type
after Terastallizing.
Do you understand
what that means?
Yes!
As long as he’s Rock type,
he has Hogator at a disadvantage.
The key to this battle
will be finding a way to turn that around.
The Terastal Course
basics test begins now.
Let the battle begin!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
Still going with that, eh?
Usokki! Substitute!
The left one!
Stone Edge!
Hogator, you okay?!
Okay! Charm Voice!
I’ve seen that move before, too.
Stone Edge!
Darn it!
He stopped Stomping Tantrum
and Charm Voice...
Guess he’s ready to counter anything
he’s seen once before.
That’s a Gym Leader for you.
What’s wrong? Already stuck?
I’m just getting started!
Gimme a bunch of Flamethrowers!
Pointless. Substitute!
No good!
He can’t land a single hit!
He needs to change his approach...
Keep it up! Flamethrower!
It seems this is all you’re capable of.
It’s getting really hot...
I have to find...
a clue to victory!
I’ve got it!
Hogator! Stomping Tantrum
on the left Usokki!
We can do this!
Stomping Tantrum on the left one!
Now the right!
Left!
Right!
Stone Edge!
Stomping Tantrum!
Usokki seems fed up
with Stomping Tantrum!
Meaning it’s just about time for...
I’ll now fulfill your expectations!
The Lie That Came True: Part Two!
Let’s go, Usokki!
He Terastallized!
Now, Hogator!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Hogator! You’re so cool!
Let’s speed things up
and finish this in one blow!
Trailblaze!
We can speed up, too!
Nitro Charge!
What?!
Hogator, use Flamethrower!
Victory is yours.
All right!
You were awesome out there,
Hogator!
Return!
You fought well, Usokki.
How did you discern the real one?
I could see it sweating.
It was thanks to you teaching me
that clues can come from anywhere, Mr. Colza.
You saw everything, felt everything,
and then... you created.
Any artist capable of that
is worthy of Terastal.
Allow me to pass you
on your basics test.
Thank you, sir!
Look! We passed, Hogator!
Roy!
Congrats!
Thanks!
I’m up next.
I’ll pass, won’t I...?
Yeah, I will... I’ve got to.
That battle made me hungry...
There’s plenty of carts over there.
Let’s go, everyone!
The art festival has only just begun.
Enjoy yourselves, adolescents!
Yeah!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Hands-On Pokémon, Parmot.
Parmot
Hands-On Pokémon
Type: Electric/Fighting
Parmot
Hands-On Pokémon
Type: Electric/Fighting
Its small body can store as much electricity
as an electric car.
Height
0.9m
Weight
41.0kg
But do you know where it stores
all that electricity?
Where does it store its electricity?
Its paws
Its cheeks
Its fur
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Where does it store its electricity?
C: Its fur
The answer is C: Its fur!
Its fluffy fur is perfect
for storing up electricity.
It uses it to store the electricity
its paws and cheeks generate.
Next episode
I passed my basics test!
Congrats, Roy!
Which means, next up is finally...!
Yeah, next up is...!
I know!
You don’t have to remind me!
You’ll handle it no problem, Dot!
Yeah! You know more
about Pokémon than any of us!
And you get along perfectly with Kuwassu!
Stop it!
You’re raising weird event flags!
Sorry.
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Dot and Gurumin
I’ve gotta pass this...!