Yo-ssu!
Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
It’s everyone’s pal, Gurumin!
Let’s liven up this livestream!
Today, I’m after all your sightings of Pokémon doing
bizarre stuff and using moves the Index doesn’t account for,
rare Pokémon,
and Legendary Pokémon.
I’m lookin’ for
all the thrilling info ya got!
All of ‘em pique my curiosity!
Let’s get those comments rollin’!
H-Huh...?
I-I’ll take anything you have,
no matter how small!
I’m waiting for your info!
Ooh! Thank you for the comment...
What?! A black Rekkuuza?!
In order to get back what was stolen—
the truth of the Rising Voltteccers—our journey continues.
Chaba Town...
It’s such a pretty place.
Yeah. The tea leaves smell great!
Maybe we’ll get to have
some matcha sweets!
Let’s have a look later, shall we?
Looks like the meet-up spot
is up there.
I’m getting kinda nervous...
Me, too.
When I think about
maybe getting to see Rekkuuza again...
Ah... There’s that too, but...
The person who submitted this info
is a Gurumin fan, right?
Nyabbyfan.
Apparently,
she’s a long-time supporter.
What do I do...?
Will I be able to keep up with her?
I haven’t been watching her vids much this past year...
Or her livestreams, either...
Don’t worry about that!
Trust me, Liko. There’s no contest!
You think so...?
I sure do!
After all, you’re NyahojaSuper—
You’re the ones, ain’tcha?!
Yo-ssu!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Diehard Follower?! A Gurumin Fan Showdown!!
Nice to meet you!
It’s NyabbySuperfan!
Or just “Nyabbyfan” for short!
Nyabbyfan...?
Is that Pikachu yours?
It’s super cute!
Real fave material!
Even those sneezes are cute!
Yeah...
Whoa! Gurumin merch!
Where did you get all this?
Oh, this?
All handmade.
You made these?!
You recreated even the tiny details!
The stitching looks so real!
Whoa! You noticed?!
Yep!
I’m a Gurumin fan, too!
A fan?
Umm...
My name’s Liko.
And I’m Roy.
Let’s get along good, all righty?!
It’s an honor to meet
the Gurumin Channel staff!
Oh, “staff” isn’t quite—
I knew it the moment I saw you!
We don’t get many tourists
‘round here, after all.
Nyabbyfan.
You saw the black Rekkuuza, didn’t you?
You said it was flying through the sky.
Please tell us more!
Wait!
Before all that,
what about Gurumin?
Where’s Gurumin?!
We came on her behalf.
Wha—?!
And here I thought
I was gonna get to meet Gurumin...
We’re sorry we disappointed you...
And who even are you anyway?
You’re from her staff,
but you call yourself a “Gurumin fan”...
Oh, I’m NyahojaSuperfan.
Huh?! You’re the legendary
NyahojaSuperfan?!
“Legendary” is a bit much...
Not telling ya.
Huh?
If Gurumin’s not coming,
I’m not telling ya about the black Rekkuuza!
H-Hey! Please, wait!
I’ll step in.
Yo-ssu! NyabbySuperfan!
Thanks so much for providing me
with such choice info!
Gurumin, Gurumin, Gurumin...
Gurumin, Gurumin, Gurumin, Gurumin...
Good thing we had her on standby...
What do I do?! Gurumin is talking to me...
So divine, so divine...!
That’s pretty intense...
I know how she feels.
Hmm?
Since I like Gurumin, too.
Even now that I’m friends with Dot,
Gurumin still makes me nervous
in her own way.
That so...?
Yeah, I getcha.
And so! Once again, NyabbySuperfan...
Guide these two to the place
where you spotted the black Rekkuuza!
That’s...!
...s-some... some...
Huh?
...something I’d gladly do
for Gurumin!
Dodorio, huh?
This feels pretty nice.
And what’s that...?
An Onidrill!
Clear skies like this
make you wanna sing, eh Achigator?
How’d you end up knowing Gurumin?
Um, it was a coincidence. Or, well...
How come she gives you
special treatment?!
Huh? Special treatment?
How can I get acquainted
with Gurumin, too?
Acquainted...?
Masquernya, what’s wrong?
Oh, say... You haven’t been commenting
on Gurumin’s vids at all lately, have ya?
Ah... There was a little while
when I wasn’t keeping up with her channel.
Well, during that time...
...she’s read out a bunch of my comments
on her livestreams, y’know!
It’s so nice when your comments
get picked, isn’t it?
What do I do?!
This is getting kinda awkward!
Hey, you think we’re almost there?
Wha—?!
U-Uh... Right...
Now just where was it...?
There aren’t exactly any landmarks
out here, so it’s hard to say...
I hope it’s still nearby.
Nyabbyfan, what were you doing
when you saw the black Rekkuuza?
What was I doing?
Uh, nothing particularly special...
And besides, why do ya wanna
find the black Rekkuuza so badly?
I wanna catch it.
Catch it?!
The black Rekkuuza is my dream.
I’ve been pursuing it ever since
I joined the Rising Voltteccers...
...and I even earned its approval at one point,
but then we got separated...
So I wanna find it again—
The Rising Voltteccers?
You’re with them?
I’ve got nothing to say to bad guys!
It’s not like that!
We haven’t done—
Oh, come on.
Exceed told everyone
all about you, y’know!
You’re to blame for ruining
Mt. Kumuri’s natural environment,
and for the bizarre effects
popping up in Pokémon worldwide!
I’m trying to tell you, that wasn’t—
If she associates with people like you...
Gurumin’s gonna get hate-mobbed!
So our image really is bad right now...
My mind’s made up!
I’m taking you down right here and now,
for Gurumin’s sake!
Huh?!
If you lose, you’ve gotta
stay away from Gurumin forever!
That’s crazy!
Understood. I accept!
Liko...
I know how Nyabbyfan feels,
which is why I’ve got to meet her feelings head-on!
Masquernya!
Now we’re talkin’!
You’re up, Gaogaen!
Gaogaen?!
You’re not using a Nyabby?!
I do know how to train ‘em, y’know!
They might both be cat Pokémon,
but how long can yours last against a Fire type?
Don’t worry, Masquernya.
You can do this!
I’ll make the first move!
Masquernya! Trick Flower!
Gaogaen! DD Lariat!
Dodge it!
You think you can escape?!
Double Kick!
What’s the matter? Not made of very tough stuff, are ya?
Is running all you can do?
That’s some unreal power...
Masquernya! Acrobatics!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
It took the attack!
Didn’t even leave a mark!
In that case...
Masquernya, go for Gaogaen’s legs!
Keep up that spirit! DD Lariat!
Flamethrower!
Look out!
Masquernya!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Masquernya, are you okay?
So? How do ya like
my blazing-hot Gaogaen?!
It’s so powerful...
Wipe that sad look off your face!
You’ve gotta get more fired up!
I can’t fall for her taunts!
I need to stay cool and find a solution here!
That Gaogaen’s got high attack power,
but uses really simple movements and patterns.
Masquernya can anticipate
what it’ll do, and dodge.
Even if it’s a bad type match-up,
this isn’t an unwinnable fight for Masquernya!
Yeah. Next time, we’ll get it!
Gaogaen! DD Lariat!
Acrobatics!
Now you’ve done it!
Double Kick!
Magical Leaf!
Rush in! Kick it away!
She’s gone?!
Trick Flower!
Crush ‘em all with a DD Lariat!
I told ya, we don’t even
feel your attacks!
Finish up with Flamethrower!
If that lands...
There’s no way...
Is she planning something...?
Wait, Gaogaen!
That went wonderfully,
Masquernya!
The attack from above
was a fakeout...
But... she never signaled
for her to trap the belt...
Guess that shows
just how strong their bond is...
We’re not down yet! Gaogaen!
Masquernya!
What’s that?
Not good, not good,
not good, not good!
Ult?!
What are you doing here?
I was gonna get ahead of you...
...and catch
the black Rekkuuza first...
Were you following us again?
Never mind that!
This is mega-not good!
Dodorio?!
I... guess I just
made ‘em mad somehow.
Over that way
is Dodorio territory.
Meaning that...
I didn’t know!
Oh, and...
Onidrill...
I guess I just
made ‘em mad somehow!
Over that way
is an Onidrill nest.
Meaning that...
I only got lost ‘cause
you left me behind in the first place!
Now’s not the time to argue!
Gaogaen! Let’s beat ‘em all up!
Guess I got no choice.
I’ll knock you all flat!
Wait! They haven’t done
anything wrong!
Huh?
What’s with you?
If we can calm them down,
I bet they’ll leave on their own.
What are you talking about?
Yeah! Let’s do it, Liko!
Okay!
Taikaiden!
Lucario!
Tebrim!
Yeah!
Pagogo! Protect!
Lucario, use Luster Cannon
on the ground!
Cap! Shadow Clones!
Masquernya,
play with them with Trick Flower!
You won’t beat us in a shouting match!
Taikaiden, use Uproar!
Let’s sing, Achigator!
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
At the end of this wide round sea,
what kinda places could there be? Hey!
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
At the end of this wide round sea,
what kinda places could there be?
What a relief.
Seemed like
they were all having fun.
Oh!
We never finished our battle...
Forget it.
I see what kinda people you are now.
If that’s your mindset with Pokémon,
there’s no way you’re bad guys!
Then, you mean...
I’ll trust what I just saw.
I was wrong about
the Rising Voltteccers.
Thank you!
I’m so glad to hear that!
Never mind that!
Where’s the black Rekkuuza already?!
Ah... Right, well, about that...
You lied?!
Wh-What a shock...
She was doing one of her rare livestreams,
but she wasn’t getting any comments...
So I wrote “I saw a black Rekkuuza!”...
...just kind of on impulse.
Is that so...?
Plus, I bought it too easily...
So it was a mega-fool’s errand?!
Let’s go, Yamirami!
Watch out for wild Pokémon
along the way!
Geez, that guy...
I’m sorry for lying to you!
Whoa!
I was hoping that if I had some serious info,
I might get to meet Gurumin...
And I wanted Gurumin to take an interest in me,
like she did with NyahojaSuperfan...
I was jealous...
Even the name “NyabbySuperfan” was me
copying NyahojaSuperfan without permission...
Nyabbyfan...
Ahem!
Can I say something?
Sure, I’m IRL friends with Liko,
but I don’t intend to give her any
special treatment as Gurumin.
I treasure each and every fan
who supports me!
And that includes you
without a doubt, NyabbySuperfan!
Gurumin...
Thank you for always commenting!
She really is... just so divine!
I hope Gurumin can count on your support
for a long time to come!
Absolutely!
I’m your diehard follower for life!
Liko... I messed up.
I won’t do anything like this again.
I’ll change my account name, too.
You don’t have to change it!
But...
I can tell you’re
a real NyabbySuperfan...
...just by looking at your Nyabby.
It was clear to see
in my battle against Gaogaen, too.
Let’s stay friends...
as fellow Gurumin fans!
Glad to see you made
a Gurumin friend, Liko.
Yeah!
We’re friends for sure too, Roy!
I’m gonna support the Rising Voltteccers
just about as much as I support Gurumin!
I’ll tell everyone they’re awesome people
who care about Pokémon!
Thank you!
We didn’t end up seeing
the black Rekkuuza,
but I’m glad we came.
Yeah.
We were able to show her
who the Rising Voltteccers really are.
Roy and I haven’t taken the wrong path!
Progress might be slow,
but I hope that someday, once again...
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Darkness Pokémon, Yamirami!
Darkness Pokémon
Ghost
Yamirami
Darkness Pokémon
Evil
Ghost
Keen Eye
Yamirami
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Darkness Pokémon
Keen Eye
Stall
Yamirami
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is coming
after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
The gem it holds is the gem
from Yamirami’s chest, now grown huge...
Mega Yamirami
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Darkness Pokémon
Evil
Ghost
Magic Mirror
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
...and able to reflect
any kind of attack!
As the gem takes attacks,
it grows smaller and smaller...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
And then...
It turns back to normal
just like that!
Next episode
You really gave it your all,
Masquernya.
Let’s have the Pokémon Center
heal you back up.
Pokémon Centers are amazing,
aren’t they?
They’re always healing up
our injured Pokémon.
Yeah. It’s thanks to them
that we can battle to our hearts’ content!
Oh, I’m sorry, Masquernya!
Let’s hurry and go.
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Pokémon Center Lady
Huh? Wait, is she...?