pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Cap was flying?
I’m positive!
Yeah, so am I.
There’s no way he can fly.
He’s a Pikachu.
I know, but...
Yesterday, when Roy battled him...
Really?
I don’t remember that...
No doubt about it!
Cap’s a special Flying Pikachu!
And... you want to investigate?
That’s right.
When exactly did Cap become Cap?
That’s how things have been
since before I came on board...
Right... I’m just so used to it,
I never stopped to think about it...
Doesn’t it make you wonder?!
I am intrigued.
I know!
Let’s try asking Friede.
Good idea!
Dot! You’ll come too, right?
I’ll pass.
Sounds like a pain.
Huh?
Instead...
I’ll play a supporting role!
Flying Pikachu, to the Skies!
Y-Yo-ssu!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
It’s a vid from the LikoRoy Channel!
So, what’ve we got planned for today?
Right! Erm...
“Chasing the mystery
of the Flying Pikachu!”
What’s this?
Are you Gurumin’s apprentices now?
I thought it might
make for an interesting video.
If it becomes a viral hit,
the views will rise like a Shibirudon going upriver!
Some day soon, I’ll be even more
popular than Nanjamo!
If that’s what you’re after,
why aren’t you in it?
Hey, Friede!
Tell us Cap’s secrets!
His secrets?
After seeing yesterday’s battle,
we’ve been wondering... Can Cap fly?
Yeah, you’re on the right track.
Maybe he can.
Where did you meet him?
Why is he “Cap”?
Huh? Huh?
Does it really matter?
Cap’s Cap.
Our reliable captain.
Don’t you feel like
he brushed us off?
That makes me even more curious.
Times like this,
you have to keep hunting for clues.
How about asking
the rest of the crew?
Cap? He’s pretty tough.
I’ve rarely ever had to treat him.
Flying?
He’s so nimble, it might look
like he’s flying at times, but...
He’s a good guy.
He’s not picky.
He’ll happily eat anything.
His power and speed are proof
he’s getting enough nutrition.
Cap... The bond with him
was that of a new beginning.
The bond of a new beginning...
So he was the first member?
Yes. If he hadn’t met Cap,
Friede would not have formed
the Rising Voltteccers.
That reminds me...
The Brave Asagi was originally
your own fishing boat, right, Gramps?
And Orio converted it or something?
Orio and I may have played a part,
but Cap is the one
who lit Friede’s heart.
Cap and Friede...
Their encounter opened up
a brand new world.
I see.
Here, enjoy.
Thank you.
Friede wouldn’t tell us anything.
He’s shy when it comes to
talking about his past.
And he doesn’t like
being caught on camera.
Is that so?
We were childhood friends.
We used to live in Kanto...
...but I moved to Hoenn.
We didn’t meet again until this ship—
Huh?
That story...
We wanna hear it all!
I could tell you myself, but...
I know!
Ting-tong-tang-tong!
Starting now, in the meeting room...
...I’ll be telling the full story of
Cap and Friede’s fateful encounter!
All hands,
gather in the meeting room!
See? Here he comes.
Orio!
What’s this all of a sudden?!
These guys were asking about you two.
You should open up.
You’re still going around
asking about that?
Well, how should I put it?
Isn’t it only natural to
want to know more about your pals?
The walls have Dred-ears
and the doors have Regi-eyes!
I’m curious about what kicked off
their amouRunpappa.
You guys...
I get it. This is as good a time as any.
Let me tell you how Cap and I met...
And how that led to the grandiose
beginning of the Rising Voltteccers.
It was after I quit my job as a company researcher
and was enjoying my free time...
Nice weather, eh?
Yeah.
No bites, eh?
Yeah...
Shall we take the boat out?
We could find a big catch.
A big catch, huh...?
How many more days
do you intend to pass this way?
Huh?
Youth should not be spent
waiting for prey to bite...
...when you can set out
and claim it for yourself.
You say that, but...
Not like I have anything else to do.
It’s a big one, Friede!
Hyah!
I’ve got nothing...
You’ve got it good
with your boat, Gramps.
You can go anywhere.
You have wings of your own.
Even this guy’s been in a mood lately.
What should we do?
Welcome!
Over here, over here!
For the first time in years,
I got a call...
...from my old schoolteacher,
Ms. Lucca.
You’ve really grown.
I never thought
I’d see you in Paldea.
I got married
and moved here from Kanto.
What about school?
I’m planning to go back
when my daughter’s old enough.
You’re a parent, huh?
That’s amazing!
I can’t even imagine it.
Why did you quit your job?
You said you’d get to do
lots of research as a Pokémon Professor.
You were so happy.
Being cooped up in a lab
just didn’t suit me.
How about researching for fun?
I’ve done enough of that.
I’m a genius Pokémon Professor, you know.
There’s nothing I don’t know about Pokémon.
So you’re at a loss.
Not really.
I’ve finally found my freedom.
I’m going to take it easy for a while.
All right.
Do you have time tomorrow morning?
Huh?
Friede, I know someone
you should meet right away.
So tired...
Who am I supposed to meet this early?
Morning! You’re right on time.
But... you’re the only one here?
Look.
Over there.
What am I looking at...?
He’s famous around here lately.
You wanted me to meet... a Pikachu?
Yep.
Sorry, Miss... But I already know
all there is to know about Pikachu.
How they live, how they act,
even their moves... There’s nothi—
Hush.
Huh?
I think it’s time.
What?
No way!
Surprised? He’s a Flying Pikachu.
Flyi— What?!
A Pikachu, flying?
Now he’s got my attention!
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Hey! You can fly...
You’re incredible!
I’m Friede. I may not look it,
but I’m a genius Pokémon Professor.
I wanna know more about you.
Let me research you.
H-Harsh...
Oh, dear!
Oh, this is nothing to worry ab—
You’re hurt!
Are you okay?
You meant him?!
Those wounds, are they...?
I’m not giving up.
My research begins!
Hey!
You’re not getting away!
He sure can run...
These are a token of our friendship.
Feel free to have whatever you like.
Doing squats with your tail?!
You’re amazing...
There must be some secret
to that tail, too...
Here.
Pikachu... Rigorous training
is all well and good,
but nutrition is important, too.
Not picky, huh?
Pikachu!
Nice weather again today, huh?
I’m used to that by now!
That won’t beat me!
Let me research you!
Huh?
Gah! No! Ow, ow ow...
Electric shocks are one thing
I can’t counter...
Yes?
Morning, Friede.
Looks like your research
is going well.
How can you say that?
Just look at this...
I am looking.
That’s how I know.
Have you learned anything
by observing him?
Yeah. He has a light body,
and quite a kick to those legs.
That explains why he’s so fast.
Leveraging those traits
with Voltteccer...
...is the secret to his flight.
Voltteccer?
A move where he covers himself
in electricity and dashes forward.
He runs in a circle,
generating an energy vortex.
He uses his well-trained tail
as a spring to leap upward,
ascending rapidly within the vortex!
That’s how he floats up into the sky.
I see.
By flapping his tail in the air,
it seems he can even hover
for a short time.
Sharp as ever, Professor Friede.
Putting all that together...
You’re incredible!
He’s the incredible one.
He must’ve failed over and over...
but always tried again; never gave up.
Compared to him...
What kind of “genius” professor am I?
I didn’t understand
the first thing about Pokémon.
I’m glad...
Glad that you two met.
That’s why you wanted me to...?
Mom!
Oh, Liko. You’re awake?
Who’s that?
A boy with a promising future,
I suppose.
Well, then...
Do your best!
Yeah. Thanks, Miss.
I continued to observe him.
There was one more thing
I had to figure out, no matter what.
Why does he push himself so far?
It’s not some battle
among wild Pokémon.
He flies once a day, always at dawn.
He even takes damage
from Voltteccer’s recoil...
Why does he want to fly so badly?
I wanted to know more.
As a Pokémon Professor.
And as an ordinary Pokémon Trainer.
I give up.
Observations, data analyses...
They’ll never teach me how he feels.
I’ve gotta get moving!
Go after him!
Lizardon, time to fly!
Been a while,
but it’s time for us to go all out!
Higher! Higher!
We’ll climb, too! Lizardon!
Whoa! We’re up higher than the sun!
So he wanted to see this sight...
This really is the best!
Hey, I gotta ask...
What about your tail?
This is bad, Lizardon!
That was a close call.
Pikachu...
You showed us a sight
we’d never seen before.
A Flying Pikachu, huh?
This world is so vast.
There’s so much
I have yet to learn.
Would you come with me?
Let’s rise higher than the sun...
...and go see the world!
Pikachu and I became partners.
And I set off toward a new future.
Gramps, I have a favor to ask.
Will you entrust the Asagi to me?
So, you were graced
with a special encounter, eh?
Why’d you need me
on such short notice?
I’m on the clock, you know.
Orio. I’m here to ask you
to lend me your expertise.
Convert the Asagi into
the best airship in the world!
Mmm—
Eh?!
Are you an idiot?
Can you do it?
I’ll just have to try!
Wh... Wh...
Whoa!
That’s one brave-looking ship.
Now, it’s become...
...the Brave Asagi!
Your taste in names hasn’t changed.
What do you think, Pikachu?
We can go anywhere with this!
I knew it, Orio!
You’re the greatest mechanic!
Thank you...
Wait, huh?
Payment...
I’ll repay you bit by bit...
...not needed!
Instead...
Let me ride with you!
Orio...
The ship will need maintenance, right?
I was just getting bored with my job.
A ship mechanic, huh?
Great idea! It’s all coming together!
And you’ll be captain, yeah?
Nope.
Pikachu...
Be the Brave Asagi’s captain!
Captain Pikachu!
Just like you rising
with your Voltteccer,
let’s fly up into infinity!
We’re the Rising Voltteccers!
Now, Cap!
Let’s set sail!
While traveling the world
aboard this ship...
...we chase after the riddles
of those ever strange, strange Pokémon.
And that’s how Cap and I
ended up taking to the skies!
M-My...
Liko, are you so amazed you—?
My mother was your teacher?!
That’s what shocked you?!
There’s so much you never told us.
Got that right.
Liko...
If not for Ms. Lucca,
Something you can’t quite put into words...
I’d have never met Cap.
Something that makes your heart beat a bit faster...
I owe your mother so much.
Something that seems to brighten up your day...
“I found some flowers I like!”
With white mist clinging onto every day
I can’t even look for what I wanna find, ooh
Liko!
My diary makes it all look so exciting
I finished editing the video, but...
What should we do with it?
“I threw it out, pretending it wasn’t mine” ...strike that
Right...
You lia-ia-ia-iar...
I don’t think
we should release it.
I agree!
My inconsolable heart
Cap and Friede’s bond
totally drew me in!
Whoa-oh whoa-oh-o-oh
Rewrite “But”/“Yet” into “I bet”/“It could be true”
I’ll have to get
even closer with Hogator!
If only I could walk on air, on a fair breeze
Greatly, smoothly, slightly, nearly, someday...
Now I know why I’m here.
I wanna fly!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents!
My mother brought
Cap and Friede together...
I bet! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
...which brought
the Rising Voltteccers and me together...
Don’t let untold tales scare you
...which led to me meeting all of you,
and to us becoming friends!
Dazzling daydreams make the world dance!
Yeah. It’s all connected!
So smile! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
No time to waste hiding away
Next time I see my mother,
I’m going to tell her
all about Nyahoja!
I wanna learn about myself!
I still don’t know anything about any-any-anything
Look, Liko!
I wanna discover myself!
The day I manage to say “I’m heading out on my own”
That’s...
Maybe I’ll grow up a little bit
The Galar Region.
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Yo! We are the Rising Voltteccers
What Pokémon will we meet next?
I can't wait for more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Then why don't we learn about more Pokémon?
First, Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Now, can you say it with Liko?
Are you ready?
Hmm... Can I really do it? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next, Pokémon that have regional forms!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! Leave it to me!!
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode! Woo!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
Engine City’s super popular sweet,
Pero-Fluffy Cotton Candy!
When Liko and friends go get some, they end up
reuniting Murdock and his pâtissier pal Mitchell!
It seems like Mitchell and Mawhip
have some history...
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
The Truth About Mawhip
Turns out the past of a sweets pâtissier
ain’t always sweet, huh?
The Truth About Mawhip