Fridge Town’s Gym Leader, Ms. Rhyme,
turned out to be a super famous rapper.
Roy and Hogator took part in her concert,
taking his implementation test on-stage, but...
To be blunt,
you’re a failure of a partner.
You’ve failed your implementation test.
Come back once you’ve
washed your soul!
That was incredible!
Nobody beats Ms. Rhyme!
Maybe I really am a failure
as Hogator’s partner...
Are you going to stop now?
Did you and Hogator
come this far for nothing?
Good point! You’re right, Liko.
Feeling down about it
won’t fix a thing.
Roy...
The real problem is her declaring
that you failed your test.
That means you’re through with your Terastal Course.
Huh?
I’m not so sure about that.
Didn’t she say, “come back
once you’ve washed your soul”?
Sounds like she’s giving you
another chance, no?
Yeah, you’re right...
Mm-hmm.
Okay, Hogator!
Let’s go challenge her again!
Hold on!
Re-challenging her is fine and all,
but how are you gonna win?
U-Uh, well...
She has another concert tonight,
so how about you take part
in that and battle her?
‘Til then, look for
some kind of clue to winning!
A clue to winning...
Hey, Roy...
Wanna try some Awesome Training?
Awesome Training?
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Me and Hogator's Song
What do you do in “Awesome Training”?
For now, we’re just
gonna have to do whatever.
It’s hardly exciting, but if you pump your stamina
and up your power and speed,
you’ll get stronger for sure.
Okay... Got it!
Give it all you’ve got, you guys!
Huh?
“You guys”?
First, a marathon through the snow!
One, two! One, two!
Why do I have to be here?
Running in the snow is tough!
Should be a nice workout!
Let’s do this, Hogator!
One, two! One, two!
I give up...
I can’t run anymore...
Roy and Nemo are so fast!
Wait... Where is Nemo?
It burns...
She has that little stamina?
The goal is that tree over there!
The wind!
We can’t give up, Hogator!
It’s getting heavier...
Let’s keep at it, Nyarote!
Nyarote?
Dot’s gone, too?
It’s way too cold out there...
Well then, let’s get to it!
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Here we go.
Let’s dash, Hogator!
Pamot, use Discharge!
Dodge it!
Welcamo, use Water Gun!
Roll!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Discharge!
Magical Leaf!
Water Gun!
Now! Flamethrower!
Ooh!
Amazing!
I’m beat...
Excellent work, Roy and Hogator.
Think it helped
boost our power and speed?
It must have!
But even with that...
It’s still Ms. Rhyme you’re up against...
True. This might not be enough
to take her down.
Yeah.
I was thinking about something
while watching your battle earlier.
What was it?
Your singing-and-attacking routine
felt kinda repetitive.
But we’ve already won
a bunch of battles doing that.
You always attack the same way,
so Ms. Rhyme knew what you were gonna do next.
If you can mix up
your movements a bit more,
I think you’ll have a shot at winning.
I wonder why Ms. Rhyme
asked you that question...
About what brings you to sing...
You said it was
to help you get stronger, right?
Yeah.
And her words at the end...
A trainer who forgets their song
is a partner who has their rhythm wrong.
Now that you mention it...
Hey, Roy... What made you
like singing in the first place?
Huh?
Um...
‘Cause my mom and dad
used to sing all the time, I guess.
Your mom and dad?
Didn’t you live with
just your grandfather?
Yeah. Mom and Dad are sailors.
See?
When I was young,
they worked on the seas just off the island.
They used to let me ride on their boat
and go out to sea.
It’s so fast!
Don’t get riled up and fall overboard!
Roy! No running on deck!
The island keeps getting smaller!
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
At the end of this wide round sea,
what kinda places could there be?
Good work today.
Okay, let’s head home.
I’m hungry!
I hear ya.
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
But then they ended up
having to leave on a long voyage.
We won’t be around for a while,
but make sure you do
what your grandpa says.
And don’t eat too much
and upset your stomach.
Sure...
You gonna be lonely, Roy?
I won’t be lonely.
Someday I’m gonna become a trainer
and go on an adventure, too!
You’ll do just fine.
I know you’ll be a great trainer.
About time you set sail.
Take care of Roy, Dad.
I will. You can count on me.
We’ll get along plenty well.
Eh, Roy?
Yeah!
Come back safe!
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
At the—
When we set sail on the great big sea,
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
Singing helped me
make friends with all kinds of Pokémon.
Looks like he’s having fun.
You befriended Hogator
right away by singing, too.
Yeah.
Right... I get it now!
Huh? Get what?
Hogator, time for
some more Awesome Training!
What, now?
You know you’ll miss tonight’s concert
if you don’t head back soon, right?
But there’s something
I need to do before the battle!
You found your clue, then.
Got it. I’ll help!
Thanks!
That’s all there is to it, huh?
Me and Liko will go back first, then.
Huh?
We need to stall for time
until Roy arrives.
Oh, I see... Guess you’re right.
Roy, Hogator... Go for it!
We’ve got this!
Are my vibes reaching you?
This night’s barely getting started!
The concert’s been going on
for quite a while.
And still no sign of Roy?
Okay! Tonight’s concert
is off the chain, too!
Then let’s flip to our signature
open participation section!
So, who thinks they’re ready
to bring some heat to this stage?
It’s starting!
Wh-What do we do?
Hmm? No takers?
Hey, man! Don’t be a stranger!
Not one brave challenger
with us tonight?
Then how ‘bout we roll right along
to the second half of the concert?
We’ll just have to make time!
R-Right.
Liko, go for it!
Huh? You’re not going to do it, Dot?
I’m no good at that stuff.
I’m no good at it, either!
Whoa!
A brave volunteer takes the stage!
Huh?
Welcamo?!
All by yourself?
Ain’t you got a trainer?
Oh, uh, err, well...
Argh! Now we’ve really
got no choice!
H-Here!
We volunteer!
Huh?!
I getcha!
So Nyarote has to shoot down all the berries
before Welcamo finishes his dance number.
Sounds like a wicked performance!
She should be able to
handle that, right?
It’ll work out... I think.
We’ve never done this before.
You serious?
Show us something that’ll knock us flat!
Come on, music!
I believe in you, Nyarote!
Nailed it!
Thank goodness.
Now we’re warmed up
and open participation time is over.
Get pumped for the second half!
Uh— Wait!
Hold it!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
I challenge Ms. Rhyme
to a Pokémon battle!
Roy!
Gah, took you long enough...
Pretty sure I already flunked you.
I washed my soul,
and now I’ve come back!
I wanna do another
implementation test, please!
Sounds like you mean it.
All right. Get yourself on stage!
Okay!
Sorry I’m late!
Do your best!
It’s all up to you now.
Thanks.
We will do our best!
This is a special test, just for you.
But special chances like this
don’t come back around.
The rules: Beat my Strinder in a 1v1 battle
with your Hogator. You in?
Yeah!
Phew! Looks like I made it in time.
Nemo!
How’d the training go? Is he all set?
Well... I’m not actually sure.
He wasn’t really training
for battle at all.
Huh?
Let the battle begin!
Let’s get this over with quick.
Strinder, use Overdrive!
Dodge it, Hogator!
Keep up the heat! Overdrive!
Flamethrower!
Blast Waves!
That was close!
But the training today
boosted Hogator’s speed!
S’pose you didn’t come back
empty-handed.
You’ve got my attention.
Strinder! Venom Shock!
Nitro Charge!
Now! Charm Voice!
Overdrive!
Hogator!
She’s so strong...
Even a close-range
Charm Voice didn’t work.
Let’s get into the groove some more!
Keep belting out Charm Voices!
Venom Shock!
Overdrive!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Time to sing, Hogator!
That’s it! That song!
Huh?
After you two left, Roy and Hogator
just kept singing that song together.
But his singing-and-attacking trick
didn’t work before...
I had the same thought...
But something’s different about it.
Different?
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Yeah, it’s definitely different!
Honestly, I’m starting to have fun, too!
Counter with Blast Waves!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Whoa! A wild chorus of cheers!
The loudest crowd all day!
Keep it up! Charm Voice!
Let’s change his tune, Strinder!
Pluck out some Overdrives!
It worked!
Nitro Charge!
Blast Waves!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Look how Hogator’s moving!
Mixing up his movements...
Is that the plan?!
That’s it, you’ve got it!
Now’s your chance, Roy!
Charm Voice!
Stomping Tantrum!
Those are some good vibes.
Sent a chill down my spine.
But I can’t just
let you have this one.
A Terastal Orb!
Wherever there’s light,
you’ll find shadow!
Get transforming!
A curse upon you!
Strinder became a Ghost type!
We’ve gotta move it, too!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Evil Eye!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Rhyme! Don’t give up!
Hey! Hey!
Smack him down! Evil Eye!
Let’s finish this! Flamethrower!
Strinder is unable to battle!
Victory goes to Roy!
We... We won...
We did it, Hogator!
That was amazing, Roy!
Thanks!
What was that song?
I finally remembered.
Singing isn’t a tool for battling.
Huh?
“Singing helps me get stronger,
so obviously I’ve gotta sing during battle.”
That’s how I started seeing it.
But that’s not what it’s for at all.
Even if you can’t talk to each other,
singing together lets you share the same feelings!
I realized I was singing
to bond with Hogator.
And that song training was what you needed
to remind yourself of all that, huh?
Yup.
Singing doesn’t help us
get stronger in a battle.
It helps us remember we’re not alone,
which helps our hearts get stronger!
Sharing the same feelings by singing...
It was all those feelings, united by song,
that made Hogator stronger!
Song is the light of the soul.
That light melds together,
stretching out far and wide.
Just like you two demonstrated for us.
Right!
I feel some formidable vibes
coming off of this little man.
But whether or not he hits
his full potential comes down to you.
Stay motivated.
You pass your implementation test.
All right!
We did it, Hogator!
What a relief!
Roy passed after all!
That just leaves you, Liko.
Yeah!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
Strinder: Low Form.
Despite its usually lethargic attitude,
it’s quite a rowdy Pokémon.
Strinder (Low Form)
Punk Pokémon
Type: Electric/Poison
Strinder (Low Form)
Punk Pokémon
Type: Electric/Poison
Height
1.6m
Weight
40.0kg
Do you know what action it performs
when inciting a battle?
What action does it perform when inciting a battle?
Intimidate
Sneak Attack
Taunt
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What action does it perform
when inciting a battle?
C: Taunt
What action does it perform
when inciting a battle?
C: Taunt
The answer is C: Taunt.
Strinder are very confident.
No matter how strong their opponent may be,
they’ll Taunt them and incite a battle right away.
Next episode
Next, it’s finally my turn!
Right, Nyarote?
Right. “Just be confident,
and do all that you can.” Exactly!
Huh? She said all that?
What’s the next Gym Leader like?
Um... He’s cool-headed, a bit scary...
And I’ve heard he doesn’t like the cold.
Well, I hate the cold too!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
The Battle of Ice! The Cold-Eyed Grusha
Let’s do our best!