With Orio’s desires made clear,
the Brave Asagi is once again
sailing through the skies with all of us aboard.
Our objective is, of course,
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes.
Though, that said,
we still don’t know where they are.
For now, we spend our days
eating well, sleeping well,
and occasionally
doing some intensive training.
Use Leafage, Nyahoja!
Hogator! Flamethrower!
Good response!
However...
Use Thunder Punch, Cap!
Hogator! Tackle!
Hogator!
Hogator, are you okay?!
He slipped on this!
Huh? What’s that?
Some sort of purple liquid...
Hmm? Yeah, what is that?
Yeah, I hear you.
All right! Let’s get to
the bottom of this!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
The Slippery, Clangy Mystery Pokémon?!
And so, Roy and Hogator
are looking into what that liquid is.
Wow!
They haven’t figured it out yet,
but it’s kinda like they’re detectives.
Pretty exciting, right?
That so?
Am I in the way?
Not at all.
I like having time by myself
to concentrate,
but reading my books
while talking to someone is nice, too.
The feeling of all kinds of different information
making its way up here is invigorating.
Besides...
Your voice is always welcome.
It’s comforting to hear.
H-Huh?
Grandma, this teacup is chipped.
Shall I put it away?
No, it’s fine where it is.
There’s something I’d like to test.
Hmm?
What was that sound?
Curious? Well then,
why not take a look?
Huh?
Investigating things
like a detective excites you, right?
That’s right.
It’s just like learning
the mysteries of Pokémon.
I see... You’re right!
I’ll be back soon, grandma!
Mm-hmm. Go have fun!
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
No luck finding
that mysterious purple liquid...
We already looked over here, though.
Wh-What? Something up?
All right! We found some!
But... how?
This wasn’t here a second ago!
Ah... No, Hogator!
Hogator!
We haven’t heard
that sound again, even once...
That’s the sound!
Huh?
There’s nothing here...
Iwanko?!
This time, for sure!
How?!
How is there nothing?!
Huh?
Is this really all we got?
Hmm?
Ah, just who I wanted to see!
Hup...
What’s wrong with drinking
right from the tap?
Oh, fine, I get it...
This good?
Thanks, Tsubotsubo.
Time for a drink!
Ah! It’s delicious!
Tsubotsubo’s Berry Juice is the best!
Thanks for the drink!
Oh... Sorry.
Bedtime, I guess.
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
We never did find out
what that sound was.
We’ll keep investigating tomorrow.
Good night, Nyahoja.
Did you hear that?
Wanna... have a look?
All we got out of that
was you tripping and slipping a lot...
That’s why I’m holding you, okay?
So you won’t slip any more.
It’s getting late.
We’ll keep looking tomorrow.
Hogator, can you contain
yourself ‘til tomorrow?
No way, right?
Kuwassu?
What are you up to at this hour?
Liko?
Nyahoja... and Kuwassu?
What was that sound?
What are they all doing?
What Pokémon is that?
Potdeath: Phony Forme.
Black Tea Pokémon. Ghost type.
Lives in antique teapots.
The tea that composes its body has
a distinct and enjoyable flavor.
Huh?
Terapagos?!
When did you...?
This sound!
That liquid!
It was from Potdeath!
Looks like they’re having a ton of fun!
Yeah...
So you were doing all this
without us ever knowing, huh?
Me, too!
Wait, Roy!
We really shouldn’t.
Huh? How come?
We figured out where the mysterious sound
and the purple liquid were coming from.
I’m thinking that...
...this is their time.
A secret, private time
just for Pokémon.
I see.
Yeah... You’re right.
Time for food, everyone!
Here you go.
Good morning, guys.
Good morning, Friede.
Hey, look at that!
Hmm?
Ah, guess we have
a Potdeath with us.
What do you mean you “guess”?
Just a new traveling companion.
What’s wrong with that?
H-Huh?
Mmmm, looks delicious!
Don’t tell me...
Friede knew Potdeath was here all along?
Maybe...
I don’t know what’s got you so confused,
but I don’t think there’s much point
in racking your brains about it.
She’s right.
What Pokémon
come on board, and how...
Small stuff like that
doesn’t matter one bit.
Anything’s fine
as long as everyone’s comfy.
That’s how things work
here on the Brave Asagi!
Right, Cap?
Eugh! That’s n-nasty!
Hmm?
Yabacha?!
Ooh!
Success, at long last!
Huh?
Potdeath seems to have
taken a shine to my favorite!
Wait, do you mean...?
No, it’s fine where it is.
There’s something I’d like to test.
That’s your teacup from before?!
Potdeath creates more of its kin
by pouring tea into cups!
So this one is...?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Black Tea Pokémon, Potdeath.
Potdeath
Black Tea Pokémon
Type: Ghost
Potdeath
Black Tea Pokémon
Type: Ghost
This Pokémon lives in old teapots.
Height
0.2m
Its body is made of black tea!
Weight
0.4kg
Is this tea tasty? Average? Or nasty?
Which of these describes Potdeath's tea?
Tasty
Average
Nasty
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that live in water!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Whaleoh, Kaiogre,
Numacraw, Kamasujaw, Gekkouga!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
This is Landau. "Rap" is as freeform as water.
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Nuoh!
Whaleoh, Kaiogre, nyoh...
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
Which of these describes Potdeath's tea?
A: Tasty
The answer is A: Tasty!
Its distinctive taste and aroma
have made it popular among enthusiasts.
But drinking too much can have
a harmful effect on your health.
Even if Potdeath offers you tea,
do exercise restraint.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
I hear when ships
get lost in the mist,
there’s a Laplace with a beautiful
singing voice that guides them out!
A beautiful singing voice...
How romantic!
But hey, what if this Laplace
is one of Lucius’s Six Heroes?!
Liko! If it is, you gotta go see it!
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
The Song in the White Mist
Don’t miss it!