Following a lead
on the black Rekkuuza,
we went to the forest
and found an injured Wooper.
Then, an incredibly
huge Oliva appeared.
It attacked us out of nowhere,
but it was actually kind-hearted
and cared for the forest Pokémon.
That kind Oliva then showed us...
...the deep wound
the forest had suffered in the fire.
The forest is hurt so badly...
Liko! Roy!
The forest is burnt
all the way through.
There’s more damage
than we thought.
As long as the forest
lacks its greenery,
there will be Pokémon like that Wooper,
unable to survive on their own.
No way...
Oliva was sharing its nutrients
with the weakened Pokémon...
...and tending to them
if they got hurt.
It’s like a forest doctor.
A doctor... That’s right.
But it can only do so much
with the forest in this state...
I’d hate to leave Oliva
and the forest Pokémon like this.
What should we do?
We should plant a forest!
Huh?!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents
I bet
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
Something you can’t quite put into words...
Something that makes your heart beat a bit faster...
Something that seems to brighten up your day...
“I found some flowers I like!”
With white mist clinging onto every day
I can’t even look for what I wanna find, ooh
My diary makes it all look so exciting
“I threw it out, pretending it wasn’t mine” ...strike that
You lia-ia-ia-iar...
My inconsolable heart
Whoa-oh whoa-oh-o-oh
Rewrite “But”/“Yet” into “I bet”/“It could be true”
If only I could walk on air, on a fair breeze
Greatly, smoothly, slightly, nearly, someday...
I wanna fly!
I’m riding the heart-pound-ifying currents!
I bet! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
Don’t let untold tales scare you
Dazzling daydreams make the world dance!
So smile! Yay-yay-yay-yay yay-yay-yay
No time to waste hiding away
I wanna learn about myself!
I still don’t know anything about any-any-anything
I wanna discover myself!
The day I manage to say “I’m heading out on my own”
Maybe I’ll grow up a little bit
The Future I Choose
Nyahoja!
Grab some berries at Lightning Speed!
Thank you, Nyahoja.
I guess we’ll want to plant lots of different berries.
Nyahoja! This time, use Leafage!
I get it.
So we’re gonna plant these.
No reception.
Signal really doesn’t reach here, huh?
What’s wrong?
I wanted to ask Friede
and the others for help.
We can try calling them later.
Molly and I will gather the berries.
Roy and Hogator,
you can till the soil.
Okay!
Let’s do it, Hogator!
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
Hogator! Stomping Tantrum!
All right!
We did it, Hogator!
Thank you, Nyahoja.
You worked so hard.
Now all we need is...
Water!
But given the season,
Paldea won’t be expecting rain anytime soon.
Aww...
Yo-ssu, all you Pokémon Trainers
out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s a vid from Gurumin!
Besides their moves,
Pokémon have skills called “abilities”!
Powering up when in a pinch!
When your foes attack...
Damaging them back!
They’ll come out in
loadsa different situations.
Even the same species of Pokémon
can have different abilities,
so understanding the abilities
of your opponent’s Pokémon...
...is also an important part
of winning battles!
The special powers of your partners...
As trainers, you’ve gotta make good use of ‘em!
Okay, video check complete.
Time to upload...
Huh?
The signal’s bad...
Hey... Don’t you think
they should’ve been back by now?
Like I said, Molly’s with them.
They’ll be fine.
But I haven’t heard a word back
from any of them!
See? Someone reached out.
Huh?
It’s from Dot. That’s odd.
The whole area’s
having communication issues?!
Maybe that’s why we haven’t heard back
from Liko and the others...
You two look after the ship.
S-Sure.
I’m heading out on Lizardon.
Cap, come with me.
Somehow, he’s...
...turning into a bigger
worrywart than me.
Liko... Roy...
Man! There’s no reception
anywhere out here?
What is it, Cap?
A Rarecoil?
I see. So there’s the culprit.
Cap, give it a scare!
Thanks, Cap!
Now the signal should...
Hello?!
Oh, I finally got through!
What is it? What’s happened?
We just tilled the soil
to plant a forest.
What? Tilling... for a forest?
Got it. I understand.
Glad you’re okay.
Huh? What was that?
Nothing.
So you need water.
Okay, leave it to me.
Lizardon, let’s hurry!
Ah, they’re here!
Friede!
This way, this way!
Everyone, sorry for the wait!
No worries.
Oh, and Orio!
It’s not just me.
Huh?!
Old man Landau!
But why?!
Even a withered tree
will brighten a barren land.
It’s time I draw
my own dulled blade.
Grant us a great blessing, Nuoh.
Rain Prayer!
Rain!
The soil’s getting wetter and wetter!
Nuoh. Water Fish Pokémon.
Water/Ground type.
If it bumps its head on boats
and boulders while swimming,
it doesn’t care.
It has an easygoing nature.
I never knew he had that Pokémon...
I hadn’t seen it before either.
Oliva?
Falling Seeds. Oliva’s ability.
Looks like the rain
brought back that power, too.
Everyone helped Oliva out,
so it must’ve wanted
to do something in return!
Look! The Pokémon came back!
Now they can all thrive.
That’s great!
I bet Oliva is relieved, too.
Ah! The pendant!
What?!
It’s just like with Rekkuuza!
But something’s weird...
What now?
Liko! Roy!
What? What is... this?!
I want you to find...
...the world’s...
Huh?
Liko! Roy! Are you okay?
Did you see that?
Yeah, I did.
What... was that?
The Ancient Monster Ball!
It went in on its own?
Does that mean...
it wants to come with us?
No good. It won’t open.
What’s with these things?!
There’s got to be some logic to them.
Huh?
But it’s clear that
Oliva approves of you.
You two should look after that ball.
Sure.
Right...
That was quite the unexpected sight...
But what say we head back
to the ship for now?
Yeah!
Liko!
You’ve given me a good glimpse
of your capabilities.
pOCket Monsters
Liko and Roy Set Off
The motif is pretty unique,
but I can’t find any info on it...
Gah! I just don’t get it!
Keep quiet when
you’re in the library.
Ms. Lucca!
It’s been a while, Friede.
My husband told me
you went off to Bowl Town,
so I thought you’d be in the library.
Have you been well, Cap?
I’ve been trying to call you.
What have you been doing all this time?
Sorry, sorry.
With my mother and all,
I thought contact would be risky.
Risky?
Risky! Risky!
Wh-What?!
Risky! Risky! Risky!
S-Sorry...
Shall we go for a walk?
Risky!
Liko, you seen Friede?
He left for the library earlier.
Oh, are those...?
My father said they’re for you.
Can I read them?!
Yeah, of course.
All right!
Wh-What happened?!
Th-Th-This! But why?!
Why? What is it?
This! This is it!
The story I know
about the Ancient Adventurer!
Huh?!
Still, you don’t really
look like much of a Pokémon Professor.
I don’t mind.
I feel better like this.
I see. Did you learn anything about
that Monster Ball you were looking into?
The materials and condition
lead me to believe it’s pretty old...
Yes.
It belonged to
the Ancient Adventurer Lucius,
who made his way to paradise
with the Six Heroes a century ago.
When I was young,
Gramps used to read me this book!
I remember this cover.
This is totally it!
“Once upon a time,
a hundred years past,
“there was an adventurer
followed by a black Rekkuuza.
“He traveled through every region,
meeting strong Pokémon,
“and forging strong bonds with them.
“Dreaming of new sights,
he took the Pokémon he befriended...
“...and headed for
the ends of the world.
“They all worked together as one.
“Racing across the land,
breaking through walls,
“bounding through the sky,
healing wounds, crossing seas...
“His adventure led him to discover...
“...a luxurious, beautiful,
and gleaming paradise.
“The adventurer, his black Rekkuuza,
and his Pokémon friends...
“...went on to live
happily ever after in this paradise.
“Praising his courage
and his endless curiosity,
“he would come to be known as...
“...the Ancient Adventurer.”
It’s true! That’s your dad!
I never imagined
you’d have read this...
Hey, is that black Rekkuuza...
...the same Rekkuuza we saw?
Then is the one that was
“healing wounds” Oliva?
Could be.
The Pokémon in the Ancient Monster Balls
were this adventurer’s partners...
That means there’s
four more of them!
Awesome! I wanna meet them all!
Don’t you, Hogator?!
The Oliva and black Rekkuuza
that appeared from these balls...
They’re two of the Pokémon
known as Lucius’s Six Heroes.
Six Heroes...
Liko’s pendant resonates with those balls...
Just what is it?
Pendant...
We saw it.
Liko’s pendant turned into
what seemed to be a Pokémon.
I see. So my girl...
Ms. Lucca, surely you know something?
You are Liko’s mother.
I don’t know much about
the pendant either.
It was my mother’s, after all.
After all! After all!
Once Liko was accepted
into Sekiei Academy,
my mother gave it to her
as a good-luck charm.
So Liko having it
is what kicked things off?
The Ancient Adventurer and the Six Heroes
were tales my mother once told me.
You’d need to ask her about them.
Galar! Old castle!
An old castle... in Galar?!
Yes, that picture book...
...was something I thought up
based on a story from your grandma.
So the book was all just lies?
“Lies” is a bit harsh...
Call it fiction.
Fiction...
What is it, Liko?
You really liked that book?
Y-Yeah... It was interesting.
Thank you. I’ll talk to you later.
So was it just made up, then?
No. There has to be
some truth in it.
We’ve even met
the black Rekkuuza and Oliva!
That reminds me,
the man we saw in Oliva’s forest...
That can’t have been a dream.
I feel like he was trying
to say something...
Was he talking to this?
I bet Nyahoja and Hogator
can feel it, too.
There are even more
exciting adventures in store for us!
Well, I should be heading back.
You’re not going to
meet with your daughter?
I was planning to get
the pendant from her...
But why don’t we let Liko
determine what’s next?
You want Liko to decide?
If I saw her, the parent in me
would just talk on and on...
I want to let her
choose her own future.
That’s how I prefer to teach.
Choose her own future, huh...?
That’s the teacher in you talking.
Didn’t I tell you the same thing?
That’s right.
Liko will be safe
with you at her side.
Enjoy yourselves.
So that’s the story.
Liko, we want you
to decide what to do next.
I’m going to meet my grandma.
If I meet her, I might learn something
about the little one in here.
Liko, I wanna come too!
Roy!
Maybe I’ll get to find out more about
the Ancient Monster Balls and Rekkuuza!
And I wanna meet your grandma
and find out what she’s like!
She’s incredible.
She goes on adventures
all over the world,
so I never know where she’ll be.
Huh? Then it’s hopeless...
Don’t you worry.
Your grandma...
...used a Pokémon
to tell me where she is!
Apparently she’s in an old castle
in the Galar Region.
The Galar Region...
Another new place!
Liko, Roy...
Looks like your minds are made up.
Yeah!
“Chase each mystery we see until it’s solved!”
is our motto,
but are you all up for this voyage?
Yeah. Sounds like fun.
Mm-hmm.
Without me,
this ship’d be done for!
There’s bound to be Pokémon
in trouble there, so I have to go.
Then it’s settled.
Let’s go! To the Galar Region!
Yeah!
And so, we departed Paldea
to go meet my grandma.
Their ship’s systems...
Their communication methods...
Their skills as trainers...
All my analyses have concluded.
Your adventures with the pendant...
...will also conclude here.
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Yo! We are the Rising Voltteccers
What Pokémon will we meet next?
I can't wait for more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Then why don't we learn about more Pokémon?
First, Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Now, can you say it with Liko?
Are you ready?
Hmm... Can I really do it? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Koraidon, Tandon, Uochilldon,
Miraidon, Donkarasu, Tritodon
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next, Pokémon that have regional forms!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Molly here. Hmm, this sounds fun.
Pokémon that have regional forms
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it's gonna explode.
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Olive Pokémon, Oliva.
Oliva
Olive Pokémon
Type: Grass/Normal
Oliva
Olive Pokémon
Type: Grass/Normal
Height
1.4m
Oliva is a Pokémon with many fruits
on its long arms.
Weight
48.2kg
But do you know
what kind of nature it has?
What is Oliva like?
Savage
Kind
Mean
See the answer after the commercials!
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What is Oliva like?
B: Kind
The answer is B: Kind.
It may be scary if it gets angry,
but normally, it’s a very kind
and gentle Pokémon.
It’s devoted to
caring for its friends.
Those arms nurture
both its fruits and its friends.
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you flustered Pokémon Trainers
out there! Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
The Brave Asagi sets sail
for the Galar Region!
Wait... What now?
More problems with the ship?
But! They say “Life has its ups and downs”...
Times like these, just enjoy the ride!
You might even bump into
surprising new faces...
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
A Sudden Picnic