I’m Dot.
The re-formed Rising Voltteccers have come to
Orange Academy for the first time in ages.
Our reason for coming here
was to seek out advice regarding Strong Spheres,
which make use of Rakurium,
a dangerous substance.
But...
After Botan and I reunited for the first time in ages,
we’ve ended up having our very first Pokémon Battle...
Whichever trainer takes down
one Pokémon first will be the victor!
Got it?
Mm-hmm.
A Booster and a Nymphia.
In terms of match-up, I have the advantage...
Well then, let the battle... begin!
Nymphia!
Attack Nakanuchan with Moonforce!
Nakanuchan! Brutal Swing!
Now! Welcamo,
use Aqua Break on Nymphia!
Good work, Welcamo.
Booster! Flamethrower!
Nymphia, attack Nakanuchan
with Moonforce!
Nakanuchan,
stop the blow with your hammer!
Welcamo, now!
Use Aqua Cutter!
Uh...
Nakanuchan!
What’s up with you, Welcamo?
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
The Knight Met at the Ruins
Welcamo’s acting weird...
He’s showing off...?
Botan’s looking good!
Pull yourself together, Welcamo!
Of course...
Nymphia’s ability, which gives Pokémon of
a different gender the lovey-dovey status...
Lovey-Dovey Body!
In that case...
Welcamo, get Booster!
Nakanuchan!
Open Welcamo’s eyes for me!
Good going, Nakanuchan!
Ooh... I never even considered that.
Welcamo’s back to normal!
Even though normally you’d need to
defeat Nymphia to remove the lovey-dovey status...
Nakanuchan managed to
snap Welcamo out of it!
All right! Let’s go, Welcamo.
Glitz it up,
go viral, and shine!
Ah, what a bind...
Now you’ve forced me to show
my Veevees’ true potential!
Sparkle, stars! Terastal!
You can be whoever you want to be!
Nymphia! Moonforce!
Nakanuchan! Slam!
What the...?!
Welcamo! Aqua Break!
Booster! Speed Star!
Welcamo is unable to battle!
The winner is Botan!
I lost...
Welcamo, Nakanuchan... Good work.
You fought well...
Man, Botan’s that strong...
I can hardly believe it.
Starrific work.
They both sure showed their stuff!
That was an awesome battle,
huh, Achigator?!
She’s not just a cute face...
The counters they both came up with were so cool!
Botan’s really strong!
She even gets to assist the Tops
at the Pokémon League, y’know.
Lemme battle next!
Osu! Sorry, but school hours are over.
Your battle will have to
wait ‘til next time.
Huh?!
Gotta be kiddin’...
Those kids have grown quite a lot.
I bet they’ll bear
even more fruit! I can’t wait!
Uh-huh!
And so, leaving
Orange Academy behind us,
we once again set our minds on
collecting the necessary data to investigate...
...the relationship between
Strong Spheres and Rakurium.
Botan-san’s data...
The info on Rakurium Signs seen in the Paldea Region
is organized in a way that makes it easy to understand...
So this one’s the latest sighting?
Hey, isn’t that spot...
...the place we explored
with Ms. Raifort before?
Those ruins?
Well, it is within walking distance.
What say we go check it out?
Come along with us, Cap!
I’ll put together a picnic set for lunch, then.
Swing by the kitchen.
Nice!
And I’ll get everything ready
for you to set out.
Make sure you don’t
overexert yourselves.
Okay!
Now this sounds like fun.
Count me in!
Seems like a Rakurium Sign
was seen in this area.
There’s no telling what kind of Pokémon
might show up, so be careful.
Hmph! You can mega-leave it
to me ‘n’ Yamirami!
We’ll take ‘em down in seconds!
Let’s split up and search from here.
Okay. I’ll contact you
if I find any Rakurium Signs!
For now, we need to
collect data as evidence.
This time,
make sure you get it on video!
Right!
Where’d you go?
I don’t spice-see you anywhere...
Um... Hello.
Hello.
My name’s Liko.
My name’s Karatou,
even though I can’t handle spicy food.
spicy food lover
Nice to meet you.
Um, what’s wrong?
Erm...
Have you seen
a Scovillain around here?
A Scovillain?
Yes-picy.
He’s my partner,
but I haven’t spice-seen him since ye-spice-day...
We haven’t seen him, have we?
That so...?
I’ll keep spi-searching around here,
so let me know if you see him.
Understood.
See ya.
We all made it to the watchtower.
Okay. I’ll head over there now, too.
All done!
This here’s my special sandwich!
See, Pagogo, Tebrim? Here it is!
Let’s make one together!
Come to think of it...
Dot, this is your first picnic, isn’t it?
I didn’t even want to
leave the ship back then...
But...
You put together a sandwich set
for me on board the Brave Asagi,
and I had fun making sandwiches
with old man Landau.
I’m gonna make
the mega-strongest sandwich!
Aw yeah!
Time to dig in!
Now then, the only place left to search...
is those ruins over there.
Let’s all go search there
in the afternoon.
Hey... We’re going to have to tell lots of people
that Rakurium is dangerous, aren’t we?
Yeah.
Which means we’ll have to go
to lots of different places in the Brave Asagi.
I think we’ll be more in need of funds
than ever before.
You’re right...
Friede and Cap took part-time jobs
looking for Pokémon and stuff before, too...
We’ve also got to
think of stuff to do...
We’ve got a lot of options.
What’s that? Money?
An ancient coin.
Useless these days.
That reminds me... Roy, you collected coins
around here before too, didn’t you?
Y-Yeah... But y’know...
I don’t really remember
that whole thing too well...
‘Cause you were under
Collecurei’s control.
What now?!
I mega-wanna hear that! Super lame!
That’s Collecurei’s power.
I’m not gonna fall for the same trick twice.
I’ve got my doubts.
There! A coin!
And over here, too! A coin!
And another one here!
Ooh! You found one too, Cap!
Geez... Those coins’re useless,
ain’t they?
Found one! A coin!
Huh? Where did everyone go?
They were with us
until a second ago...
Wait... Now Pagogo’s gone!
Pagogo!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Pagogo!
Yeah, that’s a Rakurium Sign.
I’ve gotta tell everyone!
Found one!
I ain’t losin’!
Me neither!
Geez. Why isn’t anybody answering...?
H-Huh? A-Ahh!
A Scovillain!
This is bad!
Masquernya, get its attention!
Magical Leaf!
Now’s your chance, Tebrim.
Use Heal Pulse on everyone!
Rakurium effects...
This Scovillain must be
Karatou-san’s partner.
Masquernya! Magical Leaf!
Scovillain must be suffering, too...
But Masquernya
can’t keep this up forever, either...
Scovillain! Please!
Open your eyes!
Look out!
Thank you!
You’re...
...the Carbou from back then?
Amazing...
Now’s our chance!
Pagogo, you’re up!
Everyone!
I’m so glad you’re safe!
I’m glad you came to your senses,
Scovillain.
I’ll take you to see
Karatou-san, okay?
My Scovillain!
So you found him!
Yes.
But he won’t stop squabbling...
Yeah! He’s always glad
to squabble away!
The green head’s
like a little kid, you see...
And the red one’s the older brother,
you might spice-say.
So this is normal for them...
I’m so happy to see him again...
Um... Could I ask you something?
Karatou-san,
do you use a Strong Sphere?
How did you know?
I applied to be an Exceed product tester,
and I’ve been using one.
Where is that Strong Sphere?
I don’t have it now.
But it’s super spicy strong, even in spicy battles.
I used it per-spice-tently,
and it ran out of energy.
So much that it ran out of energy...
After that, I spi-sent it back to them
so they could spice it back up!
If you’re interested,
maybe you should apply!
No... but thanks.
I should be thanking you.
This might not be a spicy tidbit,
but I just love Scovillain!
Look! There’s all kinds of Scovillain!
Oh, uh...
Some have both heads green,
or both heads red! It’s spicily rare, but...
Maybe some other time!
See you around!
Oh, you’ve been waiting on me!
Scovillain’s back with his partner.
Pagogo and Carbou
seem to get along really well...
But we’d better get going.
Carbou... Thanks for everything.
Carbou?
You want to protect me?
Thank you, Carbou!
Let’s be good friends.
Everyone...
I was trying to call you...
Liko!
How’d you do?
Those coins...
Is that Collecurei again?!
Huh?
What?
So Strong Spheres
really were behind it.
Apparently Scovillain ran off
after his trainer used it persistently.
Maybe he started to hate him...?
I think that maybe...
...using Strong Spheres too much
ruptures the bond between trainer and Pokémon.
Their bond ruptures...
That reminds me...
When we battled the Explorers,
the Kentauros weren’t listening
to their commands!
You’re right.
A video message. Who’s it from?
Dot-shi! Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
You know that Gurumin-shi collab
I’ve been askin’ you for? I wanna do it!
And we’ll make it a handshake meet
in Hakkou City! An IRL event!
Sweet, right?! Think about it!
Waitin’ to hear from you!
Whoa, hold on!
A fan meetup event?!
She’s always so pushy!
Amazing! So cool! I wanna go!
Yeah, super cool!
Sounds like a lotta fun!
Huh...? A handshake meet...?
Well, guess that’s one way
to raise funds while gathering info...
I’ll give it a try!
Yay!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Shell Pokémon, Kamex!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Shell Pokémon
Kamex
Water
Torrent
Kamex
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shell Pokémon
Torrent
Kamex
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shell Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
The two rocket cannons that were attached
to its shell combined into one, and became huge!
Mega Kamex
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Shell Pokémon
Water
Mega Launcher
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It has a firing range
that reaches ten kilometers!
Can you see that, Kamex?
Aim for that!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Not me!
Next episode
Amethio-sama...
Where could you have gone?
We can’t find even a single clue!
Let’s check
the most likely spots again.
Right, got it.
Huh? News from Gurumin?
What?! Gurumin’s holding an event?!
Wh-Why, that’s...
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Burn Hot, Gurumin Love!
Wait, what?