Look at this, Dot!
You really eat this much
first thing in the morning...?
I hear this is Uirou City’s
signature breakfast special!
More importantly,
about that building...
It’s Exceed’s Testing Center.
Apparently they’re gathering trainers
and testing a new product.
A new product?
I don’t know the details,
but they’re called “Strong Spheres.”
Strong Spheres?
I... heard someone
talking about that...
Hey, have you heard of
those whatsit-Spheres?
What are they?
I hear they’re real handy in a battle!
And they’re coming out soon!
Wow...
Rafflesia was acting weird
near that testing building.
No way that’s just a coincidence.
It’s pretty worrying...
Let’s investigate, Liko.
Yeah.
Be careful.
I’ll keep gathering more info.
Got it.
Ult?
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Strong Spheres
Didn’t expect to see Ult here...
Didn’t something
seem weird about him?
Achigator!
We’re gonna be seen!
You kids!
They’re about to start!
Hurry up!
Welcome to
the Exceed Testing Center!
Look!
Isn’t that Boc?
She was in the Terastal Course with us.
Yeah, that’s right.
It seems Ms. Boc here has been
struggling to grow as a trainer.
Y-Yeah...
I just can’t seem to beat my friends...
With this, you’ll do fine!
Handy and user-friendly!
The latest in power-up items...
The Strong Sphere!
So that’s a Strong Sphere...
That shape!
It looks like those things Spinel had.
Here. Go all-out in your battle, okay?
Y-Yeah...
No need to hold back!
The worst possible match-up...
We don’t stand a chance.
Well then, let the battle begin!
Just gotta go for it...
Hup!
Swanna’s expression changed.
Plus, that color...
Here goes!
100,000 Volts!
Right off the bat?!
So fast!
You’re pretty good.
Water Gun!
Awesome!
We have a winner!
Marvelous!
I actually won...
That was a wonderful battle!
How did it feel
to use a Strong Sphere?
Um... Against such a tough opponent...
It sure was surprising!
I’ve never seen a Water Gun
like that before.
Practically a Hydro Pump, wasn’t it?
Thank you for giving
our Strong Spheres a try!
Let’s hear a big
round of applause for Ms. Boc!
Strong Spheres
make battles even more fun!
Filming is allowed,
so make sure to tell all your friends!
Boc’s Swanna’s eyes...
They looked just like Haganail’s and Rafflesia’s
when they were rampaging.
There’s no doubt about it.
Strong Spheres use Rakurium.
The Rakurium isn’t all gone.
Boc!
Long time no see!
You guys are here, too?!
We saw your battle!
That Strong Sphere was incredible!
With one of those,
I might even be able to beat Luca and Rai!
Is it feeling okay?
You’re worn out
from working so hard, aren’t you?
I’ll go make sure it gets some rest.
See you around!
Oh, right. Ult!
There he is.
Ult!
Roy, huh?
Ult? What’s wrong?
Hey, wait...
I ain’t feelin’ so hot.
Don’t talk to me!
Huh?
Roy?
What happened to Ult...?
Sorry for the wait!
Allow me to introduce our special guests!
The Explorers’ very own...
Ms. Sango and Mr. Onyx!
Hey there, y’all!
It’s cute li’l Sango!
Cute li’l Sango!
Here I am!
Yahoo!
The Explorers...!
I locked eyes with Mr. Onyx!
I’m going numb!
I wish I could be like the Explorers!
Look.
Hmm?
Gah!
The Explorers will be holding
an exhibition match!
We’ve chosen our opponents.
They’re friends of cute li’l Sango!
Astounding! They’ve got some folks in mind!
So, who will be your opponents?
Hmm.
Please take this.
I’ll decline.
Me, too.
Huh? But...
Thanks for comin’!
It’s been forever!
You two been doin’ well?
Drop the act!
Huh?
Waaah! Why’re you so mad?
Don’t you bully cute li’l Sango!
Cute li’l Sango!
Just messin’!
I’m A-okay!
This is a real handful...
You should know
those things are dangerous!
Strong Spheres
are a superb invention.
You’re about to
taste their power firsthand!
Kyojiohn!
Time to play, Onigohri!
Looks like
everyone is ready to battle!
What a mess...
They’re supposed to be promoting the new product.
If they don’t use it, there’s no point...
If they’re not gonna use it,
give it here.
Huh? Sure...
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Now then, it’s time for the exhibition match
against Ms. Sango and Mr. Onyx, so...
Let the battle begin!
I’m gonna go all out!
Blizzard!
Flamethrower!
Hang in there, Onigohri!
They’re stronger than before!
Ice Spinner!
Dodge it!
And while you’re at it... Blizzard!
This is crazy!
Wh-What an outrageous attack!
That’s the Explorers for you!
You can’t escape! Salt Pickling!
Masquernya, behind you!
If we focus too much on the Blizzard,
we’ll get hit by Salt Pickling...
Blizzard!
Salt Pickling!
Achigator!
Leave this to me!
Masquernya, stay calm!
They’re cornered.
Onigohri! Ice Spinner!
A whole lot of Trick Flowers!
So many!
Roy!
Now’s our chance!
Flamethrower!
Onigohri!
Explorers! Hang in there!
Don’t let ‘em outshine ya,
cute li’l Sango!
Sweet! I’m startin’ to have fun!
Sango. It’s time.
Okay!
Here it comes...
And there they are! Strong Spheres!
Go, Kyojiohn!
Onigohri!
A devastating move! Absolute Zero!
Now you’re done for!
Achigator!
Good going, Achigator!
Why have you taken this so far?!
Hmm?
Just look at your Pokémon!
That way of battling
is anything but normal!
It’s the Strong Spheres, isn’t it?
And there she goes!
You know the type.
Starts whining as soon as things go south...
Cute li’l Sango’s right!
Show some manners!
Pokémon are creatures
that all love to battle.
Uh-huh! Goin’ all-out in battle
makes ‘em happy!
Doesn’t seem that way to me!
They aren’t even
looking at their trainers!
Is that all you have to say?
We know you don’t need
to rely on those things!
Your Strong Spheres
won’t outmatch us!
Masquernya!
Achigator!
We have a winner!
That’s the Explorers for you!
We’re not done here.
The Explorers see things through!
Huh?
Masquernya!
Achigator!
“Don’t need to rely on those”?
We’ll make sure ya never
act so high and mighty again!
Cap! Voltteccer!
Huh?!
Shadow Clones!
Cap!
He’s all wobbly!
Amazing!
They’re strong, all right!
That’s enough!
Ult?!
What now?
Huh?
Your battle’s finished, right?
Then face me,
the almighty Ult, next!
Coming to their aid?
Or are ya just a glory hog?
You Explorers guys are strong, yeah?
But I don’t like you!
Your battles are so lame!
Huh?!
Lemme show you a real battle!
Stop, Ult! That’s—
Of course I ain’t using this!
I mega-don’t like these things!
What I don’t like...
...is you, ya hear me?!
Onigohri, blow him away!
Yamirami! Shadow Strike!
The heck do ya mean,
“a real battle”?! That ain’t—
Now! Power Gem!
Dodge it!
Go, Onigohri!
Just blow all of ‘em away!
Wait!
The event is over.
That was a shock...
Today’s event has now concluded!
Thank you for coming!
I dunno what happened exactly,
but it was an awesome battle!
The Explorers are the best!
What a great Self-Destruct!
I love cute li’l Sango’s
new performance style!
Ugh! This makes me totally mad!
That weirdo showed up
and ruined everything!
They got away.
How should we proceed?
Let them go.
Huh?! No payback for
makin’ us look like chumps?!
Do not forget our goal.
We are the Explorers.
We must continue to present ourselves
as ideal trainers and figures of admiration.
As long as we have the public on our side,
they can’t do anything to us.
Totally boring!
Everything from Pokémon food
to urban development!
Exceed creates the ideal future,
with Pokémon.
The Testing Center’s demo event
is a hot topic online.
The Strong Spheres have
everyone’s curiosity piqued.
No way...
But the Strong Spheres
use Rakurium...
Exceed has occupied Mt. Kumuri.
There must still be Rakurium left,
and that’s the source...
If we don’t do something...!
But nobody’s gonna
believe a word we say.
I’ll believe you.
Thank you!
I-It’s nothin’!
Ult... You might’ve saved us,
but you’re just as reckless as ever.
If I saved ya,
maybe you oughta cut the backtalk!
You just wanted to run wild,
didn’t you?
What’d you say?!
Anyway, I’m glad to see you
back to your old self, Ult.
Huh? I’m always myself...
You were being all weird!
Acting... like this...
That was... ‘cause of the bus.
The bus?
Oh, you get carsick?
Shut up! Just forget it!
Anyway, wrecking those guys
I didn't like made me feel better.
All right, my mind’s made up!
I’m gonna come with you!
Huh?
I got no choice.
I worry ‘bout what’d happen to you without me!
He says he’d “worry”...
Are you sure he’s... all right?
Let’s go together.
Having someone with an eye for Pokémon
along will help us push forward!
And Pokémon are all you’ve
got an eye for, anyhow.
Shut it!
Looks like Yamirami
likes that thing, too.
What’s wrong?
Everything’s okay now.
It looks like Pagogo’s
trying to tell us something.
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Disaster Pokémon, Absol!
Disaster Pokémon
Absol
Evil
Pressure
Great Luck
Absol
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Disaster Pokémon
Pressure
Great Luck
Absol
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Absol
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Disaster Pokémon
Magic Mirror
Evil
It may look like it has wings, but that's actually
the overflowing Mega Evolution energy...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
...making all its fur stand on end!
Its attack and speed
have risen sharply...!
...so be careful when approaching.
Next episode
Roy! Where’s the black Rekkuuza right now?!
There’s no way I’d know that...
I’m gonna obtain the black Rekkuuza
and become the mega-strongest!
What is it, Pagogo?
Could there be something
off in the direction Pagogo’s crying...?
Maybe... Just maybe...
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Clash! The Roaring Dragons Gang
See you there!
See ya there!
Clash! The Roaring Dragons Gang