I’m Roy.
After the Rising Voltteccers disbanded,
my travels took me to Miare City in the Kalos Region.
There, I ended up doing
Mega Evolution training—
I’m Ult!
And with me’s Yamirami.
I’m gonna master Mega Evolution,
no doubt!
This weird old man, Master Mayonnaise,
sent me to his “Mayo-Maze Palace.”
At the end of an annoying maze...
...was this alternate-colored Lucario
called “The Yellow Blast.”
If I can smack it down, my Yamirami’s gonna
get so strong it’ll be able to Mega Evolve!
Or, that’s what I thought...
W-We lost...
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
Ult—Strongest
Gah... Urk!
Sheesh, Ult...
Eat slowly and chew your food,
like I’m always telling you.
Huh? Yeah, I know.
And you should finish studying
before you head out.
You dig in to your heart’s content, Roy.
Thanks so much, Matière-san!
These are tasty, too.
Thanks for treating me
to such a feast.
Ult invited a close pal over,
so it’s only right!
“Close... pal”?
Huh?
Are not!
So...
I went all out and made all these!
Eek!
Thanks, Fluff.
Hmph. Pipe down over there.
That was delicious!
Matière-san’s
super good at cooking, huh?
Dunno about that.
It was just like always.
“Like always”?!
So jealous...
Never mind that.
We oughta be worrying about that guy.
The Yellow Blast!
That Lucario’s strength
was out of this world, huh?
So happy-go-lucky...
Man! My Yamirami couldn’t even
get a foot in the door!
How’re we ever gonna beat it?
A chump like that... I woulda laid it flat in a single hit
if I coulda used this, the strongest Pokémon...
That’s one of your Pokémon?
Basically.
So what is it?
No idea.
Huh? You don’t know?
I’ve had this ball
ever since I was little!
It’s never opened,
but I can just tell...
It’s gotta have some kinda
awesome Pokémon inside!
Someday,
I’ll be the strongest Pokémon Trainer,
and it’ll approve of
my skills and come out!
What, you gonna laugh at me?
I’d never do that!
After all, you’re just like me!
What’s that ball?
Never seen one like it.
An Ancient Monster Ball!
It washed up
on the island I lived on,
and my grandpa gave it to me.
I always believed
there was a Pokémon inside.
Huh... So, was there?
Sure was! Wanna hear what?
Hmph! Not interested.
I bet you’d be blown away!
What the heck are you doing...?
You two really are close pals.
Hmph!
Oh right, I forgot to put on
the after-dinner tea.
Oh dear...
A blackout?
Take it easy.
That’s always happening.
Always...?
I’m sorry.
This place is so old...
Denryu!
If you’d please.
It just won’t work
without your power.
Shine down the light
of the great sun!
Mega Evolve!
Huh?!
Ahh!
It happened again!
Thank you, Denryu.
It Mega Evolved...
She’s as wasteful as ever...
Hey. If there’s some kinda
trick to that, teach me.
Oh? You’ve never
cared about it before, Ult...
Shut it!
Ooh...
So, you came to Kalos because
you wanted to perform Mega Evolution?
Yeah. Until just recently,
I’d been adventuring all over the world
with my friends, the Rising Voltteccers.
The Rising Voltteccers...
Oh! Exceed said something about them.
What was it...?
Thank you, Fluff.
“The Rising Voltteccers
caused an incident upon Mt. Kumuri...”
That’s what Exceed’s been saying,
but it’s not true!
But...
The Rising Voltteccers
are disbanded now.
My friends have gone off to school...
...or headed back home.
But I wanted to become a stronger
Pokémon Trainer, so I set out to travel.
Cap was the partner of the Rising Voltteccers’ leader,
a man named Friede.
But now, with Friede gone,
he’s been following me.
I see... I see.
Why he decided to follow me,
I couldn’t tell you...
But for now, I just wanna
get way, way stronger as a trainer...
...and meet the black Rekkuuza again!
Huh?
He was one of our friends, too.
Huh? You’re lyin’!
Rekkuuza’s a Legendary Pokémon.
And you said it was a black one?
It’s true!
I showed you
the Ancient Monster Ball earlier!
That’s quite an old ball!
Guided by the black Rekkuuza
that came from this ball,
I set out on an adventure
with my partner,
and even got Rekkuuza
to approve of me a little.
You serious?
So where is Rekkuuza now?
We got into some big trouble,
and he protected us,
but we wound up
being separated after that.
Which is why
I wanna meet him again!
So that’s your dream, Roy...
The black Rekkuuza belongs to me!
Belongs to you...?
I’ve made up my mind!
A black Rekkuuza sounds so freakin’ cool!
I’m gonna be the strongest trainer,
so that’s perfect for me!
Hold on!
Catching Rekkuuza is my dream!
But you ain’t caught him yet, yeah?
He’s a wild Pokémon,
which means anyone can try and catch him.
Th-That’s...
Well, am I wrong?
No, you’re not wrong...
You hit the nail on the head, Ult.
Then with that settled,
I gotta get to Mega Evolution training already!
Let’s go, Yamirami!
Again? Just running off
before we were done talking...
How strange...
Huh? He was like that earlier, too.
The moment he heard
about Mega Evolution, he ran off...
Wow, Ult did that...?
Hey, Roy...
Could I ask you for a favor?
A favor...?
I want you to
become friends with Ult.
Huh?! Me?
Ult’s never cared so much
about anyone before!
Have you always lived with Ult,
then, Matière-san?
Mmm... Let me tell you about him.
At some point,
I started to see him around town a lot.
I learned he was living in a back alley.
So I brought him here,
where he’d be warmer than some back alley.
You did that for him...?
I don’t have a mom or dad either,
and I used to live a similar life here in Miare.
But I had someone
who took care of me.
This man...?
I’ve been through
all sorts of trouble...
...but thanks to him,
I managed to stand on my own two feet...
...and now, as you can see,
I work as a detective!
Matière-san, you’re a detective?!
Huh? Did I forget to mention that?
Just like that man once did for me,
I taught Ult how to read and write,
and how to study.
And now, I hope that someday
he finds something he truly wants to do.
Matière-san...
Ult’s never gotten along
too well with me,
but you could be his friend.
You think so?
You two make good buddies!
Then I’ll try
talking to Ult some more.
Let’s go, Achigator!
Lemme in already!
Huh? Is it locked?
Lucario, ya punk!
Didja start gettin’ scared of me comin’ for payback?
Then we’ll just have to force our way in!
Yamirami, break it down!
Wait, you can’t do that!
You still don’t stand a chance yet!
It’s already getting late today,
so how about we do some
Mega Evolution practice tomorrow?
Hey, Lucario! The name’s Ult!
I’m gonna master Mega Evolution in no time,
then come back
and beat you for sure, you hear me?!
Let’s go home, Yamirami!
Let’s go, Achigator.
pOCket Monsters
Episode: Mega Evolution
Yamirami...
Mega Evolve!
Argh! It failed again?!
What’s with this thing?
Does it even work?!
Ours isn’t reacting at all, either.
What should we do?
Master Mayonnaise said that the bond
between Pokémon and trainer was important...
Hmph! These rocks fake or somethin’?
That guy did seem fishy.
Who are you calling fishy?
You got some nerve showin’ up!
Hrm, hrm...
I thought I’d drop in to assess your progress,
only to find you loitering around out here.
Hey, old man Mayonnaise!
How dare you give us these phonies?!
We can’t Mega Evolve at all!
Hey, Ult...
I assume you two lost
to the Yellow Blast.
Huh? How do you know that?
Why, it’s all so clear to me!
I ain’t lost yet!
If I battle Lucario again and win,
then I’ve won!
Still, still intent to push on, are you?
‘Course I am!
I’m serious about this, too!
I wanna be able to Mega Evolve!
Mm-hm, mm-hm...
That passionate ambition is good!
Well then, allow Master Mayonnaise to impart upon you
the secret to Mega Evolution, as befits a master!
Really?!
Then say it, say it!
Mega Evolution is
evolution that transcends evolution!
And transcending evolution
is normally impossible!
To make the impossible possible,
what should you do?
Trainer must know their Pokémon,
and Pokémon must know their trainer.
Their feelings must align,
each believing deeply in one another!
That is the invisible bond
that will guide you to Mega Evolution!
The bond...!
Yeah, but how do we
actually do that?
Combat will demonstrate better
than contemplation.
Why don’t you two
try having a battle?
With this dude?
With Ult?
Fine by me. I’ll show ya
that I’m strongest-er than you.
I’ll accept the battle!
Begin!
Strike without delay!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Dodge it, Achigator!
Rock-type moves are super effective.
A direct hit from one of those...
...is a crushing victory for me!
Yamirami!
Use a Power Gem barrage!
Dodge it!
Perfect timing, Achigator!
You’re such cowards.
As if runnin’ away
is worth cheering about!
Hrm...
If even one of ‘em lands,
you’re KO’ed!
Yamirami, keep up the Power Gems!
Push, push, push ‘em back
with all ya got!
Achigator, stay calm and dodge it!
Move forward!
Keep going!
Close in on Yamirami!
Ya think I’ll take that?!
Power Gem!
Yamirami?
Charm Voice!
Yamirami!
It’s super effective!
Now you’ve really gone and done it...
Yamirami, use Hell Thrust!
What’re you doing, Yamirami?!
No way you’re outta juice already,
are ya?!
One more Hell Thrust!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Yamirami!
Hang in there!
Good work, Achigator!
Your timing was perfect!
I’ll just have to use
my secret weapon.
Shadow Strike!
Can’t dodge an attack
comin’ from behind, can you?
Achigator.
Now, Nitro Charge!
What?!
Run like the wind, Achigator!
Seriously?!
Yamirami!
All right!
Not yet... This ain’t over yet...!
I’ve still got this one!
Come on out!
Fight for me!
How come...?
How come you won’t come out?!
That’s enough!
Victory goes to Roy and Achigator!
We did it, Achigator!
I feel like we’re closer than ever
to Mega Evolving!
Tend to its wounds.
I... I’m the one...
I’m gonna become the strongest trainer...
Ult. Let me ask you something.
Yeah, what?
Do you believe in your Yamirami?
‘Course I do. It’s my Pokémon!
That did not show in your battle.
It was obvious from your first attack.
By blindly ordering it to use Power Gem,
you wore Yamirami out, which dulled its reflexes.
By the end, it couldn’t muster up any power or speed,
even for Hell Thrust, the move it takes such pride in.
If you had noticed
Yamirami’s condition,
you would naturally have adapted
your fighting style.
Enough already!
He don’t play fair, just runnin’ away and all!
Huh?!
That is a valid tactic in battle.
Roy believed in Achigator,
and gave him appropriate orders.
And I believed in Yamirami
when I was battlin’!
The other Monster Ball you carry...
At times, your feelings laid with that
more so than Yamirami.
Thinking that Pokémon would save you
when you most need it...
That surely,
it would come to your aid!
That is simply
laying your burden on another.
And, as we saw,
the Pokémon did not come out.
Shut up!
This stupid jerk...!
Doesn’t matter.
Yamirami’s my Pokémon.
It’s been by my side
since back when I was all alone here.
Through rainy days...
Through hot summers...
Through stormy days...
Through cold winters...
It’s been there for me!
I’m gonna become the strongest trainer
and be able to Mega Evolve Yamirami!
I understand how strongly
you feel about Yamirami.
But what about Yamirami?
Huh?
Who are you to Yamirami?
Have you ever considered
how it feels?
How Yamirami feels?
No idea. We can’t exactly chat.
Mm-hm, mm-hm...
It seems you are blind to Yamirami.
Just like in the Mayo-Maze Palace.
Even though Yamirami noticed the pit,
you ignored it.
Is that true, Yamirami...?
Sensing each other’s feelings,
even without exchanging words...
That is what it means
to share a bond.
Mega Evolution is beyond
your wildest dreams. Give up on it.
What am I supposed to do?!
Ult...
Whoa!
Lucario!
You weren’t watching our battle,
were you...?
Wait up!
It went inside.
Huh? The gate’s...
Is it trying to say
“Come and face me again”?
You up for it, Ult?
Who do you think you’re talkin’ to?!
Let’s do this!
Oh, right... We’ve gotta get through
this maze again, don’t we?
Which way did we go yesterday...?
H-Hey, Yamirami!
Ahh! Hold on!
Ult!
Yeah! Yamirami remembers the way!
So you were payin’ attention
the whole time!
Guidin’ me along
when I was only ever lookin’ down...
Awright! Yamirami!
Let’s go together!
Watch out...
There’s a pit there.
Heh...
Guess you ain’t on the same page!
Yamirami, give it your best...
...jump!
The painting?!
I can’t stand detours, y’see.
Yamirami noticed it before.
So I had to go along with it!
That’s amazing, Ult!
This maze’s taught me that
trainers need to know their Pokémon.
But... I still don’t know enough!
I wanna know even more about you!
And I bet I’ll find out...
If I fight the Yellow Blast—
the Lucario waiting through there!
Yeah.
Trainers and their Pokémon?
Who’re you?!
Oy-ssu! I am Count Oyster!
This one is Shouyu the Shinobi.
No seriously,
who’re you?!
who are you?!
U U U U You & I...
U U U U You're not dreaming...
If nothing else, at least shout! (Woo!) The hex of impatience digs in
Though boors may cloud your vision, turn aside and keep walking
Why was I given this life? (Why?) Fate tests my very body
An evening star alone, closed eyes waiting for the light
Then, everything hiding in the flames...
All the sadness and hatred, blow it away, golden wind!
U U U U You & I... For such is love? Don't give me excuses!
U U U U You're not dreaming... Who are you? Don't get in my way!
Raising the curtains... is the task entrusted to us
Next episode
Right when we wanted
to battle Lucario...
...even more
weird old guys showed up!
Seems like we’ve gotta
beat them to proceed.
But they’re pretty tough opponents!
Ult, let’s combine our powers.
Hmph! Roy, you really think you’ve got
enough power to combine with mine?!
Then let’s go, Yamirami!
Achigator, us too!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Mega Evolution—
Bonds
Our great endeavors...
...ain’t to be missed!
Mega Evolution—Bonds