My name is Liko.
The drive to discover, the drive to learn...
These are the feelings
that set us on our journey.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we, the Rising Voltteccers,
set off for Paldea.
We’re here!
Whoa!
It’s so pretty!
Hey! Run!
Roy! Hogator! Have plenty of fun
and work up a good appetite!
Tonight, we’re having barbecue!
Barbecue? All right!
What about Orio and Molly?
Don’t worry, they’ll be there.
Those two are real hard workers
and deserve the treat.
We’ll go stock up on ingredients.
So don’t wander too far, you two!
Sure thing!
I shall keep an eye on them.
All right, counting on you.
Have a nice trip!
Hey, Gramps,
aren’t you gonna swim with us?
I prefer simply admiring the sea.
Gotcha... Where’s Dot?
I did invite her, but...
What?! The sea?!
You end up all sticky
if you go for a soak,
it stings real bad if you get sunburnt,
and it’s the worst when your skin starts peeling...
Why would I wanna go there?
Yeah, sounds like Dot.
Oh... Nyahoja?
What is it?
A white Digda?
It’s so long!
Umidigda. Garden Eel Pokémon.
Water type.
Though it looks like Digda,
it is an entirely different species of Pokémon.
Huh, really?
Neat!
Ooh!
Look at all the Pokémon!
The sea and the beach are so clean.
Living here must be nice.
Indeed!
And who keeps
that beautiful sea so clean?
‘Tis I!
I spend each day with my partner Yabukuron,
who loves to eat trash,
preserving the beauty
of my beloved sea!
Made me jump...
Wh-Who might you be?
You may call me Swim Trunks Guy!
Swim Trunks...
...Guy...
I would do anything
for my beloved sea!
Ah! Oh, no!
There’s some trash over there!
Let’s go, Yabukuron!
I don’t totally get it,
but he sure loves the sea, huh?
Look, Liko!
How cute!
Ooh, long time no see.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Transform! The Hero of the Ocean, Irukaman
Namiiruka. Dolphin Pokémon.
Water type.
It likes playing with others of its kind
using the water ring on its tail.
It uses ultrasonic waves to sense
the emotions of other living creatures.
Huh?
One of them has different markings...
Somebody, help!
Somebody!
Not good!
What do we do?
When someone’s in trouble...
Over there!
What’s that?!
A yacht? A boat?
No, it’s...
The Hero of the Ocean, Irukaman!
Awesome!
Irukaman is the Hero of the Ocean
who saves those who are in trouble!
Thank you, Irukaman!
Huh? This little one is Irukaman?
This is Irukaman in its Naïve Forme,
and the hero from before
was Irukaman in its Mighty Forme.
When someone’s in trouble,
Irukaman transforms.
Transforms?!
Probably!
Probably?
In truth, no one has actually
seen it transform.
Huh...
By the way... Who are they?
We devote our youth to snapping photos
of the Hero of the Ocean, Irukaman!
They call us... The Snap Kids!
The Snap...
...Kids...
Lemme show you some photos
we’ve taken of Irukaman!
Ooh!
Whoa!
Cool!
With the Scout Pokémon Minezumi
watching out for Irukaman for us,
we’ve been able to
snap all sorts of photos!
Still, isn’t it crazy how this little cutie
can turn into such a cool hero?
Hey, do you have any photos of
Irukaman’s transformation sequence?
We’ve never been able to snap it.
But wouldn’t it be great to see
Irukaman’s transformation sequence?
I don’t mind not seeing it.
If nobody’s seen it before,
I’d bet Irukaman doesn’t want
anyone to see it transform...
Seeing something it doesn’t want seen
wouldn’t feel right.
Irukaman!
You’re the coolest!
Mm-hmm!
Hogator!
Roy!
Irukaman can stretch and contract
its water rings at will,
allowing them to be
used as life preservers!
I-Incredible...
Hogator! I’m sorry for
not keeping an eye on you!
I’m glad you’re both okay!
Thank you, Irukaman!
Somebody!
Propelled by water expelled from its blowhole,
Irukaman can soar through the air!
Thank you, Irukaman!
I lost my bike key!
The bubble lenses on Irukaman’s eyes
give it keen vision!
It can see tens of kilometers away!
Thank you, Irukaman!
It swims at a speed of 50 knots.
Its superstrength allows it to
easily lift a cruise ship with a single fin!
Thank you, Irukaman!
Lovecus scales are worth a pretty penny.
I should rake in a fortune with these!
The deadly Jet Punch!
Irukaman can launch its bubble gloves
like jets of water!
A super-jump powered by
the water from its blowhole!
Followed up with
an Irukaman overhead kick!
Irukaman protects the peace
of the ocean yet again!
Thank you, Irukaman!
Thank you!
Isn’t Irukaman just so cool?
This shot of Irukaman
saving Hogator is awesome!
I can’t take it anymore!
I’ve gotten so many
different photos of Irukaman,
but not a single one
of that crucial moment...
Crucial moment?
The transformation sequence!
Huh? That’s a lost cause.
Nobody’s ever even seen it,
let alone snapped it.
When Irukaman saved Hogator,
the Naïve Forme Irukaman
was right there.
I had the chance!
Since nobody’s seen Irukaman’s transformation
sequence before, it’d be huge if we snapped it!
Well, that goes without saying...
But Irukaman only changes into Mighty Forme
when someone’s in trouble.
That’s it!
Huh?
Someone.
Help.
I hurt my leg.
How’d that sound?
Okay! Okay!
It transforms when someone’s in trouble,
so if we make trouble, we’ll get a chance
to snap that transformation sequence!
Now... Show us your
transformation sequence...
Irukaman!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
“I love seaside Pokémon.”
“You’re making me want to
go to the seaside with my Pokémon.”
“I love the seaside.
Do you like it too, Gurumin?”
What’s so fun about
getting drenched with salty water?
I don’t get it...
Huh?
“Have you heard of the legendary hero
protecting the seas of the world?”
That’s Irukaman, obviously.
Its Mighty Forme is so cool!
“And no, we’re not
talking about Irukaman.”
Huh? Wait, it’s not Irukaman?
A legendary hero
protecting the seas of the world?
Is there someone
like that out there?
Someone.
Help.
Should we really be doing this?
Someone!
Help!
He’s a pretty good actor.
Here it comes!
It’s Irukaman.
Help!
Someone!
Someone, help!
Oh, no! Let’s go, Hogator!
What’s wrong?
Huh?
It couldn’t be...!
What are they?!
Help!
They’re really mad...
We’ve gotta calm them down.
Hogator, use Charm Voice!
Hogator!
There’s no way it could transform
with all those cameras pointed at it...
What should I do?
Of course.
Right!
Nyahoja! Magical Leaf!
What’s going on?!
I can’t see a thing!
What do we do?!
Irukaman?!
Irukaman versus the Gakegani Army!
The showdown of the century commences!
Go for it, Irukaman!
Go for it!
Irukaman uses Jet Punch!
Gakegani’s deadly Scissor Cross
strikes true!
Irukaman’s chest is its weak point!
Huh?!
Irukaman’s in deep trouble now!
A wise Mukuhawk hides its talons,
but bares them when the time is right.
Now, then...
It seems the time has come
for a Forme Change!
Migh... Migh... Migh...
Migh...
Mighty... G!
Migh!
Irukaman!
What should we do?!
What’s that?!
A yacht?
A boat?
No, it’s...
The legendary hero protecting
the seas of the world, Mighty G!
Mighty... G!
Mighty G...
Samehada! Aqua Jet, go!
Good boy, Samehada.
Long time no see, Irukaman.
Huh?! You two know each other?!
Irukaman.
Do that on that,
and that like that, and that’s that.
All he said was “that”...
It understood?!
Everyone!
Cheer for Irukaman! Come on!
Right! Irukaman! Go for it!
You can do it, Irukaman!
Calm those Gakegani down, Irukaman!
Go for it, Irukaman!
You can do it! Irukaman!
Go for it!
Irukaman is taking in
all of our cheers!
Migh!
Th-That’s...!
Irukaman and Mighty G’s
deadly Hero Hug!
Love and peace! Mighty G!
What a sight!
The hugs make
the Gakegani’s rage melt away!
Gakegani-chan... Love and double-peace!
Mighty...
G!
Mighty G’s so cool!
Do you know what makes heroes so cool?
Huh?
It’s...
When you cry out for help,
their big hearts always hear-o!
Huh?
Mighty!
Thank you, Irukaman!
Thank you, Mighty G!
A hero’s heart
needs to be strong too, huh?
Huh? So when you started calling for
Irukaman’s help, you were faking it?!
I really wanted to snap
its transformation sequence...
You can’t do that!
What if there were people who
actually needed rescuing somewhere?!
We’re sorry!
We’ll never try to see
its transformation sequence ever again!
I got to see it...
But... I can’t tell them that.
Let’s keep its transformation sequence a secret.
Just between us.
Gramps?!
What happened?!
I-I just threw out my back...
Are you okay?
I’m fine.
I guess three minutes is the limit
for my Mighty Change these days...
Guess what? Irukaman and Mighty G-san
saved us just a little while ago.
I-Is that so?
Think we’ll see him again?
I know we will!
He’s always watching over us!
Isn’t that right, Gramps?
Ack!
Wherever he might be now,
if we’re ever in trouble, the Hero of the Ocean
is bound to come rescue us!
My secret is safe...
“The legendary hero protecting
the seas of the world, Mighty G.”
He’s not a Pokémon, so who cares?
I got lots of photos of Irukaman
from the Snap Kids!
Ooh!
Isn’t that nice?
Hmm? What is that?
Some strangers rolled in recently
and put that up.
They’re a suspicious bunch,
if you ask me.
A suspicious bunch...?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
Irukaman: Mighty Forme.
The Hero of the Ocean,
whose ancient genes have awakened.
Irukaman (Mighty Forme)
Hero Pokémon
Type: Water
Irukaman (Mighty Forme)
Hero Pokémon
Type: Water
Height
1.8m
Before transforming (Naïve Forme)
By transforming from Naïve Forme,
it gains a certain power.
Weight
97.4kg
But do you know what that power is?
What power does it gain when transforming?
Flight
Superstrength
Jet propulsion
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that live in water!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Whaleoh, Kaiogre,
Numacraw, Kamasujaw, Gekkouga!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
This is Landau. "Rap" is as freeform as water.
Pokémon that live in water
Ordile, Nuoh!
Whaleoh, Kaiogre, nyoh...
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What power does it gain
when transforming?
A: Flight
B: Superstrength
C: Jet propulsion
What power does it gain
when transforming?
A: Flight
B: Superstrength
C: Jet propulsion
The answer is: All of them!
When it awakens its genes,
it powers up dramatically!
It can lift ships with its superstrength,
and even fly using jet propulsion!
But its biggest source of strength
is the sense of justice in its heart!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
You know how some shops
get those huge lines?
I’m not into the waiting in line part, but don’t they
make you wanna know what the buzz is about?
At one such shop, Liko and Roy get targeted by
a mysterious girl who’s after some limited-supply sweets...
I sense a battle brewing...
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters:
A Letter of Challenge From the Explorers
Where have I seen her before...?