pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
That’s the right area.
Start by looking from somewhere with a good view.
Be careful. We don’t know
how the target might react.
First, we need data.
I’m counting on you, Cap, Roy.
Exhilarating adventures
are a personal favorite.
I’m getting psyched!
How about you, Achigator?
Is this...
...the evidence in question?
Let’s follow them, Achigator.
My name is Roy.
I’m a Pokémon Trainer on an adventure
to meet strange Pokémon and solve their mysteries.
And most importantly, to meet up with
the black Rekkuuza I parted ways with a year ago.
But as for the moment...
Dot just contacted me for the first time in ages,
and I’m investigating a sighting
of a Pokémon acting abnormally.
What is it, Cap?
That’s...
Kekking. Lazy Pokémon.
Normal type.
The world’s laziest Pokémon.
It only rolls over and moves
when there is no more grass to eat.
The “world’s laziest Pokémon”
is doing this?
No, it’s just like Dot’s source said.
That stuff...
It could be evidence of Rakurium.
Gotta send her the data.
Roy!
Now that I’ve found you,
your luck is through!
Ult...
Hmph! Thinkin’ you can run from me
is mega-extremely naïve!
Quiet down!
Oh, no! Where’d it go?!
Liss’n up, Roy, Cap!
The black Rekkuuza...
belongs to me!
Wait!
Roy!
You won’t be walkin’ when I’m done with ya!
How dare you sneak ahead of me?!
For cryin’ out loud...
Right, Yamirami?
Right now, I’m investigating
the Kekking that was back there.
Not the black Rekkuuza.
Don’t you lie to me!
There’s mega-no reason
for me or you to care about Kekking!
There actually is.
But if you don’t care,
then don’t come with me.
I’m comin’ with you.
Don’t follow me.
I’m goin’!
No!
I said I’m goin’, so I’m goin’!
Fine, do whatever you want.
Did it find something?
Let’s check it out!
There’s the Kekking.
Good work, Taikaiden.
What are you doing, Yamirami?!
Get back here!
That’s one outrageous way
to say hello.
If ya wanna battle, I’ll take you on!
Don’t get carried away, Ult. That’s...
It’s messed with us,
and we mega-can’t let that slide!
Right, Yamirami?
Cap! Shadow Clones!
Sure is fast for how big it is.
It really is no ordinary Kekking...
What?! Whaddaya mean by that?
We can talk later.
We’ve got to stop it!
Shut yer trap!
I coulda told you that much.
Achigator! Nitro Charge!
Stay just like that, Taikaiden!
Use Electric Ball!
Achigator, you use Flamethrower!
Follow ‘em up, Yamirami!
Power Gem!
This is putting the rest of
the forest Pokémon in danger.
Achigator! Taikaiden!
Keep them all safe for me!
If this is the power of Rakurium...
then back then, we...
Quit complaining
and start battling, Roy!
Ult...
You ain’t planning on getting all
mega-gloomy and runnin’ away, are ya?
No way! Not me!
I’ll wrap this up nice and quick!
You’re up, Lucario!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Mega Evolve!
Lucario, use Metal Claw!
Cap, use Thunder Punch!
Now! Hell Thrust!
Great hit, Yamirami!
Destroyer Beam?!
Wha—?! That was on a whole ‘nother level
from its other attacks!
No doubt about it...
That’s Rakurium!
We can’t let it
keep rampaging like this.
Ult!
I hear ya, Roy! Let’s do this!
Yamirami!
Good work, Yamirami!
Destroyer Beam doesn’t work
on Ghost types.
Okay, we’re up next...
Lucario!
Infight!
Eerie Light!
Now, Cap! Voltteccer!
Huh? Did you say it fired
a pink Destroyer Beam?!
Yeah.
But the forest Pokémon are all fine.
Even Kekking went back to lazing around
after it was knocked out and woke up.
Going off the Index,
that kind of behavior is unimaginable...
That pink mist
was just like back then...
Yeah, what we saw at Rakua.
But how could it be...?
Pagogo and the Six Heroes
should have destroyed all of it.
If this is Rakurium,
we need to do something about it.
Back then, we made a promise
to Mr. Lucius...
Sealing it away isn’t enough!
Please!
I want you to work together
to get rid of the Rakurium!
I know you can do it—
No...
You are the only ones who can do it!
You’re right...
Dot!
It’s snack time!
I-I told you not to
just barge in like that!
What?
But you’re not even streaming!
Well yeah, but still...
Today’s a Mom specialty: Hotcakes!
I’ll look into things from here
and contact you if I figure anything out!
Hello, Roy!
Ms. Blanca sure hasn’t changed.
Even with the Rising Voltteccers gone...
...our adventures aren’t over.
I’ll have to go tell her that.
I know you’re there, Ult.
Hmph. You’re a real buzzkill.
But I couldn’t care less
about you spotting me!
C’mon, you’ve gotta have
some kinda goal of your own, right?
The black Rekkuuza!
Same goal you’ve got, ain’t it?!
Yeah, the same one you’ve got.
So no sneaking ahead of me! Got it?
Guess I’ve got no choice.
Wait up, Rekkuuza!
Roy?! He’s gone!
That... jerk...
He left me behind!
Ult... I had no choice.
I have to tell her.
Similarly,
Pokémon have eighteen types.
And learning the match-ups
between various Pokémon,
including those bearing combinations of two types,
is an important factor in battles.
Terastal is another intriguing topic.
Rather than being
a fixed trait per Pokémon...
Okay, that’s all for today.
Next, everyone gather on the grounds.
Right!
Liko! I’m going on ahead!
Daikenki! Race ya to the grounds!
They’re both so full of energy...
Don’t you think, Masquernya?
We should get going, too.
My second class is battle training.
My name is Liko.
I’m attending Sekiei Academy
in the Kanto Region as a Pokémon Trainer.
The weather’s nice again today.
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Sekiei Academy is a place where trainers
can learn alongside Pokémon.
It’s full of students attending
from all sorts of different regions.
Even though I switched to remote classes
right after enrolling,
I’ve had a year to really
settle into school life.
New students have arrived with the new school term,
making this place livelier than ever.
Over the past year, my dorm roommate Anne’s skills
have been recognized at Sekiei Academy,
and she’s doing great things
on the select team.
Anne’s so cool!
Hey, did you hear the rumor about Principal Cyano
from Blueberry Academy getting in touch with her?
Whoa! She’s Sekiei Academy’s ace!
Next up, Liko!
Coming!
Let’s go, Masquernya!
Let’s have a good match!
Then let the battle begin!
Huh?
Huh? Huh?!
Where’d I leave my toothbrush?
Right there!
It’s in the pen holder.
How’d it end up in there?!
I suppose, maybe... I put it there?
Isn’t it because you always put things down
without thinking, so you forget where you left them?
And you’re doing that
without thinking about it either, Liko.
Huh? Oh...
You think so?
You really weren’t thinking about it...
So, it still... hasn’t come out ever since?
Yeah...
Must be tired out and sleeping, then.
Yeah, you’re right.
Hey... Are you okay?
With what?
Absolutely! I’m fine!
Well, I hope so...
I know!
We’ve got the day off tomorrow, right?
Come train with me!
You too, Masquernya!
Yeah! Okay.
Pagogo...
Yo-ssu! Spinnin’-‘n’-groovin’!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Comin’ in for a min?
It’s everyone’s pal, Gurumin!
By the way, everyone!
Lately, people’ve been been sending me
info saying they’ve seen Pokémon...
...doin’ bizarre stuff and using moves
the Index doesn’t account for!
And Gurumin’s curiosity is piqued!
If you could send me any vids you know of,
I sure would appreciate it...
Plus, of course, I’m seeking info on any and all
sightings of Legendary and rare Pokémon and the like!
She says she’s seeking info, Liko!
Huh, what?
Gurumin, in this vid!
Haven’t you been watching?
Oh... No, I haven’t kept up lately...
I can watch them later.
More importantly,
when do we start training?
Oh, right.
Counting on you, Masquernya!
Let’s do it, Daikenki!
Masquernya, let’s go for it!
Daikenki, you all set?
Good going, Daikenki!
Keep it up, Masquernya!
Hey, Anne...
Huh?
Is it true that Blueberry Academy
got in touch with you?
And how it was the principal himself,
or something...
You heard about that?
Yeah, it’s true, actually.
That’s amazing!
Won’t be long now until you’re
flourishing in the Pokémon League.
You think so?
I sure do!
Yeah...
That’s my dream,
so I’ll give it all I’ve got!
Anne’s moving forward.
She’s strong, tough,
and headed towards her dream...
But I’m just...
Did you hear? There’s been another one...
A wild Pokémon went on a rampage in Hoenn.
Seriously?!
It’ll hit Kanto soon,
don’tcha think? Scary stuff!
And you know what’s causing it, right?
That suave director guy from Exceed
said it in an interview!
Oh, Director Spinel!
That’s right!
It’s that toxic substance produced at Mt. Whatever
a year ago that’s having this effect on the Pokémon.
And those “Rising Voltteccers” people
are the ones behind it all, right?
They’re the worst!
Calling themselves “adventurers”
while they go and screw up the environment!
But the people at the Explorers are gonna fix it,
so big props to them!
Hey, you two!
Don’t run your mouth about stuff
you know nothing about!
Anne?
Anne! Over here!
Liko? But...
Just come on! It’s okay!
Aside from Anne, nobody here knows
I was a member of the Rising Voltteccers...
Or...
...about what happened back then.
Friede!
What are you doing?! Hurry up!
Cap, look after everyone for me.
The events of one year ago...
...are being altered
without me even realizing.
But I’m just...
Found you!
Liko!
Roy?!
To the Skies Once More, Part One
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Guiding Waves Pokémon, Lucario!
Guiding Waves Pokémon
Steel
Lucario
Guiding Waves Pokémon
Fighting
Steel
Steadfast Heart
Force of Will
Lucario
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Guiding Waves Pokémon
Steadfast Heart
Force of Will
Lucario
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials.
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Black patterns have spread
all over its body, right?
Mega Lucario
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Guiding Waves Pokémon
Fighting
Steel
Adaptability
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
They mark places the energies of Guiding Waves
and Mega Evolution mixed together and flowed through!
It uses Guiding Waves
to pick up changes in its surroundings...
...and predict any movements
its foes might make!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Its attack power went way up, too!
Next episode
Roy goes to visit Liko, who is attending
Sekiei Academy, for the first time in ages.
He also has a joyful reunion
with her friend Anne...
...which leads to a Pokémon battle.
He doesn’t have just
Achigator and Taikaiden with him.
Roy has brought a new friend,
Lucario, as well.
While Anne and Roy battle,
Liko disappears, acting somewhat odd.
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
To the Skies Once More, Part Two