The three of us are right in the middle of
our Terastal Course.
Dot challenged Mr. Aoki
at Champuru Gym.
In a big surprise,
Kuwassu evolved into Welcamo!
She may have lost the battle,
but she passed her implementation test.
You did it, Dot!
Next, it’s Roy’s turn.
We’re headed to Fridge Town!
Yep, nice and warm.
We’ll have to climb frosty Mt. Nappé
to get to the Fridge Town Gym,
so we’ve got to be ready
for cold temps!
I can’t stand the cold.
I don’t wanna get anywhere near Mt. Nappé...
Just imagining the snow
is giving me chills!
You kinda...
Kinda what?
...look like Gurumin!
Huh?
You look good! Great, even!
Super Gurumin!
It’s totally you!
E-Easy now...
Sorry...
That’s what happens
when you bundle up too much.
Roy?! You’re not planning on
going like that, are you?!
I wanna ride a sled, make a snowman,
and have a snowball fight!
I’ll work up a real sweat
having all that fun.
So this should be enough.
No way! You’ll catch a cold
right before your implementation test!
You think so?
Definitely!
Wait... Is this gonna be
your first time in the snow, Roy?
Yeah!
Well, I mean, I’ve seen videos before.
It’s white and sparkly and cold, right?
Doesn’t it sound like fun, Hogator?
The wind’s getting colder.
Is it gonna snow?!
I hate this. I wanna go back...
Once we’ve gone through here,
we’ll be at Mt. Nappé.
Let’s go, Hogator!
Snow!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Our First Snow! Ho! Hoga!!
It’s so cold!
Wow! It’s so pretty!
Yeah, snow might be pretty at first...
Then it melts, gets all gooey and soggy,
and is basically the worst.
Huh? I won’t feel cold if I start dancing?
I’m too cold to even think about dancing!
Ah, right... You don’t like the cold,
do you Nyarote?
Wanna get in?
Wait!
Nyarote?
Kachikooru. Ice Chunk Pokémon.
Ice type.
It protects itself by coating its body
with ice made out of frigid -100 degree air.
It fights with Sebie
whenever it meets one.
Sebie?
I wonder what those are like...
Sebie. Ice Fin Pokémon.
Dragon/Ice type.
It lives in forests and craggy areas.
It uses its dorsal fin to cool the inside of
its nest like a refrigerator.
Wow...
More Pokémon!
There aren’t a lot of places to find berries,
so they’re natural gathering spots.
It looks really mad about something!
Wait a sec...
Does it think Hogator’s a Sebie?!
Hogator! You okay?
It’s snowing!
And you’re happy about it?!
It’s not just snowing...
This is a Blizzard!
Nyarote, get in here.
I am freezing!
Somebody stop them!
Tebrim?!
There she goes again,
beating them up then healing them up...
Geez, that was rough...
C’mon, let’s hurry!
It’s still a long way ‘til Fridge Town!
Look!
It’s all frozen over!
Weren’t we supposed to be in a hurry?
It’s really pretty!
That looks like fun!
Ooh, awesome!
That was amazing!
C’mon, Dot! Join us!
Oh, uh, I’m fine...
Don’t be like that!
Hey, wait, wai—!
Nyarote, come out
and play with everyone.
Looking good!
Here goes!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
So cute!
Kumashun. Freezing Pokémon.
Ice type.
If it spatters you with its frosty snot,
you’ll get frostbite.
Whoa...
Mt. Nappé is full of Pokémon
I’ve never even seen before.
W-We’re not here to cause trouble!
Oh no! Sorry, sorry!
Uhh... Wh-What now? What now?!
A Tunbear!
Not good! It’s really mad!
Welcamo! Aqua Break!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Now’s our chance!
Right!
Thanks.
I-I can’t run any more...
Guess this is that Tunbear’s territory.
Let’s all head into that cabin!
We should be fine now.
Let’s get a little rest.
That warmed me right up.
Nyarote... Good job toughing it out
even though you can’t stand the cold.
You really did look like a Sebie!
Playing in the snow was a ton of fun.
This is from when we went to the beach!
We’ve met so many Pokémon...
And it was all so much fun,
wasn’t it, Hogator?
Roy...
Hmm?
It’s still quite a trek to Fridge Town,
so we’d better stay here tonight
and set out again in the morning.
It’s still pretty cold, even in this cabin...
And it’ll only get colder overnight.
We should split up and look for something
we can use as firewood while there’s time.
Let’s meet back here
before it gets dark.
Yeah. And make sure to steer clear of
that Tunbear’s territory.
Got it. Be careful out there.
We don’t have time to
play around right now.
Very nice! Thanks!
Ooh, nice!
See if you can find a bunch more!
Think we oughta head back now?
Hogator?
Hogator!
Wonder where he went...
Snow.
We’ve gotta get back
before it gets dark.
Taikaiden!
Fly up and look around for Hogator!
Hogator!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Hogator!
Hogator... Where did you go?
Hogator?!
I’ve been looking for you!
Huh?
This is the snowman we made.
Does that mean...
...I’ve been going in circles?
Hogator!
Hoga—!
The Tunbear?
I’m back.
Welcome back.
That just leaves Roy.
How far did he go?
I didn’t see him even once.
I wonder if he’s okay...
Hogator!
I had no idea being apart from Hogator
would feel like this...
Hogator’s out there somewhere...
Shivering cold and scared,
just like I am...
Get! Back! On your feet!
Don’t give up, don’t give up! Go for it!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Don’t give up, Hogator! Go for it!
Get! Back!
On your—
Hogator!
Don’t! You! Forget it!
Hogator, don’t give up! Go for it!
Hogator...
Hogator!
What a relief!
Our song’s unbeatable!
A Sebie...
If Kumashun’s here, that means...
Tunbear!
Taikaiden, Hogator... Let’s move!
Ah, man...
Really, Hogator?
A Kachikooru?
Won’t be good
if they start fighting again...
I know!
Ta-daah!
If Hogator can look like Sebie,
then Sebie can look like Hogator, right?
Oh, good...
Hogator turned into a Sebie!
Not good!
Hogator...
It thinks you’re a Kumashun,
doesn’t it?
Hey!
Roy!
Where have you been?!
We’ve been worried!
I had a run-in with the Tunbear.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
‘Cause Hogator
turned into a Kumashun!
Hogator turned into...
...a Kumashun?
So, where’s the firewood?
It’s gonna get really cold overnight!
S-Sorry...
Cuddling up with Hogator
would keep you warm!
Gah...
Hogator! Once we reach Fridge Town,
it’ll be time for our implementation test!
I feel like the two of us can do anything!
Let’s go!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Ice Fin Pokémon, Sebie.
Sebie
Ice Fin Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ice
Sebie
Ice Fin Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Ice
A solitary Pokémon.
Height
0.5m
When two Sebie fight, they decide the winner
using a certain body part.
Weight
17.0kg
But do you know what part that is?
What do they use to decide fights?
Their hand feathers
Their fins
Their tails
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What do they use to decide fights?
A: Their hand feathers
The answer is
A: Their hand feathers.
When they fight, they use the feathers
on the backs of their hands to decide the winner.
Whoever has the biggest
and most colorful ones wins!
Next episode
This is the town of snow
and requiems, Fridge Town!
I hear their live concerts
draw huge crowds!
All right! Implementation test time!
I’m challenging Gym Leader Rhyme!
Look! A concert’s starting!
Huh?! No way! She’s Rhyme?!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Resound, My Soul! The Challenge to Rhyme
Hogator, let’s sing!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Hoga!
Resound, My Soul! The Challenge to Rhyme
We won’t give in! Go for it!