You deserve a little something.
Ooh... Thank you.
How goes it?
I have Lucius’s memoirs,
Ms. Diana’s adventure log...
...and records of all Pokémon
resembling Terapagos in the Paldea Region.
I’ve been trying to
comb through all of it, but...
How’s the ship?
Repairs coming along fine?
Yeah.
Though I’m still only half done.
You’re halfway there already?!
You really are a genius of a mechanic!
Y’know, I’ve been thinking about
a way to give it a boost, too...
A boost?
I dunno just yet if it’s gonna work,
but keep an eye out!
Sure. The Brave Asagi’s in your hands.
Guess Cap’s looking forward
to it being fixed, too.
I’ll do everything I can
to get us airborne again!
Now, then...
I’m heading out for a bit.
You figure something out?
Nope.
Just something
I’ve been wondering about.
I might be able to dig up a clue
to the mysteries of Terapagos.
Oh, but first...
There’s one thing I’d better confirm...
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Eternal Blessing
How ‘bout we... take a breather...?
We’ll be at Orange Academy
once we get through here!
Home stretch! You can do it!
Hey! Liko!
Huh?!
Anne!
Ain’t seen you since school!
Are you guys also heading back
to the academy?
Yeah! Wait, you’re going there too?
Yup! I passed my Basics test!
Huh?
She evolved into Tebrim!
Whoa, Taikaiden too?!
Never seen that Pokémon before!
Did ya catch it, Liko?!
Oh, um... This little one is, uh...
No... more... I give up...
I can’t take another step...
Then how about
we break for snack time?
Yeah!
Anne, why don’t you join us?
You sure?
Awright!
Wow... I never would’ve guessed
that pendant was a Pokémon!
It was quite the surprise.
It’s so cute!
Liko and Terapagos...
You look great together!
Why hide it away?
It’d look great on you!
Flying all around in an airship
on an epic adventure with friends!
Man, I wish I was you!
And we’ve still got a ways to go!
Still?! Where are you headed?
A faraway place,
though we don’t know where it is yet.
This little one wants to go there,
and I want to take it.
That’s why we’re
doing the Terastal course.
And I’m putting
everything I have into it!
Liko... You sure have changed!
You’re way more confident.
Y-You think so?
Must be nice,
traveling together and all.
But I’m Liko’s BFF, y’know!
So, Roy and Dot!
Let’s be friends, too!
You bet!
Yay!
You too, Dot!
Huh?! U-Uh...
Let’s be good buddies, ‘kay?!
Y-Y-Yes, let’s...
I won’t slack off, either!
I’m gonna kick butt in the Pokémon League,
just you wait!
Don’t do that, Kanuchan!
That’s not even iron!
So many new friends!
It’s Friede!
Hey! You all doing well?
Yeah! We’ve almost made it to Table City.
We’re taking a little break right now!
Perfect timing, then.
There’s one thing
I’d like to confirm with you...
When Terapagos resonated
with Laplace and Galarian Fire,
you saw “mysterious sights,” right?
Yeah.
With Lucius?
When that happened...
Did you see a pink haze, too?
Huh?
A haze? I think there was...
Yes, I remember that for sure!
Same thing with Oliva.
I was wrapped in a mysterious pink haze.
Okay, so it wasn’t just me!
Why do you ask?
It might be a clue to solving
the mysteries of Terapagos and Rakua.
I’ll call you back!
Keep up the hard work
in your Terastal course!
What was that about?
Do you think he’s
looking into Terapagos?
I should focus on
what I can do right now, too!
I have to learn all about Terastal!
Liko! Look out!
I’m so sorry! You okay?!
Yeah.
Thank you, Terapagos.
Enhancing your future with your Pokémon.
Leave it in Exceed’s hands.
All right, I’ve worked up my resolve...
Let’s do it, Cap!
I am extremely sorry!
Now, now...
Raise your head, Professor Friede.
Showing your face after all this time
is more than enough.
No, no!
I only got my job here at Exceed because of
your enthusiastic approval of my thesis, Director Crave.
Ah... And what a fascinating thesis it was!
It was brimming with
your love of Pokémon.
But then I left the company
for my own selfish reasons.
I’ve been nothing but trouble for you!
I expected it to happen just how it did.
Huh?
Settling down in a stuffy lab
is just not who you are.
You’ve kept up your research,
haven’t you?
Yes.
I’ve been traveling the world
by airship with my friends,
pursuing the mysteries of Pokémon.
I’m satisfied with my life now.
This is our captain,
Captain Pikachu.
I see...
A Pokémon reveals much
about its trainer.
I myself have kept up Exceed’s research
for the betterment of Pokémon and trainers alike.
Professor Friede,
I believe our aspirations are perfectly aligned.
Seems the dirt on his cap
caught its eye.
I see your Chillaccino
still likes things neat and tidy.
Incidentally, Professor Friede...
There must be a reason you visited us today, yes?
Right...
Please tell me all about
the Eternal Blessing.
I was only on the research team
for a short time,
so I didn’t get to hear much from them.
And because I quit,
I never got to hear anything more.
What makes you so interested in it now?
I’m pursuing the mysteries
of a certain Pokémon.
There could be some connection
between them.
You’re so forthright
when it comes to Pokémon.
It’s just like you.
Director...
I don’t know what it was, either.
It was passed down from higher up,
and managed solely
by an external research team, but...
Higher up?
Much as I hate to admit it...
Even as Director,
there are those I cannot disobey.
That so, huh?
It may not be much help...
...but here’s the ID card
you left with us.
Your security pass should still work.
You’re still in our records.
Th-Thank you so much!
You may as well poke your head into the lab too,
while you’re in the neighborhood.
Sure.
This place hasn’t changed a bit.
A Bachul? Does that mean...?
M-Mr. Friede?!
Hey, been a while.
I was so worried
after you disappeared like that!
How is everything?
Does this mean you’ve finally returned?!
Is this Pikachu your new partner, sir?!
He looks so cute in that cap!
You haven’t changed a bit, either.
I swung by to look something up.
Look something up?
Like in our research data archives?
Good timing, actually.
Could you help me?
I’ll treat you!
You sure have strange taste, sir.
Not sure why you’d be interested
in a concluded project...
There you are!
Huh?
Hey! What’s with this?!
Quit messing around.
No, not that photo...
This one.
The Eternal Blessing...
That seems to be its name.
What does it mean?
I think its proper designation—
It really does look like it...
Huh? Like what?
Pull up the research material.
I want to review all of the data.
Sure. Just a sec.
What is it?
Where did it come from?
If I can figure that out...
That’s weird.
What’s up?
Well... I just got locked out
of the database all of a sudden!
Maybe it’s a server error?
Should we try again later?
Something smells fishy here...
Sir?
It’d be quicker to see it for myself.
Where is it now?
Um... It should be in
the underground vault.
Got it. I can handle the rest on my own.
Huh? Let me escort you!
There’s no one else down there...
Nah, no need.
Thanks!
Keep up your research!
He didn’t have to run...
He hasn’t changed a bit, either.
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
It’s pitch black down here.
Thanks, Cap!
Through here, huh?
Huh?!
Wasn’t this place
supposed to be empty?!
Um... Mind if we head on in?
Hey, hold on now!
No choice... Let’s do this, Cap!
Shadow Clones!
Launch a flurry of
Thunder Punches!
Wasn’t this project already
over and done with?!
What’s with the huge guard detail?!
Is that it?
Oh, no... Have we been spotted?
Wait, Cap!
That’s—!
Guess I owe Director Crave an apology...
Let’s hurry!
It’s full of junk...
What is it, Cap?
What’s this?
“The Eternal Blessing”...
“Rakurium”?
I struck out after coming all this way?
Wait! I’m not trespassing!
Guess that’s not gonna gonna cut it.
Lizardon!
Cap! Break through with a Voltteccer!
Stop!
That way!
Right!
That should be far enough...
You showed some real grit too, Cap!
But... that “Eternal Blessing”...
Or rather, the Rakurium...
If it was that well-guarded,
it must be important somehow.
Did someone else get to it first?
If Director Crave took it,
he wouldn’t have just handed me my keycard...
But...
Who, then?
Thanks for today, Liko!
It was fun!
No, I should be thanking you.
I’m glad Nyarote
and others had fun, too.
You know, Liko...
I was kinda nervous
about coming to Paldea.
I’d never been outside Kanto.
“Can I really handle this?”, y’know.
I see...
I was nervous
when I came to Sekiei Academy, too.
Just how it goes!
Everyone is at first.
But with Nyarote...
Well, she was Nyahoja
back then, but still...
With her by my side,
I could step forward.
Yeah, same with me.
When I got here, I looked at
Futachimaru and Sand and thought...
“I’m not scared when they’re with me!
“They can take me anywhere!”
“Take you”?
It’s thanks to them
that I’ve made it this far.
I... I decided that I’d take
Terapagos to Rakua, but...
What if Terapagos is the one
trying to take us to Rakua?
Liko! I can see it!
Terapagos!
Let’s go together!
We made it!
We’re back, Orange Academy!
I have brought him.
Amethio...
How long has it been
since we last met like this?
I called you here for but one reason.
Let me hear of your resolve.
My resolve...
For the sake of our eminent prosperity...
We must have the Eternal Blessings...
The Rakurium...
More Rakurium.
I am, thus, awaiting the true awakening
of the key—Terapagos.
Then...
Once Terapagos awakens...
You must seize it.
Amethio...
Fulfill your duty as heir of my blood.
It is an honor to be your grandson.
I shall not fail to serve you...
Grandfather.
You performed excellently.
To hear your resolve, Master Amethio...
Master Gibeon was most pleased as well, no doubt.
I am nothing like my father.
I shall take up my grandfather’s will.
I expect great things from you,
Master Amethio.
I will seek further power
to accomplish my mission.
Will you accompany me, Soublades?
Has something happened?
Spinel is on the move.
He’s heading somewhere
in a car by himself.
I thought so...
Should we pursue?
We might still—
No, don’t chase him too far.
You’ve done well.
Surveilling him was well worth it.
He’s plotting something yet again.
I may have fallen short
with the black Rekkuuza,
but this time...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Silencing Pokémon, Tebrim.
Tebrim
Silencing Pokémon
Type: Psychic
Tebrim
Silencing Pokémon
Type: Psychic
Tebrim picks up strong emotions
as loud noises,
Height
0.6m
so she uses a certain method
to try and reclaim silence.
Weight
4.8kg
But do you know what that method is?
How does she reclaim silence?
She covers her ears
She gets violent
She runs away
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
How does she reclaim silence?
B: She gets violent
The answer is B: She gets violent!
When she finds someone
holding strong emotions,
she uses her pigtails
to dish out powerful punches...
...knocking them unconscious
to silence them!
Next episode
We’re back, Orange Academy!
I wonder what we’ll be doing next
on our Terastal course!
Principal Clavel says
he had an interesting idea!
Indeed!
I have invited some illustrious guests,
and I wish for everyone to have “dazzling” battles!
Illustrious guests?
Who could they be?
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters.
Showdown! The Paldea Elite Four
The Elite Four?!
Make sure to watch!