The three of us are taking
a Terastal Course in the Paldea Region!
Roy and I have managed to pass
our basics tests.
Now, it’s finally Dot’s turn.
We’re on our way to
our next destination: Hakkou City!
Te! Te! Terastal!
Sparkling, glimmering Terastal!
He’s in a good mood, huh?
Passing his basics test must be
a real weight off his shoulders.
He’s really taking it easy.
D-Don’t worry!
Even I was able to pass!
It should be no sweat for you!
Err... You don’t have to
fuss so much...
A new Gurumin video!
I scheduled that one in advance.
I made some videos ahead of time;
before the Terastal Course.
Um... Would any of them happen to
have been filmed... while out and about?
Gurumin doesn’t film
“out and about.”
Well...
Guess maybe I could, someday...
Really?!
Hey!
Huh?
I can see it!
Hakkou City!
So, it’s finally time...
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Dot and Gurumin
How about we go shopping first,
then do that after? Sound good?
Over there! It was over there!
This place is just as awesome
every single time!
Look, Nyarote! It’s a Nyahoja!
Doesn’t that take you back?
Ah, so you made it to Hakkou City.
Yeah, we just got here.
You should swing by the dock!
You can bed down here
while you’re in town.
Thanks.
Dot!
I got some Tamantu-la-Torte
from my part-time job!
Y-You didn’t have to...
See ya.
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Nanjamo-neesan...
Hakkou City’s specialty...
Wasabi sauce!
That spicy flavor is so addictive!
It’s Nanjamo!
She’s so cute!
Nanjamo-san’s super popular!
Think we can see her
before the basics test?
She’s a busy person,
she doesn’t have that kind of time.
Heya!
Been a long brillian-time, ya read me,
Gurumin-shi sans the suit?
Looks like...
...she does have the time.
Nanjamo-neesan?!
What are you doing here?!
Whatcha mean?
The one who showed ‘em this dock
in the first place was yours truly.
Well, that’s the gist of it.
Still... You don’t live here
or anything.
Don’t be so stuffy, no-no!
Having somewhere to kick back is a must
for a streamer who shows their face.
Anyway... Eat up, kids!
These oughta look familiar:
Tamantu-la-Torte!
Let’s dig in!
Yeah... Still just as good.
Is the course going well?
Yeah, I’m hanging in there.
It’s going great!
Good to hear.
So, Dot’s gonna face Nanjamo next.
Oh! Gurumin-shi sans the suit!
Before your basics test,
could you do me an itty bitty favor?
Huh?
What’s this about?
Gurumin-shi sans the suit!
My basics tests are shown on special
Whozat TV livestreams!
Meanin’, meanin’...
Today, we’re gonna rehearse for it!
Huh?! You’re gonna stream it?!
C-Cameras...
This may be rehearsal, but I want you
battlin’ it up like it’s the real deal!
But, but! I can’t have you
goin’ up against me today...
And so, I’ll have one of your IRL pals
step in as your opponent!
Leave it to me!
IRL pal rep! Yay!
Leave it to those two
to get carried away.
They’re in high spirits.
Well, guess we’re about to find out
how much Roy has improved, too.
Wellzen...
Let’s get to battlin’ it up already!
I’m not streaming today,
but for the real deal, the whole world’s eyes
will be on you, Gurumin-shi sans the suit!
Dot’s acting a bit odd...
You’ve got this, Dot!
Well then, well then...
Let the battlin’ it up begin!
Go! Hogator!
Let’s do it, Kuwassu!
Nitro Charge!
Kuwassu!
Then we’ll use—
Cameras...
Now!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
We did it!
Sorry, Kuwassu...
Dot’s not acting like her usual self...
Oh my, my...
Gurumin-shi sans the suit,
what’s wrong?
Um... With all those cameras
pointing at me...
My mind just kinda went blank...
The cameras?
But you stream as Gurumin
all the time...
Oh, dear...
Belly-ve I read ya.
Did you get stage fright
‘cause you were sans suit on camera?
Dot...
Don’t worry!
I’ve got some great advice for you!
Influencers and Terastallizers
both need the same skill...
They gotta glitz it up!
Glitz it up? By Terastallizing?
How come?
You gotta Terastallize gorgeously,
and put on a good show
for everyone watching!
Glitz! Glitz!
If you Electroweb their eyes,
you’ll be on your way to
battlin’ it up and hypin’ it up!
That so?
You know,
she might have something there.
But if I’m not Gurumin, how am I
supposed to have a “glitzy” battle?
No, no! Don’t you fret,
Gurumin-shi sans the suit!
‘Cause I, Nanjamo...
...will zap ya with
just the spark of inspiration you need!
It’s a good thing
Nanjamo-san’s so nice.
Yeah...
I’ll make an exception
for your basics test...
...and let you take it
as Gurumin-shi!
If we collab, my views are bound to
rise like a Shibirudon going upriver!
Though she wasn’t exactly
doing it for her...
But... Do you think
Dot’s okay with this?
What do you mean?
How should I put it?
Gurumin isn’t Dot...
Like... there’s nobody inside Gurumin?
That’s not quite what I mean.
A Gurumin livestream?!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
Today’s my first livestream in a while!
Hey, look!
Right off the bat,
I’ve got a big, big, big announcement!
There’s something
I’m gonna be trying soon!
Wait, does this mean...?
She’s going to announce
that she’s taking the test as Gurumin?!
And that thing is...
That thing is...
Is...
...coming up soon!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Taste good?
Time for a spotlight on churros from
“Smooch-A-Churro!”, everyone’s fave!
Gurumin looks like
she’s having a ton of fun!
She did say she could try filming
while out and about, but this is...
Be sure to try ‘em
if you’re ever in Hakkou City!
Right, Kuwassu?!
Kuwassu...
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Looking good, Kanuchan!
So cute!
A streamer?
What’s going on?
Who is that?!
Ooh, it’s Gurumin!
Yay! Take all the photos you want!
Thank you! You’re all amazing!
Yay!
Well, I did what I had to do.
Now, how’s the response looking?
Good. Seems like it was a hit.
Now I know I can
glitz it up during the test...
Kuwassu? What is it?
Dot!
You looked really fired up!
My viewers seem to like me
being out and about, too.
Yeah. It looked a lot of fun.
The cameras didn’t bother me
even a little!
I really just... feel stronger
when I’m Gurumin!
Hey, Dot... The “something” that
Gurumin almost talked about before...
It’s gotta be...
...that you’re taking the Terastal Course
basics test as Gurumin, right?
Yeah. I’ve got Nanjamo-neesan’s
permission and everything.
I see...
Is that not okay?
Huh? No, I think it’s fine...
I really do, but...
I was wondering if you’re really okay with it?
What do you mean?
I got the feeling
you were forcing yourself.
Streaming out and about
as Gurumin all of a sudden,
and making yourself act
extra cheerful...
Huh? Was she?
I-I wasn’t... forcing anything...
Kuwassu? What are you doing?
Stop it, Kuwassu!
Kuwassu, do you also think
Dot’s been acting odd?
Hey, Dot... Are you absolutely sure
about taking the test as—?
It’s fine!
I made up my mind.
I’m taking the test as Gurumin.
What’s the big issue?!
Such a pain...
Kanuchan?!
Burorom. Single-Cylinder Pokémon.
Steel/Poison type.
It is said to have been born when an unknown
Poison Pokémon entered an engine dumped at a scrapyard.
Burorom...
It seems sort of angry.
We’ve gotta save her!
Hogator, use Flamethrower!
Kanuchan, return!
Gurumin...!
It took Gurumin!
Oh no!
Where did it go?
Over there!
It’s still angry...
But we have to get Gurumin back...
What are those kids doing?
Isn’t that a Burorom?
Is something happening?
What’s that?
What? What’s that?
What is this?
What?
What’s this?
Kuwassu?!
Kuwassu!
Kuwassu... But...
I can’t battle out here...
We have to help her!
Yeah.
Hogator!
Let me do this.
Yeah.
Let’s go, Kuwassu!
Water Gun!
I need to deal with those
rapid movements somehow...
But how?
Gotta focus!
Okay.
Fire off Water Gun over and over!
No good! It’s just gonna
keep dodging Water Gun...
No, I’m sure Dot has a plan!
Keep it up! Water Gun!
Now! Kuwassu, use Kick Down!
All right!
She used Water Gun to lure it closer!
Finish it! Water Gun!
Yes!
Huh?
They... became friends?
Amazing!
Who is that girl?!
She was great!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
My, what a fiery display
of battlin’ it up!
Nanjamo-neesan...
Whoa!
It’s Nanjamo!
Didja all get the image of her battlin’ it up
burned into your brain-folders?!
Cause I have big, big, big news!
This quiet and intelligent girl...
...is a trainer set to face me
as part of her Terastal Course!
Huh?!
For real?
You can do it!
Her basics test will be livestreamed
exclusively on Whozat TV at a later date!
I got high hopes, Dot-shi!
“Dot-shi”?
Electrowebbing your eyes!
The Electrical Streamer!
Whozat? This was Nanjamo!
See ya!
Oh right, Gurumin!
Huh? Where’d it go?
No rips anywhere?
Yeah, looks fine.
What a relief...
Liko, Roy...
Thank you for grabbing that.
Ah, sure thing...
Um... I’m sorry for
yelling at you earlier.
Huh?
When I was battling with Kuwassu,
The cameras stopped
bothering me entirely.
That was the first time
Nanjamo-neesan called me Dot-shi.
Maybe I’ve earned
a bit of respect from her.
I’ll be taking my test as Dot.
I’m counting on you, Kuwassu.
Facing Gurumin-shi would’ve been
more popular and more hype,
but stuff like this
is fun now and again.
Don’t hold anything back,
Dot-shi!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar.
Today, let’s take a look at
the Single-Cylinder Pokémon, Burorom.
Burorom
Single-Cylinder Pokémon
Type: Steel/Poison
Burorom
Single-Cylinder Pokémon
Type: Steel/Poison
Burorom is a Pokémon that
clings to rocks in order to move.
Height
1.0m
Weight
35.0kg
But what exactly does Burorom
use those rocks for?
What does Burorom use its rocks for?
An energy source
Wheels to move with
Protective armor
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does Burorom use its rocks for?
A: An energy source
The answer is A: An energy source!
Burorom can convert
the rock’s matter into energy.
When the rocks start getting small,
it swaps them out for new ones.
Next episode
It’s finally time to battle Nanjamo-neesan...
I’m all nervous...
Huh? Why are you dancing, Kuwassu?
Hey, hey!
Boogie-woogie and razzle-dazzle, yay!
Roy and Hogator, too?!
Yo, yo!
Today we’re gonna hit the rhythm!
Liko and Nyarote, too?
What’s got into you?!
Yay, yay! And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Glitz It Up, Terastal!
Dance Dance Kuwassu!!
Hey!