Hmm?
“The Rising Voltteccers Save The Day”?
“Another Honor to
the Rising Voltteccers’ Name”?
What is all this?
The Rising Voltteccers
have been out and about?
Yeah...
Seems to be making the rounds
on some online news sites.
We’ve been relaxing, so who could it be...?
That does look like
the Brave Asagi... kinda...
The Rising Voltteccers is us!
I ain’t likin’ all this about fakers showin’ up!
But it’s odd...
Judging by the articles, they’ve been helping
people in trouble, and treating injured wild Pokémon...
They’re... nice?
They’re good guys...?
Good, bad, whatever!
Dunno what their game is,
but I’ll smack some sense into those fakers!
It’s not like we know
that’s what they are yet...
But it is curious. For now,
what say we go and try to meet them?
Yeah.
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
The Fake Rising Voltteccers Appear?!
Oh! If you’re looking for
the Rising Voltteccers,
I hear they cleaned up
all the trash in the park!
The Rising Voltteccers...
I heard they helped
find a lost Pokémon!
They’re not here...
They did say that
they went in this direction...
And the Brave Asagi sighting
came from around here, too.
Whatever the case,
just how far ahead did Ult even go...?
He was so eager, going all
“I’m gonna be the one who finds ‘em first!”
He’ll just have gotten himself lost,
and eventually wind up...
And speak of the devil...
So you did get lost.
Found you, Fake Rising Voltteccers!
Hold on! We’re the real ones!
Real ones?
Gimme some proof then!
Proof?
Come to think of it,
that’s a tough one.
How do I know you’re not a fake Ult?
Huh?! Obviously I’m the bona fide,
one-of-a-kind Almighty Ult!
Then the same goes for us!
Nuh-uh! You’re suspicious!
Hey...
Over there!
The Brave Asagi!
It really is our ship...
What do we do?
Wait and see what happens?
What good’s that gonna do?!
Let’s go!
Hold on!
We don’t know what we’re up against.
Let’s approach cautiously.
Wait...
Is that...?
What is all this?
It’s tiny!
A van...?
What’s going on?
Did you need something from...?
All of you...
Could you really be...?!
We’re back!
We got loads!
It’s Roy!
Dearie Liko!
Ms. Dot!
It’s the Rising Voltteccers!
We’re your fans!
Huh?!
Fans?!
Please let me shake your hand!
Please sign these!
Lemme see your Mega Ring!
So cute!
Erm... Uh, what exactly is going on—?
Hold up!
You ain’t got a me in there?!
Oh no, we do!
That’s Yamirami, ain’t it?!
I really like you, Roy!
‘Cause you’re so super cool!
Cool...?
Ever since our son saw you on the news,
he’s been a big fan of the Rising Voltteccers!
Huh?! But it was Mighty G
that saved everyone, wasn’t it?
All my friends like Mighty G,
but I know the truth!
The Rising Voltteccers
are the real heroes!
You just gotta be! Right?
W-Well, I dunno, are we...?
Our boy tells us he wants to go adventuring,
just like Roy and his friends.
So Liko made me all this!
May dis!
Huh?
Tee-hee! He means me!
And now our whole family
is crazy for the Rising Voltteccers!
All of us are passionately...
...cheering you on!
Then, that means this...
Dot did that for me!
Huh?
I refurbished a van we weren’t using
to look like the Brave Asagi!
Can’t fly, though!
So our family hopped on board,
and now we’re traveling, see!
Yeah! Feeling like
we’re the Rising Voltteccers!
Liko! You’re so cute!
The cutest the whole world over!
So basically, they’re cosplayers...
I never expected
they’d be fans of ours...
Hey! Let’s have a battle!
Huh? A battle?
I wanna fight the Rising Voltteccers!
Good idea! While we have you!
Could we have a battle,
to commemorate meeting you?
A battle sounds great!
I’ll give ya a bout
with my strongest Yamirami!
We’ll take you on!
Hurray!
Yay!
Well, if it’s for commemoration...
All right... Let’s go, Beanie!
And us, too!
Here!
Chuu-cha!
Rai-o!
Papa and Mama use Raichu, huh?
They’ve even got a Pichu!
The battle’s a 4v4!
Meaning whoever defeats
the entire other side wins!
And no holding back, okay?
Yeah, for sure!
Beanie! Wild Volt!
He’s fast,
but I can predict his trajectory!
Masquernya!
Intercept with Magical Leaf!
That’s Chuu-cha’s Cat Rattler.
Masquernya!
Good going!
You’re wide open!
Yamirami! Shadow Strike!
Rai-o! 100,000 Volts!
So bright!
He got rid of the shadows...!
Those Raichu are strong!
Yeah, they’ve been trained well.
Beanie! Next, Wild Bolt on Wanival!
Avoid it with dance steps, Wanival!
Nice catch! Retry!
Dodge it, Loudbone!
Nice pass! Retry!
Beanie! Go, go!
I can’t predict
where it’ll come from...
What an incredible combo.
Let’s keep calm
and look for our chance!
If we can’t predict
how Pikachu’s gonna be movin’...
...then let’s take out
the Raichu first!
Yamirami! First up’s that one!
Papa’s in danger!
Beanie, use Thunder!
What?!
Wanival! Protect everyone
with a rotating Aqua Cutter!
What a brilliant block!
Awesome! So cool!
That’s the Rising Voltteccers for you!
Now they’ve started praising us...
Kinda throws me off my game.
Let’s use this momentum!
Wave Tackle!
Hey!
What’re you playing at, Wanival?!
It paralyzed him?!
We can’t ignore that Pichu either!
Isn’t this fun, Beanie?
We’ll keep going! Wild Volt!
And we’ll support you!
Chuu-cha!
Rai-o!
I’ll make an opening!
Then it’s up to you!
Wanival! Head for that Raichu!
I won’t let you!
Beanie, use Iron Tail!
Whoa!
I’ll come help you now!
Chuu-cha!
Loudbone! Charm Voice!
Wanival!
Change your target to Pikachu!
That Pichu again...!
Yamirami! Eerie Light!
Heh! Go take a nap.
Thanks, Ult!
Wanival! Wave Tackle!
Rai-o! 100,000 Volts!
Beanie!
That was awesome.
You two really tried your hardest!
You were very cool, son!
Thank you!
Mama, it seems like the kids
tuckered themselves out playing.
Which means that, starting now,
this is our time, Papa.
Let’s enjoy this battle...
...to the fullest!
Mega Rings?!
Chuu-cha!
Rai-o!
Mega Evolve!
The Raichu... Mega Evolved?!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
Mega Raichu...
...X!
...Y!
They’re here!
Th-They’re mega-cool, ain’t they?!
Raichu Mega Evolving...
I’ve never seen that before...
...but you’re down to
battle ‘em, right, Loudbone?!
Let’s keep going! Masquernya!
Wanival! Kick Down!
Follow it up, Yamirami!
Use Hell Thrust!
Send Thunder crashing down!
What’s up with the way it moves...?
I can’t predict that!
Time to hit you hard!
Wild Volt!
Loudbone! Stomping Tantrum!
No way...
When did that happen...?
Wanival, you fought well!
Take a break, Yamirami!
So cool!
An attack as fast as lightning!
Now, it’s 2v2! The score’s even!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
EM Levitation!
Rai-o, leap on!
They can fly?!
But Magical Leaf will still...
Iron Tail!
Plus, Thunder!
It’s hard to predict
that Thunder’s trajectory...
Their ability to fly is an issue, too.
Which should we aim for first...?
Maybe... Mega Raichu Y...
Liko! Roy! I have a plan!
Good going! You’re strong!
Thanks, Dot!
I bet that’ll work!
Let’s give it a try!
Loudbone!
Aim a Flare Song right between them!
Iron Tail!
Masquernya! Lightning Speed!
Show them some Thunder!
His tail?! What?
She tangled up his tail
when they passed by...?!
The plan worked!
From his previous attacks,
I worked out that Mega Raichu Y uses his tail
to amplify the electricity from his head.
Papa, I’m coming!
Chuu-cha!
You leave me no choice!
Use 100,000 Volts from your cheeks!
Counter with Magical Leaf!
You did it, Masquernya!
You won’t beat me that easily!
Chuu-cha, move!
Rargh... You sneaky little...!
Masquernya!
Get beside Loudbone!
Oh my, you’re giving me
a single target!
Take them down with Wild Volt!
Take the attack, Loudbone!
Masquernya,
you hide behind Loudbone!
Dig in your heels!
That’s not good!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
We did it!
Thanks for trusting Loudbone
to come through!
Sure! I had total faith
that you’d stop it!
This’s the Loudbone that stopped
Rekkuuza’s Draconic Masterstroke, after all!
Our combo’s the strongest there is!
That was the best!
You’re so strong,
Rising Voltteccers!
Thanks for battling us!
Yeah! We got to have a great battle!
We enjoyed ourselves, too!
Those Raichu were strong foes...
Just who are you?
Mama and Papa
used to be Elite Trainers!
In our much younger days.
We even went and challenged
the Pokémon League...
Your Pikachu’s got potential, too.
Might even be like Cap someday.
All right!
I’m so glad we got to meet
the Rising Voltteccers!
Chances like this are so very rare!
Oh...
What brought all of you here, anyway?
Actually, the idea that you guys are the Rising Voltteccers
seems to be making the rounds.
We found out
by looking at online news.
They thought we were the real thing?!
I had no idea.
I’m not terribly familiar with the net...
We’ve caused you
a whole mess of trouble then, haven’t we?
We’re sorry!
O-Oh, no, it’s not...
Regardless of how much we adore you,
we can’t have people making that mistake!
Do we have to stop
playing pretend Rising Voltteccers?
Don’t stop!
After all...
You’re cheering us on!
It makes us happy!
Yup! You ain’t bad guys or nothin’!
After all, it was your good deeds
making the rounds!
Everyone...!
Go and have plenty of adventures!
We’ll be cheering you on, too!
Okay!
I’ll have loads of amazing adventures!
Just like the Rising Voltteccers do!
Let’s set off!
Right-o!
See ya!
Kinda puts a smile on your face,
doesn’t it?
Just the thought that your adventures
ignited the spirit of adventure in someone else.
Yeah! So we’ve got to do
everything we can, too!
We can’t just stand around
doing nothing!
Awright!
Let’s get back to the ship and set off!
Hey, Cap! We’re setting off!
Huh...? Cap?
Weren’t you just outside?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Raichu!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Raichu
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Mouse Pokémon
Electric
Static
Raichu is a Pokémon
with many different forms,
but which of these is
a form that has yet to be found?
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
Alolan Raichu
Mega Raichu X
Kyodaimax Raichu
C: Kyodaimax Raichu!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
If people ever did find one,
you’d wanna go see it for sure, right?
Looks like Alolan Raichu go surfing!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
You’d wanna surf with one someday
if you could, right?
Next episode
Ooh, seems like you guys’re in a good mood.
Somethin’ good happen?
Next episode
Why’d ya clam up all of a sudden?!
Yer eyes are mega-dartin’
all over the place.
Next episode
Eh, whatever!
So, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Secret Metamon Rhapsody
Uh... Wh—?
Huh?! Metamon?!