We’ve finished our
Terastal course Basics tests!
Now we just need to get our reports ready,
and return to Orange Academy!
And so...
We headed into the forest to search for
the one not of this world;
a mysterious Pokémon
Roy had heard about from a trainer he met.
Hey! One not of this world!
If you’re there, come on out!
You think that Pokémon really exists?
It’s gotta! Don’t you wanna meet
the one not of this world, Dot?
Well... If I could get it on camera,
it’d be great material for Gurumin...
You wanna see it too, right, Liko?
Yeah. If it’s out there,
I’d like to see it.
I think I’d be able to
write a great report on it!
Are you okay?
The forest’s getting thicker and thicker...
Feels like anything could pop out...
Is something wrong, Mibrim?
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Mibrim and the One Not Of This World
Something’s coming...
P-People?
What a relief...
Did we get away from it?
We’re safe...
Huh?
“Get away from it”?
Thank you.
Um... What happened to you?
Huh?! At Orange Academy?
Yes. We came to Paldea
to take the Terastal course.
Hey, same for us!
You’re taking it, too?
On the way to our course gyms,
we got lost in this forest.
We’ve had a rough time.
A rough time...?
As we were heading through the forest,
we got surrounded by fog
all of a sudden,
and we couldn’t tell
where we were going...
Before we knew it, we wound up at a river bank.
There was this tall tree there,
and it had a ghostly face...
It was a really creepy place!
We couldn’t go any farther,
so we decided to turn back
for the time being...
But then the strap on my bag broke.
I cut off some vines hanging from the tree,
and managed to fix it up.
Then, just when
we were about to leave...
That’s when it appeared!
A mysterious Pokémon?
Yeah... One we’ve never seen before.
It started flying at us
the moment it saw us...
We battled it to try to drive it off,
but we didn’t stand a chance...
Running was our only option.
I’ve never met a Pokémon
so vicious before.
It was scary...
Like something out of this world!
Out of this world?
You think it’s...?
The one not of this world.
Yeah.
We’re looking for that Pokémon!
Huh?!
But why?
We figured we could find it
to write a report on it.
The fact that there are witnesses
adds some credibility.
And it could still be close by!
Are you serious?!
That’s a really bad idea!
It’ll attack you!
If we all go in, it’ll be just fine!
We’re not joking around here!
Thanks for the first aid!
Goodbye!
They left...
Seems like the one not of this world
is crazier than we thought...
But if it’s that amazing,
I wanna meet it even more!
Somewhere deep in the forest...
Fog rolled in!
Just like what they told us.
Feels like we’re getting close!
Mankey!
Are they... mad at something?
Mankey are generally short-tempered...
But this isn’t normal.
Are you okay, Mibrim?
What was that shout?!
Is that it?
The one not of this world?!
Konoyozaru. Rage Monkey Pokémon.
Fighting/Ghost type.
When the force of its rage
exceeded its critical point,
it gained power unconstrained
by the limits of flesh.
Konoyozaru...
Power unconstrained by flesh...
I get it! So that’s why it’s
“not of this world”!
It vanished!
Up there!
This isn’t looking good for us.
We better run!
Yeah!
Got it!
Liko, Dot... Think you can hold it still?
Let’s give it a try.
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
Nyarote, give me a big Magical Leaf!
Now! Nitro Charge!
Yes! Now’s our chance!
Did we manage to get away?
Looks like it.
That Konoyozaru was something else!
Huh? Wait...
It’s a river!
A tree with a ghostly face!
Is this the place
those three were talking about?
Huh? What’s that it’s holding?
Is it... a vine?
That reminds me...
She mentioned using a vine
to fix one of her bag straps!
They’re really mad...
What if this place
is the Mankey’s den...
...and that tree is
important to them somehow?
She cut the vine,
which was part of that tree...
And that’s why they’re so mad?
If that’s the case...
There’s also three of us...
...and they had similar-looking
Pokémon to ours, right?
So the Mankey think
we’re the culprits...
Listen, please!
We didn’t cut that vine!
Here they come!
We have to fight!
Kuwassu, use Aqua Break!
Charm Voice!
Lightning Speed!
Terapagos!
Thank you, Mibrim!
Konoyozaru!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
The Mankey and Okorizaru
cleared a path?!
It’s like they’re scared of
the Konoyozaru...
Or showing it respect, maybe.
Anger that went beyond
the limits of flesh...
Maybe this Konoyozaru is
like a guardian deity to the Mankey.
Thank you, everyone!
Hogator, use Stomping Tantrum!
Aqua Break!
Magical Leaf!
Attacking one by one won’t work.
Let’s surround it and attack all at once!
Nyarote!
Kuwassu!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Water Gun!
It’s so strong...
Amazing...
You’re amazing, Konoyozaru!
Mibrim, are you okay?
If it hurts, you can
go back in your ball.
Huh?
Ah! Wait!
Nyarote, dodge it!
Huh? Now they started fighting...
So it’s not their guardian deity, then?
Mibrim!
Something across the river?
Is that...
a pile of berries over there?
Those probably belong
to the Mankey, right?
Over there!
I get it now... The vine she cut was probably
connected to that tree over there.
The Mankey used it like a rope
to cross the river and reach their food storage.
So they got mad because they couldn’t reach their food?
Yeah. The Mankey, the Okorizaru...
and probably the Konoyozaru, too.
Yeah, that’d make me mad for sure!
I know!
In that case, don’t we just have to fix it
so they can cross the river again?
Yeah!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Think this is long enough?
No way.
It’s gotta be a whole lot longer.
This should work...
These ones are too thin...
Heated by the blazing sun
The concrete is scorching hot
Thank you!
Just leave them there.
With my performance sneakers
I fly through the air like an airship
That time we joked together
Both singing that song of our dreams
I still have it in my pocket
Now, sing out! To the ends of the stars
All the happiness, all the sadness
Counting on you, Taikaiden!
of the days I cried thousands of times
Now, feel proud! At the end of the rainbow
I have so much I want to say (hello, hello)
Hey! Mankey!
Now you can get over here again!
The clock strikes (hello, hello)
I stop the video, (hello, hello)
brush my teeth, (hello, hello)
and fall asleep (hello, hello)
Are you doing well? (hello, hello)
I bet you are well! (hello, hello)
I can go on
with your song!
Let’s head over there, too.
Yeah.
Now, see the dream to its conclusion!
They look so happy!
I know, someday, my ever-treasured
You picked up on the fact that
the Mankey wanted to cross the river...
rainbow flower will bloom
It’s all thanks to you, Mibrim!
To make sure I never lose it
Huh? Did you just...?
let’s walk together
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
Aren’t you getting a bit too excited?!
Aww... They started fighting again...
They were so happy
just a second ago...
Besides, it’s their fault
the rock fell to begin with...
Konoyozaru is the evolved form
of Okorizaru?!
Look out!
A battle between Konoyozaru...
No way we’d be able to
approach them now.
Are you okay?
Huh? Where’s Mibrim?!
Over there!
Mibrim! Look out!
She’s trying to stop the battle!
Mibrim!
Mibrim...
...evolved?!
Tebrim. Silencing Pokémon.
Psychic type.
It will silence anyone with strong emotions,
no matter who they may be.
Tebrim...
It “silences” them?
Whoa...
Sh-She beat them up,
then healed them up...
I wonder if the Mankey
will get along now.
Gathering those berries
wore me out...
Oh, right!
I wanted a Konoyozaru vid...
Too bad I didn’t also record
Tebrim beating the Konoyozaru down...
Let’s stay good friends, Tebrim!
There’s still so many Pokémon
we’ve never seen before!
Yeah. I wanna learn a whole lot more!
I wanna connect with
and befriend all sorts of Pokémon!
After this, I think I’ll be able to
write a nice report!
Me, too!
Yeah.
Hmm... Might be a bit small.
Looks like you’ve
outgrown my hood, Tebrim.
Now, let’s get back to Orange Academy!
Yeah!
Yeah.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Rage Monkey Pokémon, Konoyozaru.
Konoyozaru
Rage Monkey Pokémon
Type: Fighting/Ghost
Konoyozaru
Rage Monkey Pokémon
Type: Fighting/Ghost
The evolved form of Okorizaru.
Height
1.2m
It requires a certain kind of energy
in order to evolve,
Weight
56.0kg
but do you know what that energy is?
What does it require to evolve?
Kindness
Rage
Sadness
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it require to evolve?
B: Rage
The answer is B: Rage!
When it evolves, it gains the Ghost type.
As a result, it gains power
beyond the limits of flesh!
Next episode
Friede here.
It’s time for my huge preview.
Sounds like Liko and company
are doing well on their Terastal course.
To look into Terapagos and Rakua,
I’ve gone to the Exceed Company.
Seems like they’re hiding
some important secrets...
But do you know what those secrets are?
See the answer
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Tune in to catch
Eternal Blessing!
Me and Cap are gonna be the stars!
Eternal Blessing