The three of us are
taking a Terastal Course!
Roy and I have managed to pass
our basics tests.
Now, it’s finally time for
Dot’s test in Hakkou City...
A battle with Nanjamo-san!
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s a vid from Gurumin!
Now, I’ve got a fantastic guest
here with me today!
C-Can you believe it?!
It’s the super popular streamer, Nanjamo!
Electrowebbing your eyes!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Hey, everybody! Gurumin-shi
called me over to star in a vid today!
And lemme thank you
for collabing with me before, too!
I should be thanking you!
So Nanjamo, I hear you’re giving
a Terastal Course basics test soon?
And you’re gonna be facing
a trainer with a Kuwassu, just like mine?
Uh-huh, uh-huh! I may not look it,
but I am a Gym Leader!
Lemme say, yours truly is hopin’
the way she fights is true to herself.
I can’t wait for her to glitz it up!
Me and Harabari are gonna
put her through the wringer!
W-Well, don’t be too rough, now...
On the day of, the big event’ll be
streamed exclusively on my channel!
So make sure to gather ‘round
your screens, everyone!
Whozat? This was Nanjamo!
And so, that’s it for the vid today!
Let’s go groovin’ again sometime!
Okay... It’s posted.
So many views already!
Nanjamo-neesan is something else...
“Fighting true to myself,” huh...?
What is “true to myself”?
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Glitz It Up, Terastal!
Dance Dance Kuwassu!!
Fighting true to yourself?
Yeah. Nanjamo-neesan said that,
so I’ve been giving it some thought.
I battled that Burorom yesterday, yeah?
You were really cool, Dot.
And so was Kuwassu!
When that happened...
I came up with a plan and saw it through.
Maybe that’s what
“fighting true to myself” is?
What’s this?
An analysis of Harabari.
I input Kuwassu’s moves
and simulated them battling.
If I stick to the plan a hundred percent,
I should be able to “glitz it up.”
Whoa!
You’re incredible, Dot...
I want the plan to be
as comprehensive as possible.
The unexpected can happen,
whether in battle or on stream.
On stream...?
Oh, that reminds me...
Of what?
Oh, well, just... It reminded me
of a Gurumin vid that went viral.
Huh? O-Oh...
What, what?!
I goofed during a livestream.
And so, this is how
you throw a Monster Ball!
Oops!
Well, that was a surprise!
Wait, what the?!
G-G-Gah! I’m stuck!
Hold on... Kuwassu!
What was that?!
That was funny!
I think Kuwassu was having fun, too!
I didn’t go like I planned, but it ended up
spreading the word about Gurumin anyway.
From ghastly to glitzy,
wouldn’t you say?
How long are you gonna watch that?!
S-Sorry...
Harabari is an Electric type,
and he’s evolved.
In comparison,
Kuwassu is an unevolved Water type.
The worst kind of type match-up...
I need a winning strategy.
That Spark is powerful, too...
That’s it!
So, if I take advantage of
Kuwassu’s speed...
Are you sure
I don’t need to come with?
I’m absolutely sure.
And... What is all this?!
Oh...
That’s awesome!
Right?! I’m gonna go all out
cheering for you with these!
Absolutely no way!
He’s so ridiculous,
making such a big deal out of this...
I’m sure Murdock’s
just been worried about you.
I get that, but...
Huh. They are here after all.
It seems one of them
is taking their basics test.
Let’s keep monitoring them.
This is a total drag.
Sandwich-chan is hungry for
some of those famous local churros...
We need all the intel
we can get on Terapagos.
Ah, Sandwich-san
and Onigiri-san, is it not?
P-Principal Clavel?!
I don’t believe your coursework
takes you to this city.
Um, well...
Oh, I see now.
You wished to see
how your friends are doing.
Huh?
I know well how you feel.
Liko-san, Roy-san, and Dot-san
are showing remarkable progress.
You’ve come to watch the test?
Huh?
Yeah, kinda...
Marvelous.
I am pleased to have students
so passionate about their studies.
Well then,
let us watch the test together.
When was it, again...?
He seems to have
misunderstood.
What a total drag.
I’m going for churros.
Hey! Hold on!
Right then,
we can all walk there together.
Oh?
The arrangements are all done.
Good work.
They said the battle
will be in the central plaza.
My dear students.
Mr. Principal!
Is everything okay?
I’m traveling around to get a sense of
how everyone is doing so far.
Dot-san, please do your best
in your basics test.
Oh... Yeah.
I hear you have all been working very hard,
which brings me great pride.
Y-Yes!
Yeah!
How has your journey
treated you so far?
U-Um...
I made a Lizardon sculpture
in Bowl Town!
Oh-ho!
And making it helped me realize...
...that you can find clues in all kinds of places!
What do I do here?
My test’s about to start...
Go on ahead, Dot.
We’ll catch up soon.
...Terastallized at the perfect moment,
R-Right. Thanks!
and Colza-san passed me!
I see. So you’ve had
a very positive experience.
Yeah!
How about you, Liko-san?
Huh?!
Oh, um, I...
...went through
a whole lot of stuff in Cercle Town!
Oh-ho! “A whole lot,” you say?
Electrowebbing your eyes!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
It’s time for Whozat TV!
Now then, now then,
today’s the livestream you’ve all been waiting for!
Just what’s in store today? Well...
A Terastal Course basics test!
And facing me,
Hakkou Gym’s illustrious Gym Leader, is...
A girl who could make a crying Kanuchan
hush on the double... Dot-shi!
Go, Dot!
You got this!
Stay calm... Stick to the plan...
Just stick to the plan.
Can’t wait another second?
Then let’s get this basics test
started already!
Let’s get to battlin’ it up!
Let’s go, Kuwassu!
‘Kay, sorry but I’m goin’ first!
Harabari! Use Spark!
Now, Kuwassu! Run for it!
Huh, huh?
Spark again!
Kuwassu! Move and dodge it!
Belly-ve I read ya!
Pretty smooth! You spotted the wind-up
before Spark went off, Dot-shi!
Heh... Now it’s our turn to attack!
Hey, whoa, whoa!
You’re wide open!
Go! Water Gun!
What am I going to do?!
Just kiddin’!
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
Dot!
Getting appropriate sleep is certainly
an important aspect of being a Pokémon Trainer.
Go for it!
Yes... I agree...
I’m pleased that you do.
I hear that a long soak
in a tepid bath is good for you as well.
It warms up your entire—
Huh? Roy-san,
what do you have there?
Uh, right...
I was wondering how Dot’s test was going...
Of course!
This is no time to be chatting!
We must make haste!
Right!
Come on, Nyarote!
You too, Hogator!
That’s Harabari’s ability,
Making Electribbity.
He can convert damage
into strength.
So let’s take
all that stored power, and...
Kuwassu! Spark incoming!
Dodge it!
Discharge it!
Kuwassu!
Oh, no!
I’ll keep going!
Going? Where to?!
To a sparkling world!
Harabari! Spark!
Kuwassu, dodge it!
Dot!
Go for it!
Nice, nice!
My viewer count is skyrocketing!
Everybody! Make sure you tune in to all of
Nanjamo’s shocking, sparkling streams!
In that case...
Kuwassu, use Kick Down!
All right!
Follow it up with Water Gun!
Whoa! You’re pretty good, Dot-shi.
Wellzen, we better heal up a bit!
Harabari! Slack Off.
Isn’t he the cutest
when he’s slacking off?!
Everybody! Screenshot time!
Oh no you don’t! Water Gun!
Do it again! Water Gun!
Water Gun!
My attacks... aren’t working...
All healed up and raring to go!
One more time! Discharge!
My, oh my... What a mess.
The stream cut out?
Technical difficulties of some kind?
I need to use this time
to come up with a new plan...
Gah, I’m drawing a blank!
This is way too unexpected!
Oh! The unexpected...
From ghastly to glitzy, huh?
Okay, Kuwassu!
Let’s shine even brighter!
Bring on the haters!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine on!
Kuwassu Terastallized!
She’s Terastallizing now?!
What the?!
Now’s when you wanna Terastallize?!
You gotta be kiddin’ me,
Dot-shi!
Nice footwork!
Keep it up! Kick Down!
Huh? You’re not using
a Water-type attack, Dot-shi?
Good job, Kuwassu!
One more time! Kick Down!
Go, go, Kuwassu!
Go!
Could that have been...
Aqua Break?!
Wow!
A new move!
The stream’s back up!
We can finally
get the stream goin’ again!
Everyone! Thanks for waiting!
Seems like I oughta
take this seriously, too!
We’ve been waiting!
Go for it!
Callin’ on inspiration’s li’l lightbulb!
Time for Nanjamo to
show off her true power!
Harabari Terastallized!
She picked now?!
Now, that’s enough rechargin’!
Time to get zappin’!
Discharge!
Kuwassu! Use Aqua Break!
Nanjamo’s so strong!
Awesome match!
Kuwassu!
Now then, there may’ve been
a li’l goof in there...
But your basics test has now concluded!
Dot-shi,
tell us how you’re feeling right now!
I hate to admit it, but...
I lost.
But! But!
That’s not all, right? Right?
Uh, um...
It was fun, I think...
That’s it, Dot-shi!
Huh?
Despite the setbacks and the goofs,
you had fun battlin’ it up
while stayin’ true to yourself!
And that’s how
you glitz it up, Dot-shi!
Having fun is how you
glitz it up?
Precisely! Having fun is
mega important for a Pokémon Trainer!
Ain’t that right, everybody?
Precisely!
You were great!
Look! The likes are flooding in!
And so, Dot-shi!
Regarding your basics test...
You pass!
You did great, Dot!
Dot!
You did it!
You passed!
Thank you.
And you, Kuwassu... Thank you.
Everyone!
What’d you think of tonight’s livestream?
It showed Dot and yours truly
battlin’ it up marvelously!
Burn it to your brain-memory!
Overwrite to make room!
And so! Electrowebbing your eyes!
The Electrical Streamer!
Whozat?
This was Nanjamo!
See ya!
You did wonderfully, Dot-san.
You passed your test
in marvelous fashion.
R-Right!
Now then...
You have each passed
your Terastal Course basics tests.
Allow me to congratulate you
once again.
Thank you!
Next, I will ask you
to return to the academy.
But do not forget to interact with wild Pokémon
on your way back, nor to write your reports.
Right, our reports!
I am sure you’ll find it rewarding.
Mr. Zinnia and I both expect
great things from you.
Right!
And by the way, ahem...
Dot-san, I hear you are
well-versed in streaming.
Huh? Uh, yes.
If you wouldn’t mind,
could you teach me all you know about it?
I ask because our academy...
Well, how should I put it...?
I’ve come to think lately that
taking some kind of...
...initiative in that direction
will be essential for us.
Think this is gonna take long?
And... what is this “glitz” thing
all about, exactly?
No idea...
Uh, um, it’s...
Uh, to have fun, or something.
To have fun? And what else?
Um... It’s kinda...
Like wanting yourself
to sparkle!
To sparkle?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar.
Today, let’s take a look at
the Electric Frog Pokémon, Harabari.
Harabari
Electric Frog Pokémon
Type: Electric
Harabari
Electric Frog Pokémon
Type: Electric
This belly-button dynamo on its belly
is its electricity-generating organ.
Height
1.2m
When it generates electricity,
it moves in a characteristic way.
Weight
113.0kg
But do you know how it moves?
How does it move when generating electricity?
It shakes
It expands and contracts
It rolls around
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
How does it move
when generating electricity?
B: It expands and contracts
How does it move
when generating electricity?
B: It expands and contracts
The answer is B: It expands and contracts!
It generates electricity by expanding and contracting
muscles all over its body, its abs in particular.
Despite appearances,
it has some amazing abs!
Next episode
So these wild Pokémon reports...
Where do we even start?
Mmmph...
Shouldn’t we start by picking
what Pokémon to observe?
Mmmph...
Liko, what’s got you
so deep in thought?
What’s the difference between
“re-port” and “re-port”?
That’s what’s on your mind?!
If you wanna know
how Liko’s report turns out...
Next time on Pocket Monsters,
A Thorny Nyarote?!
The Mysterious Flower Pillar
...you might just find out!
Mmmph...!
A Thorny Nyarote?!
The Mysterious Flower Pillar