Tsk, still up and kicking...
Is that all we could manage?
Let’s withdraw.
We’ve seen Rekkuuza’s strength
for ourselves.
We should regroup for now.
We’re okay!
Murdock!
The balloon’s wrecked,
but the ship itself is fine!
The Pokémon are okay, too.
What a relief!
I shall go aid them.
You guys go after
the black Rekkuuza!
Got it!
Listen, Rekkuuza!
My name is Liko!
I’m a Pokémon Trainer!
I want to take Terapagos to Rakua,
where Lucius went!
Please lend us your strength!
Rekkuuza!
Thanks to you,
I got to go on an adventure!
The thing I wanted
more than anything!
So right now...
my heart’s pounding!
I want to battle you!
It responded?
All right, I’ll join you!
You too, Dot!
Huh?! Me?!
Guess I’ve gotta do it.
Cap! Lizardon!
Nyahoja!
Hogator!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
Having Come So Far
I couldn’t do a thing last time...
This time, I’ve got to!
But... How do we even approach?
Let’s split into two teams.
Roy, with me!
Yeah.
Let’s go, Hogator!
Cap, you handle
Nyahoja and Kuwassu.
Send them into the skies!
Let’s drive it
towards the lighthouse.
Yeah!
Flamethrower!
Cap, now!
Kuwassu!
Magical Leaf!
Water Gun!
Nyahoja!
Kuwassu!
Thank you, Cap!
I have a plan.
Okay.
Cap, launch them again!
Kuwassu!
Fire a Water Gun at the ground!
Then Kick Down on Nyahoja!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Hogator, use Charm Voice!
We did it, Hogator!
It’s super effective!
Nyahoja, nice!
We landed a hit!
Whoa...
Is it starting to take us seriously?
Dodge it, Lizardon!
Hogator!
Lizardon!
Kuwassu! Give Hogator a boost
with Water Gun!
I’m so happy you’re okay!
Thanks, Kuwassu!
Nice, Kuwassu!
Kuwassu!
Are you okay?
Hang in there!
Watch out!
Spinel, that worm...
I thought he was scheming
something in secret...
Amethio...
I’ll be taking the black Rekkuuza.
Follow your own path!
Soublades!
Soublades...
...Terastallized?!
Ghost Dive!
If we wanna stand a chance...
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Surpass your potential!
Lizardon!
Tera Burst!
Amazing!
Terastal is unreal!
Don’t get in my way!
You don’t have time
to be picky!
We need to stop that attack...
Have Soublades ride on Lizardon!
Soublades!
Dragon Claw!
Sword of Regrets!
Shadow Claw!
Tera Burst!
Let’s end this with the next hit!
Don’t give me orders!
Dragon Claw!
Shadow Claw!
Return!
What was that move?!
Draconic Masterstroke.
Hogator?
Hogator...
Looking good, Hogator!
Show it your power!
Is that Nitro Charge?
Wow... Roy and Hogator are both...
Right, I decided I’d take
Terapagos to Rakua.
I need to step forward, too!
Farther!
With Nyahoja!
Terapagos...
And everyone else...
I want to help them!
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
Magical Leaf!
Nyahoja?
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Nyahoja!
She evolved!
It’s Nyarote...
She...
Yeah!
Magical Leaf!
Go! Nitro Charge!
You did it, Hogator!
Nyarote...
Are you okay?!
You fought well, Nyarote.
Rekkuuza...
Nyarote... Thank you.
Amethio-sama!
Good to see you’re okay!
Naturally.
We’re leaving.
Are you sure?
Next time,
I will have that Pokémon.
Amethio...
Um...
Thank you for earlier.
Don’t misunderstand.
The black Rekkuuza is my quarry.
There is nothing else to it.
Hey!
Liko! Roy! Dot!
You did great!
You’re all okay!
Told ya.
Thank you.
You let us focus
on the battle with Rekkuuza.
Ooh, she evolved into Nyarote!
Isn’t that great, Liko?
Yeah.
But...
What’s wrong?
We... lost...
I still couldn’t catch it...
And this time...
...our beloved ship...
Liko. Roy.
If you admit defeat and give up,
your adventure ends here.
You’ve met so many people,
been through so much...
You’ve never doubted
the path you chose, right?
I...
Now that you’ve reached Rekkuuza,
what have you gained?
Nyahoja has evolved.
Hogator has learned
lots of new moves.
Nyarote...
Hogator...
As long as you don’t give up,
you haven’t lost.
Your battle goes on...
Your adventure goes on.
The ship can be fixed.
We’re still in working order!
You reached Rekkuuza,
who once seemed so far away.
That’s incredible by itself!
We... We really have come far,
haven’t we?
With Pokémon by my side,
I’ll do just fine!
We can go
as far as we want to!
I won’t give up!
I’ll find the rest of the Six Heroes,
and take Terapagos to Rakua!
And I’ll get strong enough
for Rekkuuza to approve of me!
A-And I...
I don’t want to sit
on the sidelines!
The mysteries of the world
that Liko and Roy are chasing...
I wanna know more about them!
Yeah!
Friede, please tell me!
How do we Terastallize?
Lizardon was amazing earlier!
So was Amethio’s Soublades!
If we could battle like that...
I see.
All right!
In that case, I’ve got a good idea!
We’ll repair the ship.
We were hoping to
research Terapagos in Paldea, anyway.
So...
Liko, Roy, Dot...
You three...
...begin Terastal training!
T-Training?!
What are we gonna do?
You just let me worry about that!
I’m hungry, Murdock!
Time to go shopping
and have a picnic!
Let’s get it done in a flash!
Don’t spend too much.
C’mon, let’s splurge today!
Our expenses are higher than ever
right now, you know...
Thank you...
...for taking us this far.
Even all of you combined
could not handle the black Rekkuuza.
I must apologize.
No matter.
Allow the Rising Voltteccers
to gather the Six Heroes.
Give us another chance.
We won’t fail you again.
Shrewd thinking, Gibeon-sama.
You intend for us to take Terapagos
once its power is recovered.
Yes.
We will have them
work for our cause.
Then what should we do?
Monitor Terapagos
and that girl... Liko.
I shall return to Rakua...
The Rakurium will be mine.
This adventure is not over.
Isn’t that right,
Lucius?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Heavens Pokémon, Rekkuuza.
Rekkuuza
Heavens Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
Rekkuuza
Heavens Pokémon
Type: Dragon/Flying
It flies endlessly through the skies,
rarely descending to the ground.
Height
7.0m
Regular color
Weight
206.5kg
Do you know where Rekkuuza lives?
Where does Rekkuuza live?
A mountaintop
The moon
The ozone layer
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, cute & sweet Pokémon!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Varinich,
Tarpple, Mawhip!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Murdock here. Dot... Just watch this!!
Cute & sweet Pokémon
Vanipetit, Puppymocchi, Vanirich,
Tarpple, Mawhip! Yes!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
Where does Rekkuuza live?
C: The ozone layer
The answer is... C: The ozone layer!
Rekkuuza lives in the ozone layer,
much higher than any mountain.
It’s said to have lived there
for hundreds of millions of years.
The skies stir up
your spirit of adventure!
Next episode
All you Pokémon Trainers out there...
It’s time for the preview!
What’s the Terastal training
Friede mentioned gonna be?
Dunno...
Sitting under waterfalls, maybe?
Looks like we’ll be
going to school in Paldea!
That’s studying, not training...
jugyou                 shugyou
Hey, wait! A school in Paldea...
You mean that school?!
It has to be!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Heart-Pounding! Orange Academy