Liko!
Liko! It’s almost time!
Right! I’ll be going soon!
Nyarote, Mibrim. It’s morning.
Good morning, Terapagos.
My name is Liko.
I’m a Pokémon Trainer.
Until just recently, I was traveling on
the Rising Voltteccers’ airship, the Brave Asagi.
We went through so much
on our travels...
The Terapagos that awoke
from my pendant...
The Pokémon known as
Lucius’s Six Heroes...
Meeting and battling them
made me feel that...
...I need to learn more
about Pokémon!
And that I need to
get stronger as a trainer.
So, in order to study Terastal,
I’m going to be an exchange student
at Paldea’s Orange Academy.
All right, everybody. Let’s go.
When I got back from my trip...
I’m home.
Liko!
I’m so glad you’re home safe!
Welcome home, Liko.
...the reunion with my mother and father
was a little embarrassing.
But I was happy to see them again.
I’m home... Father, Mother.
Um... Let me introduce you.
This is my partner, Nyarote.
I’m Lucca. Nice to meet you.
It’s so good to finally see you.
So Nyahoja evolved into Nyarote?
You’re amazing, Liko!
Have you gotten
a bit taller too, Liko?
Looks like you’ve been through a lot.
Yeah! I have so much to tell you.
Morning!
Morning.
Well then, I’ll be off.
I’m off, too!
Be back safe.
Well then, I’ll say goodbye here.
Give it your all, Liko.
Yeah. You too, Mother.
Um... This is the spot, right?
Hey! Liko!
Morning!
Morning, Roy! Dot!
Is that Orange Academy’s uniform?!
Yeah!
We had ‘em get us some!
That’s great!
They’re so tight... Do we really have to?
Since when do short-term courses—
Dot...
It looks great on you, too!
You think so...?
Is that the Sekiei Academy uniform?
It’s so cool!
It’s been a while since I’ve worn it.
Terapagos was in there?!
Yeah. I was thinking it wouldn’t stand out
if it was in there.
You’re right.
If Terapagos gets spotted,
it could be trouble...
Good idea.
Amazing!
Hey, let’s take a photo
with the three of us!
Huh?
I’d rather not.
Sounds like a pain...
Come on!
We don’t get to
wear uniforms often...
Guess I can’t stop you...
Okay, I’m taking it!
Perfect! Looks great!
Let me see...
Hmph. You done now?
Let’s hurry up and go.
Then...
Let’s go!
To Orange Academy!
Together, we challenge, chasing the future
(Let’s go!)
We gather, let’s catch it, chasing tomorrow
(Hey, let’s go!)
Never give up - Every time you fall, stand up
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
(hey buddy)
Imagining, dreaming, with my friend (oh)
The light ahead of us, so bright
Once it catches your eye
The rest is easy, leave it to me
You and I will add to our story (oh-oh)
Always a little bit more (We are)
Closer than yesterday (Best friends)
I’m making my debut into a new world with you
We’re the challengers
It’s set into motion now, our fateful adventure
Watch us, tell us...
(hey buddy, let’s go)
We are buddy-buddy-buddies, chasing piles of dreams
Wish it, and it’ll come true, you know it
Get over here, Challenger
Now, to chase spark-spark-sparkling bright tomorrows
Leap out into that vast sky
You sparkling Challenger
We’re the challengers
Hand in hand, flying up-up-up higher
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
(Take a step out, go!)
Let’s challenge
Heart-Pounding! Orange Academy
Nice to meet you!
Yes, nice to meet you as well.
I am the Principal of
Orange Academy, Clavel.
And this is our board chair...
Omodaka. Nice to meet you.
Well then, allow us to explain
the Terastal Course...
One of the battle studies programs we offer
features a Terastal-only curriculum.
In order to learn about the uniquely
Paldean phenomenon of Terastal,
trainers are coming from all over the world
to attend our course here.
Terastal is a phenomenon where
Pokémon sparkle and shine like jewels.
They all look so cool!
Many kinds of Pokémon Terastallize,
gaining special powers.
It’s thought to be related
to the Terastal Energy...
...that emanates
from beneath the Paldea Region.
I’ve seen those near my house!
However, many facets of it
are yet to be understood.
These mysteries are a subject of
ongoing research by Pokémon Professors.
Interesting...
Trainers can demonstrate this
Terastal phenomenon with their own Pokémon.
These tools—known as Terastal Orbs—
play an essential role in that task.
However, only trainers permitted to do so
by Paldea may use these Orbs.
I give these to you.
Please take good care of them.
Right!
Ah, yes...
Allow me to ask you a question.
Why do you seek the power of Terastal?
There’s a strong Pokémon
I really wanna battle again!
I... have a place I hope to find
with Nyarote and everyone else...
A sight I simply have to see!
I...
I want to discover...
...all of the mysteries
of the world’s Pokémon.
Mm-hmm.
The course’s curriculum is simple.
First, we’ll have you learn
all about Terastal,
and then travel across Paldea
to battle its Gym Leaders.
Well then,
please head to your classroom.
To show you the way,
our student council president—
Excuse me!
Liko? Roy?
Nemo!
It’s been so long!
Long time no see!
Nice, nice...
Looks like your efforts are bearing fruit.
Is that Pamot?!
He’s gotten really big!
Yeah!
He evolved into Parmot!
You’re already acquainted?
Yes. She helped us out
in Bowl Town once.
Nemo... In the flesh...
The Champion Rank...
It’s my first time meeting you, though.
Nice to meetcha!
Y-Yeah...
Oh, yeah... Roy!
Remember our promise?
Next time we met, we’d battle!
Yeah! I’ve been looking forward to it!
All right!
Then let’s get to it!
Nemo-san.
I would ask that you, as our student council president,
show them around the school first.
Ack! Sure...
Orange Academy is a historic school;
one of the world’s oldest.
You can learn everything you need
to be a Pokémon Trainer here.
There are Pokémon all over the place here!
Everyone seems to be having fun!
Mr. Hassaku!
Oh, Nemo-san.
Terastal Course students, I take it?
I am Hassaku,
art teacher at this academy.
Heyo! Chili-chan here!
Goodness, messing around again...
Should we know them?
Hey now, I wasn’t messin’ around...
That’s Hassaku-san and Chili-san
from the Pokémon League Elite Four!
That getup...
You’re from Sekiei Academy, ain’tcha?
Huh? Oh, yes! My name’s Liko!
I hear tell that star trainers who could hold their own
in the Pokémon League are gatherin’ here...
Not at all!
I’m still new at all this!
Anyway, kiddo, guess you’re out here
repping your school.
Give it all ya got!
Rep? I hadn’t even
thought about that...
I’m representing Sekiei Academy...
That’s right!
I’ll do my best!
Now that’s really got me fired up!
And you know what that means!
A battle! Right, Roy?
Yeah!
It’s time for class, everyone.
Ack... Interrupted again...
Osu! I’m Kihada,
the battle studies teacher!
Okay, let’s get this lesson started.
First! We meet up in the yard!
Huh?!
Okay, let me explain
the specifics of this course.
Exercises, start!
One! Two! Three! Keep it up!
One! Two! Three!
How did I get myself into this?
During the course, you’ll take two tests administered
by Gym Leaders: basics and implementation!
Now, burn it into your muscles!
One! Two! One! Two!
All right! Two chances to
battle a Gym Leader!
They test if trainer and Pokémon
are using the power of Terastal correctly,
and whether a trainer is fit
to wield a Terastal Orb!
Now, look alive!
One! Two! One! Two!
Osu! Next, an important rule
to keep in mind for this course!
One! Two! Keep it up!
Right!
One! Two! One! Two!
Students must never Terastal Battle
other students during the course!
You’re only to gain experience
by battling Gym Leaders!
Right!
One! Two! One! Two!
The school will assign you a Gym Leader
based on your individual aptitude!
Right! One! Two!
First, for your basics test, you’ve got to pass muster
in a battle with your assigned Gym Leader!
Got that?
Right!
All right!
Then we’ll end our exercises here!
Osu!
Right...
So here’s where you were.
You weren’t in your classroom,
so I’ve been looking for you.
Sorry... I just couldn’t sit still.
Hey! I’m Zinnia,
the biology teacher.
I’ll send you the app
with all your curriculum info on it.
Try to interact with wild Pokémon
along the way as much as possible.
I’ll be asking you to do reports,
so don’t forget to save photos and videos.
Give it your all!
Osu! Check the app
to see where you’re assigned!
I got Kaede-san’s gym
in Cercle Town...
I wonder what she’s like...
I got Bowl Town.
That means I got Colza-san!
How about you, Dot?
Hakkou City.
Huh?!
So... Nanjamo-san?!
You can’t be serious...
Osu! That’s all for this lesson.
Well then, let’s get back to class!
Right.
Liko?! No way!
Anne?!
I came here for the Terastal Course.
You too?
Yeah, along with Roy and Dot.
Let me introduce you.
This is my classmate, Anne.
I’m Roy!
Liko’s told me so much about you!
Dot. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
I’m Liko’s BFF, Anne from Sekiei Academy.
So, Mijumaru evolved!
Same for your Nyahoja.
We’ve both grown.
Yeah!
Oh, I know! Let’s do something
I’ve been waiting for forever!
Huh? Do you mean...?
Of course! A battle, what else?
pOCket Monsters
Terastal Debut
A battle to celebrate your reunion!
Are your minds and bodies ready?!
I remember it. Back then...
When I’d only just started as a trainer,
Nyahoja and I battled Anne and Mijumaru.
It feels so long ago now.
Go for it! Both of you!
Now, each of you, get your friend’s
blood pumping with a heated battle!
Let the battle begin!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Futachimaru, use Water Pulse!
Good going, Liko!
Pretty good, Liko!
Futachimaru!
Go for a Shell Blade barrage!
Nyarote, get some distance!
She can’t outspeed us!
Nyarote, use Lightning Speed!
Futachimaru! Toss your hotachi!
It hit!
Don’t let your guard down!
Turning Swallow Strike!
Nyarote!
Oh my...
That’s super effective
on Nyarote, Chili-chan!
She had something to make up for
Futachimaru’s Grass-type weakness.
But they’re just gettin’ started.
Those two...
They’re students from Sekiei Academy.
You can really feel
the spirit in this battle.
Nyarote, are you all right?
Okay.
But I have to do something
about those hotachi attacks...
I know!
Nyarote!
Use your bud to stop
Futachimaru from moving!
I won’t let you! Detect!
Finish it! Shell Blade!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
It’s over!
The winners are Liko and Nyarote!
What a great battle!
Yeah.
It really showed how much
they trust each other.
Thank you, Futachimaru.
We won...
Nyarote!
Liko!
I’m frustrated...
But I still had a ton of fun!
Let’s battle again sometime!
Next time, I won’t lose!
Yeah! We’re going to get stronger, too!
Right, Nyarote?
That was an interesting battle.
You said it.
Connecting with other schools
will help our school flourish, too.
And help us find more people
for the League, to boot.
Shrewd as ever, ain’tcha?
What’s goin’ on?
Were you battling?!
This time, I wanna battle—
It’s time. The assembly is starting,
student council president.
Ack... Understood, Top...
Here you are.
Thank you.
Going camping with everyone...
Doesn’t that sound like fun, Hogator?!
Oh, right...
We’ll have to live in tents...
This is starting to bum me out...
Sorry for the wait!
Hey, where should we go first?
Seems like Cercle Town’s the closest.
That’d mean doing your test first.
Is that okay?
Me, up first...
Yeah, let’s do it!
It’s settled!
Everyone, the time has come
for your departure.
Please take care on your travels.
Awright!
We slid home safe!
No, we were clearly out by a mile.
Hmph. Total drag...
Oh, there were still students
yet to arrive?
I do apologize.
One of us slept in, despite how important—
No, I shouldn’t make excuses.
Your names?
I am Ony—
...Onigiri.
This is San—
...Sandwich.
Totally lame!
Nice to meetcha!
Name’s Sandwich-chan!
Onigiri-san and Sandwich-san, correct?
You’re not on the list.
Naw, that can’t be right.
Just look harder!
Donning this uniform is proof positive
of my readiness to train.
Super serious mode again?
What was that?
What’d ya say?
Hmm?
Students must be
courteous to their peers.
If you cannot obey the rules,
you will fail this course.
Fine...
You heard the man.
It is what it is.
Still, this is peculiar.
They’re nowhere on the list...
Principal...
Is something the matter?
These students aren’t on the list.
I see.
It seems like a database error.
I will see to them.
You will? Thank you.
Well then,
if you two could just follow me.
Fine!
Those two...
What are they scheming?
They’re taking the Terastal Course...
Just like us...
For now, we’ll have to wait and see.
Yeah.
That’s how our Terastal Course began.
Feels like I’m rebuilding it
from scratch...
Orio.
How’s the Brave Asagi coming?
Hmm... It’s gonna be a while.
It’s from Liko.
She says,
“We’re all leaving for the course.”
Now they can finally
make their Terastal Debut.
Good to hear.
“Look after yourselves!“
So?
You’ve got something
in mind, don’t you?
Yeah.
I’m going to start following a hunch.
I’ll leave the Brave Asagi
in your hands.
Roger.
Then...
Guess I better get back to it!
Gotta make sure we keep up, too.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Grass Cat Pokémon, Nyarote.
Nyarote
Grass Cat Pokémon
Type: Grass
Nyarote
Grass Cat Pokémon
Type: Grass
A Pokémon characterized by
a long coat of glamorous fur.
Height
0.9m
It hides a certain thing beneath its fur,
Weight
12.2kg
but do you know what that is?
What does it hide beneath its fur?
Berries
Coins
A vine
See the answer after the commercials!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
That mysterious power everyone has
I want it too, come look and listen with me
Heart pounding at the display (display)
Leap past it, runaway (Yeah)
Action! Dodging and weaving every which way
The mystery in my pocket, it must be adventure
Soaking up sun and rain, that's how seeds sprout
Gotta beat my yesterday 1,2,3,4!!
Even by the smallest margin (Trial & error)
It's a new personal best!
Telling a real hero-to-come's Story
Look to the future, someday I'll get to claim Victory
Nice to meet you, to the beat y'all
It's super promising!
I'm all set to hone my skills until I'm satisfied
(Ready, hop! Ready, jump!)
And go! Head past the furthest reaches
Never bind myself with limits
Just seek out my way, 'til I catch it for sure
(Beyond!) Hope's at a perfect 100%
(Reload!) Keep trying, every time
Again, again, again...
Hello, future!
Journey with buddy! Leap out!
Turn up the heat!
Ride on! In peak form! Hey!
Coolly say "Let me battle"
Aee aye (Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!...)
Alright, stay tuned, come on!
See you again tomorrow!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it hide beneath its fur?
C: A vine
The answer is C: A vine!
It hides a long vine beneath its fur.
There’s a bud on the end of it,
which it can swing around like a yo-yo.
Next episode
The Terastal Course begins!
We’re headed for Cercle Town.
You must be excited to meet
the Gym Leader, Liko!
Wait, Liko?
What’s wrong?
Why are you spacing out?!
Being first up to bat
must be nerve-wracking...
My first time Terastallizing...
I’m going to ace this!
And so! To be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Ready, and...
Liko and Nyarote, Put Your Hearts Into It
I’m going to ace this!