To get permission
to enter Paldea’s Great Crater,
we battled Omodaka-san, the Top Champion
of the Pokémon League, and we won.
Now we can keep moving forward!
This is the Zero Gate.
The Pokémon League
controls the systems here.
Where’s Ms. Briar?
She’s meeting us
at a research facility inside.
Let’s go! To Paldea’s Great Crater!
See you. You were cool out there.
Thank you. See ya.
Let’s go, Sango.
Wahoo! This rules!
Area... Zero...
I never knew Paldea’s
Great Crater was so beautiful...
Ooh!
Whoa, they’re huge!
They’re so big...
Any Paradox Pokémon?
I don’t see any...
Maybe they’re deeper down?
Wouldn’t it be cool if we saw some?
All well and good,
but don’t forget why we’re here.
To find Entei!
Exactly!
Stare...
Listen up, Sango.
Our orders were strictly
to observe them.
Be discree—
We’ll lose ‘em
if we drag our feet!
Onigohri!
Honestly...
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Totally Awesome Pokémon in Area Zero?!
Welcome to Paldea’s Great Crater!
Thanks for coming.
So, shall we get straight to it?
Right.
The site where Entei was recorded is a ways away,
but it’s within walking distance.
The Great Crater
extends deep underground,
and we’ll follow the edge of the cliffs
downward to reach our destination.
Here’s the observation site in question.
No way to tell whether this is
the Entei from the Six Heroes.
But if we head over there...
We might find some clues, right?!
Yes, that’s right!
Smart thinking.
But this is Area Zero.
There are many sections unexplored by humans,
and dangers abound.
I want you all to keep that in mind.
Okay!
Well then, how about I lead the way?
We’re currently in what’s referred to
as the upper strata.
There are enormous
Terastal crystals beneath us.
Enormous...
Even bigger than the ones here?
That’s right.
You want out?
Give me a sec.
It’s still glowing as bright as ever!
Happy to be back home?
Um...
Hmm?
Ms. Briar, have you seen
any Paradox Pokémon?
Yeah, I have.
Here, Pokémon can be found in,
ostensibly, future and ancient forms...
...which should have no place
in the present day.
And those are called Paradox Pokémon.
Future and ancient, eh?
What potential causes
have been theorized for that?
Right...
This is still purely in the realm
of conjecture, but...
If, let’s say, you start with the workings
of the Terastal phenomenon...
Paradox Pokémon, huh?
I wanna battle them!
I wonder what their lives are like.
A Nokokotchi!
Whoa! They’re already so far ahead!
They’re gonna leave us behind!
Let’s hurry!
They don’t have the slightest suspicion
we’re tailing them...
Totally bored...
That’s a funny noise!
What are you doing, Sango?
Stay quie—
Did a Paradox Pokémon
make that sound?
Let’s ask Ms. Briar about it later!
Yeah!
Huh? What’s wrong?
Something’s there!
Roy, hurry up!
Sure, be there in a sec!
Uh... Is that a Rarecoil?
Oh! More cries!
We can ask her
what made that sound later.
Yeah!
Hide!
That way looks
a heckuva lot more fun!
Hey, wait!
You can’t run off!
Honestly...
Always such a handful...
Huh?
Where’d they go?
I was sure they ran over here...
Maybe this way?
Huh?
Oh, it’s just a Purin?
Don’t freak me out like that.
Pipe down!
I toldja to pipe down!
Rargh!
What was that for?!
You were laughin’ at Sango
just now, weren’t ya? Huh?!
Huh? Ya wanna go?
Well, do ya? Huh?!
Achigator, dodge it!
You okay?
Okay!
Time for a battle, Achigator!
Charm Voice!
Nitro Charge!
Huh?
Hmph.
You’ve got some guts, I s’pose.
I’ll just blow you away in a snap!
Onigohri!
Totally huge...
Run, Onigohri!
Hmm?
You tripped! Totally lame!
Bweh!
How dare you?!
Wuh-oh...
Gettin’ some bad vibes right now...
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
What’s your deal, loser?
Paldea’s Great Crater is fulla dudes
givin’ the stink eye! Cracks me up!
Actually, “ticks me off” is more like it!
So I think I’ll just blow ‘em all away right now!
Onigohri, use Crunch!
Whoa... You ain’t half bad.
Ain’t done yet!
Blizzard!
And follow it up
with another Crunch!
No struggling, ‘kay?
It hit you head on...
That totally cracks me up!
Hmph!
Hah...
All this laughing’s worn me out.
So how’s about
I wrap things up already?
Ice Spinner!
Go! Go! Go, go, go!
What?
Oh, don’t even think about it.
Show it you got guts, Onigohri!
Ice Spinner!
Guess that shrill voice
was your only strong suit.
When you’re too scared to even speak,
you’re totally lame.
Well, you could go
take a nap for all I care.
Let’s go!
Self...!
De...!
Struct!
Oh.
Yeah. Let’s go, Achigator!
Use Nitro Charge!
Follow up with Flamethrower!
Hey... Hold... Ugh...
Y-You’re going too fast...
Are you okay?
Huh?
Where are Roy and Achigator?!
We did it!
Thanks! That was a ton of fun!
I’ll come visit you again sometime,
so we should definitely do another battle!
Aga! Agaga!
Aga! Aga! Agaga!
Guh... What a total pain...
But seeing that totally huge Pokémon
running scared totally cracked me up!
You were totally awesome, too.
Guess you’re an Onipurin.
oni
What’s wrong, Onipurin?
What was that?
Nope, that’s total nonsense to me.
P-Pipe...
...down!
Huh?
Huh?!
What do we do?!
We have to look for...
No, first we should let Friede and Briar know.
There you are!
Glad I caught up with you!
What were you thinking?!
We were just about to go looking for you!
Sorry, sorry.
I got separated during the battle.
The battle?
With what?
It looked like a Rarecoil!
But with loads of black hair!
A Rarecoil... with hair?
Huh?
What kinda Pokémon is that?
Hey!
Get on down here!
We found a good spot!
That Onipurin...
Went in here, right?
P-Pipe down!
No singing, got it?!
Sango.
Huh?!
What’s your deal?
Where were you?!
You can’t go
wandering off on your own!
What is that Pokémon?
Onipurin.
I kinda caught it.
“Onipurin”?
Yeah! Could stand to pipe down some,
but it’s pretty neat I guess!
Right?
Tastes great!
A Rarecoil covered in hair, huh...?
Yeah! It was really cool!
You may have
made it back safely this time,
but anything could happen in the Great Crater,
so don’t go running off on your own.
Yeah. Got it. I’ll be careful.
Everyone...
Sorry, but I’ll be turning in early.
Tomorrow, we’ll finally reach
the site where Entei was spotted.
Anything could happen,
so you’d better save your strength as well.
Ms. Briar, what Pokémon
makes that sound?
Hmm?
Oh, that’s a Screaming Tail’s cry.
A-A Screaming Tail?! Wh-What?
Could that be a Paradox Pokémon?!
Shh!
Ah...
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Paradox Pokémon, Screaming Tail.
Screaming Tail
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Psychic
Screaming Tail
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Psychic
It looks like a Purin,
but it has a bigger body,
Height  1.2m
Purin
and a distinctive long forelock
that resembles a tail.
Weight  8.0kg
A certain magazine claims it’s a Purin from
some number of years ago, but do you know how many?
It's said to be a Purin from how many years ago?
One hundred thousand years
One billion years
Ten trillion years
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
It's said to be a Purin from how many years ago?
B: One billion years
The answer is B: One billion years!
Its primal appearance and ferocity led to rumors
that it was a Purin from a billion years ago.
Credible or incredible?
It’s what you make it!
Next episode
Entei!
It really was in Paldea’s Great Crater!
It’s resonating with Pagogo!
This one really is
Entei of the Six Heroes!
We’ll need to earn its approval
in battle for it to join our crew.
Time for an all-out clash!
What was that move?!
It’s so incredible!
Is that really an Entei?
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Ready, and...
A Huge Battle! The Earth-Gouging Inferno
Battles are fun!