We, the Rising Voltteccers, have arrived at
the foot of Mt. Kumuri under Rekkuuza’s guidance.
We headed up the steep mountain trail,
with help from each of the Six Heroes.
And then, as we pierced through
the clouds covering the mountain...
Wow...
The clouds are below us...
It really is the place
where heaven and earth meet...
That clean air
sure feels nice, eh, Cap?
What an unbelievable place
we’ve made it to...
Oh...
It was waiting for us!
Whoa...
There’s a forest!
Well, that’s a surprise...
Huh?
Wh-What?
Do you think maybe
it wants to have a rest?
Ah!
You were right!
That was kinda cute.
Oh, so is Pagogo going
to be leading us from here?
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
We've Arrived! The Paradise of Rakua
Over there!
There’s a ton of ripe berries!
They’re huge!
Huh, wonder what sorta
berries those are...
There’s so many kinds
I’ve never seen before.
All of them look highly nutritious.
Dot, I think you can
take off your coat now.
Whoa, you’re right.
Normally, it’d be inconceivable
at this elevation, but...
It’s warm!
The underground heat keeps things temperate,
paving the way for a rich natural landscape.
Isn’t that strange, Nyarote?
Plus, the terrain here dips in,
like a crater...
Sheltered from outside influence,
a splendid environment must’ve formed here,
outside anyone’s notice.
I see...
What bothers me is the source
of this underground heat...
According to the Elderwoman in Kumuri Town,
this mountain isn’t a volcano...
So how do we explain the heat?
And what could’ve caused this terrain?
How about we keep going for now?
Yeah!
This sure is something...
Watch your step, you two!
I’m all good! Thank you!
You couldn’t find us an easier path?
The utter lack of any man-made paths
means there’s a good chance this is Rakua.
Still, some paradise this is...
Huh?
There’s so many Pokémon!
Now this is incredible!
It’s a real treasure trove
of wild Pokémon!
They don’t seem wary of us at all...
Maybe they’re just
not worried about us?
Look...
There’s hot-tempered Pokémon
who aren’t fighting,
and natural enemies cozying up
to each other without a care and coexisting.
I get it...
Rakua’s a place that all kinds of Pokémon
can come to and live in peace...
That’s why they aren’t blindly afraid of us,
or getting in our way...
Everyone who comes here
is simply naturally accepted...
Maybe that’s
what’s special about Rakua.
This little one seems pretty friendly.
What do you think they’re saying?
They’ve already made friends!
That’s Pagogo for you.
Looks like they’re welcoming us too,
thanks to Pagogo.
An Eevee... With a Booster,
a Nymphia, and even a Leafia?!
Ooh! It’s not every day you get to
lay eyes on those in the wild!
Amazing...
I gotta send this to Botan!
Wow...
I just snapped an awesome photo!
Hmm?
Pippi!
And even a Pixie!
I’ve never seen either before...
Same for me!
People hardly ever get to see
Pokémon this rare, after all.
Wow...
That was so cute!
H-Hey! Is that...?!
Viridion!
A Legendary Pokémon!
That’s so cool!
And now Thunder...
Guess the rumors that Legendary Pokémon
visit this place were true.
We really have made it to Rakua!
Mm-hmm!
There’s a lot of evolved Pokémon, too.
They can grow big and strong
in the rich natural landscape here.
Even the tough-looking Pokémon
are relaxing...
They’re all living in peace...
Since the sky’s so close here,
they can get plenty of sunlight, too!
This sure is a Pokémon paradise, all right!
What’s wrong, Friede?
Oh, nothing.
I just can’t imagine the sunlight and the temperature
are all that’s behind the environment here...
Meaning there’s something else to it?
These lands are probably imbued
with some kind of special energy...
...which draws in all these Pokémon.
A special energy...
You mean Rakurium?
But even assuming it is
due to the effects of Rakurium,
I don’t see any pink crystals here.
Moreover, it bothers me how there’s
no hint of the events from a hundred years ago.
You’re right...
Rystal-san said Rakua
was on the verge of collapsing.
Yeah.
Is this really the Rakua
we’ve been searching for?
Seems like we’ve only just
reached the entrance.
If we go deeper in, maybe we’ll find
something Lucius left behind!
Yeah!
Huh? Dot?
I’m fine... Just worn out.
But even so...
I wanna keep going!
I wanna see more!
I feel the same way!
I’ve been non-stop excited!
Same here!
I could keep walking for hours!
Looks like it opens up.
Let’s hurry, Achigator!
Aw, it’s just an open field.
Pagogo? You want to go that way?
All right, let’s go!
No, we’ll be stopping here for today.
Huh?!
C’mon, let’s keep moving!
I’m good to keep going, too!
Look at the sky.
The sun’s about to set.
When did it get so late...?
I didn’t notice at all...
Guess I was really
running on adrenaline...
Let’s have a good night’s rest.
Even if the Pokémon here are peaceful,
dense forests can be dangerous at night.
Yeah!
Fieldwork doesn’t get done in a day.
Look forward to doing more tomorrow!
You sure made quick work of that...
During our Terastal Course,
we camped out together a lot.
Mm-hmm!
So you didn’t just grow as trainers,
but as adventurers, too.
It’s so pretty...
The stars are so close.
Kinda feels like
I’ve become a Rekkuuza!
I could never have even imagined it
before setting out on this adventure...
Kanto, Galar...
Traveling around Paldea with everyone...
The Kitakami hamlet, Johto...
And then Area Zero
in the Great Crater...
I’ve gotten to go
to so many places...
And we met
all sorts of people, too!
Yeah!
We’ve met so many people...
...and gained so much experience!
They were all such lovely people!
And they were so strong!
I wanna battle them again!
Our Pokémon have grown too,
thanks to them.
Nyahoja...
I hope we’ll stay good friends!
Hogator! You look so cool!
What a relief!
We did it! We won, Achigator!
Kuwassu!
Huh?
Kuwassu?
Let’s be good friends.
Sure is one unbelievable
adventure we’ve had.
And Rekkuuza’s Monster Ball
is what guided us here.
When I was younger,
I could only hope for this stuff...
To be like the Ancient Adventurer...
Adventuring with my friends,
seeking the Six Heroes...
...and finally arriving in Rakua.
It feels like a dream!
Do you think Lucius and Rystal-san
would’ve gazed up at the sky like this, too?
They must’ve!
Them and everyone else, too!
Yeah...
Liko?
What is it?
When I start thinking about how
our adventure might be almost over...
...I get a little bit sad.
Oh, I see.
We’ve taken Pagogo to Rakua now...
If Pagogo decides it wants to stay here in Rakua,
where Lucius once was...
...then will I have to say goodbye...?
You can’t know that for sure yet!
Roy...
Pagogo chose you as its partner,
so it must wanna stay with you forever!
Yeah.
I doubt Pagogo came here to Rakua
just to say goodbye to you.
Dot...
Er, well... Th-That’s just the kinda vibe I get
when I see Pagogo together with you!
Thank you.
I feel like I want to respect Pagogo’s wishes,
whatever they might be, but...
Right.
No point in me being the only one
getting all sad.
Right now, I want to enjoy our adventure
together as much as possible!
What might lie ahead?
What will tomorrow bring?
I want to treasure
those exciting thoughts!
Hey!
About time you guys get to bed!
Okay!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
We’ll make this spot our base camp,
so leave your tents up,
and leave any heavy luggage here.
Sure!
There! That should make walking easier.
Fire: Extinguished!
Everything I need: Packed!
Today, we’ll try heading deeper in!
I wanna lead the hike!
Now, let’s set out in high spirits!
Yeah!
It’s so quiet here...
Yeah...
There aren’t any wild Pokémon
around here, either.
Achigator?!
Are you okay?
Business as usual, huh?
A rock hill?
But there’s something about it...
Huh?
Stand back a bit.
Cap! Thunder Punch!
Something’s underneath?!
Hmm?
This doesn’t look natural...
But I can’t imagine
it’s man-made, either.
And look at this color...
That’s the color of Rakurium, isn’t it?
I’ve picked up components comparable to
Terastal energy in the surface of this wall.
Then, this is what
Rystal-san mentioned...
It must be the barrier that Pagogo
once used to save Rakua from collapsing.
There’s something inside, isn’t there?
We let our guard down,
thinking we’d made it to Rakua...
...but the place we need to go...
...is in here.
Certainly seems like it.
How can we get in there...?
Liko.
Lucius and Pagogo
created this barrier.
Maybe Pagogo—and you, as its partner—
can do something...
I’ll give it a try...
We’ll give it a try, Pagogo!
Pagogo!
It must’ve used
too much energy in one go.
Might be best for you to
let it rest in its ball.
Right.
Rest up, Pagogo.
You three, stand by here for now.
I’ll go in to check for any danger.
I’ll meet you back here
once I’ve found a safe route,
so be sure not to
run on ahead without me.
Well, that’s what I’d
normally say, at least...
But here in Rakua,
things are anything but normal.
If anything happens, then...
Liko, Roy, Dot...
You should think
and act for yourselves!
Okay!
Got it.
You look out too, Friede.
Right. Let’s go, Cap.
Whoa! Something just...
What’s wrong?
Some wild Pokémon?
It’s gone... Did I imagine it?
So this is raw Rakurium ore...
Looks like we’re
good to keep going for now.
We should get back to
Liko and the others.
You’re...!
This totally cracks me up.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Paradox Pokémon, Mighty Tusks.
Mighty Tusks
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Ground/Fighting
Mighty Tusks
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Ground/Fighting
A Pokémon known for its distinctive enormous tusks
that can crush stone, and for its solid scales.
Height
2.2m
Weight
320.0kg
But do you know what kind of
disposition Mighty Tusks have?
What disposition do Mighty Tusks have?
Aggressive
Jovial
Calm
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What disposition do Mighty Tusks have?
A: Aggressive
The answer is A: Aggressive!
Though it’s rarely been witnessed,
some reports suggest...
...they attack Pokémon and people
who so much as return their gaze.
One must be cautious
not to approach them carelessly.
Next episode
The Explorers have attacked!
They’re raring for a fight!
How did they find this place?!
And they’ve got Pokémon
we’ve never seen before.
If we want to head deeper into Rakua,
we’ll just have to battle them!
Roy! Dot! Are you ready?
Yeah!
If we all work together...
Yeah! If we do,
there’s no way we’ll lose!
Let’s put an end to this!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Rising Voltteccers VS The Explorers!
The Rising Voltteccers
The Explorers!