We met with Mr. Sodayo,
the globe-trotting Pokémon Journalist...
...and got some promising info
about Entei from him.
Apparently, someone has spotted Entei
in Asagi City in Johto.
Let’s split up and look for intel on Entei!
Yeah!
All right!
I can’t wait to see Asagi City!
What’s wrong?
The Brave Asagi...
Orio converted it from
Gramps’s ship, the Asagi, right?
Per Friede’s crazy demand.
And you managed to make it
the best airship in the world.
So, does that mean Asagi City is...?
It’s my hometown.
I was thinking just that!
It’s been quite a long time
since I was last here.
What kinda delicacies
does Asagi City have?!
What’s good to eat?!
Roy! We’re not here to play tourist!
Come, now...
Since we’re here, I can show you around town
while we gather information on Entei.
Woo!
Huh?
Where’s Murdock?
He said he was staying behind
to test out a new dish.
Mawhip, we won’t be making sweets today.
We’re making a traditional
Asagi City dish...
Chirashizushi!
First, we put the boiled rice
in the sushi tub...
Whoa!
Hey!
Give that back!
Come on!
Oop...!
Whoa!
Hey!
Hey, wait!
Hey, wait up!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Landau Returns to His Hometown
So this city’s where you grew up...
Though it was
quite a long time ago, mind.
There’s lots of Pokémon around, too!
Just around that corner,
there’s a tasty shaved ice stall...
Or so there used to be...
It’s a Smartphone Rotom shop now...
Since we’re here,
I’ll go ask about Entei!
Excuse me!
Have you seen an Entei around here?
Entei?! No, nothing of the sort!
I’d like to someday, though.
The bookstore here...
Well, that used to be here...
It’s an empty lot.
There’s a tasty
dumpling restaurant here...
Or rather, I’m certain it was here...
I wonder if it’s a lonely feeling, seeing your hometown’s
changed from how you remember it...
This hometown seems to have
changed quite a bit.
Huh? “This” hometown?
Does that mean you have
other hometowns?
Every port is a hometown to me.
But as people change, cities change in turn.
That’s true all over.
Oh!
This used to be an empty lot,
but now it’s a bakery!
Oh!
That used to be a coin laundry,
but now it’s a milk stand!
He seems to be having fun.
No sightings, huh...?
Where could Entei be?
Guess it wouldn’t be
easy to find, after all...
Good things come to those who wait
as patiently as a sleeping Kabigon.
The sea and the Pokémon
have stayed the same, any hometown I go to.
So, why’d you venture
outside this city, Gramps?
Because Pokémon were there.
Huh?
What kind of world lies beyond this sea?
What kind of Pokémon would you meet?
Would you not wish to find out?
Yeah!
Maybe Gramps was just like us once,
when he was younger...
Hey, you think that guy’s from around here?
Let’s go ask him about Entei, too!
Excuse me!
Oh, no! I forgot!
Do you think that Wooper’s his?
Ah! Nyarote!
Eeeek!
Huh?!
Wh-What was that?!
Something’s coming!
Oh, it was just the TV...
All righty. Made it just in time
for the good stuff.
Hey! Come on, dear!
I told you, something’s coming!
What is it?
A Teppouo? A Harisen?
A Chonchie?
No!
A Pichu? A Togepi?
A Sunnygo would be most welcome.
Just look!
Something’s coming!
So what is it, already?
A terrifying Samehada!
What was that about?
Hoho! Samehada was so young back then...
You a Ginjirou fan, then?
Huh?
Been an age since
I met a fellow Ginjirou fan!
Um... Excuse me...
Who is Ginjirou, exactly?
You don’t know him?!
Asagi City’s own superstar: Ginjirou!
Aglitter-aglimmer!
Ginjirou!
Huh?
Isn’t that...?
This is his celebrated debut film,
“Ginjirou, the Man of the Sea
VS Samehada”!
“VS Samehada”?!
Yep. There used to be
a film studio in this very city.
They churned out oodles of films.
But the cream of the crop
was the “VS Samehada” series!
Ooh! That sure takes me back!
A smash hit where Gin takes on
a ferocious man-eating Samehada!
After “Ginjirou, the Man of the Sea
VS Samehada 2” and “3”...
...came “Ah, Longing in Asagi...
VS Samehada”!
Huh?
The fourth film went in a whole new direction;
a heart-wrenching love story...
...with Samehada in it!
Followed by “Goodbye, Diamond
VS Samehada”!
A sporting spirit flick about the sweat and tears
of a baseball team that’s never won a match...
...with Samehada in it.
“The Glittering High-School Dossier
VS Samehada”!
A heartwarming teen flick portraying
the growth of teacher and students alike...
...with Samehada in it.
Th-That is... certainly something.
The “VS Samehada” series
blessed the world with numerous masterpieces!
They sound like total B movies, though...
You’re a really big fan of
Mr. Ginjirou, huh?
A big fan?
That doesn’t even begin to describe it!
He’s my whole life!
After his final role in
“Sports Day of the Dead VS Samehada”...
...Gin vanished from the silver screen.
Aspiring to be more like Gin,
with his partner, Nuoh...
...I protect these shores
with Wooper here.
The day may come when Gin
returns to our shores.
Huh? Hold on...
Which movie had a Nuoh in it?
I don’t see one anywhere.
Indeed. Nuoh wasn’t in the movies.
But it was an irreplaceable part of them!
Right, uhh...?
I never did introduce myself.
My name is Landau.
I’m Liko.
I’m Roy.
Dot.
I’m Mamoru, proprietor of a fishing boat
rental shop and protector of these shores!
Gin would oft film “VS Samehada” flicks
on these very shores.
If there was ever a lack of good waves,
Nuoh would whip some up with Surf!
Ah yes, indeed it would.
You knew that already, Gramps?!
Huh?
It’s a famous tale among Gin fans!
They’re all familiar with it.
Do you think Mr. Ginjirou’s
somewhere in this city still?
I knew it!
He’s Mighty G!
Huh?
Gin is Mighty G!
Here, look!
Mighty G and Ginjirou
aglitter-aglimmer! Look!
You’re right!
So Mighty G was an actor
when he was younger!
M-Migh...?
The hero protecting
the seas of the world: Mighty G!
He’s friends with Irukaman!
He’s way cool!
Hmm...
Phooey! That there ain’t no Gin!
Huh...?! It’s totally Gin!
It’s Mighty G aglitter-aglimmer!
He ain’t “aglitter-aglimmer” worth jack!
Who even is that old geezer?
Ginjirou’s an eternal star
of the silver screen...
He’d never grow old!
C’mon, look closer!
Hmph! Hmph! Hmph!
Hmph! Hmph! Hmph! Hmph! Hmph!
Guess he doesn’t wanna face
the reality of his personal hero getting old...
Ahh... Sure is a nice day today.
Oh, I know! Since you’re here,
want to pay a visit to his holy sites?
Holy sites?
The Whirlpool Islands are where the first
of the “VS Samehada” movies was filmed.
They’re the place where
Ginjirou’s legend began.
Indeed.
I believe those whirlpools were the stage
for the first battle with Samehada.
Ooh, right you are!
Talkin’ to folks who know about Gin
saves me breath!
Wow!
These things are intense!
Glitzy stuff!
Sharitatsu!
Sha! Ri! Ta! Tsu!
Sharitatsu! Where’d you go?!
Give me back my sushi tub!
Huh?
Nuoh, have you seen the Sharitatsu?
What’s going on?
Sharitatsu!
Are you okay?!
Whoa!
Just playing dead, huh?
Ow!
Sharitatsu!
Well, guess that’s that...
I’d better look for something
to use as a replacement.
Let’s go, Iwanko.
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Aglitter-aglimmer! Ginjirou!
You do a mean Gin!
The Whirlpool Islands here
are a holy site for us Ginjirou fans.
Gin stepped on this very rock...
Come on.
Give it a touch, as a souvenir.
When I was a lad, they used to tell kids we’d be
trapped on the Whirlpool Islands if we were naughty.
Wow...
Ooh, a Tattsu!
Spotting such a sought-after Pokémon
really makes coming here worth it!
Huh?
Oh! Right over there, you can see the stairs
where Gin trained with the Hitodeman in “VS 2”!
I’ll show you the way!
O-Oh... Sure.
This’ll be great for my next Gurumin vid!
What is it, Nyarote?
Huh?
The Sharitatsu?!
Huh?!
Oh, no!
Why are they here?!
At this rate,
they’ll get sucked into the whirlpool!
We have to save them!
Yeah!
Welcamo! Let’s move!
Achigator!
Welcamo, use Water Gun!
Nyarote, use Magical Leaf!
Achigator! You and water don’t mix,
so watch out!
Taikaiden, take to the sky
and rescue the Sharitatsu!
Huh? It made your head spin?!
Return, Taikaiden!
Wh-What do we do...?
Wooper?!
What is it?
Wooper and Sharitatsu
are in the whirlpool!
Wooper!
Well then, it seems the time has come
for a Forme Change.
Urk!
I can’t swim!
Please, save my Wooper!
R-Right...
Wooper and those sushi-looking Pokémon...
They’re goin’ round and round
the whirlpool...
...like it’s some sorta
giant sushi-go-round!
Save my Wooper! Please!
Save my Wooper
from the sushi-go-round!
Huh? Something’s coming!
It’s Nuoh!
Nuoh?!
All right!
Phew...
So you’ve come to my aid, Nuoh.
The Nuoh behind the scenes
is the unsung hero, after all.
Looks as if the whole cast has arrived!
Time we got started!
Migh... Migh... Migh...
Migh...
Mighty... G!
Migh!
Could that Nuoh be...?!
What’s that?
A yacht?
A boat?
No, it’s...
The legendary hero protecting
the seas of the world!
Mighty G!
It’s Mighty G!
That’s Mighty G?!
Nuoh! Surf!
Come on!
A man of the sea,
arriving atop Nuoh’s waves...
Aglitter-aglimmer...
It’s Ginjirou!
Go for it, Mighty G!
Mighty G! Save everyone!
Th-This is...
Samehada! Whirlpool!
Go!
“The Giant Sushi-Go-Round VS Samehada”!
Good boy, Samehada!
Wooper!
I’m glad you’re okay!
Gin— Err, I mean, Mighty G...
Thank you so much for saving him!
Thank you, Mighty G!
So Mighty G really was Ginjirou after all.
Every human has a history!
Every hero has a history!
A true hero has a wide-ranging career-oh...
...in this wide-open world out here-oh!
A wide-open mind... Right you are!
I’ve been acting narrow-minded,
not wanting to accept how times change...
You’re still super cool,
now as Mighty G!
As aglitter-aglimmer as ever!
Mighty G!
Bye-bye!
Thank you, Mighty G!
Mighty G sure was cool.
I hope I get to meet him again.
Ow, ow, ow...
Are you okay?
I’m fine.
I may not be able to last
even three minutes anymore...
Good work.
Friede!
You learn anything?
Nope, didn’t turn up
any promising leads.
Me either.
Nobody’s seen Entei anywhere.
What? You kids are looking for Entei?
Ah, Mr. Mamoru here runs a fishing boat
rental shop, and protects these shores!
A customer that rented a boat from me
mentioned seeing an Entei.
Really?!
Whereabouts was it?
Said it was near the archipelago
off the shore here...
Oh, probably around here.
If we go there, we can meet Entei!
We’re home!
We’re back!
Welcome back!
I’m starving!
Now then, what’s this new dish of yours?
Ta-daah!
An Asagi City delicacy!
Chirashizushi!
Wow, pretty! Looks tasty, too!
Looks yummy!
Wait, why’s it in a washtub?
I didn’t have a choice.
The Sharitatsu took off with—
Hey! That’s my sushi tub!
Whoa!
Hey! It’s too late now,
but give it back!
It’s no longer chirashizushi...
Now it’s chaos-hizushi!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Water Fish Pokémon, Nuoh.
A Pokémon that doesn’t like sunlight,
and spends a lot of time underwater.
Nuoh
Water Fish Pokémon
Type: Water/Ground
Nuoh
Water Fish Pokémon
Type: Water/Ground
Height
1.4m
But do you know how
the Pokémon Nuoh acts by nature?
Weight
75.0kg
How does Nuoh act by nature?
Dim-witted
Dainty
Violent
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
How does Nuoh act by nature?
A: Dim-witted
The answer is A: Dim-witted!
Nuoh is very dim-witted.
Even if it bumps its head
on riverbed boulders or boat hulls,
it just keeps on swimming
without a care.
Next episode
We’re headed to an island offshore,
seeking Entei of the Six Heroes!
Entei is the Volcano Pokémon.
Apparently, it’s found near volcanoes!
That means Achigator’s gonna be the star!
No, it’ll be the Water-type Welcamo!
Nyarote, let’s all try our hardest, okay?
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
A Fierce Fight With Entei! A War Cry of Fire!!