Pursuing an Entei sighting,
we’ve arrived in Area Zero!
It’s a mysterious place,
where many Paradox Pokémon live.
We’re hoping to meet
the real Entei of the Six Heroes this time!
Our hopes are rising!
What a sight!
Such a mysterious spot!
That was rough...
A picturesque view!
Everyone!
This is the place
where Entei was recorded!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
A Huge Battle! The Earth-Gouging Inferno
I see, so that happened
at the Shining Pond...
Then the legend claiming that you can
speak to people from the past was true...
But! Why didn’t you
tell me that yesterday?
U-Umm...
You didn’t give us
much chance to, I guess...
Um... Could I check the footage
from the observation camera one more time?
Yeah.
Here.
Thank you.
If only we could see
the whole thing a bit more clearly...
While past records
are vague on many points,
it’s clear that Entei have inhabited
these lands since ancient times.
I suspect that Lucius may have met
his Entei in these very lands, as well!
I believe the same.
Then, after parting with Lucius,
Entei returned to Area Zero...
And several days ago,
the observation camera got it on video.
I hope it’s actually
the Entei from the Six Heroes this time...
It’s gotta be!
Once we’re done eating, we’ll make our base here
and start by searching for tracks.
Okay!
Man...
Sitting and watching is a total drag...
We’re on a mission, you know.
Huh? Quit bossin’ me around, blockhead.
What?!
Huh?
Ugh! Pipe down,
for cryin’ out loud! Return!
Sheesh...
Huh?
Pagogo?
What is it?
Entei!
But... it looks kinda...
...different from the one
we saw in the Johto Region.
Like in the shape of its head...
If they’re resonating, that means...!
So it really is
Entei of the Six Heroes!
Guess they’re saying
it’s all up to you now, Liko.
Yeah!
We’re trying to go
to Rakua with Pagogo.
Oliva, Fire, Laplace, and Basagiri...
All of them became part of our crew
and came with us.
We want to bring all of you to the place
you made your promise with Lucius.
Entei, won’t you come with us, too?
An Ancient Monster Ball!
So you’ll join our crew?
Thank you! I’m sure Raku—
H-Huh?
Why’d you do that?!
Wonder if it’s saying
“Just try and take it back.”
Yup, exactly.
Huh?
We’ve had to win the approval of
each of the Six Heroes before they came with us.
So this must be Entei’s condition
for joining up with us.
Right.
But if we want to get that back...
Yeah.
No choice but to battle!
Utterly fascinating...
Not a chance I’m letting
an opportunity like this pass me by!
Entei is a Fire type.
Water, Ground, and Rock
are super effective against it.
Yeah. Meaning we should focus our attacks
around Achigator’s Stomping Tantrum, and...
Welcamo’s Aqua Break!
Got it.
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Welcamo, rush in!
What? It didn’t work?!
Aqua Break!
Aqua Break didn’t work either?!
He got burned?!
Here it comes, Liko!
Nyarote! Acrobatics!
No, Liko! Get back!
Huh?! Dodge, Nyarote!
You’ll get burned if you touch it.
Yeah.
That’s probably some move that
superheats its fur to strengthen its defense.
Our attacks don’t work...
And if you even touch it,
you take damage instead...
Then... what can we do?
It went away...
That move probably uses up
a whole lot of energy.
When the move ends,
that might be our chance.
Dot, have a Burn Heal.
Use it on Welcamo.
Wh-Wh-Whoa...
Th-Thanks.
What was that just now?
I’m certain that wasn’t
any move Entei uses...
Close-range attacks
are too dangerous for now.
We’ll push it to use that defensive move again with
Welcamo, Nyarote, and Achigator’s long-range attacks.
When that move runs out,
hit it with a Thunder Punch from Cap!
Good plan!
Yeah.
Okay!
Water Gun!
Use Stomping Tantrum!
Magical Leaf!
Keep it up with Water Gun!
Stomping Tantrum!
Magical Leaf!
Good work! Run around it!
Now! Thunder Punch!
Th-That barely did anything?!
Was that Dragon Pulse?!
Huh? A Dragon-type move?!
How can Entei do that?
I get it...
So that’s what’s going on...
Yeah, very well could be.
It seems you’ve reached
the same conclusion.
I thought something was off
from the moment I laid eyes upon it...
But now I’m certain of it.
Certain?
Of what?
What stands before you is no Entei.
That’s one of Area Zero’s
unique Pokémon...
A Paradox Pokémon!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
A Paradox Pokémon...
You mean it’s a different
Pokémon from Entei?
Strong visual similarity to certain other Pokémon
is said to be their distinguishing feature.
Though they may have commonalities,
they should be considered
entirely separate species of Pokémon.
Strong visual similarity...
Then the Rarecoil-looking guy
from yesterday was...?
Separate species...
But Ms. Rystal called it Entei...
The existence of Paradox Pokémon has only been
recognized thanks to research from recent years.
A hundred years ago,
it could easily have been mistaken for an Entei.
Here it comes!
Dodge it, Achigator!
Dodge and use Thunder Punch!
Just not very effective after all, huh?
If it’s a different Pokémon,
our approach to battling it has to change.
Dot, what’s your opinion?
Considering the moves and
battle match-ups we’ve seen so far...
It’s probably a Fire/Dragon type.
The only move we have that’s
super effective is Stomping Tantrum.
Plus, Cap’s Electric moves
barely have any effect.
It’s a tougher opponent than an Entei...
But that doesn’t change our plan!
Draw out its defensive move
with long-range attacks,
and when it runs out this time,
attack with Stomping Tantrum!
Got it!
Welcamo! Water Gun!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Huh? It’s not going for it?
Saying those aren’t even
worth guarding, huh?
What do we do, Dot?
Think, think, think!
Magical Leaf is a bad match-up...
Water Gun isn’t strong enough...
Is there any other way?
That’s it!
Welcamo, jump into the river!
Distract it with Shadow Clones!
What are you hoping to do?
Welcamo, fire a bunch of
Air Cutters from there!
More, more, more!
Is that...
...Aqua Cutter?
Whoa! That’s so cool!
Nice work, Welcamo!
There it is! The defensive move!
You’re up, Roy!
Leave it to me!
Achigator! Stomping Tantrum!
Stomping Tantrum hasn’t
dealt damage even once thus far...
But each time it fails, Stomping Tantrum’s
strength doubles due to the frustration!
The defense wore off!
Achigator! Go!
We did it!
Amazing!
It’s super effective!
All right! If we keep this up...
Marvelous!
Everyone!
One more time, let’s...!
Huh? What’s it doing?
Why, that’s...!
It’s the ability of Paradox Pokémon,
said to raise their skills via absorption of sunlight...
Ancient Activation!
Watch out! It’s planning something!
So hot!
What is that heat?!
Incredible...
It’s like an earth-gouging
pillar of fire...
Could it be?!
I assumed it was merely a brief note
on the Pokémon’s appearance, but...
I’ve worked out
the name of that Pokémon!
Its name, as listed
in the Scarlet Book, is...
...Gouging Inferno!
Gouging Inferno...
What an incredible attack!
Not good!
Cap! Shadow Clones!
Cap’s going to...!
Achigator! Nitro Charge!
Save Cap!
All right!
It’s so strong...
This Gouging Inferno...
This is fun... So much fun...
It’s fun?
When we’re backed into a corner?
It’s an unknown Pokémon,
with no available data...
But in the thick of battle, we’re uncovering
its ability and weaknesses bit by bit,
and working out how to fight back...
It’s just... Pokémon are so much fun!
Battles are so much fun!
I know how you feel!
Yeah, it’s fun!
We will figure it out...
A way to take down Gouging Inferno!
Yeah!
Huh? Gouging Inferno is acting...
...kinda weird.
Could it be confused?
Possible.
Could be a move like
Reversed Scale or Petal Dance,
which cause confusion
after the rampage ends.
In which case, our best chance
will be right after it uses that move.
Give it a try, Dot.
I’ll leave the plan up to you.
Okay!
First, we need to manage to
avoid that attack.
We’ll all launch long-range attacks in turn,
so it can’t hone in on one target.
Then, after the move ends,
it should get confused.
And that’s when...
We attack with a super effective
Stomping Tantrum, yeah?
No, that won’t work!
Dot?
That won’t work in this battle!
Lemme go!
What’s it matter!
It’d just be an itty bitty battle!
Our orders were only to monitor them.
And I’m tellin’ ya,
I’m just gonna give ‘em an itty bitty beating
in the confusion! They ain’t gonna see me!
Lemme go!
I see, so that’s what you’re thinking...
Yeah, sounds like it could work!
We’re gonna make it work!
Now then, how will this resolve?
Here it comes!
Nyarote, shine in full bloom!
Let’s go, Achigator!
Shine bright,
crystallization of our dreams!
Welcamo!
Glitz it up, go viral, and shine!
Keep your distance, Welcamo!
Don’t let it get near you!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Dodge it!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
Air Cutter!
Magical Leaf!
Flamethrower!
Should be about time...
Welcamo,
fire off Aqua Cutters like crazy!
It’s confused.
Now! Get out of the water, Welcamo!
Okay! Cap!
Thunder Punch!
And now that it’s soaking wet...!
Ooh!
Nyarote, grab the belt!
Gouging Inferno!
We got it!
If we get the belt back, we win!
Right?
Have we earned your approval now?
What is this?
A fragment of Pagogo’s memories.
So then... That’s Lucius?!
Ow, ow, ow...
You rascal.
Wait up!
Got it!
Looks like I win today, Entei!
You’re really good friends now, huh?
Befriending it was an uphill battle,
but it finally seems at ease around me.
I’m glad I came here and met Entei.
Or rather, I should say...
I’m grateful for every single meeting I have.
Now, let’s make for Rakua together!
Yeah!
What was that?
Thank you.
What we thought was an Entei
was really you all along, Gouging Inferno.
All right!
That just leaves the black Rekkuuza!
Yeah!
The black Rekkuuza!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Paradox Pokémon, Gouging Inferno.
Gouging Inferno
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Fire/Dragon
Gouging Inferno
Paradox Pokémon
Type: Fire/Dragon
A Pokémon with a distinctive
large and spiky head.
Height
3.5m
It’s said to get a boost
during certain weather,
Weight
590.0kg
but do you know which of
these types of weather that is?
In what weather does it get a boost?
Sunny
Cloudy
Rainy
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
In what weather does it get a boost?
A: Sunny
The answer is A: Sunny!
Apparently, it has an ability...
...that lets it activate energy
by absorbing sunlight.
Said ability is called Ancient Activation.
Next episode
Now Rekkuuza’s here?!
Hold on!
We just got done battling!
Nyarote and the others are tired out...
Pagogo...
We can still keep going, right?
This’s been my dream all along!
We can’t stop now, can we?
Yeah. If we all work together...!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
Crossing Beyond the Rainbow’s Glow
Crossing Beyond the Rainbow's Glow