If a Nuoh shows favor to water,
the water’s favor it shall know.
It seems the time has come
for a Forme Change.
Migh... Migh... Migh...
Mighty... G!
Migh!
It’s still pouring...
Aw, I was hoping
we’d get to play in the sea...
Doesn’t look like we’ll be going out
until the storm lets up...
Man, and I got all mega-prepped
to have some fun, too!
Yamirami, what’s wrong?
There ain’t nothin’
out there, though...?
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
A Storm, Followed By Surfing Surfugo
Armorgaw, hang in there!
Just a bit further...
If we can just make it out of this storm...
A yacht? A boat?
No.
It’s...
Mighty...
G!
G?
Young man!
Allow your weary Armorgaw to rest,
and ride atop my Samehada!
The storm is getting stronger! Hurry!
Return, Armorgaw!
Samehada! Aqua Jet!
Go!
Good boy, Samehada.
You saved me. I appreciate it...
Gramps? Mister Mighty...?
G!
Come on out.
Armorgaw, are you okay?
If the sky and the sea are out,
I’ll need to find some other way to get around...
Young man.
Do not be reckless.
Relax here and wait
for the storm to pass.
I’m no “young man”!
My name is Amethio.
My lower back is complaining...
I’d better take my leave soon.
Now then...
I haven’t got the time to relax.
This cave may lead somewhere.
Let’s check it out.
Are you okay?
Your face is so pale...
Are you eating properly?
To eat is to live!
If you do not eat,
your body and soul cannot grow!
Let me present...
Might Makes Rice!
Rice?
Nuoh! An ounce of prevention
is worth a pound of cure! Go!
Potatoes... Carrots...
Onions... Curry powder?
Take this.
With this, you can make curry rice,
and eat curry spectac-curry-ly.
Eat curry spectac-curry-ly?
What ever does that mean?
My friends! Farewell!
Have you ever
made curry rice before?
No... Never.
Surely you’ve at least boiled rice?
Well, I’ve roasted berries
over a fire...
Mighty G’s Deadly Hero Cookin-G!
My friends! When making curry rice,
first you must wash the rice.
Nuoh! Water Gun, come on!
Hero Rice Washing!
Is this all right, Mister Mighty...?
G!
To enhance the flavor, once you’ve washed it,
let it soak for around thirty minutes!
Use that time to prepare the curry!
Deadly Hero Peeling!
Samehada! Go!
My friends! Potato sprouts are toxic!
Take care to remove them!
Promise Mighty G that you will!
Soublades! Sword of Regrets!
He sucked all the nutrients
out of the carrot...
Is that all right, Mister Mighty...?
G!
Deadly Hero Onion Cutter!
What’s wrong?!
Nothing...
Are you crying?
Certainly not!
It’s the onion!
The onion stinging my eyes
is just ag-onion-izing!
The onion stinging your eyes
is just ag-onion-izing?
What ever does that mean...?
My, you’re soaking wet!
You’ll catch a cold like this.
Go and dry your clothes.
Migh? They’ll take quite a while
to dry like that!
Remember to wring out
your wet socks!
Deadly Hero Wringing!
I see! So that explains why
I could never get them to dry before...
Like this?
And to ensure
that your clothes don’t wrinkle...
Deadly Hero Slapping!
I see!
Is this good, Mister Mighty...?
G!
Armorgaw! Hurricane!
This isn’t good!
Incredible...
It’s dry already, Mister Mighty...
G!
Ooh... It really is curry...
My friends!
There are kids awaiting a hero
in these wide-open seas out here-oh,
so I ought to get going.
Thanks for all your help.
I’m used to eating alone.
What did I just hear...?
Deadly Hero Love & Delicious!
Let us all enjoy your first-ever curry
together, Amethio!
Let us dig in!
Let us dig in.
When the storm lets up,
where will you go?
I’d decided to look for
something that I could do.
The path I choose to follow
will be the right one...
I want to prove that to Grandfather!
Stopping during a storm
to eat a delicious meal with others...
That path, too, is right.
It really does feel nice
to dine with company, huh...?
I suppose this wasn’t half bad.
Good boy, Amethio!
Good boy!
Please do not treat me like a child.
Farewell! Amethio!
Thank you, Mister Mighty...
G!
It’s time we move as well!
Huh? What’s that?
A yacht?
A boat?
No, it’s...
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
What a lovely breeze!
Sun’s nice and bright, too.
I’m gonna head back!
You’re leaving already?
You ain’t even swum yet!
I’ve got a tenet
not to swim in the ocean.
“Tenet”...?
I’ve had plenty of fun already.
I wanna go make some shorts
of that collab I did with Nanjamo-neesan.
Make sure to replenish the water
you’ve lost through sweating!
Okay!
Huh?
Dot?
Wasn’t she going back to her room?
Found one!
A coin!
Gah! That Collecurei...!
It got you again?
Why’s it always me...?
Is something going on?
Everyone’s waiting.
For what?
For Surfugo.
Surfugo?!
This island gets some
gnarly waves after a storm,
so we can enjoy some rockin’ surfing
with a rockin’ Surfugo!
And you are...?
Hodad Guy!
Hodad...
...Guy...
Cap!
Are you going surfing too, Murdock?!
If they say some gnarly waves
are coming,
it’d be a real waste
to pass ‘em up!
Ain’t that right, Cap?
Where’s old man Landau?
No idea.
Probably off fishing
with Nuoh somewhere, I’d guess.
It’s here!
It’s Surfugo!
Surfugo. Treasure Pokémon.
Steel/Ghost type.
Its body seems to be
made up of a thousand coins.
It gets along well with others
and can make friends with anybody.
Coins?
So then,
Collecurei evolve into Surfugo?
Surfugo!
It’s the real thing!
Lemme take a photo with you!
Me, too!
Time for some
rockin’ surfing with Surfugo!
Yay!
Why don’t you guys go surfing, too?
You won’t have a whole lotta chances
to surf with a Surfugo!
Yeah, I’ll go for it!
Sounds like mega-fun!
I’ve never surfed before...
Maybe I can give it a try?
How about you, Dot?
I’ll pass!
Found one!
It got me again!
It’s not getting in now.
Found one!
We’re leaving, guys!
H-Huh?
Welcamo?
This is so awesome!
Wait, really...?
Wai...
Wait, really?!
Dot, you’re going surfing?!
Don’t have much choice.
I can’t exactly tell Water-type Pokémon
not to play in the sea...
Welcamo,
let’s have some fun together.
The biggest gnarly wave
of the season’s comin’ in!
It’s “Let’s Party Surfing Time”
with Surfugo!
Collecurei?!
Watch out!
If you fall into the ocean...
Guess I haven’t got a choice...
Just don’t control us
this time, you hear?
Collecurei!
That was a close one...
Are you okay?
Don’t push yourself too hard!
Here it comes!
Yay!
I’m feeling mega-rockin’!
Go!
Woo-hoo!
Welcamo...
We’re actually surfing!
It really is made out of coins...
Are you having us gather coins because
you want to become a Surfugo? Is that it?
See you again!
Bye-bye!
Surfugo!
You’re the best!
You’re glowing!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow...
Ow, ow...
I didn’t just hurt my back...
My knees are aching, too.
I really mustn’t overexert myself...
Old man Landau!
Where have you been?
Oh, here and there...
We got to go surfing
with Surfugo!
It was so much fun,
wasn’t it, Dot?
Dot?
Something I’ve been thinking over this whole time...
How can I stop getting controlled by you?
I used to idolize the way
Nanjamo-neesan shined, too,
so I think I kinda get how you feel.
I’ll gather coins for you!
You don’t mind, do you?
Welcamo? Nakanuchan?
Collecurei...
Can I catch you?
Come on out.
Collecurei, you don’t need to
control us anymore.
We’re friends now.
Ooh, you befriended Collecurei?
Yeah. Now I don’t need to worry about
Collecurei controlling...
Found one! A coin!
Collecurei!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Armor Pokémon, Banguirus!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Armor Pokémon
Evil
Banguirus
Armor Pokémon
Rock
Evil
Raising Sand
Banguirus
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Armor Pokémon
Raising Sand
Banguirus
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Armor Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Enormous energy is stored
in the red bit on its torso!
Mega Banguirus
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Armor Pokémon
Rock
Evil
Raising Sand
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Now that it’s exposed,
it can unleash even more intense power!
It acts solely on an instinctual
urge to destroy, so be careful.
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Oh...
Be very careful!
Next episode
So our next stop, Manpuuku Town,
has some mega-tasty stuff, yeah?!
Yeah, I hear they’ve got a market.
Murdock’s been thinking up lots of dishes
to decide on what to cook,
and Achigator said he’d do
a hundred knee lifts to empty his stomach!
Huh? So those are knee lifts
Achigator’s doing...?
Beats me!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Mega-Awesome?!
The Unopenable Dark Ball
Huh?! You mean summin’s
gonna happen to my Dark Ball?!
Mega-Awesome?!
The Unopenable Dark Ball
Beats me!