What is it?
Seems like it wants to go that way.
Wonder what’s over there...
Fusube City is in that direction.
A ton of Dragon Tamer
clan members live there.
Dragon Tamer?
I think Mr. Hassaku
was one of them, too.
That’s gotta mean
they’re something special!
Something wrong?
There’s a post
from about a year ago...
...where someone says they saw a black Rekkuuza
in the rocky mountains of Fusube City.
Huh?
But there’s no photos or anything.
They could’ve just been seeing things.
A black Rekkuuza sighting in a place
that’s home to a Dragon Tamer clan...
One year ago...
That’s when we split up!
Let’s go, Yamirami!
Ult?!
The black Rekkuuza...
belongs to me!
The sighting was
a whole year ago, you realize?!
We should go check it out, too!
Yeah! If they’re Dragon-type specialists,
we might be able to dig up some clues there!
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Clash! The Dragon Biker Gang
The time’s finally come
for me to obtain the black Rekkuuza!
It’s getting late, Ult.
We should call it for today.
If we head into the rocky mountains now,
it’ll be night before we’re there. Plus, everyone’s tired.
Lucario!
Let’s go gather firewood!
That was mega-close!
You nearly deceived me yet again!
Huh?
Roy! You were gonna head off and leave me behind
while I was asleep again, weren’t you?!
It’d be dangerous
if we got lost at night!
Hah! I’m not falling for that!
U-Umm...
I’m gonna go on ahead of you,
and then I’ll catch the black Rekkuuza!
Suit yourself.
Ult!
Is he going to be okay...?
I’m mega-lost!
Hey!
Ult!
You came back?
Huh? What?
Great timing!
Could you help me make the pancakes?
That’s it! You’re doing great!
Careful, Masquernya!
You’ll make me spill it!
So, Ult... Why do you want
to befriend the black Rekkuuza?
‘Cause I wanna be
the mega-strongest, of course.
The strongest?
I’ve gotta get stronger...
And win the approval of...
I see. You’ve got your reasons
for wanting to be stronger, huh?
Huh?! What’s wrong?!
N-Nothing’s wrong!
Let’s dig in!
Ult! Come down!
Look! See? It’s Yamirami!
Huh? Yamirami!
Come and eat with us, Ult!
I’m not hungry!
I can tell that you are!
Shut up!
Did I mess up with Ult, somehow?
He’s just embarrassed
he got lost and wound up back here.
He’ll come down eventually.
Traitor.
What am I supposed to do?
This is mega-throwing off my groove...
Tasty!
How could they let these go to waste
after working so hard on ‘em?!
Mega-tasty!
Geez, can’t you keep it down
this early in the morning?
Ult! You ate all the pancakes?!
They were mega-tasty!
Right, Yamirami?
Why would you eat them?!
Why...? They were leftovers.
Liko made those
as breakfast for everyone!
Huh?
Ah, but... we can just have berries
we find along the way for breakfast. Right?
Ult! If you’re going to come with us,
you’ve gotta keep us in mind, too!
I-I’m the one doing you
a favor by coming along!
You oughta be accommodatin’ me!
What?!
U-Umm...
If only they could get along...
Let’s ask that man!
Excuse me!
Where’s the black Rekkuuza?!
Huh?!
It was sighted in this area.
Would you know anything about that?
No, doesn’t ring a bell.
More importantly, the Dragon Biker Gang
hangs around this area, so be careful.
The Dragon Biker Gang...?
They’re outcasts
from the Dragon Tamer clan.
Beating people up
just for crossing eyes with them...
Extorting people for Monster Balls...
There’s endless rumors about them.
Apparently, their hideout is over there,
and now they won’t let anyone near it.
We’ve come this far,
so we’ve got to keep going.
Yeah!
Honk-honk! Honk-honk!
Mototokage?!
But they shouldn’t be in this region...
The way of the invincible
roaring bike!
Let us show you
dragon flowers in full bloom!
Ready to battle!
Capes are the best!
We are the Dragon Biker Gang!
Ride on!
So you’re the...!
You’re on the Dragon Biker Gang’s turf!
There’s two paths you can take.
Either leave this place right this second,
or be blown away by the supremely dazzlin’ Mototokage
we went all the way to Paldea to catch!
Make your choice! Ride on!
Ride on!
Have you seen a Rekkuuza
around here, by chance?
Ack!
Rekkuuza, you say?
We don’t know nothin’
about no black Rekkuuza!
Huh? Did you say “black” Rekkuuza?
You fool!
Whoops!
Do you know something about it?
We’re searching for
the black Rekkuuza!
We said we don’t know nothin’!
We’re the black Rekkuuza’s friends!
Huh?
Yer full of it!
We’re not lying!
We went to Rakua together!
Rakua?!
Where’s that?
Ain’t that the health spa
that opened in Uirou City recently?
Huh? You went to a health spa
with the black Rekkuuza?!
No, we didn’t!
See? You were lying!
We really did go to Rakua together!
That’s no fair!
What is a “health spa”?!
You be quiet, Ult!
Could you be with Team Wiggle?
“Wiggle”...?
If you’re part of that Team Wiggle
messing with our turf, we’ll make ya pay!
We’ve got nothing to do with that!
So, looks like you do wanna
get blown away by our Mototokage!
Mototokage! Dragon Dive!
Ride on!
Lucario, dodge it!
We just want to see
the black Rekkuuza!
If you know something about it,
please tell us!
See it to do what?
What else? I’m gonna obtain it!
Obtain it to do what?!
I’m gonna become the mega-strongest!
Yamirami! Hell Thrust!
Hah! I can handle
these three all on my own!
Just try us!
Mototokage! Dragon Pulse!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
You’re girls?!
What’s the problem with that, huh?!
I don’t like your tone!
Well?!
Looks like you found out
how to really get on our nerves.
Mototokage! Lose your cool!
Dragon Dive! Ride on!
Ride on!
Yamirami! Hell Thrust!
Yamirami!
Hang in there, Yamirami!
Now clear off already!
Let’s move.
Ult... You’re too reckless.
I wasn’t bein’ reckless!
Pagogo?
Pagogo...
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Achigator,
make sure you don’t eat too much.
I like you...
I really like you.
Wiggle! I love you!
Smooch!
The Miniryu!
He’s stealing the eggs and Pokémon?!
I won’t let anyone
get away with hurting Pokémon!
Yamirami! Shadow Strike!
Yamirami!
Achigator!
Seriously...
Return, Achigator!
Wiggle! Wiggle!
Could you be... Team Wiggle?!
Life’s a wiggling road!
Time wiggles when you’re having fun!
Wiggling is justice!
Um...
We are... Team Wiggle!
And you bunch aren’t wiggling at all!
Meaning... Are you part of
that Dragon Biker Gang?!
Huh?
Make ‘em wiggle, Arbok!
Thunder Fang!
Lucario! Metal Claw!
Roy! Stay out of this!
I’m more than enough
to deal with this guy!
There’s another one!
Habunake! Sludge Bomb!
The eggs!
Masquernya! Are you okay?!
Ult! Didn’t you want to
become the strongest?
The way you are now... Thinking you can handle
everything by yourself... You’re not strong at all!
You’re just pretending to be strong!
You’ll never be the strongest like that!
Lucario! Cap!
We’re gonna protect those eggs no matter what!
You’re right...
Let’s go, Roy!
Yeah!
Yamirami!
Break past your max
with outrageous power!
Mega Evolve!
Gain true power
and surpass yourself!
Mega Evolve!
Liko! Stop these guys
from getting away!
Got it!
Masquernya!
These little ones need...
Roy! Ult!
Lucario! Luster Cannon!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Wiggle! You’ll regret this!
All right!
We did it!
Thank goodness.
You guys...
Let us thank you
for protecting the Miniryu eggs.
Thanks.
Wait!
If you know something,
please tell us!
The black Rekkuuza
saved us one year ago!
And we haven’t seen it since!
One year ago...
Please tell us anything you know,
no matter how small!
Dazzling!
Some mighty fine eyes ya got there.
I like you.
Get on.
Huh? So there is
something you can tell us?
Thank you very much!
The day I obtain the black Rekkuuza
and become the mega-strongest is nigh!
I don’t like your tone.
You’re a waste.
Hold— Wait!
Rekkuuza!
Is this for real...?
Rekkuuza woke up...
Looks like it’s okay!
I’m relieved... Just so relieved!
It arrived at this shrine one year ago.
It’s been sleeping here ever since.
What is this?
A shrine for Dragon-type Pokémon
to refresh their energy at.
We spread rumors about how anyone
who comes near this place will have a bad time...
...to make sure everyone steered clear.
If people found out the black Rekkuuza was here,
they’d kick up a huge fuss. It’d be a real pain.
Then you’ve been protecting
the black Rekkuuza...
Thank you!
Only natural.
We are from the Dragon Tamer clan.
Rekkuuza!
The Rakurium, which should be gone,
is still out there in the world.
We want to get rid of the Rakurium!
To fulfill our promise to Mr. Lucius!
This time, you can leave it to us!
Yeah! Thanks!
Have a nice long rest here
so you can get better soon.
Hey, Rekkuuza!
Ult?!
How did you get in here?
I will obtain you
and become the mega-strongest.
What are you talking abo—?
Hey!
Rekkuuza...
Tough luck for you!
You’re not gonna get to be my friend just yet!
Huh?
The only Rekkuuza worth my time...
is the strongest one there is!
I don’t need one so weak
it’s lying down for a nap somewhere like this!
Got it? If you wanna be my friend,
hurry up and get better already!
I’m gonna get way, way stronger, too!
Please take good care of Rekkuuza.
Leave it to us!
We swear on our capes
that we’ll keep it safe!
Ride on!
Honk-honk! Honk-honk!
Really...?!
But I’m sure it’ll get better.
What should we do now?
How about going to Paldea?
Paldea?
I think we’d better meet Murdock in person
and discuss what our best next move is.
Agreed! I wanna tell him
we reformed the Rising Voltteccers, too.
But why Paldea, then?
Murdock’s working at
Ms. Kaede’s Soapberry place now.
Ooh, is he?
I’ll leave right away too,
so let’s meet up in Cercle Town!
Okay!
All right!
With that settled, let’s get going!
Huh? You’re coming too?
Naturally! ‘Cause we’re friends!
Right, Liko?
Huh?
Yeah!
Let’s go! Roy! Liko!
Where are you going?
Wh-Where...?!
You’re hopeless with directions,
so just follow me.
I suppose they do get along...
in their own unique way.
Umm...
Where did I put my socks?!
Nakanuchan, stop it!
Who’s calling now,
when I’m in such a rush?!
Nanjamo?!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
The Parent-Child Pokémon, Garoola!
Parent-Child Pokémon
Garoola
Normal
Early Bird
Scrappy
Garoola
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Parent-Child Pokémon
Early Bird
Scrappy
What’s it gonna look like
when it Mega Evolves?!
Garoola
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
The kid in her pouch
temporarily grows up!
Mega Garoola
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Parent-Child Pokémon
Parent-Child Affection
Normal
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
It fights to protect its mother,
which just makes its mother
get fired up even more!
Oh, what a rascal you are...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
They can pull off perfectly synced
combos with their parent-child bond!
Hey! Hey! Madam Dot!
Next episode
Seems like a mysterious Pokémon
is making mischief in Hakkou City!
Huh? Mischief?
I hear that Pokémon is causing trouble
for people walking through the city!
Now that is a cause for alarm.
We’ve gotta do something!
And as for whozat Pokémon...?
Yeah? Yeah?
And so!
You’re keeping it secret?!
But I wanna know...
Next time on Pocket Monsters...
The Prankster Maggyo’s Nice Smile?
And she said it anyway...
Whozat? This was Nanjamo!
The Prankster Maggyo's Nice Smile?