Thank you, Soublades.
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Carbou's Wish
This is Amethio-sama’s house.
We’ll be safe here.
We can talk inside.
Um... Are you sure we should go in there
when Amethio isn’t even home...?
Don’t worry about that.
His father, former Director Crave,
said we’re free to use this place however we wish.
His father...
He’s concerned for
Amethio-sama’s safety, like us.
Thank you.
The events at Mt. Kumuri one year ago
shook up our organization.
Spinel took over for Gibeon-sama,
and now the Explorers and Exceed
are just puppets dancing to his will.
Hamber-sama covertly ordered us
to take on the duty of searching for Amethio-sama.
He is the only one
who can oppose Spinel.
Where is Amethio now?
We have no idea.
We even combed this estate
for clues, but alas...
But he’s got to be hiding somewhere.
Can you think of any likely places?
M-Me?!
You may’ve been enemies,
but Amethio-sama approved of you.
Please give us your thoughts!
If you were Amethio-sama,
where do you think you’d go?
If I was Amethio...
This...
Is this Carbou... his Soublades?
Apparently, his father kept so busy...
...that Amethio-sama
spent all his time with Carbou.
He was an irreplaceable partner
to Amethio-sama.
Amethio when he was young...
The woman in the painting
on the stairwell...
His mother.
Apparently, she died in an accident
when Amethio-sama was young.
Where were these taken?
I remember us going there
on a family outing.
Yeah... The one time we did
anything you might call an “outing.”
I was the one
who took those photos.
Where?
Understood.
I’ll send you a message right n—
I’ll send it later. Just sit tight.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Director Spinel!
What brings you all the way out here?
I was wondering how you were doing,
and figured I’d stop by and see you
while I was here on inspection.
Well, then...
Those Strong Spheres...
Are they actually...?
Worry not.
Everything is proceeding smoothly.
Just got it!
What’s it say?
A nature-rich archipelago
off the eastern coast of Hakkou City...
He says the family
cruised out there together.
Apparently, that’s the same island where
Amethio-sama met Carbou.
Amethio sincerely cherishes that place...
If Spinel was after him,
and he’d be in danger no matter where he went...
Let’s go check it out!
Just leave everything
to us ‘til we get there.
Well, I say that,
but this thing runs on autopilot.
It’ll still be a while,
so how about you get some rest?
Masquernya, are you hungry?
I thought this might happen!
Err, I prepared something for you as well,
so please be my guest.
Thank you!
It’s the least I could do, considering
this might just lead us to Amethio-sama!
What’s wrong?
How did the two of you
meet Amethio?
That was... well...
I am a new member of the Explorers,
starting today!
My name is Zir!
Likewise. I’m Conia.
As for your assignment here...
Man, talk about rotten luck.
We’re stuck babysitting some little snot...
You shouldn’t be complaining.
It’s Gibeon-sama’s grandson.
The heir to the fortune.
If we can slip into his good graces,
we’ll be promoted in no time.
I getcha. You’ve got a point there.
But soon, we saw who he really was.
I’m Amethio.
Don’t get in my way.
His talent for completing missions
with poise and precision.
His discipline
in never neglecting his training.
Good work. We’re pulling out.
Sir!
We saw that he was the real deal...
...and soon vowed
our allegiance to him.
He didn’t have any faith in us at first,
but eventually considered us friends.
Which is why we want
to aid Amethio-sama once more.
Amethio...
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Already been a year since then, huh...?
We should be far enough out
to be safe for now.
Amethio-sama. Let’s head back to HQ,
so we can consider our next moves.
No. You two head back
to the Explorers on your own.
Hamber will work something out for you.
And you, Amethio-sama...?
Sorry.
Let me be alone.
Stop!
You’re Amethio, right?
You’re coming with us!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
I won’t cause any trouble.
Will you let me rest here a while?
I couldn’t save Grandfather.
“Follow the path of your own beliefs”...
Those were the orders
Grandfather gave me...
But I don’t know
what I ought to seek.
Grandfather is gone.
I can’t rely on Hamber.
Even those two
who were always near...
I couldn’t even show my face
to my own father.
There’s nobody left.
It’s like you’ve found a little brother!
Grow big and strong someday
so you can protect Amethio, okay?
What am I thinking...?
Have I been found?!
Liko!
Amethio! There he is!
Amethio-sama!
You guys...
So you’ve been living in there?
Yes.
I’m just glad to see you’re okay.
Sorry for not contacting you.
Spinel’s hunters were relentless.
You caught it?
Yeah. It promised to protect me.
Protect you...
Amethio-sama!
Please take back the Explorers and Exceed!
Exceed? What do you mean?
Your father was ousted from his seat as Director,
and now Spinel’s doing whatever he wants.
The world’s decided to brand the Rising Voltteccers
as villains thanks to Spinel’s lies, too.
Our truth was stolen away.
Sounds like something he’d do.
Listen. The Rakurium isn’t gone.
That’s impossible...
Spinel’s trying to spread these tools called
Strong Spheres, which make use of Rakurium!
So extraordinarily foolish...
We, the Rising Voltteccers,
are trying to stop him.
It was our promise with Lucius...
This time, we want to
completely eliminate the Rakurium!
I see. I understand what’s going on.
But there’s nothing I can do.
Amethio-sama!
Now’s the time to stand up!
For your father’s sake, too!
It’s pointless!
Now that I’ve lost Grandfather...
And the Explorers... I’m powerless.
Are you going to give up?
You can’t just give up
after hitting one stumbling block!
You’re the one who taught me that!
Carbou?
Carbou...
Are you saying you want to battle?
Give it up.
You can hardly expect
to match Soublades.
Amethio!
I want you to battle Carbou!
Did you not hear me?
There’s no way that—
We won’t know that for sure
unless we try!
Very well.
Soublades.
Don’t blame me
if you wind up in tears.
Carbou! Ember!
If we’re short on power, then...
Carbou, get in close to Soublades!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Dodge it!
Keep it up! Psycho Cutter!
Even getting close
is going to be hard...
Naturally.
Their size and power are worlds apart.
We’ve still got options!
Carbou! Clear Smog!
Poison moves are
not very effective on Soublades.
But... I suppose this was your real goal.
Now! Ember!
Behind you!
Carbou!
Ghost Dive...
When did he call for that...?
That’s enough.
Put it back in its ball.
Huh?
It’s still...?!
That’s enough already!
Carbou!
It’s not giving up...
Carbou will never give up!
Aim for Soublades!
Psycho Cutter!
It dodged!
Ember!
You did it, Carbou!
Landing a single hit is hardly...
Soublades is the same...
Soublades...
Carbou! Ember!
Is that the end?
You really tried your best, Carbou.
I warned you...
You couldn’t have won.
Amethio...
Thank you.
Carbou wanted to battle Soublades...
...and I didn’t want to let it down.
We’ll be even stronger next time!
Not giving up, huh...?
Huh?
Zir. Conia.
Sorry, but I can’t go with you.
Amethio-sama!
You are Explorers.
There are moves you can make
from the inside.
Things that I can’t do...
But you can.
I think I’ll start by looking for
something that I can do.
Yes, sir!
Then... Take this.
That’s...
It’s from Hamber-sama.
His Zygarde Cell. It’s for you, Amethio-sama.
So he wants me to gather
Grandfather’s Zygarde...?
Amethio.
Though our paths might differ,
I believe in the path that you choose.
That concludes our report.
Fine work.
Take care on your way back.
Sir!
I’m glad you are safe.
Yep, it should be all better now.
Thank you, Molly.
Isn’t that great, Carbou?
Carbou had a nice battle.
Huh? You can tell?
You bet.
Liko!
Are you here?
There she is!
Ship maintenance is gonna go a bit longer,
so how ‘bout we head out and have some fun?
Ooh, good idea!
Hey!
If you’re goin’ somewhere,
I’m comin’ with ya!
Don’t scare us like that, Ult!
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolving today is
the Hermit Crab Pokémon, Yadoran!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Hermit Crab Pokémon
Psychic
Yadoran
Hermit Crab Pokémon
Water
Psychic
Oblivious
Own Pace
Yadoran
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Hermit Crab Pokémon
Water
Oblivious
Own Pace
Yadoran
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Abilities
Hermit Crab Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
The Mega Evolution energy
has fully concentrated into its Shellder tail,
Mega Yadoran
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Hermit Crab Pokémon
Water
Psychic
Shell Armor
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
turning it into
an impenetrable suit of armor!
Since the Shellder grew huge
and swallowed the Yadon whole,
you might think
it’d get pretty cramped...
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
...but it seems like
it’s pretty comfy in there.
Next episode
Where’s a coin?
Coin, coin, coin, coin, coin...
There!
Collecurei!
You’re gathering coins
for Collecurei again?
Why is it always me...?
Ack, something’s coming...
A yacht?
A boat?
No, it’s...!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
A Storm, Followed By Surfing Surfugo