The Rising Voltteccers, a band of adventurers
led by Friede, continue their journey.
The awoken Terapagos was a peculiar Pokémon
that wasn’t even in the Pokémon Index.
Terapagos hopes to find Rakua.
But to do that, we must find
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes...
...and recover Terapagos’s power.
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we’re headed to the Paldea Region.
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s a livestream from Gurumin!
So let’s have some more fun
learning about Pokémon today—
Huh? You can’t hear m—
Ack, no way!
Are you okay?
What happened?!
Gah! Hold on a— Whoa!
I-I’m coming in!
I’m not looking!
Gurumin is Gurumin!
There’s nobody inside her!
Well, today’s stream is canceled...
Our next stop is Tetsuron Town.
Stock up on any supplies we’re lacking.
Nice, Tetsuron Town!
I was running low on iron for ship repairs!
Tetsuron Town?
A town famous for industrial products,
including machines.
I see.
If you’re going into town,
get me a mic!
A condenser-type
unidirectional cardioid!
H-Huh? Hold on,
I don’t think I got all that...
It’s a kind of mic!
I can’t stream without it!
I don’t know
anything about that stuff...
Um... Err...
If you like,
why not come with us?
Huh?
No, that’s just...
Good idea! Come with us!
No way!
Dot already has so much to do!
She couldn’t possibly
go into town to shop!
Oh! There it is!
There’s smoke!
Dot?!
I’ve decided...
I’m going shopping with you.
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
Kanuchan and the Hammer of Her Obsessions
Glad you were able to get your mic, Dot.
Well... Of course I could handle this much.
Where’s she going?
I guess we’ll just have to follow her.
Hey! What’s all this?
The specialty shop district.
Stores here sell more niche stuff.
Sounds like fun!
Let’s take a look!
Oh! Wait!
Don’t run off on your own...
Geez.
Is this an old TV?
It’s so bulky...
Is there something inside it?
Wow!
This is how people
used to listen to music!
What’s this?
Might make a good prop
for a video.
Yeah.
I’ll take this!
Right away, ma’am.
Huh? Liko? Roy?
Sheesh, where did they go?
I told them not to
run off on their own...
No.
If I call them,
they’ll think I got lost.
Hey! You again?!
Huh?
Let go already!
How many times do I have to tell you?!
This iron belongs to us!
You can’t just go making
hammers out of it!
All right? You understand?
Don’t come back again!
Here.
You okay?
Uh...
H-H-Hold on!
I just bought that!
Who are you?
Kanuchan. Metalsmith Pokémon.
Fairy/Steel type.
It pounds scrap iron to make a hammer.
It remakes the hammer again and again
until it’s satisfied with the result.
Turning a mic into a hammer...
Geez.
What a weirdo.
Dot!
Where are you?
Over here!
Where did you go?
We thought you got lost.
You’re the ones who were lost.
Wha—?
We’re back!
Welcome back!
Everything go okay? You didn’t get hurt?
You had me so worried!
You went shopping!
I’m so proud!
You’re fussing too much.
All right!
Today, we’re gonna have a party!
Whatcha craving?
I want curry!
A curry party sounds nice!
But we had curry yesterday...
The waves are still.
But I sense a storm approaching.
Is a secret storm in store, hmm?
A storm, in store-hmm...
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
All right, what should I tend to first
now that I’ve got all that iron?
The plumbing in wet areas?
The ceilings?
Nah, it’s gotta be the stuff in the engine room.
It’s all pretty worn down.
What?!
Who did this?!
I won’t be mad, so fess up!
Looks like you’re already mad...
Murdock! You didn’t turn it all
into pots and frying pans, did you?!
Huh?! Of course not!
Then... Molly?
What use would I have for iron?
Well, you’ve got a point, but...
Then who could’ve...?
Iron...
Could it be...?
What’s this?
Did a Pokémon do this?
But Kanuchan
wouldn’t have done this...
Huh? Kanuchan?
Why are you here?
You came to show me this?
It’s a nice hammer.
Take good care of it.
There’s no way
you would’ve taken it.
Which means someone else
must be behind it, but...
Dot, who is that?
Oh, um...
This is Kanuchan.
She came to show me her hammer.
She loves iron,
and turns any that she finds into hammers.
What’s that?
Murdock...
A Pokémon that loves iron.
Iron?
No! Well, that’s not wrong, but—
Is this the culprit
behind the missing iron?!
After her!
Right!
Hey!
It wasn’t her!
Wait!
Nyahoja!
This way!
Wait!
Please, wait!
She’s quick!
What’s wrong, Liko?
Murdock says she’s the culprit!
You’re not getting past us, either!
What’s all this?
She’s the culprit!
Culprit?
Hold it!
You’ve got it all wrong!
It wasn’t Kanuchan!
She didn’t take the ship’s iron!
Kanuchan isn’t the culprit!
She just came here to show me
her cherished hammer.
She just came here to see me!
Plus, there was a huge hole back there.
Something else came aboard the ship.
The real culprit!
Yeah, Dot’s right.
Kanuchan’s not the culprit.
Friede...
What makes you think so?
The iron was never stolen.
It was eaten.
The scraps left behind
show Pokémon bite marks.
And Kanuchan aren’t known to eat iron.
You don’t have to run anymore.
It’s okay.
Everyone understands now.
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
The answer is Mimizuzu!
That’s the culprit?!
Mimizuzu. Earthworm Pokémon.
Steel type.
It lives in arid deserts.
It maintains its metal body
by consuming iron from the soil.
When did you set that trap?
It’s bigger than I expected.
Here it comes!
The hammer!
Kanuchan.
Let’s get your hammer back!
You cherish it.
It's your favorite, right?
Let’s go!
Hold on!
Dot?!
Everyone!
You cut the anchor, didn’t you?!
And now you’re taunting us!
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
It’s surprisingly nimble.
Dot!
Where’s Mimizuzu?
Looks like it’s underground.
Dot! Don’t worry about us!
Get Kanuchan her hammer back!
Right!
Self switch, on!
Kuwassu, use Water Gun!
Of course...
Kuwassu, use Water Gun over there!
That’s it!
Oh?
Again! Water Gun!
Dot has some sort of plan.
Keep it up! Water Gun!
I get it.
She’s trapping the Mimizuzu!
What do you mean?
Mimizuzu is a Pokémon
that rusts easily when it gets wet.
So that’s why it’s only
crawling on the dry ground!
Good thinking, Dot.
That’s why she didn’t
soak the ground surrounding her!
To lure it in!
You fell for it!
Kuwassu! Pound!
Now, Kanuchan!
She did it!
Nice one!
Kanuchan!
That was amazing, Kanuchan!
Kanuchan, I’m sorry for
chasing you around earlier.
I’m sorry, too.
Well then, take care.
Don’t let anyone else
take your favorite hammer!
Okay, let’s go.
Yeah.
What is it that I’m supposed
to say at times like this?
Do you really want to
come with me?
Kuwassu...
Kanuchan...
Would you mind if I caught you?
Thank you.
Come on out!
Let’s be good friends, Kanuchan.
Now the ship needs even more repairs.
But we’ve gained something
even more valuable, haven’t we?
Yeah, something priceless.
Kids sure grow up quick.
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s a livestream from Gurumin!
Sorry about last time.
But now my setup’s back up and running!
Plus, I’ve got great news!
Allow me to introduce
my new friend!
This is Kanuchan!
What do you think?
Isn’t that hammer super cool?
Iron’s always drawing
Kanuchan’s eyes!
She’ll make a hammer
out of anything.
Huh?
Hold on! Hold on!
Hey—
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Metalsmith Pokémon, Kanuchan.
Kanuchan
Metalsmith Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Steel
Kanuchan
Metalsmith Pokémon
Type: Fairy/Steel
The hammer Kanuchan holds is handmade.
Height
0.4m
Weight
8.9kg
Do you know what she collects
to make her hammer?
What does she collect to make her hammer?
Wood
Metal
Rocks
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Pokémon with "don" in their names!
Let's have Roy show us how it's done!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Friede here! This'll be a snap!
Pokémon with "don" in their names
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it's Lizardon!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
What does she collect
to make her hammer?
B: Metal
What does she collect
to make her hammer?
B: Metal
The answer is B: Metal!
The primary material
in her hammers is metal, such as iron.
She remakes them over and over again,
so she can often be seen in places with lots of scrap iron.
Where there’s metal,
there must also be Kanuchan!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
What’s this?
Nyahoja is acting weird.
She snuck off the ship and headed
into the forest... What happened?
While looking for Nyahoja,
Liko arrives at a mysterious facility.
What’s going on here?
Nyahoja’s past will now come to light!
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Farewell, Nyahoja?
You’re kidding, right? Right?