My name is Liko.
The drive to discover, the drive to learn...
These are the feelings
that set us on our journey.
Terapagos, who awoke from
my mysterious pendant,
was a peculiar Pokémon
that wasn’t even in the Pokémon Index.
Terapagos hopes to find Rakua.
But to do that, we must find
the Pokémon known as the Six Heroes...
...and recover Terapagos’s power.
We are the Rising Voltteccers...
To seek out the remaining
three of the Six Heroes...
And to uncover the mysteries
surrounding Terapagos...
...we’re headed to the Paldea Region.
Ahh...
Weather’s so nice you’d never believe
it was storming yesterday!
Right, Cap?
I-It’s all torn up...
Did a branch fly into it
or something?
Okay! Let’s fix it!
Orio should have
the sewing kit with her.
And pass her a message for me.
“Counting on you
to inspect the rest of the ship.”
Got it!
That just leaves...
What’s up?
Friede. Since we’re going to be here a while,
am I fine to give the Pokémon check-ups?
Yeah, sounds good.
The calm after the storm.
It may appear a time of peace.
But one man’s joy
is another’s sorrow.
So then, to which side
shall our scales tip today?
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
An SOS From a Wakkanezumi?
Okay, you’ve got
a clean bill of health.
Huh? Liko...
What is it?
I heard you were doing check-ups.
Could you take a look at Mibrim?
Mibrim?
She seems out of sorts, somehow...
It was probably yesterday’s storm.
She was frightened
by a storm once before.
Right...
If only we could do something
to help her mood...
That’s good,
we got a smile out of her.
What a relief.
That looks nice and fluffy, Mibrim.
I get the feeling Lucky and Mibrim
might be kindred spirits.
Good work, everyone.
What’s wrong?
Did you have a hard time
in the engine room yesterday?
You really buckled down
through that storm.
I’ll give you a check-up.
Are you okay?
Lucky, please see to Lizardon.
Amazing!
It perked back up in an instant!
Next up is Tsubotsubo.
Mibrim?
Lucky.
There’s a thorn stuck in it.
Don’t worry. I’ll have it right out.
See?
You were right! It’s so tiny.
Okay, that just leaves...
What is it?
Maybe she’s trying to imitate
Lucky’s Healing Pulse?
I guess Lucky’s
got a cute little apprentice.
Hope you do figure out Healing Pulse.
You can do it, Mibrim!
What is it?
Something going on outside?
Lucky!
A Wakkanezumi.
It’s hurt.
Tell me about Wakkanezumi.
Wakkanezumi. Couple Pokémon.
Normal type.
They use their incisors to cut up bits of
useful nesting material, then make off with them.
The pair sticks together
no matter what.
“The pair”?
So there should be another one?
But... It’s nowhere nearby.
This could be an emergency.
Don’t worry, Mibrim.
Mibrim is scared...
She must be taking in
this little one’s feelings.
For now, I’ve administered
some first aid.
Let’s go back to the infirmary
and have it rest.
Then we just need to
find the other one.
Hey!
Is it saying “Follow me”?
Is the other Wakkanezumi
in the forest?
The storm yesterday
must’ve knocked it over.
Your partner is in there?
It’s feeling weak,
judging by that cry.
Might be hurt.
We have to hurry and save it.
Ready, and...!
No good.
It won’t even budge!
If we could widen this gap...
Nyahoja!
Let’s go, Nyahoja! Scratch!
Looking good.
Keep it up!
No use...
I might be able to fit.
Could you give it a shot?
Yes.
Mibrim, can you wait out here for me?
Got it. Once we save Wakkanezumi,
we’ll head straight back out.
Be careful.
Right.
Where could it be?
There!
Molly, if you could...
Okay.
What a relief.
What’s wrong?
You saw us pull your friend out, right?
Molly and Lucky are looking after it.
It couldn’t be...
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Liko? What’s going on?
Hurry on out.
R-Right...
Mibrim, this must be hard for you...
How about you go back without me?
Molly.
There could be more
poor little ones hurt in there!
Huh?
I’ll go and look!
Look after Mibrim!
Hey, Liko! Hold on!
Don’t be reckless!
Sorry! I’ll be right back!
Liko!
What is it, Lucky?
You want to bring that egg
down to them?
In that case...
All set.
I leave them in your hands.
A fork...
Which way should we go?
A-Are you okay?
What do I do?
Maybe I should
turn back for now...
Mibrim?!
Didn’t you go back outside?
Is that...
Lucky’s egg?
You wanted to bring that to us?
Mibrim, don’t push yourself too hard.
Even if we can’t see them...
Right, I understand.
Here!
And there’s two of them!
Don’t worry.
You’ll be okay now.
What?
Watch out!
Thank you, Nyahoja.
That must’ve been scary.
But everything’s fine now.
Yeah. Nothing to fear.
Thank you, Nyahoja.
The way back caved in...
Nyahoja managed to save us once, but if there’s another collapse...
Plus...
They’ve gotten weaker.
I need to get them to Molly, and fast...
Right. Of course.
Let’s give them Lucky’s egg.
That might perk them up.
They’re not eating it...
They don’t have the strength to eat...
I-It’ll be okay.
If they can’t eat,
I need to figure something else out...
That’s it.
Mibrim...
Try using Healing Pulse.
Don’t worry.
I know you can do it!
They came around...
Thank goodness!
Wow! You’re amazing, Mibrim!
Thank you.
Okay, let’s get out of here!
But... How do we get out?
Everybody ready?
Yeah!
One, two...!
We did it!
Liko!
Hold on!
You had us worried!
Th-That hurts...
Any injuries?
No, I’m not injured.
And neither are they.
That so? Glad to hear it.
When I poked around earlier,
this seemed like the only exit...
How’d you get out?
Oh, right.
It was thanks to these little ones...
What do I do?
Um... What is it?
...and that was that.
Awesome!
They were so weak before...
Mibrim learned Healing Pulse
and healed everyone.
Ooh!
Mibrim did that?
Thank you, Mibrim.
Are you okay?!
Hey! Sit still for a sec!
I’m not done with your check-up!
Ikkanezumi. Family Pokémon.
Normal type.
The larger pair protects
the little ones as they live together.
So they weren’t Wakkanezumi,
they were Ikkanezumi.
Yeah. I was so focused on
treating the patient I already had,
I didn’t even
consider that possibility.
It’s thanks to Mibrim’s determination
that we got everyone out safely!
Huh? Where did Ikkanezumi go?
They ran off
with Lucky and Mibrim in tow.
Looks like it’s going to get even livelier
‘round here.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Family Pokémon, Ikkanezumi.
Ikkanezumi (Family of Four)
Family Pokémon
Type: Normal
Ikkanezumi (Family of Four)
Family Pokémon
Type: Normal
This Pokémon forms groups consisting of
a larger pair and smaller individuals that all act in unison.
Height
0.3m
Family of Three
Weight
2.8kg
But do you know
how these groups are related?
How are their groups related?
Parents and children
Siblings
Nobody knows
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
So exciting and thrilling
This adventure we've just started
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky!
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Molly here. Sounds like this'll be worth my time.
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky!
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
How are their groups related?
C: Nobody knows
The answer is C: Nobody knows!
While they’re often seen working together,
their relationship is unknown.
When they evolve,
the smaller ones pop out of nowhere.
But when they protect one another,
they really do seem like a family!
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
This time, the Rising Voltteccers have arrived at
the town of iron and machinery, Tetsuron Town!
And it seems like Dot, the quiet and intelligent girl,
has met a new Pokémon there!
But the crybaby Kanuchan
doesn’t make things easy,
and I—I mean Dot—
ends up in trouble!
And so! To be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Kanuchan and the Hammer of Her Obsessions
She just can’t ignore a crying kid.