What...?
What’s going on?
This feels like a bad omen...
“It’s the same as
one hundred years ago”?
So the black Rekkuuza truly has
brought disaster to Mt. Kumuri!
Huh?
It can’t be...
Everyone...
Hold on now, what is that?
A truly ominous scene...
I hope Liko and the others
are okay out there...
Still no luck
getting through to them.
Argh! It’s just so frustrating!
Stay calm. Nothing we can do
besides sit tight and believe in them.
I know, but still...
The Core will soon activate.
If Pagogo’s going to
purify the Rakurium...
Let’s go, everyone!
Right!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
The Earth-Quaking White Zygarde
Let us attack all at once!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Nyarote! Magical Leaf!
Welcamo! Aqua Cutter!
Achigator! Flamethrower!
I suppose it won’t be so easy.
Maybe we need to focus on landing moves,
instead of counting on outnumbering him.
Zygarde is a Dragon/Ground type.
What’ve we got
for super effective moves...?
Oh! Achigator’s Charm Voice!
All right! Let’s get up close
and hit him, like with Rekkuuza!
Liko, let’s run support!
Right!
Nyarote! Lightning Speed!
Welcamo! Kick Down!
Achigator!
Rush in with a fiery dash!
Now! Charm—
Zygarde. Ground Force.
We can’t even get near him...
Soublades! Shadow Claw!
Core Punisher.
My number of opponents matters not.
All who defy me will be cut down!
So that’s the kind of power
a Zygarde wields...
We’ve got to stay on guard against
Ground Force wrecking our footing.
Then let’s attack from the air!
Achigator! Head over that way
with Nitro Charge!
Thousand Arrows.
Achigator!
Nothing less from Gibeon-sama.
Not a single blind spot.
Welcamo! Dodge it!
Nyarote! Dodge!
Run for it, Soublades!
Now! Shadow Claw!
You truly are pathetic.
Core Punisher.
Soublades!
Nyarote!
Amethio!
Don’t recklessly charge in all alone!
Didn’t you ask us
to fight alongside you?!
Yeah.
Right.
Coming in from ground level doesn’t work,
coming in the from the sky doesn’t work...
What do we do?
For now, let’s all push forward!
But if we just rush in without a plan...
No, there’s some merit to his idea.
If we’re to have a chance at winning,
we must disrupt his offensive position.
Yeah!
Nyarote!
Close in on him,
but don’t stop moving!
Follow Nyarote’s lead!
Measly pests...
Thousand Arrows.
There has to be a clue
for us somewhere...!
And there it is!
Dot?
Once he fires off that move...
Look! His attacks let up
until he regathers his Cells!
I see! So in that moment...
...we have our chance
to strike back!
Then that’s what we’ll do!
All right! Run, Achigator!
Welcamo!
Nyarote!
Soublades!
Recycling the same tactic...
Sheer folly.
Strike them down
with Thousand Arrows!
Dodge!
Their intent from the outset
wasn’t to attack...?
There’s our opening!
We can do this! Magical Leaf!
Charm Voice!
Aqua Break!
Shadow Claw!
Thousand...
Waves!
Core Punisher.
Soublades! Ghost Dive!
Ooh, it’s super effective!
Nice, Achigator!
Thanks, Amethio.
It succeeded due to
everyone being in sync.
For Zygarde to suffer
even a single hit...
I have failed.
Don’t worry!
Our feelings are just as strong!
Do not hold back.
Zygarde! Core Punisher!
Welcamo! Aqua Cutter!
Soublades! Psycho Cutter!
Once more... Core Punisher.
Flamethrower!
Magical Leaf!
Aqua Break!
Sword of Regrets!
Thousand Waves.
Nyarote, hang in there!
Hang on, Achigator!
Don’t lose your spirit, Welcamo!
Soublades!
All right! They held out!
Acrobatics!
Charm Voice!
Aqua Break!
Shadow Claw!
Take the attacks, Zygarde!
He let them... on purpose...?!
Ground Force.
Achigator...
Welcamo...
Soublades...
Nyarote...
Spared by your type resistance,
were you?
That will not save you again.
Terapagos,
and the others as well...
Let them all be blown away!
Zygarde! Core Punisher!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Nyarote!
A whole lot of Magical Leaves!
If we don’t do something...!
This battle is over.
No...
I will not give up!
Nyarote! Hang in there!
Nyarote is trying so hard to protect
Achigator, Welcamo, and Soublades...
Everyone is trying so hard
to protect everyone else...!
Pagogo...
Liko!
What are you...?!
It’s too dangerous!
Nyarote!
I’m right by your side!
My feelings are aligned with yours!
Pagogo... The Six Heroes... Lucius...
I want to link
all of their desires together!
I want to protect all of them!
Liko! Nyarote! Don’t give up!
Go for it!
Nyarote!
She evolved...
She evolved?
She evolved?!
She evolved.
She evolved!
You evolved!
Masquernya!
Soublades!
Thank you.
Soublades will, most likely,
only be able to muster one final attack...
That won’t be enough
to defeat Zygarde.
We will carve out a path for you.
Amethio...
I leave it in your hands,
Liko and Masquernya!
This ends now!
Ground Force!
Masquernya!
Soublades!
Do not approach me!
Core Punisher!
Protect Masquernya!
Sword of Regrets!
Soublades!
She’s got Zygarde cornered!
Masquernya!
Non-stop Acrobatics!
Such insolent behavior!
Zygarde, Core Punish—
Surprise Attack!
Dodge it, Zygarde!
Core Punisher!
Not good!
If that hits...
Masquernya!
That was Trick Flower!
A new move!
Zygarde was...
That can’t be!
Masquernya!
That was amazing, Masquernya!
Zygarde?
Zygarde!
Keep attacking!
This isn’t over yet!
Zygarde!
Stop! Zygarde! Don’t go!
Stay at my...!
Why...?
Why?!
Surely you see now, Gibeon.
Zygarde has approved
of Liko and her allies.
You have lost.
Why...? How could I have...?
To these...
These children!
You’ve done this
to me again, Lucius?!
I’ve been foiled by someone
of your bloodline again?!
Just what is it that sets me
and the lot of you so far apart?!
Our bonds.
By trusting their trainers,
Pokémon can become stronger without limit.
That is how they rose
above you and Zygarde.
Bonds...? Trust...?
Such immaterial concepts
cannot even be proven by science!
In the face of a great material power,
they’re no more than empty prattle!
Pokémon are strange,
strange creatures.
They can bring about miracles
that we humans can’t hope to quantify.
When their feelings united as one,
Liko’s Masquernya managed to evolve.
Grandfather! I felt it, too!
The moment when my desires
united with Soublades’s.
The whole reason Zygarde
fought alongside you...
Do you not think it was
in order to show you that?
That bonds between people and Pokémon
bear monumental possibilities?
Possibilities...
Pagogo?
Pagogo!
Rekkuuza!
That’s...!
Pagogo’s third form!
It Terastallized!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Magician Pokémon, Masquernya.
It has great athletic abilities,
Masquernya
Magician Pokémon
Type: Grass/Evil
Masquernya
Magician Pokémon
Type: Grass/Evil
Height
1.5m
and excels particularly
in explosive power and flexibility.
Weight
31.2kg
It also has a special skill
that uses its cape,
but do you know what that skill is?
What is Masquernya's special skill?
Singing
Magic tricks
Dancing
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What is Masquernya's special skill?
B: Magic tricks
The answer is B: Magic tricks!
By scattering light using its cape,
it can make it look like
its flower has vanished!
It takes its foes by surprise
in battles!
Next episode
Masquernya...
Tebrim...
You’ve evolved, and become much tougher...
You’re glimmering so brightly!
Pagogo...
Thank you for bringing us to Rakua.
We really have come so far...
What will we discover next?
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
At the End of the Adventure