Roy, Dot, and I passed
our Terastal Course.
Next, we set off to meet Ms. Briar,
who is researching Terapagos.
We’ve now arrived at the Kitakami hamlet
with the Rising Voltteccers.
We’ll be taking the bus
to Suiryoku Town.
Once we arrive,
everyone start asking around.
Gather as much information
on Ms. Briar as you can!
Yeah!
Or... that was the plan, but...
...there’s nobody here!
Yeah, no kidding...
Has something happened?
Well, now what do we do?
Something troubling you?
Sorry to bother. We’re looking for
someone by the name of Ms. Briar.
This is her.
Do you happen to know her?
Hmm... Sorry, can’t say I do.
May I ask you something else?
Sure!
Where are all the townspeople?
We haven’t seen any of them.
They’re off to the hamlet’s
Harvest Fête today.
The hamlet’s Harvest Fête?
This place is famous for its apples...
So we hold a festival hoping to
bring in a big apple harvest.
A festival?!
Sounds great!
Then let’s go ask around
at the festival!
Which should we get?
Whoa!
I want one!
Thank you!
This looks so...!
Thanks.
Looks like so much fun!
Welcome!
Now then, who should we ask...?
Huh? What’s that?
That Pokémon!
Is that a Yabasocha?!
I don’t answer to outsiders.
Oh... Well, I mean,
I am an outsider...
But I’m not shady or anything.
I’m just interested in taking a look at
your Yabasocha, as a Pokémon Professor.
So, could I, please?
Just for a sec?
Hmm...
In that case...
If you can beat me,
I’ll consider allowing you
a quick look.
Beat you at what?
Hmm, let’s see...
First... How about
we face off at that stall?
I see.
I’m happy to
take you up on the offer...
...but we’re not exactly
pushovers, y’know.
We’ll just see
if you’re any match for me.
Now...
Let the game begin!
He actually just wants to play around
at the festival, doesn’t he?
Maybe, yeah.
Well, festivals don’t happen every day.
How about we have some fun too,
and look for info along the way?
Yeah!
What do you want to do?
Good question...
There’s so many tasty-looking treats!
What should we try first, Achigator?
Something smells good...
Is it over that way?
Atchi?
That way?
Huh?
Where’d that good smell go?
What’s this thing?
Does it intrigue you, boy?
Huh?!
Um... What is it?
Oh, it’s... uh...
What is it, exactly...?
Huh?! You don’t know either, mister?
Well, you see...
Someone lost this thing, an’ I found it.
But I just know
it does something interesting!
My intuition’s screamin’ it at me!
Telling me this here’s a toy
the kids’re bound to enjoy.
Festivals don’t happen every day.
A fella just has to put up an exciting stall
for the dear kids in his dear hamlet, ya know?
But I ain’t got a clue
how to get it working.
By the way, boy...
Do you know how to use this?
Huh?!
Um...
It looks like you’d press
these buttons...
Ooh!
It worked!
That’s it, that’s it, that’s it!
Now something fun’s
bound to hap—
Nope...
Nothing happened at all!
Huh?
Does this mean...
...me and Achigator have...
...swapped places?!
Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
Oh, it's rained for so long, my heart's grown so cowardly
Can't bring myself to look for rainbows, I'm always so dejected
Oh, but how I'd like to take that step forward
To set out, as if guided to something that'll excite my heart
My wish to meet you at our promised place
When I find it amid my thoughts... Oh, my heart
It pounds so fast, like I can make it to the future you entrusted to me
Now... Even if it looks like you're stuck, it'll be okay
I'll send you cheers to connect us, so listen: Yeah, yeah, oh!
I know you've got a one-of-a-kind story in you
Ascend and unleash your gleaming starlight
Take one more step from here and you'll see that you can go farther
No matter how many tears you shed, I just know you'll be okay
I'm a Pokémon, and You're Me?!
All right!
We caught a yo-yo balloon!
Terapagos!
Are you okay?
What should we do next?
Wait, huh...?
Roy and Achigator are gone.
You’re right.
Where could they have gotten to?
What in the blazes happened?!
The Achigator’s
in the boy’s body...
And the boy’s
in the Achigator’s body...
L-Looks like it...
Now, that could be bad news.
Huh?
Well, that’s a miraculous device
that lets people and Pokémon swap places, aye?
If anyone finds out that I’ve got it...
I beg ya, boy!
Don’t breathe a word of this!
O-Okay...
For now, we should swap back.
Let’s see...
So, what we did before was...
Huh? It’s not working!
That’s weird...
Are the batteries dry?!
Hey! Where are you goin’?!
I’ll catch him.
Right... Just make sure nobody else
figures out what’s goin’ on!
I’m beggin’ you, boy!
Just leave it to me.
I’ll make sure no one finds out!
H-Huh?!
I’m having trouble running...
Uh, how does Achigator do it...?
Like this!
Whoa!
Wow...
It’s a totally different view!
So this is how Achigator
sees the world...
Roy, what happened?
Huh?
Huh?!
You’re acting weird.
Th-This is bad!
pOCket Monsters
Rekkuuza Rising
Uh... It is you, isn’t it, Roy?
Chigee.
Wrong.
We’ve got it wrong?
So you aren’t Roy?
Chigee.
Wrong.
So are we wrong or not?
Which is it?!
Liko! Dot! That’s really not me!
Oh...
A-Achigator...
...is speaking?!
Aren’t you Roy?
Huh? Then...
You’re Achigator?
Then...
Does that mean...?
Yes. We’ve swapped places.
Th-This isn’t fair...
There’s no way you should’ve
been able to beat me!
Say what you will,
the results speak for themselves.
Now, about Yabasocha—
In which case...!
Face me in that one next!
Candy cutting, eh?
I see...
So that weird device wound up
swapping Roy and Achigator around.
So bizarre things like that
can actually happen, huh?
I didn’t want anyone to know, especially ‘cause
the man at the stall asked me to not tell anyone...
Well, you can’t really do anything
about us finding out,
so let’s just make sure nobody else does
and meet back up with the old guy.
So that’s where you were!
You all having fun at the festival?
If you see something you’d like,
I’ll treat you.
All right!
Huh?!
Did Achigator just... speak?
I-I don’t think so! Why?
What are you talking about, Murdock?
Aga! Aga!
N-Never mind that!
Murdock, did you say you’d treat us?
Ah, yeah!
Right now, think of me as
Mr. Anything-You-Want!
What do we do?
If we have anyone else along,
we risk them noticing the swap...
I wanna enjoy the festival, too.
Okay. So let’s get our treats quick,
then split up quick!
Mr. Anything-You-Want!
Treat us, please!
Okay! What do you wanna eat?
Candy apples, huh?
Thanks.
It’s good!
Whoa!
Using Achigator’s flames to caramelize the candy,
and bake the apple inside just right...
Th-That makes it...
baked apple candy!
That looks really yummy!
Hey, could you bake this one, too?
Huh?!
Standing out like this
won’t end well for us!
Right.
I’m sorry.
This little guy
isn’t feeling too well right now.
Huh?
Thanks for the food, Murdock!
See you later!
Perfection, no?
Grrr...
You just got lucky, that’s all!
Now I’m really mad!
Next, let’s settle this
with a Pokémon battle!
You sure about that?
I’m gonna crush you and get back to
enjoying the festival in high spirits!
Sounds good to me.
A Pokémon battle’s the best way
to know a Pokémon, after all.
Get ready to eat dirt!
Yabasocha!
Let’s go, Cap!
Uh...
Molly, what’s this line for?
Well, you see...
I was giving this girl some first aid
because her geta scraped her between her toes...
And it seems like a lot of kids
are having similar issues.
We really should avoid
taking any detours...
But...
Let us help!
Achigator?!
Did you just spea—
Geta!
Oh, of course.
For the geta injuries...
Use these.
There. You should be
all set for now.
Thank you very much.
Whoa!
Geta, geta.
Yes, right...
I should put my geta on.
Thank you.
Geta!
Y-Yes, I should be able to
wear my geta just fine now...
Well, nobody figured it out,
but things did get pretty weird...
Whisk-Whisk Cannon!
Cap!
Okay!
That move restored
Yabasocha’s stamina!
Now, the tables have turned!
Finish him!
One more Whisk-Whisk Cannon!
Go! Thunder Punch!
Yabasocha!
Which way to the old guy?
Umm...
Atchi!
That way!
It’s Orio.
We better move it
before she spots us.
Yeah.
Is she having trouble
with something?
Seems that way.
Same as before,
don’t tip anyone off.
Right!
Ahh... It’s no good.
I just can’t get the heat to kick on.
Darn it, I’ll have to
close up shop for today...
Please, hold on!
Ah, it’s you three.
Is the stove broken?
Yeah.
I was hoping I could make enough
for the customers in line, at least...
But I guess we’re out of luck.
Gotcha...
Oh, of course.
Yeah, let’s give it a shot!
Um... Maybe you could cook the yakisoba
with Achigator’s flames?
Achigator?
He cooked a candy apple
to perfection earlier, and it tasted great!
Mmmm!
Ooh! That might just work, then.
Huh?
Achigator!
Thank you, Achigator.
Looks like he’s having trouble
handling his flames...
Is Achigator not feeling well?
Huh?! Oh, uh...
Chigee.
Wrong.
He’s not?
All right.
Just my imagination, I guess.
What happened?
It’s tough to control.
I was trying to shoot out
a smaller flame...
I see...
Then let’s think of something else.
Lemme try one more time.
You sure you’re okay?
Achigator!
Aga, aga-ga, aga-aga, ga!
Aga, aga-aga, aga-aga, ga!
A-ga, aga-ga, aga-aga, ga!
Aga, aga, aga, aga, ah!
Mister! Now’s your chance
to cook the yakisoba!
R-Right!
Amazing!
Even swapped around,
Roy and Achigator make a great team!
Eat up while it’s hot.
Looks good!
Smells great.
Okay, catch up with you all later!
Thank you, Achigator!
Mom!
Here you go.
Let’s have our yakisoba over there.
When I grow up
and become a trainer,
my first partner’s
gonna be an Achigator!
That feels good to hear, doesn’t it?
Oh! There you are!
Boy! Achigator!
I managed to fix the thing!
Well then, here goes.
Did it work?
Achigator...
Wait, who’s who?!
It’s me! I’m back!
What a relief!
Whoa! Who’s there?!
W-We’re Roy’s friends!
Um, mister!
We’d like to try swapping too!
Uh...
Please!
W-Well... Okay, just this once.
Keep it a secret.
All right!
Okay, on the count of three...
Huh? It’s not working...
Give it here.
That...
...might have broken it...
Seriously?!
Huh?
It says... “Syn... ch... romachine” on it...?
Romachine?!
Is that the owner of this thing?!
Ahh! I’m sorry!
I broke it, Romachine!
Forgive me, Romachine!
Looks like you all
enjoyed the festival.
Yeah! We went through a lot,
but it was a ton of fun.
Hey, you!
Next, face me in ring-toss!
As much as I’d love to
accept that challenge,
we’ve all got to go
look for Ms. Briar.
Ms. Briar’s my homeroom teacher.
Huh?!
She’s over at
the Shining Pond right now.
Then we can meet her
if we head over there?!
Correct.
But oh no, how sad!
You need permission
to go to the Shining Pond!
Naturally, the caretaker won’t give permission
to any random outsider who—
You may go!
Huh?
Are you sure?
Yes.
I heard how helpful
you were to my daughter.
Your daughter?
Hey, it’s you...
Thanks for earlier.
Shizune?!
Guess I missed something...
But we’re good to go, then?
Yes!
Th-This isn’t fair! Argh!
Well then, new plan...
Let’s go! The Shining Pond awaits!
Yeah!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, let’s take a look at
the Matcha Pokémon, Yabasocha.
Yabasocha
Matcha Pokémon
Type: Grass/Ghost
Yabasocha
Matcha Pokémon
Type: Grass/Ghost
A Pokémon that made a teacup its home.
Height
0.2m
If you drink Yabasocha’s tea,
it steals a certain something from you.
Weight
2.2kg
But do you know what that thing is?
What does it steal if you drink its tea?
Memories
Sense of taste
Life essence
See the answer after the commercials!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Time to shine, together
Ready 3, 2, 1, Ahhh
So where now? Frustrations? Delusions?
All In My Head, Let's Go!
Had enough? Too tough? Hey, there's just no way! Let's Go!
Just do it! (Big Up!) Just win it! (Big Up!)
Passion volley! (Pa Ra Ra Yeah)
You're no failure, you're no loser
Just keep on chasing until you catch up
The feelings entrusted to us (ah eh ah eh) make us stronger
Meeting, parting, all of those supporting us
Bring them along for the ri-i-ide!
Rise Up!! Make it to that super effective amazing wish
Rise Up!! Make it to that possible future we promised
Assemble, grant your wish
3, 2, Ready? Big Bang!
Rise up, this adventure is for us, Go Go (Let's go!)
It's a blazing journey, and when we make it...
Hop, Step, Get it!
Come On, Rise Up!!
Come On, Rise Up!! (ah ah ah ah)
Make a change, you can take it, you can do it, yeah!
Rise Up, Pikkaan
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer!
What does it steal if you drink its tea?
C: Life essence
The answer is C: Life essence.
If you drink Yabasocha’s tea, it sucks out
your life essence, and you’ll lose your energy.
Careful not to drink any by mistake!
Next episode
Wh-Whoa! Kanuchan!
What’s wrong?
Did that hammer
you were working on break?
Don’t cry, Kanuchan.
Kanuchan’s been gathering materials and making hammers
for a while now in hopes of powering up, huh?
It’ll be okay.
I know you’ll make
a fantastic hammer!
And so, next time
on Pocket Monsters:
Kanuchan’s Hammer
Wasn’t Built in a Day
Keep at it, Kanuchan!
Kanuchan's Hammer
Wasn't Built in a Day