The Rising Voltteccers were traveling across Galar,
following up on sightings of the black Rekkuuza...
But we struck out every time.
Then, my grandma’s
suggestion brought us to...
Check out all the stuff for sale!
A street market, huh?
Talk about lively.
The stand Grandma mentioned
should be here somewhere...
Shouldn’t Ms. Diana have come with us?
I did ask her to come along...
I found this ancient text
at my old friend’s shop a long time ago.
Part of it describes
what sounds like a paradise.
I think she’s set on deciphering
that ancient text at the moment.
There! The Lampler signpost!
That’s the stand!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
A long (long) road ahead, and at its end
I'll think of you
Someday, let's shake hands
and laugh as one
The rainbow shines out
and at its end
I found my dream
The Stolen Treasure
Um, pardon me?
Hrm? Customers?
Good day! Don’t be shy! Feast your eyes!
I’ve got some mighty fine goods in stock!
Um, no, we...
You couldn’t’ve come at a better time!
I just got some rare treasures in!
Stuff you don’t see every day!
This’ll win ya any battle, no question!
Huh? For real?!
Positively!
This’s some super potent
Sleep Powder!
A truly terrifying item that’ll put
all battlers on the field to sleep!
That’s awesome!
Huh? But if your Pokémon fall asleep too,
how are you supposed to battle?
Good question.
And check this out!
Rarest of the rare!
A Smartphone Rotom fossil
from 20,000 years ago!
Whoa! This stand’s crazy!
Smartphones didn’t exist
20,000 years ago...
But wait! There’s more!
Um... You’re Mr. Tepen, right?
We came here on a tip
from my grandma, Diana.
Huh? Diana?!
I’m her granddaughter, Liko.
Ms. Diana, you say?!
I know her real well!
We went on quite a few adventures
together back in the day.
What? You and Grandma?!
Positively!
Oh, how that takes me back...
One time, we were exploring
some ruins in the woods,
and got caught in an Ariados’s web and
hung upside down for a week straight!
I thought I was a goner for sure!
Huh? A whole week?!
Wouldn’t all the blood
flow to your head?
Say, Liko... Is it just me,
or is this all sounding really fishy?
Y-Yeah...
But Grandma vouched for him...
So? You looking for something?
Oh, um...
Well, we’re looking for
a ball that looks like this...
You know anything about it?
Oh, my goodness!
You do know something?
N-No! Uh, I’m not so sure...
Mind if I take a closer look?
Like, at the whole backpack!
Huh? Uh... I guess.
Hmm... I see...
Heck of a rare ball...
Never seen anything like it,
I’m afraid!
Oh, I see...
Don’t fret. It wouldn’t be any fun
if we found it that easily.
I guess you’re right...
Yeah. Well, um...
Sorry to bother you.
No problem at all!
Say hi to Ms. Diana for me!
What’s wrong, Mibrim?
Hogator, you hungry?
Uh... So am I, come to think of it...
It is almost lunchtime.
I see. Mibrim must have been hungry, too.
All right! Shall we grab something to eat?
Yeah!
Hup!
Wanna check some more stands
while we’re here?
I’d like to ask around
about the black Rekkuuza.
Good idea.
Nyahoja? What’s wrong?
The backpack!
It’s moving?!
A Tamagetake?
But why?!
It’s gone!
It’s gone! It’s gone!
The Ancient Monster Ball is gone!
What?!
But why?! Did I lose it somewhere?!
Maybe when you took it out at the stand?
That’s got to be it!
Let’s hurry back!
Went off without a hitch.
C’mere, all of you!
All right! Closing time!
The stand’s gone, too!
Why?!
Um, excuse me... What happened
to the shop that was just here?
Oh, he packed up in a real hurry
and ran off somewhere.
He closed up that early?!
No, I think we’ve been had.
The look in that Tepen guy’s eyes
changed the second he saw Roy’s ball.
If he swapped the ball
with Tamagetake on purpose, then...
You’re saying he stole it?!
Oh, no!
He must have.
Why else would he close up and run away?
Mibrim, were you trying to warn us?
She must have sensed
his malicious intent.
I see... I’m so sorry.
In any case, he can’t have gotten far.
Let’s look for him!
Right!
But why would he take Roy’s ball?
Maybe it just caught his eye
as an antiques dealer...
Or perhaps...
It couldn’t be...
the Explorers’ doing?!
Yup. I got my hands on
something you’ll love.
I’m bringing it to you as we speak.
You’d best make it
worth my while, you hear?
Where did he go?!
Let’s split up and search.
It’ll be easier to find him that way.
Yes, good idea.
Lizardon!
Liko and Roy, you go that way.
We’ll look from the air.
Call me immediately if you find him.
Don’t engage in battle
until he’s shown his hand.
Got it!
Seems really easy to get lost here.
Yeah...
Everything looks the same.
There he is!
Hold it, you!
I’m sorry! I mistook you
for someone else!
Calm down, Roy.
Remember, if we find him
we call Friede first.
Oh, right.
This oughta be far enough.
Tch!
Found me already?
Listen up!
Take this to the usual spot.
Don’t let anybody nab it from you!
Now, go!
There he is.
Hold it, you!
Give it up!
Why, if it ain’t the customer from before!
You need somethin’?
Don’t play dumb!
I know you stole Roy’s Monster Ball!
Give it back, now!
“Stole”? Why, there must
be some mistake!
Gonna try and act innocent, are we?
Then let me inspect your goods!
By all means.
Well? Did you find it?
That’s weird... Where did he hide it?
Lampler’s not here!
Where’s the Lampler you use
as the sign for your stand?
Agh!
G-Good question...
It’s a fickle one...
It might have wandered off...
I see. You gave it the ball.
Better hurry after it...
Or should I just question him
and make him say where it went...?
Heave!
Huh?
After him, Lizardon!
Hey, what’s the big idea?!
You’re not getting away!
Hey, you!
Was that your Lizardon?!
What are you gonna do
about our stands?!
Uh... Um... Well, you see...
You’re fixing this!
You’re not leaving ‘til you do!
Liko!
Friede!
Did you find him?
So there you have it.
We’re stuck for the time being.
You’ll have to search for Lampler.
It’s run off somewhere with the ball.
Exercise caution
if you end up having to battle it.
Got it!
Hey! Quit slacking off!
Ah, sorry!
Cap.
Lampler...
Lampler!
We will find it! Right, Hogator?
There!
It’s not just Lampler?!
pOCket Monsters
The Gleam of Terapagos
Are those Pokémon its friends?
That bag the Lampler’s carrying!
Looks like that’s where the ball is!
Yup!
Hey! Give me my ball back!
Hold it!
Let’s go, Nyahoja!
In there!
Is this a museum?
So many old things...
It might be hard to find them in here.
You find ‘em?!
Those are just regular lamps...
Let’s check up here.
Nyahoja!
Hogator!
They got away!
As if!
Gah!
The stands are all squared away,
and the customers are back.
What do you think?
It’s good! Well done!
How about working for me, dude?
I’ll pay you real good!
I’m not really cut out for retail...
Right... We have to
catch up to Liko and Roy.
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Hold it!
Where’d they go?!
Nyahoja and I will look this way!
Okay! Then we’ll go this way!
There they are!
Stop right there!
That Monster Ball is mine!
It’s really important!
I said stop!
You wanna battle?!
Dodge it, Hogator!
Ember!
Hogator!
Seems I shook ‘em off.
Ah, you two!
Where’s the ball?
Lampler ran this way, you said? Got it!
We’ll be right there, too!
Stop!
We have to get that bag!
Nyahoja!
Cut the string with Leafage!
More Leafage!
In that case... Nyahoja,
use Leafage while running around!
We’re not hitting...
Mibrim?
Thank you!
Lampler! Attack with Thief!
Oh, no!
Liko!
Roy!
Those creeps!
Mr. Tepen, why are you doing this?!
Were you lying when you said
you adventured with my grandma?!
Huh? Adventured?
Hmm, did I do that?
Give the ball back!
It’s very important!
Well, it just so happens someone came by my stand
and said they’d pay handsomely for a ball like this one!
It was the Explorers!
So I’m real sorry,
but would you mind lettin’ me have it?
We can’t!
If you won’t give it back,
then we’ll take it back!
That so? Guess there ain’t
nothing for it, then.
Hogator! Flamethrower!
Use Lightning Speed on Lampler!
Side Change!
Wrong target!
Flamethrower!
Dotakun! Rain Prayer!
All right, in that case...
Kaiden!
Spark!
Well done!
Hitotsuki! Metal Sound!
What?!
The Tamagetake from before?!
Very well done!
So that was one of your Pokémon, too!
Uh...
But it’s asleep?!
You see that?
It even knocks out Grass types!
That’s my super potent
homemade Sleep Powder for ya!
It really does knock out
your own side, too.
Sure looks like this battle’s over.
Cap!
Th-This sure ain’t good...
Agh... Eep!
That’s enough!
All hands on deck...
Case closed, I’d say!
What a relief!
Now, what to do with you?
Roast me, simmer me,
do whatever you please!
Well, if that’s what you want!
Tepen! Fraud!
peten
Grandma!
D-Diana?!
Weren’t you deciphering
that ancient text?
Sure was. But right at the end,
I finally understood...
...that this “ancient text”
you sold me was one big fake!
Tepen! Fraud!
F-Fake? Now, that ain’t
a nice thing to say!
It’s the real, genuine article...
If it’s not a fake...
...then why does it end with
“Watch the conclusion online”?!
How could you pull this on me?
I thought we were friends!
Windie. Burn him to a crisp!
G-Grandma, that’s going too far!
I swear... What happened to you?
You used to be an adventurer,
with a passion for excavation!
Huh?
We’d explore ruins together all the time.
I really thought we were done for
that time Ariados strung us up for a week straight!
That was true?
I was always like this.
Deceit and theft’re my specialty.
It’s way easier and way more
my style than adventuring.
Oh, is that so?
‘Scuse me for a second...
Look!
Huh?!
They say Domirror reflects the truth.
You see?
Your heart’s saying that you want to
go back to the good old adventuring days!
I’m just not cut out for it.
I always end up regretting it.
It’s scary, it’s tough...
I’m too much of a coward for adventures!
The only scary part is the first step.
Take that first step,
and you forget the fear!
You looked far happier
back then than you do now!
Those Pokémon are precious partners
whom you met on your adventures, aren’t they?
Don’t you feel ashamed,
making them assist you with your evil deeds?
I’m sorry...
I’m so sorry...
Grandma... I love you!
I am so, so sorry...
I’m starting fresh.
Someday, I’ll be exploring ruins again!
Together with all of them!
That’s a promise!
Oh, of course!
I owe someone else an apology, too!
For being unable to sell the ball.
You mean the person
who wanted the ball?
Can you tell us
anything about them?
About them?
They were some sorta
Monster Ball artisan...
Said they’d pay
any price for rare balls...
A Monster Ball artisan?
It wasn’t the Explorers?
This is where I was supposed to take it.
If you’re curious,
we can go take a look.
Yes! Let’s go!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, we’ll be taking a look at
the Lamp Pokémon, Lampler.
This Pokémon absorbs souls
to light the flame in its body.
Lampler
Lamp Pokémon
Type: Ghost/Fire
Lampler
Lamp Pokémon
Type: Ghost/Fire
Height
0.6m
It’s said to often haunt a certain place
that everyone’s familiar with...
Weight
13.0kg
But do you know what place that is?
Where does Lampler often appear?
Hospitals
Schools
Libraries
See the answer after the commercials!
Yo! We're (Yeah!) the Rising Voltteccers
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
Rising
Voltteccers
Rap
What Pokémon are we gonna find next?
Now, time for some more adventures!
Yo! Ready, go!
Let's keep on learning about more Pokémon
How about Pokémon with "gon" in their names?!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Now, can you say it with Roy?
Are you ready?
So, can you do it too? Give it a try with me!
Pokémon with "gon" in their names
Flygon, Uonoragon, Gonbe,
Toroggon, Dugong, Kabigon, yay!
Brave in heart-heart-heart
Surfing through the skies
Exciting and thrilling
An adventure is starting
Take the helm, set a course for the world
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Let's learn about more and more!
Next up, Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"!
Let's have Liko show us how it's done!
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky
Now let's have our guest give it a go!
Let's go!
Molly here. Sounds like this'll be worth my time.
Pokémon that rhyme with "ki"
Fake Tears Usokki, moonlit night Blacky
Happy Egg-holding Lucky
Brave Bird-Bird-Bird
Take to the skies with courage
Fly in the sky-sky-sky
Heading to our destination
Even if we get hurt and stumble at times
Proving we're friends with our hand sign
Together we're the Rising Voltteccers!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar
Now, time to announce
the correct answer.
Where does Lampler often appear?
A: Hospitals
The answer is A: Hospitals!
Lampler is always looking for
chances to absorb souls.
Perhaps the reason it often haunts hospitals
is because it’s targeting weak people and Pokémon.
Beware of suspicious lights...
Next episode
Yo-ssu! All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
Y’all been groovin’?
It’s huge preview time!
The tip from that super fishy Tepen guy
led them to a Monster Ball factory!
Hmm? What’s up with Orio?
Huh?! She’s leaving the crew?!
That’s awful!
That means Orio’s trying to go away...
Orio’s trying to Ori-go!
And so, to be continued next time
on Pocket Monsters!
Orio and the Monster Ball Artisan