We made it to Cercle Town!
Hey, so...
This Soapberry place we’re meeting up at.
It’s got a ton of mega-tasty sweets, right?
I’m gonna eat eight of ‘em
without a doubt, you hear me?
Eight of them?
Why a random
unimpressive number like that?
Then I’ll eat a hundred!
No way you’re gonna
manage to eat a hundred.
Yeah, I will!
No, you won’t.
Well, feel free to
eat as many as you want...
But the reason we’re going
is to meet up with Dot.
And also...
I know, I know.
Proving your determination
to that Sherbet guy, yeah?
It’s Murdock, though?
Okay, so I was practically right!
There’s Soapberry!
Do—
Hey!
Dot!
I haven’t seen you in so long, Dot!
Have you been doing well?
You been eating well?
Did you eat breakfast today?
Hey—
Oh! What about lunch?
Well—
If you already ate lunch,
have some snacks!
We’ve got loads and loads
of tasty sweets!
You sure have grown!
D-Do you think he missed her?
Not so close, Murdock!
Whoops, sorry.
Geez.
You’re a grown-up.
You should be able to keep your cool.
I-It’s normal for grown-ups to act like this
when they’re happy too, you know...
Oh my!
It’s Ms. Liko.
Ms. Kaede!
It’s been quite some time.
I’m so glad to have the chance
to see you again.
That’s how a real grown-up handles it.
Can’t argue with you there.
Somehow, I feel like I'm the only one
living on foregone time
Just like you have done
I know I have to evolve my tomorrows
Paint a scene of sprinting through fields
in a Magical show
A traveler of time wandering lost
for a phantom utopia
Searching for it, losing sight of it, and here all along
is the fading light! Get it back!
In this world only I have reached
I alone am, I am alone, different
I can't go back, can't turn time back
but still I gotta let my wishes fly free again
With a burning hot and boiling
Flaming Melody
Now, together, we'll get it back
Yeah, our utopia
Just open your eyes, stretch out your hands, and find yourself
waking up there! Get it back!
The future!
Get it back!
Cercle Town, Place of Reunions!
They look delicious!
What’s with these sweets?!
They’re mega-sparklin’ at me!
Ahh! So bright!
Mega-sparkle! Mega-sparkle!
And who’s this?
His name’s Ult.
A friend who trained with me.
Thank you, Mawhip.
Me too! Me too!
Hey! I was first!
I was first...
My, oh my...
What a lovely little fellow
you’ve got there.
Oh, is this your first time
meeting him, Ms. Kaede?
This is Cap.
Nice to meet you. I’m Kaede.
You’re a reliable little guy,
aren’t you, Cappy?
“Cappy”...?
Don’t be shy. Dig right in!
There’s more where that came from.
Pagogo, your face is
covered in pudding.
I see you’ve gained
a new partner, Ms. Liko.
Yeah!
My, my! Can’t have you
eating Paggy, now.
That reminds me, Murdock...
Where’s Iwanko?
Oh, it’s here.
Lugarugan!
So it evolved!
A Lugarugan!
Is it Midday Form, or Midnight Form?
Huh? Oh, it’s Midday Form.
For a Midday Form...
...it’s a bit...
Chubby, ain’t it?
Yup, it’s chubby...
S-So cute!
Mind if I pat you?
You’re so squishy!
Isn’t my Lugarugan the best?
How’d it wind up
so squishy and chubby, though?
Ah, well, you see...
After everyone split up...
I ended up working
as a pâtissier here at Soapberry...
But I could never quite make sweets
that made me go “Yes, perfect!”
Day after day,
I attempted everything I could think of,
with Iwanko taste-testing
it all along the way.
Then, one day...
And that’s why
it’s a bit chubby right now.
So it overate...
The sweets Mr. Murdock makes are ever so tasty,
even when they’re a work in progress.
Aw, but...
But how should I put it...?
They lack that finishing touch
that makes you go “Yes, perfect!”
Exactly right...
This stuff is mega-tasty, though.
When did you eat all that?!
I’m takin’ those!
Hey! Don’t hog them all to yourself!
You guys should’ve
eaten ‘em faster, then!
Seriously...
W-Water...
Here, drink up.
What’s wrong?
You really ought to drink some.
You certainly were thirsty.
I can get you some more.
Ow...
Geez...
What’s with you, huh?
Sorry.
Yeah.
Thank you too, Yamirami.
You’re pretty nice, ain’tcha?
Ooh! So you noticed, eh Ult?!
Yep, Dot is really nice. And smart.
Super family-oriented, too.
She’s my proud niece!
Huh? Niece?
Dot’s my younger sister’s daughter.
Daughter... But that means... you...
You’re a girl?!
This whole time, I couldn’t tell
over the Smartphone Rotom...
I-I-I held her hand...
What’s wrong, Ult?
I-It’s nothing!
Never mind that, you guys...
You didn’t come here
just to scarf down a buncha sweets, didja?!
You’re the only one
scarfing down sweets here.
Shut it!
Look, you had a ton of things
to talk about, right?
Uhh... The Strong Spheres,
the Explorers, and all that stuff...
Dot... Those things he’s talking about...
You haven’t been poking your noses
into any dangerous business, have you?
Nah, no sticking our noses into anything.
Well, that’s good—
We dove right in headfirst.
Huh?!
Wh-What do you mean?
You see... We’ve re-formed
the Rising Voltteccers.
You re-formed
the Rising Voltteccers...?
Right.
At the moment, wild Pokémon from all over
are going on rampages,
and people are saying
it’s the Rising Voltteccers’ fault...
But we’ve discovered that the Explorers
and Exceed are involved.
They’re using Rakurium to develop these
“Strong Sphere” things that make Pokémon act violent...
...and are trying to
spread them worldwide.
But we still need more proof.
That’s why,
as we continue our adventures,
we want to investigate
the effects of Rakurium...
...that are popping up worldwide,
and their connection to the Explorers.
And we want to get back
the truth of the Rising Voltteccers!
We came here today
to tell you about all of this.
Oh, I see!
You’ve all figured out
just what you need to do, haven’t you?
Yep, that’s right!
Are you going to be okay?
I mean...
Won’t it be dangerous out there,
with you all on your own?
Thanks for worrying about us.
But we’ll be fine!
We’re much stronger
than we used to be!
And by the way, I’m mega-strong!
Ult, just stay quiet for a sec.
How come?!
You always get us sidetracked when you butt in!
Still, though...
Nuh-uh, I don’t!
Murdock...
Yeah, you do!
When’s that ever happened before?!
Huh?!
Well then, how about having
a Pokémon Battle with me, Ms. Liko?
Huh?
If you could show him
how you’ve improved with a battle,
perhaps that would help
set Mr. Murdock’s mind at ease.
You’re right.
I’ll show you a Pokémon Battle that’ll
send your worries flying to the far end of the sky!
Just you watch.
S-Sure...
Well then, let’s get started. Beary!
“Beary”?
Ms. Kaede’s partner Pokémon,
a Himeguma.
Wait, she’s a Ringuma?!
It’s huge!
My little one has evolved, too!
Right?
And as for Beary’s
opponent in battle, I pick...
...Paggy!
Huh?!
pOCket Monsters
Mega Voltage
Never thought she’d pick Pagogo.
Liko’s got a nice smile on her face.
I can tell she’s
mega-totally motivated.
Let’s have a good battle, Ms. Kaede!
Likewise to you.
Let’s go, Pagogo.
There it is!
My! What a lovely form your Paggy has!
This battle is shaping up to be
quite enjoyable, just as I’d hoped.
In which case...
We ought to get moving, too!
Beary, use 100,000 Horsepower!
Pagogo! Protect!
Paggy’s tough.
Pagogo... Primal Power!
Let’s go with Arm Hammer!
And let’s keep up the attack.
Consecutive Cut!
Pagogo! Protect!
There’s more where that came from!
Pagogo!
That’s one strong Ringuma!
That’s a Gym Leader for you.
Pagogo, are you okay?
If I want to beat
Ms. Kaede and her Pokémon...
I have to move further and further...
...forward!
Pagogo!
Huh?
What’s Liko planning?
Liko...
Beary...
Further...
Just a bit longer...
More...
Nearly there...
Further forward!
Now! Arm Hammer!
Pagogo! Rapid Spin!
She did it!
Oh my!
Ms. Liko... Just look at
how well you battle now!
Then we ought to do something, too...
Beary!
Show me your newly-grown wings!
A Bug Terastype... In that case...
Pagogo! Primal Power!
That won’t work. Consecutive Cut!
You continue to increase
the power of your moves...
But...
I have you now!
Pagogo!
Tera Cluster!
You can do it...
Go! Pagogo!
Beary! Consecutive Cut!
Return, Beary.
That was wonderful, Ms. Liko!
An utter defeat for Beary and I.
You did it!
That was so cool, Liko!
Well, guess you might be
pretty strong, huh?
Thank you!
Liko...
You’ve shown me plain as day...
...how well you can fight a Pokémon Battle,
and how strongly you feel about this.
Just what you’d expect...
...from the Rising Voltteccers!
Yeah!
All right!
Now, we have achieved our objective.
So let’s get goin’ already!
How come you get to
boss us around?
How come?
‘Cause I’m the leader, duh.
And who decided that, huh?
Well I don’t care who’s the leader,
but don’t you think he’s right
that we should get a move on?
Yeah.
Even now, as we stand here, the Explorers
are getting ready to spread Strong Spheres all over.
Ideally, we should gather info
while on the move.
And to do that...
A ship...
The Brave Asagi!
We can gather proof quicker
if we’re aboard the ship!
Yeah!
Right...
The Brave Asagi, huh...?
If only it was still around...
Huh?
“If only it was still around”?
So you mean the Brave Asagi
isn’t around anymore?!
Y-Yeah...
What do you mean?
Did I neglect to mention?
Mention what exactly?!
Oh, when we split up...
Orio said she was going to
dismantle the Brave Asagi.
Huh?!
Seriously?
No way... What do we do?
Then...
Let’s have her make a new one!
Don’t copy me, Roy!
You’re the one who was copying me!
Yeah, that’s it...
Let’s ask Orio to make us a new ship.
Yeah. Our very own Brave Asagi.
You kids...
Murdock!
Where’s Orio?
Tell us!
C’mon, quick!
You kids... sure are...
Any reply from Orio?
Nothing yet.
Well, we can work stuff out
when we get there.
Okay, then!
See you around, Murdock!
We’re heading off!
All right!
Say hello to Orio for me!
You stay hard at work
trying new recipes, Murdock!
They’re something else, those kids...
Strong wills... No doubts...
Ms. Kaede.
Yes?
I was the one who said it...
Said what?
That the Rising Voltteccers should disband...
and leave the ship.
That we’d only be keeping those kids
stuck in place if we kept going.
I couldn’t bear that.
But to tell the truth,
I never wanted...
Ms. Liko and her friends have emerged elegantly
from their cocoons and spread their wings.
When it’s Agehunt migration season,
they’ll just keep on flying,
no matter how haggard they become.
You, too, can still spread your wings, Mr. Murdock.
Wouldn’t you agree?
Yo-ssu!
It’s time for Mega Gurumin’s
Mega Mega! Mega Evolution!
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Mega Evolving today is...
The Atrocious Pokémon, Gyarados!
Atrocious Pokémon
Flying
Gyarados
Atrocious Pokémon
Water
Flying
Intimidate
Gyarados
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Atrocious Pokémon
Intimidate
Gyarados
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Atrocious Pokémon
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Classification
What’s it gonna look like when it Mega Evolves?!
Don’t you wanna know, everyone?
Its true form is...
...coming after these commercials!
Ready Go
I’ve found my way through the moon night
With you I saw the sunlight, oh
In our linked hands
is the map we call hope
Speed up, speed up, more and more
Get it now, get it now, tomorrow’s waiting
Carefree as riding a floating airship, we can go
Evolve for the future
Heart getting stronger
When I’m with you, we’ll go so far
If we meet, shake hands
Balls filled with dreams
Try opening them up for adventure
Not giving up is everything, wouldn’t you say?
If I’ve got my bond with you, then all the time
Dreams come true, ready go!
Ready Go
(All the time dreams come true, ready go!)
Go go go
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
Time for the Mega Evolution
you’ve been waiting for!
Mega Gyarados
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Atrocious Pokémon
Water
Evil
Mold Breaker
It leaps out of the water by firing water jets
from the red parts on its sides,
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
propelling it faster than Mach speed!
It has a rough temperament,
but it’ll obey commands
from a trainer it deeply trusts.
Mega Gurumin's Mega Mega! Mega Evolution
You gotta be really careful around it!
Next episode
Let’s set off for the Galar Region!
Yeah!
We only just made it to Paldea
and we’re on the move again...?
We’ll be boarding a boat
from Hakkou City.
I love traveling by boat!
When we set sail on the great big sea,
But it’s a pain and takes forever.
Can’t we get there any quicker?
a tiny little Camome came flying by.
We’d love to, if we could.
Ahh... Our poor Brave Asagi...
At the end of this wide round sea...
Once we meet up with Orio,
I’m sure we’ll be traveling by airship again!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters...
A Flightless Orio, and...