Long ago, there was a bird.
One day, the bird fell asleep in mid-flight,
and a tragedy occurred.
It crashed into a long rock
that protruded up from the earth.
The bird had a disease which would cause it
to turn to stone upon crashing into a rock,
and there it remained, frozen in place,
as aeons passed by.
During some eras,
it was an object of worship...
...while during others,
it served as a drying rack.
Though its function
shifted across eras,
it became deeply rooted
to the area.
And now, in the present day...
In a matter entirely unrelated
to that bird...
...we have the story of a city.
Hello, dear my friends
yume o katatte sugoshita hibi o oboeteru?
Do you remember the days we spent talking about our dreams?
otona ni naru tte muzukashiin da ne
Being an adult is way too hard
kakushiteta mono sagashi ni ikou yo
Let's run off and find what we stashed away
Hey!
chirakatta kokoro nugisute
Throw your cluttered mind away
kumo wa oyoide
Swim through the clouds
kao agete tobidashite ne
Lift your chin up and run away, hey
ame wa agatte
The rain has stopped
issho ni utatte
Sing along with me
te o tsunaide
Hold hands with me
Nobel Matsuri Prize
watashi wa waratte
When I smile
kimi mo waratte
You smile with me
kitto kou yatte
I know that just like this
mata ai ni ikou
We'll meet again
Closed
Big Bro, what was
your star sign again?
Capricorn.
Wow. I present to you...
This week for Capricorns—
Hold on!
Don’t lead with “wow”!
Okay.
Then here’s a revised version.
Revised version?!
So, the ranking for Capricorn is...
Ba-dum ba-dum
ba-dum ba-dum...
Aw, just forget about it!
I don’t believe in that stuff, anyway!
Fine.
Okay, just tell me my lucky item!
Chapter #
Makabe
Household
Is this... actually what it is?
Yep. It’s written right here. Miniskirt.
I see.
So... is this good enough?
What?
Has the lucky item
granted me luck yet?
Who knows?
It has, right...?
Yeah. I looked at it, so it must have!
Via sublimation...
All right!
Wear it!
Wear it, Tatewaku.
Dad!
That’s exactly what
I was hoping to avoid doing!
Well then, what will you do?
I-I... I-I’ll just keep it with me all day,
and make sure it never leaves my side!
Was what I said that jarring?!
Sorry, sorry.
Listen, Tatewaku...
If your lucky item had been curry rice,
what would you have done?
Would you have
simply looked at it all day?
Or kept it with you all day,
never letting it leave your side?
Of course you wouldn’t have, right?
Tatewaku... Curry is meant to be eaten.
And skirts...
...are meant to be worn.
You mentioned wanting to participate
in the next soccer match, yes?
If that new part-time girl shows up,
you’d be able to go to the match.
But there’s no guarantee
that she will show up!
So... put it on, Tatewaku.
For your luck’s sake!
So, what are you going to do?
What?! What the hell’s so funny?!
This is my lucky item!
Don’t take pictures!
To Mom...
To Ecchan...
Don’t send it to people!
Don’t preserve this memory!
Where were you even
keeping that microphone?!
Someone, help me!
STAFF ONLY
Huh? Wait, where’d they go?
When did they stop chasing me?
City
South
Middle
School
Matsuri, if you could have
a single superpower, what would it be?
Chapter #
Friends
The ability to make money
come outta my hands nonstop!
So greedy!
And how about you, Ecchan?
Me?
The ability to make
all of that money counterfeit!
No fair! I’ll get caught!
I cannot allow you
to take over the world that easily.
But Ecchan, that ability...
...would be useless
whenever I’m not around.
So you finally noticed, Matsuri-kun...
Who are you?!
Good evening. I’m Ecchan.
Oh, good. It’s just you, Ecchan.
Without you,
my ability will not manifest.
So, my reason
for choosing that ability...
Is it clear yet?
Nope, beats me.
Think about it a little.
What I’m really after
isn’t the ability.
Yes...
Matsuri...
It’s you!
Ecchan!
Marry me—
REJECTION THROW
Rejection throw!
No sweat!
Classic Ecchan!
Not joining a club and watching sumo
every day has served you well!
That’s not true!
I’m in the Going Home Club!
I’m the Going Home Club’s champion!
If you’re the champion,
what does that make me?
You’re the Going Home Club’s
champion, too!
Two champions!
Shall we eagerly
defend our titles again today?
Let’s defend our titles
and make our mark on history!
Arashima Temple
We’re almost at
the crossroads of farewells.
Fifty yen... Let’s get some juice.
Throat
Aim for the
trashcan.
What’re you doing, Matsuri?
Imagining money
coming out of my hands.
Knock it off, Ecchan!
Don’t send those waves at me!
Mokumesei Manor
I don’t think I can go on any longer.
Please, let me take a break.
C’mon, Sensei, you can do it!
Mr. Editor, I’ve made it this far
with nothing but bummer jokes,
but now...
I’ve got no joke ideas left.
RESUME
I
Please paste
your photo
here
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
RESUME
I
Name:
Nagumo Midori
Western Cuisine Makabe
Heya!
All right, good.
Ooh! You’re really going at it, huh?
Oh, you came at just the right time.
Bring this over there.
Blah... Sure, sure.
Here, take th—
First player, giant pawn.
Second player, medium-size gold.
Ten seconds.
Chapter #
Kata-Yakisoba
One, two, three, four, five, six...
It went in—
Please pretend you never saw that!
Huh?! No, no, no, no!
There’s no way you’re gettin’ outta this!
It went straight in!
Well, what would you do, then?!
Run away!
Ouch!
The owner can’t just run away!
We’ll just hafta tell him
we’re sorry, then!
GOOD
IDEA
Ouch!
Jackass!
How can you act so pure?!
If I apologize...
He’ll yell at me!
That’s so obviously true,
it snapped me wide awake!
Here. Come here.
I can’t say this too loud, but...
...we’ve got no choice
but to trick him.
Since I can’t say it too loud...
He went on and on about his plan,
but my ears felt so fuzzy
that I couldn’t even lift a finger...
SO
Otter Perignon
I bought a real famous one!
Good. Did you get the receipt?
In your wallet.
Great work.
All right, then...
Are you ready?
Kata-Yakisoba
Department
OWNER
Things are already heating up!
Wine & Bag
Department
NAGUMO
Ready, set...
“On the house.”
Sorry!
I am terribly sorry!
I’m so sorry!
Sorry!
Oh, I cannot possibly
apologize enough!
How delightful!
I knew that installing a microphone
was the right move!
Chapter #
Doctor Adatara
Not at all, you two.
Please, raise your heads.
The reason the cork struck my forehead,
and why I became soaked...
...is that you so kindly offered me
complimentary champagne.
It left a dent...
Your thoughtfulness
is most gratifying.
It is only a modest gesture,
but allow me to grant you this...
A Thoughtfulness Award.
This guy...
...hasn’t even noticed
the kata-yakisoba!
I delivered the food.
Why are you bowing down like that?
You actually showed up!
Thank you so much!
You looked like a total flake
based on your résumé,
so I was super worried!
Hey!
As embarrassing as it is,
this is all thanks to me wearing that miniskirt!
All right, I’m gonna go to my room
and get back to my homework—
Hot... H-Hot!
Why is there kata-yakisoba in my bag?!
Wh—
Ahh, so it was just Tatewaku’s bag
this whole time?
Phew
Good thing, huh?
It is not a good thing!
How the hell’d you even fit
two servings of kata-yakisoba in my bag?!
Don’t you get it, Tatewaku?
Do you really expect me to get it?!
You did wear a skirt
for a short time...
But... you quickly
switched back to pants.
BUT
In other words, that’s life!
You doomed yourself to this fate
when you took off your lucky item!
Then how did this happen...
when I’m still wearing it?!
Well, this sure seems familiar!
Don’t just go straight back to work!
Don’t just go straight to eating!
Don’t just go straight to
taking the staff meal home with you!
If you’re gonna mess with me,
then mess with me!
What the hell’s wrong...
with this stupid horoscope?!
What’s with this sorry excuse
for a lucky item?!
That place is smoking again.
Izumi Wako
Chapter #
Oh, no!
Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no...!
I think... that this...
...is totally one of those
“I lost my point card!” situations!
I don’t have a clue
where I might’ve lost it,
so I’ll sniff some Kaimei ink
to calm myself down a bit.
Perhaps it’s due to
this gentle, nostalgic scent,
but for whatever reason,
I find myself reflecting on my life so far.
Those utterly average,
unremarkable twenty years...
...feel a bit depressing,
even to me.
At times like this...
I touch the gills underneath the cap of
one of my dear sweet shiitake mushrooms to relax!
Academically speaking,
this may have the same effect as hot milk.
On a whim, I decide to stroke the surface
of the shiitake mushroom as well,
and fall in love with
its indescribable, velvety texture.
Perhaps this fluttery feeling
could spirit me away to some incredible new world,
away from my ordinary
everyday life...
Just thinking about it
gets my heart racing.
To calm my overflowing emotions...
I touch the putty eraser
that I keep hidden in my pocket,
kneading it at a steady pace.
Every part of the shiitake mushroom
is indispensable.
Whatever the case might be,
I am grateful for this encounter.
Paru paru paru. Point paru paru.
On a whim, I decide to chant a blessing,
hoping for my point card to appear.
“I’ll make your wish come true.”
I-It’s a god!
With such images
dancing through my head...
I get a good feeling
that everything will work out all right,
and so I briskly
make my way to the police box.
The officer is out.
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
Reality truly is cruel.
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
If you recognize
this tsuchinoko
Please tell us!
Excuse me.
Are you looking for this?
Western Cuisine Makabe
Stamp Card
・1 point per meal
・5-10 points: Gift
・15 points: Free Meal
Why yes, I am looking for this!
And just like that, it was found!
Thank you, Mr. Officer!
The god I made yesterday
must have true power.
I return to my room...
...and give the Papico packed into the tip
as an offering to the god.
Papico Sample
The bit of Papico packed into the tip,
which I eat just before it melts,
is exceptionally delicious.
The main thing is also delicious.
What if I add another layer of happiness
to my current level of happiness?
Could it be that I’d become
dangerously happy?
I stretch the putty eraser,
forming the fluffy spots that appear
just before it breaks apart,
and begin gently tapping on them.
The mystery of this cottony substance
being formed from a hard putty eraser...
The bliss of crushing it
all by myself...
This is truly the bestest, super-duperest,
happiest time of all!
However, this happiness
is of a different flavor,
which makes me realize there are so many
different kinds of happinesses left for me to taste.
Reality truly
is cruel.
Oni Kamaboko
Mr. Bummer
A joke...
Anything...
A bummer joke...
We do have...
one ultimate trump card available...
I’m going to say it!
This week’s chapter
will be the last.
Huh?!
A-A joke idea...
has just come to me.
Chapter #
Room 203
‘Sup.
S-S-Sorry!
W-Were you doin’ something dirty?!
A-Absolutely not!
I was just taking
a photo of some broccoli!
Why’d you come
barging in like that, anyway?!
Well, y’know,
I got some leftovers from the staff meal.
Don’tcha wanna
have some too, Niikura?
Thanks for the...
...food.
What’s that smirking
“mwahaha” look for?
Okay! That’ll be one thousand yen!
You hustler!
Chapter #
Speaking of,
how did your part-time job go?
Well, get a load of this...
Two servings of kata-yakisoba
flew straight in, like “whoosh”.
Wow, sounds like a busy day.
You could say that.
What’ve you been up to, Niikura?
I went to university.
You should really go too, Nagumo-san.
To university, I mean.
Like “whoosh”?
Like “whoosh”!
By the way, what were you doin’
with that broccoli earlier?
Ooh! You wanna know?
Mitake Camera
X Month Issue
Ta-dah!
Mitake Camera
X Month Issue
This is the magazine
I bought this morning.
Here, take a look at this!
“Broccoli & Cat”
Michael J. Niikura (Age 18)
Honorable
Mention
Michael J. Niikura (Age 18)
Yes. Me!
That’s awesome!
Like, seriously!
How much didja win for it?!
Nothing. Zero yen.
That’s dumb.
Hey!
The grand prize is a hundred thousand.
A hundred! Thousand!
That’s the dream, isn’t it?
That’s two whole months’ worth of rent.
Show me the grand prize winner.
“Milk Crate and Ikameshi”
Izumi Wako (Age 20)
GRAND
PRIZE
100,000
Yen
We’ve got this!
Niikura, do they accept pictures
taken on a cell phone?
Yeah, I think anything is fine.
For real?! We can totally
get that hundred grand!
Niikura... Niikura,
what d’you take your pictures with?
Oh, I... just use a regular old
boxy camera.
So cheap!
‘Kay, lemme borrow that!
I understand.
Just for you then, Nagumo-san...
Awright!
However!
Please wait until
the end of the month.
Once I get paid,
I can use the money I’ve saved...
...and buy a single-lens reflex camera!
I’ve been working
super hard and saving up!
Until then, I’ll be taking photos
like crazy and submitting them all!
That’s so cool...
Huh?
Niikura... Looks like you already know
what it is you wanna do.
Wh-Wh-Where did that
come from all of a sudden?
The thing that’ll be your thing
through your college days...
You already found it.
That just kinda surprised me.
So... do you wanna be
a photographer someday?
W-Well... If I can manage it,
that’d be great, but...
Why all this out of nowhere...?
Don’t you have anything, Nagumo-san?
Something you want to do?
Yeah, sure I do.
I’ll help you out.
We’ll find it together—
Wait, you do?!
Then what was
that whole spiel for earlier?
Whaddaya mean “spiel”?
So what is it, then?
This thing you want to do.
Something fun.
Then, well...
I guess you should do something fun.
There’s so many things, though.
I can’t choose just one!
But... if I’m gonna do something,
I wanna do the most fun thing possible!
S-S-So...
So pure!
Dream
boyatto shiteta kisetsu wa
I entered a haze
okamainashi ni tokete ku
And the seasons melted away without a care
yudaru toori o toho de going on
Going on foot down the red hot street
-
yume ka utsutsu ka wakannai kedo
If I'm in a dream or not I can't even tell
nebou tsuide no pinchi mo
Sleeping in then ending up in a pinch
mekurumeku yokubari mo sou
Yes, even being blinded by greed
hazukashii no mo muki ni naru no mo
Feeling ashamed and getting uptight
ima ga tabegoro rashii no
Seems that they're all in season right now
itsumo to onaji furi de
Pretending things are just the same
kyonen to chigau natsu da
But summer is different this year
yakkai demo tanoshii
So annoying but so much fun
kimi wa kimi ga ii
You're still you and you are great
neko mo shakushi mo hashiru kono machi de
Everyone and their mother hustles and bustles through this town
kimi to kyou mo itai no
But I just want to spend today with you
yane no mukou ni
Beyond the skyline
kakureta taiyou
The Sun is hiding
aa natsu ga yuku
Ah, summer is going by