Twin Indigo of
Melting Snow
Man, oh man...
Getting seasick is the worst.
You on a trip?
I’m visiting my father.
He lives in Kotobuki Village.
That’s pretty rough.
What do you mean?
Haven’t you heard?
Word is a violent Pokémon
appeared in the Snow-White Forest.
Ooh! This is some fine work!
Is this your first time
in the Hisui Region?
No, I come to the Snow-White Forest
for wood once a year.
I figured it was about time
I started teaching my son the craft.
Boo!
Hey! Akio!
My, what an energetic young man.
I’m very sorry.
Hold it.
There’s a Pokémon in that forest...
A vicious one...
What’s it like?
Have you seen it?
It’s called Zoroark.
A Pokémon
persecuted by humans...
...said to have died
and been reborn.
Persecuted?
Why... would they do
something like that?
People and Pokémon...
...can never coexist.
Can I look over there?
Just don’t go too deep in.
Mm-hmm.
Wai— Sto—
An Azure Spring's Walk
Episode Two
“Lingering Snow, Red”
- Releases Wednesday, June 8 -