Wait!
Thank you!
Over here!
Here, look.
Akio...
Dad.
Twin Indigo
I moved here
soon after you left home.
It’s been three years.
Have you been doing well?
Do you think
I could stay for a few days?
I came to search for herbs
in the Snow-White Forest.
You’re still pretending
to be a doctor?
What is that?
We don’t know.
It’s happened several times recently.
Something might be happening in the forest...
A Pokémon!
It’s hurt!
Wait! Stay in here!
Somebody, please...!
Why are you closing the gate?
Shouldn’t we go help it?
Get back inside!
But it’s hurt!
We should help it!
I believe there are other
injured Pokémon in the forest.
Won’t someone please join—?
Why should we
have to help Pokémon?
Hmm?
It’s their fault we can’t go
into the forest, you know.
Yeah! It’d be much better
if those monsters just disappeared.
Yeah, that’s right!
We, the Security Corps, will go.
What do you mean?!
We are not going there
to help the Pokémon.
But it’s undeniable that
something strange is happening in the forest.
We need to investigate
for the village’s safety.
Why are you
so fixated on Pokémon?
I don’t know.
But...
I want to understand them.
You can’t walk in the snow
with shoes like those.
Good luck!
Take care!
Don’t do anything reckless!
You’re not scared?
No.
There’s somebody I’d like to see.
What is that?
The heavens are...
When did...?!
Follow him!
Hey, look!
Those are...
Hey!
They’re protecting their young...
It’s too dangerous!
Come back here!
Come back!
What are you doing?!
I want to give this
to the little ones.
I know it’ll help!
Akio!
The Pokémon are...
Let’s go!
We should get them
to the village.
We’re not equipped to do that!
There’s something weird here!
Hurry!
All of you, run.
No! You’re coming with us!
Dad!
Let’s go!
This way!
Hurry!
We have to get away!
What’s going on?!
What is it?
My friend...
came for me.
I...
...don’t know why you’re
so fixated on Pokémon.
But...
Perhaps you...
Come visit once in a while.
Twin Indigo of
Melting Snow