Oh!
Ow...
Julian, why don’t I drop you off?
I’m good, I can walk.
See you.
Huh?
Huh?!
I didn’t call for a taxi.
I told you I don’t want a taxi—
Huh...?
Wh-Whoa!
Hey— Gogoat?
Let me down!
Wow!
Wh—
Gah!
G—
Wh—
Whoa!
Th-Thanks...
I...
...didn’t want to go to school,
to be honest.
My friend and me...
Hey...
Take me somewhere even more fun.
I don’t want to...
...go to school.
Huh?
Gogoat?
Whoa!
Lucas!
Julian!
Sorry I’m late!
All good, don’t worry.
Let’s hurry!
O-Ow...!
Ugh! What gives?!
I’ve got to...
...apologize to Lucas.
Lucas...
Ow!
Julian!
I’m sorry!
I’m sorry, too.
Huh?
What are we gonna do?!
We’re gonna be late!
Don’t worry,
we can still make it on time!
Right?
Let’s go!
ashi o tomete futo furikaeru to
When I stopped, and looked back on a whim
sukoshi atama sageta kimi ga ita
there you were, your head turned slightly down
fushigi na jumon ni kakerareta you de
And just as if some strange spell was upon me
kokoro no oku o subete minukareta
you could see straight into my heart
warai mo sezu okori mo shinai kimi wa
The way you never laughed, never got mad at me
boku no zutto tomatta jikan o ugokashiteyuku
You set my long-stopped time back in motion again
dakishimeta omoide ga
The memories I held so close
hitotsuzutsu afuretekuru
all spill out one by one
hashirinukete sagashitsudzuketa keshiki
Racing through, looking for the right view
futo ukanda natsukashi no basho e
I dropped by a nostalgic spot on a whim
tomaru wake mo naku oikaketa
I couldn't stop—Just wishing
suteki na ano hi no futari to ashita e no kitai o negatte
for that lovely day of ours I've sought, and my hopes for tomorrow
mada kakushita boku no kimochi o
The feelings I've still kept hidden
ato sukoshi de miserareru no ni
I was so close to revealing them
fukakkou de bukiyou de tsutaerarenai mama
But I'm just so clumsy and awkward, I couldn't manage it
mata furidashi ni
And I'm back to square one
ano hi no ooki na senaka ga hajimete yuuki o kureta nda
The broad back from that day gave me the first piece of courage
tsugi wa hontou no boku ga
Next time, it'll be me
tsugi wa chanto kotoba de tsutaetai nda
Next time, I want to tell you with my own words