And now, at long last
the final match begins!
When the dust settles, which of them
will lay claim to the glory of victory?!
Let’s do it, Kucheat!
Come on out, Sirknight!
Let’s go, Sirknight.
We’re the strongest!
Wha—?!
G-Gah... Ow, ow, ow, ow...
Oh, man! I’m gonna be late!
Sorry, Sirknight!
Headin’ out!
I’m heading out for my deliveries!
Now, time to set off!
Coming!
I’ve got a package for you.
Oh, sorry!
There you go.
Thank you very much!
I’ll leave it here for you, all right?
Thank you.
I’ll need your signature!
Give me just a minute!
Whoa! It’s a package, Emonga!
Ooh, it’s from Grandma! Wow!
Thank you—
Ralts! Psyche Beam!
Kirlia! Psyche Beam!
Sirknight! Psyche Beam!
Wow, look!
Juicy-lookin’ Taupol Berries!
Yummy!
Sorry for the wait!
Right, Emonga? Aren’t they yummy?
I’m exhausted...
There sure were
a ton of deliveries today...
I’ve gotta be in early again tomorrow,
so I better take a quick... shower...
Finally found it!
If I put this and this together...
Look, Sirknight!
It’s a Mega Stone!
Using that Mega Stone,
and my Key Stone...
...along with the bond we have,
we can Mega Evolve!
Next tournament, we’re gonna win!
The fierce battle has concluded,
and finally...
...we have a winner!
Let’s go, Sirknight.
Sirknight...
Sorry...
...I couldn’t become Champion...
Yuugo!
You’ll end up missing your train!
Sirknight...
Let’s go!
It’s the start of a new journey!
Sirknight?
What are you doing here?!
Sirknight! You’ve gotta run!
Sirknight!
Forget about me and run!
Let’s go, Mega Sirknight!
Moonforce!
That’s...
How did it get in there?
Sirknight...
You really are the best partner!
Sirknight.
We’re always gonna be the strongest!
There’s plenty more in the POKÉTOON series!
Subscribe to the channel and go find your favorite episodes!