Ow, ow, ow...
Huh?
Hmm... Where could it have gone?
You there...
Then... let’s have a battle.
If I win, will you return that?
Right!
Go, Kinokoko!
Mind Headbutt!
Would you like to learn
to battle like that?
Then... Come with me!
Whoa! Are you okay?
Think it’s lost?
Kinogassa!
Still hanging in there?
Big man Haidai’s
got some moves to dish out.
Best hold on tight,
or you’ll get washed away!
One more serving of Crab Hammer!
Hey, hold on!
Mr. Haidai...
I’m sorry!
Dat’s a real lively Pokémon!
I truly am sorry...
You’re good at locking in on a target
and hitting them, huh?
With some training,
that’ll be a great asset.
So, Carbou...
Let’s see to it that you can
win battles with honor.
Go, Bakuuda!
That’s enough!
Yeah.
Carbou, come here.
Come on, this way.
This armor has been passed down
in my family for generations.
And you know what’s interesting?
There’s a legend linking it to Carbou.
The protagonist is a meek Carbou,
with a strong sense of justice.
It’s the exact opposite
of how you were when I met you.
It ends up having to fight
this mean Gänger...
...but being so meek,
it’s not good at fighting.
Yet, even that Carbou...
...chooses its own future.
Carbou?
It... was true...
Guren'arma...
Congratulations.
You’ve chosen your own future, too!
Guren'arma?
Now then, tomorrow’s the day
of the tournament!
Don’t be afraid to take part, everybody!
And bring your friends!
You’re finally up
in the next match, correct?
Yes.
How do you feel
about your chances?
Good question...
My Pokémon have grown so strong
that I barely recognize them.
I hope to battle well too,
so I don’t hold them back.
Thank you!
Is that someone’s Pokémon?
It’s not time
for the next match yet...
What is that aura...?
Guren'arma!
Wide Force!
It’s acting weird...
Like it knows what
Guren'arma will do next...?
Stop it in place!
Fire Vortex!
Guren'arma?
Guren'arma!
Did it just... smile?
You beat that bad Pokémon!
Your Guren'arma’s so cool!
What an achievement!
Oh, we wouldn’t say that.
Hey!
Guren'arma!
Hey...
Soublades...
Would you like to
come with me, too?
Since you two
seem to get on so well...
No, huh?
The Carbou Who Were Childhood Friends
Heading higher than anyone, further than anyone
dare yori takaku dare yori tooku
As I head my way
michi no tochuu
I’ll be fine even without you
kimi ga inakutatte daijoubu
I can look to the sky
sora o aogu
Someday, let’s both compare our answers
itsu no hi ka kotaeawase o shiyou
Whoa
Just like the day when my tears ran dry,
namida mo karekitta itsuka no you ni
every wound I take as a shield is my pride
mamoru tame ni tsuku kizu wa hokori
Wake up from my dream and it’s all gone,
yume kara samete subete motodoori
no, I’ve moved forward but still far from my goal
iya sono saki ni tatsu no sa goal wa tooi
Even if I’m scared, even if I’m sad,
kowakutemo sabishikutemo
gotta find a reason and light my own fire!
jibun ni hi o tsukeru riyuu o mitsukero
‘Cause this pain I gotta treasure,
mata meguriau sono hi made wa
‘til the day I see you again, yeah?
kono itami ga takaramono ni naru daro?
Let it beat loud (Yeah)
sawagidasu (Yeah)
My heart is singing out (Yeah)
kono kodou ga utau nda (Yeah)
Don’t stop me
boku o tomenaide
I’m not just anyone
dareka ja nakute
Yeah, it’s me just like old times,
sou sa boku no mama de
I gotcha (Yeah)
So, I’ll see ya when we meet again...
sore ja mata au hi made...
There are other works in this series!
Subscribe to the channel
and support the Pokémon!