Over my summer vacation,
I decided to observe my friend, Okorizaru!
Okorizaru is very short-tempered.
Whether it’s playing...
...or eating.
Even while dreaming, it’s angry.
And that got me thinking!
“I would very much like
to see Okorizaru not be angry!”
Okorizaru!
Are you hungry, by any chance?
Easy does it...
Here you go!
Here you go! Here you go! Here you go! Here you go!
Have this, as well!
Hmm...
Operation Food was unsuccessful.
Of course!
Do you feel itchy anywhere?
It’s not too hot for you, is it?
Please tell me if it hurts, okay?
Let’s get you all freshened up!
Let’s get you looking really cool!
That came out great!
Hmm...
Operation Nice and Refreshed
was also unsuccessful.
Of course!
Cute things!
Sparkly things!
Fun things!
Usso ussoso ussosososo!
Hey!
Let your mind be at rest...
Feels lovely...
How do you feel, Okorizaru?
This operation, too,
was unsuccessful.
After that,
we tried a wide variety of things.
Picnicking...
Stargazing...
Mountain hiking...
Sunbathing...
But through all of it,
Okorizaru remained angry.
We went skiing...
Canoeing...
Ziplining...
And watched a movie!
We ate a king-size parfait, as well!
We went to hot springs...
...and to a concert!
Yahoo!
Okorizaru, what should we do next?!
Pottery, perhaps?
Or should we form a band?
Of course! How about skydiving?!
What is it?
Okorizaru...
Did you want some
curry-flavored popcorn, perhaps?!
And at that very moment...!
I finally understood!
Perhaps all Okorizaru wanted
was to become stronger!
Huh?
So ya started Pokémon Battling, didja?
A lanky li’l wimp like you...
Best joke I’ve heard all year.
So, allow yours truly...
...to teach ya a thing or two
about real battling!
Dellie!
We were triumphant!
We triumphed...
...and triumphed...
...and triumphed, and triumphed,
and triumphed...
...and triumphed.
We won...
...and won...
...and won, and won, and won,
and won, and won, and won!
We, um... We won many battles.
Oh, my! Okorizaru may have
pushed the Champion into a corner...
...but it might finally be out of steam!
Okorizaru!
You mustn’t give in!
We’ve worked so hard
to get this far!
We’ve done so, so much...
The two of us!
We will win!
Okorizaru!
Let us do this!
Fist of Wrath!
Whoa!
A new Champion is born today!
We did it...
Surely, Okorizaru must be
satisfied now...
Hmm?
Okorizaru?
Unbelievable!
Okorizaru evolved into Konoyozaru!
Amazing...
Ultimately...
...Okorizaru stayed angry
through it all.
But I will not give up!
My next observation project
will be on Konoyozaru!
I’m scared!
(hai hai)
(Yeah! Yeah!)
(pakkaan)
(Ka-thunk!)
You're always so hungry, and your hair won't sit right
onaka ga suita shi kamigata mo kimaranai
itsumo furimawasarete ippai okocchattari shite
You always drag me around and get angry at me
dakedo ganbatteru kimi wa mabushii
But you're so dazzling when you give it your all
kao o agereba uso mitai ni sora harewatatte iku
When I look up, the sky is so clear it almost seems fake
sou desu!!!
Of course!!!
subete uketomete jibun tsuranuite yuke
Accept any and all challenges and remain true to yourself
okotte (YES!!!) tanoshinde (YES!!!) zenryoku de ikiru
Getting mad (YES!!!) Enjoying yourself (YES!!!) Living life for all it's worth
sou desu!!!
Of course!!!
kimi to issho nara mainichi adventure
With you, every day is an adventure
super positive (YES!!! YES!!!)
Super positive (YES!!! YES!!!)
future dream (YES!!! YES!!!)
My dream for the future (YES!!! YES!!!)
kono yo no genkai tsukinukero
Break through all the limits of this world...
ai yai yaah
Ai-yai-yaah