Just one more...
I’m off!
Okay!
Mommy!
Wait!
I’m all done with today’s chores!
Very well.
You have ten seconds
to present your case.
I’ve gotten really good at
doing my chores
so I’ll be okay even without
you and Daddy!
So please,
let me go on a journey!
Not happening!
Why?!
All my friends
got to go already!
Plus, weren’t you and Daddy
Pokémon Trainers when you were younger, too?
So why can’t I?!
Because you don’t pay attention
to your surroundings.
It’s too dangerous for you.
But...!
I’m heading off to work!
No luck again, huh?
C’mon, Daddy, tell Mommy...
I can’t convince her for you,
Tsubomi.
She’ll understand someday.
I can’t wait for “someday”!
I wanna head out with Flamebud
and try to become Champion, just like you did!
Daddy’s always been my hero.
Is that you and Flamebud?
That’s right.
Here comes a Flamethrower!
So cool...
Lizardon’s down!
The battle is over!
The winner of match 4 is...
And that’s why I’m gonna
be the Champion!
I’ll do it for you!
Thank you. I’m rooting for you.
But Mommy...
Daddy couldn’t even do it.
How could you become Champion?
...she said!
How can she know if
she won’t even let me try?!
Oh, it’s time to feed Flamebud.
I’ll do it!
I gotta deepen my bond
with Flamebud!
C’mon, eat!
Look over here.
Eat up!
You again?!
You’re not allowed
to feed Flamebud!
C’mon!
Keep it together!
You’re a Lizardon!
What a cute tail!
He used to be really cool!
Flamebud and I are gonna
go on a journey...
...to become the
Pokémon League’s Champions!
Show ‘em!
Flamebud! Fly!
F-Flamethrower!
Too bad!
Let’s go.
Oh, fine!
I’ll go on a journey on my own!
Th-Thank you for your patronage!
There goes my allowance...
First I gotta catch a Pokémon!
A Pikachu! All right...!
There!
No way!
I’m gonna catch something!
There!
Waaait!
C’mon!
No waaaay...
I only have one Monster Ball left...
What do I do?
Maybe I shouldn’t have bought
all those Potions...
Wh-What?!
That one’s Nidoran, right?
He’s kinda cute!
He hasn’t noticed...
Oh, no!
Are you okay?
Stop!
You saved me...
You’re hurt.
You need help.
Here! A Potion!
Thanks for helping me.
You’re really strong.
But...
You have to be careful,
or you’ll get into more trouble
like before.
You have to keep a look out...
Because you don’t pay attention
to your surroundings.
It’s too dangerous for you.
Is this how Mommy felt?
We might be pretty similar.
C-Could you be...
...his Mommy and Daddy?
Y-You’re wrong!
He was just helping me...
S-See you!
Wh-Wh-Wh—
Why?!
Don’t follow me...
Is that my hat?
What’s that?!
What’s going on?
It’s Nidoking!
Hide, quickly!
Wait!
They’re just angry because
they think I took their son!
This is no place for children!
Doesn’t look like
they’re listening.
This is bad!
I have to...
Tsubomi won’t answer my calls!
She’ll come home
as soon as she gets hungry.
Hot!
Are you all right?!
She takes after her father...
Flamebud!
Tsubomi!
You’re supposed to call if you’re late!
...I’m sorry.
It’s my fault
the Pokémon are fighting.
Flamebud! Please help me!
Flamebud is my Pokémon.
He won’t listen to you...
Flamebud.
Please!
If we don’t do something fast...
Don’t worry.
I won’t hurt your
Mommy and Daddy!
Flamebud!
Flamethrower!
Tsubomi...
Flamebud! Great Blaze!
So cool!
She stopped the Pokémon...
She reminds me...
...of you when you were younger.
Don’t worry. He’s all right.
See you, Nidoran.
You want to come with me?
Looks like we’re safe now.
That’s a relief!
Tsubomi!
Mommy! Daddy!
I’m sorry I made you worry.
You’re not hurt, are you?
I’m fine!
I can’t believe you managed
to ride Flamebud!
Thank you, Flamebud!
Mommy! Daddy!
I want to go on a journey
with Nidoran!
Tsubomi...
My heart was beating so fast
when I was riding Flamebud.
I want to have more exciting adventures
like that, with Nidoran!
We’ll become stronger together, and then
we will become the Pokémon League Champions!
All you need for an adventure is
your own dream and partner.
You’ve met yours, huh?
Give it your all.
No matter what trouble you run into,
you’ll find a way if you work together.
Do you mean...?!
Yes.
You have my permission
to become a Pokémon Trainer.
Yaaaay! Finally!
Quiet down!
Let’s go home before you
fall and hurt yourself!
You can have some of your favorite
Mushroom Curry tonight!
For real?
I love Daddy’s Curry!
See you later!
Sure.
Take care of yourself.
You’re still worried?
What if she doesn’t make it...?
I’m afraid she’ll get hurt.
I was happy when I lost to you.
Flamebud and I both...
...gave it everything we had.
I suppose you’re right.
I lost after that, too,
but I don’t regret it.
I got to have an
adventure of my own...
And I met you.
The adventure was
just the first step.
Tsubomi’s dream
is only just beginning.
Look how far she’s gone already.
Here it comes!
Let’s do this...
Partner!