Wow!
The real deal!
So cute...
Hmm?
A Lucky...
...with a hat?
Hmm...?
Ah! I have to go
to my uncle’s house!
Let’s see...
The Safari Zone warden’s house is...
Ah... Ah...
Achoo!
Achoo! Achoo! Achoo!
Gweh... My nose is so itchy...
Oh?
A Lucky?!
Huh?! So big!
Oh!
Wait a minute...
Is this...
...you?
Hold it!
Gimme back...
...my hat!
Darn it! Got away from me again...
Oh!
Uncle Bozly?!
Hmm? Oh...
Meg?
What took you so long?
Thanks for having me over
for the week, Uncle!
Just now...
Hmm?
That Lucky with the hat just now...
Do you not like her?
Hmph!
Just a resident troublemaker
of the Safari Zone, that’s all.
Aww, c’mon!
Let me go with you!
Not happening. Too dangerous.
Not a job for a kid.
I’ll be good!
I doubt it.
Then... I’m going exploring
with Orachiff!
You really think Orachiff
ain’t coming with me?
Hmph!
Hmm?
Oh! It’s Grandpa and Mom...
Uncle’s there too, and...
Lucky?!
Geez! What’s his problem?
Can’t believe he actually
left me behind...
Well, fine!
I can explore all by myself!
Huh?
Nothing but places I can’t go!
...can’t go! ...can’t go! ...go!
Hmph... It’s always no, no, no...
Huh?
Sounds like... wind?
Oh, no!
This is awful!
Wh-What do I do...?
Um... A Potion...
Do I have one somewhere?
Oh!
Lucky?
Wow!
Oh, thank goodness!
Wha—?!
It’s that rare Lucky with the hat!
I want to add her to my collection!
Let’s open a clinic together!
If I catch you,
my dreams’ll come true!
Come be...
...my partner!
She vanished!
Wait for me, my Lucky!
I didn’t know...
...Lucky could go that fast.
Huh...? What...?
Was that... another move?
Well now!
You’ve all perked right up!
That’s awful strange...
Even the lookout head nodded off.
And that Miniryu was all sparky,
like electricity was going through it!
Electricity?
No way, not unless a nearby Pokémon
used some paralysis move.
And then...!
That Lucky with the hat
came to help!
Just happened to be passing by, eh?
Nuh-uh! I know what I saw!
I don’t want to talk about her.
Uncle, why do you hate that Lucky?
If you had a fight,
why don’t you just make up?
You’re just a kid,
you wouldn’t get it.
Yeah, well, you...
You’re not actin’ like a grown-up!
She was...
...my old man’s—
your grandpa’s partner.
Things used to be fine...
But when I took over
as warden after my pops,
I inherited that one hat
from him...
...only for that troublemaker
to steal it and run off.
Huh?!
I’m going out for night patrol.
You just get to bed, all right?
I wonder why Lucky
stole Uncle’s hat...
Ah!
A Yayakoma!
Need a towel!
Will it be able to
fly again tomorrow?
Thank you, Lucky!
So you’re not gonna
give Uncle his hat back?
Are you trying to
tell him something?
Oh...
Do you wanna come inside
‘til the rain stops?
I won’t say a word to Uncle—
You’ve got a lotta nerve,
showing up here again...
How long are you gonna
drag out this game of tag?
Hmm?
Is Uncle home?
Stop! Urgh!
What’s with you, huh?
Are you that against
me being warden?
I’ve been doing my best
to make the Safari Zone a better place...
But you just keep
getting in my way.
Enough already...
Gimme back...
...my hat!
Um...
Did you guys... make up?
Huh...?
Wh-Wh-Wh—
What just...?!
We have not!
Glad you’re feeling better!
So, like...
Lucky got away
from Uncle again last night.
Hmm...
Something wrong?
Seems the Saihorn are misbehaving.
Gotta go check up on them in person.
Lots of Pokémon
have been acting weird lately.
I had it in mind to seal up
the southern caverns today...
Oh, yeah! Uncle, you’ve been
blocking off too many places!
Well, I gotta!
Otherwise,
trainers could end up in trouble!
Why are the Saihorn so mad?
Well, there are Hanekko nearby,
so I figure it’s ‘cause of
their Rage Powder.
Hanekko?
Ha... Hane... Ha... Ha...
Achoo! Achoo! Achoo! Achoo!
Aaaah...
Achoo!
What’s the matter?
Hay fever?
Urgh... No...
Pokémon powder moves
just make me like this...
I sneezed a bunch when I was
at the place you found me yesterday, too...
Which pond did you find
that paralyzed Miniryu at?
Um... It was in the northern part
of the Safari Zone...
Mmh? Don’t tell me...
How come?
Are you going somewhere?
Y-Yeah...
You wanna...
...tag along?
Ah... Ah...
Achoo!
Need to wait in the car?
I wanna come with!
This oughta help a bit, yeah?
Ooh!
Whoa!
Awesome!
Guess I closed off the paths
the wind blew through...
Which meant Hanekko and the rest
couldn’t ride the wind anymore and got stuck here.
They couldn’t circulate like normal,
which led to problems for other Pokémon.
Orachiff!
I knew it!
Look, Uncle!
Lucky keeps coming to help!
I can’t believe it...
Upsy-daisy!
Wow!
So pretty!
It’s like a flower field
reaching up into the sky!
Huh?
Uncle!
Hmm?
You and Lucky...
You’ve both been doing your best
for the Safari Zone.
You’re exactly alike!
You were always...
trying to help me?
And you taking the hat...
Was that your way
of saying “Follow me”?
Lucky...
Everything I did...
I’m sorry.
Please continue...
...to protect the Safari Zone with me!
Oh!
She gave you your hat back?
More or less...
And that’s quite a tan
you have, Meg!
Yeah!
See you later, Uncle!
Be nice to Lucky!
Hmph.
Looks like my big brother
learned to loosen up a bit.
Was that thanks to you?
Huh? Me?
Mom...
I guess there’s lots of
different kinds of grown-ups, huh?
There sure are.
Oh... Oh, yeah!
Mom, that reminds me...
Huh?
What?!
Whoa, what the...?!
Huh?!
That was Lucky
And this was Lucky
But nobody even notices
Don't need no magic
Let's just imagine
Daydream up futures in the clouds
In your mischievous ways
Sometimes you fade away
I just want to be by your side
One more time
You
Yoo-hoo-hoo
Don't you wanna dance?
That's enough ups and downs, no no no
Yeah, just shake it, dance with me
Yoo-hoo-hoo
Don't you wanna dance?
Come on, wake up, I'm here, baby
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Lucky dance is for you, baby
Lucky dance is...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
There are more episodes
in the POKÉTOON series!
Subscribe to the channel
and support Pokémon!