Oh! Hey, Kamina!
Another day, another song?
Yeah! Cause...
...when I turn fifteen,
I’m gonna enter the Grand Prix!
aa machikirenai no
Ah, I just can't wait
kirakira no stage
For that twinkling stage
tonari ni wa sou, partner
And at my side, that's right! My partner
fan no egao ni kakomarete
Surrounded by the smiles of all my fans
dare yori mo stage de kagayaku no
I'll shine brighter on the stage than anyone
fuan na hito mo, shippai shichatta hito mo,
All the anxious people, all the people who've made mistakes,
okubyou na hito mo, kinchou shiteiru hito mo
all the shy people, and all the people who're nervous
minna matomete egao ni shichau no
I'll take every last one of them and make them smile
Dance with me!
watashi wa Kamina, Kamina
I'm Kamina, Kamina
sono hi ga kitara
And when my day comes
saikou no partner to issho ni
Along with an unbeatable partner
hikarikagayaku ano stage ni tatsu no
That shining stage so far away, is where we will stand
watashi wa Kamina, Kamina
I'm Kamina, Kamina
Who’s your partner, miss?
U-Uhh...
I’m scouting for one righ—
Hey! I love your singing voice!
How’d you like to sing with me?
Just take a look!
Look at everyone’s smiles!
They’re all waiting for you!
yuuki o daseta kimi to mietekuru yo
With your bravery, I can finally picture it
suteki na keshiki ga soko ni
That marvelous scene, why it's right there!
kitto futari nara motto saki made
Surely together, we'll get to go even further
ikeru hazu
than we could alone
Hey, Tyltto!
How about you become my partner?
Three years have passed!
The day’s finally here!
It’s my fifteenth birthday!
Now I can send in my application for the Grand Prix!
Renée and her partner made their debut at fifteen,
so we can make our debut at fifteen too, can’t we?
We’ll finally get to stand on the stage!
All right, Tyl!
The Grand Prix’s next month!
Let’s practice again today!
Then, how about we race
to our usual park?
Ready... Bang!
I went the wrong way again...
That pose looks great, Tyl!
Step, step, step...
We’re syncing up!
Our harmony sounds incredible!
Gonna keep on practicing
in your dreams?
How about we touch up
the pre-chorus dance routine a bit?
Let’s do our best out there today!
What’s wrong, Tyl? You’re so tense!
Relax, relax!
Now, let’s go!
Are you all excited?
Time to watch the birth
of a brand-new star!
So then...
Let the Twinkle Grand Prix...
...begin!
How is she not here yet?
She’s not gonna make it in time.
What’s her contact info?
Let’s just put the next girl on first.
It was crazy crowded
and I got separated from Tyl!
Hey, hey! Looks like the Grand Prix’s
really heating up!
Tyl, where are you?
That last performance was amazing!
I wonder what the next girl will be like.
Oh, I can’t wait!
Tyl, your singing voice
is just so lovely!
How’d you like to sing with me?
Our harmony sounds incredible!
Tyl, you’re the best!
I believe in you, Tyl!
Tyl!
You evolved?
Your neck’s grown really long!
So cute!
It appears your Tyltalis
has found the perfect partner.
Whoa!
Thank you!
You’re starring in the Grand Prix, no?
Good luck.
Huh? Yeah.
Gotcha.
You were this close
to missing your chance...
...to prove that
what I saw was real...
...and you would one day
sing upon a grand stage.
There are places...
...that Pokémon alone,
and people alone, cannot reach.
But Pokémon and people both share
the same desire to have their songs heard.
Now, Tyltalis!
Show me the unbeatable bond
between you and your partner!
futari de hitotsu
Two connected as one
kokoro no naka no honoo
Inside the heart, there lies a flame
shinjite susumeba
Trust in it as you go on
ooki na hikari ni naru
And it'll give off a bright light
maigo ni naru no mo warukunai
It's not bad to get lost at times
anata no koe ga michishirube
I have your voice to guide me back
futari de hitotsu
Two connected as one
kyoukai o koete
Cross over the borderline
Lost and found, we go la-oh-oh
futari de hitotsu
Two connected as one
kyoukai o koeyou
Let's cross over the borderline
It Mega Evolved!
I’ve never seen that before!
We need to go our way tonight
We keep moving, moving on
susumitsudzukeyou
Let's keep moving forward
This moment is ours
We keep moving on
Ahh... That was so much fun!
You really turned into
a whole new you, Tyl!
I never would’ve guessed the necklace
the lady with sunglasses gave us was a Key Stone.
It just stings a little
that we didn’t win.
What’re you doing? That tickles!
How about we make some big fireworks
with Destroyer Beam next time?
There’s plenty more in the POKÉTOON series!
Subscribe to the channel and go find your favorite episodes!