Now, taking the lead
is the boy in the red cap!
Following behind
is the girl in the round glasses!
She had a late start, but little by little
she’s making up the distance!
Her legs, trained through
many games of tag, are...
Umm...
Right, super strong!
Now, just past the hill
awaits the cliffside curve!
The young man pedals hard
to climb the hill, too!
They’re neck and neck!
The girl takes the inside!
Whoa! Forget the inside,
she’s gone completely off-course!
Where are you going,
girl in the round glasses?!
Ahh! She races right into the barn!
Watch out!
She just barely avoids the Pokémon
and keeps going!
A hair’s breadth from colliding!
The girl has made it out of the barn!
And they reunite...
She’s turned the tables!
Your dinner’s going to get cold.
Aww... Due to a sudden onset twister,
the race has been temporarily halted.
As soon as the weather clears up—
Who were you just calling a twister?
Also, this... is not a toy.
Yurado,
I’ve made your favorite pot pie today.
Pot pie?!
Who will be the first to break through
the pie crust covering the plate?
The spoon goes in!
Competitor data, check.
Past results data, check.
Director’s comments... Huh?
Me first!
Excuse me, dear customer,
if you would kindly
allow me to pass by...
They’re gone!
Garoola?
Oh!
The director’s comments?!
Now that’s my partner for you!
Mom, your stopwatch.
Ah.
Now that’s my daughter for you!
Much obliged.
Yurado!
Mom has an important job again today,
so if you would please
afford me some silence.
I beseech you!
Okay.
And same to you.
And it’s begun!
The Butterscotch Cup!
I’m Karimna,
and I’ll be your commentator today.
All done!
Hey, how about
we make a diorama today?
One even bigger than Dad’s!
One where we can commentate on skiing,
and rock climbing too!
Our time limit:
Until that tournament ends!
Our mission this time...
...is to make no noise
while we build it.
First, we tear up paper.
Then, we stick it onto the bowl.
Yeah, it’s looking the part!
I think I might be a genius!
This is Competitor Eramisu’s
first time entering!
He passed the preliminaries with flying colors,
advancing to the top eight!
Could he have any secret plans
up his sleeves for the finals?
The cheers, filling the venue’s dome,
spur on the Pokémon to fight harder!
The lift’s all done!
Now, lastly,
let’s make a snowy mountain!
We’ll connect the summit
and the house with the lift!
Won’t that be just the best?
Is this what they call a “snowscape”?
Chandela uses Evil Pulse!
That hurt! A harsh strike!
Garoola returns the favor
with Giga Impact!
Go get something I can fit in here!
Yeah, stuff like this!
Wait, isn’t this a Mega Stone?!
That’s precious, so put it back!
Chandela’s done for!
After a tenacious display,
it now exits the stage!
It returns to its trainer.
Sent out next is...
Yukinooh! Just the kind of play
we’ve come to expect from Competitor Teriora!
Now, what will Competitor Eramisu do?
The burn she suffered from attacking Chandela earlier
is wearing away at Garoola’s stamina little by little!
Whoa! And now,
Yukinooh Mega Evolves!
Competitor Eramisu
is truly teetering on the edge of a cliff!
Garoola is unable to move
due to the recoil from Giga Impact.
Will this spell the end
for their battle?!
Competitor Teriora
piles on another attack!
Mega Yukinooh uses Blizzard!
It dealt huge damage!
Now! If you won’t Mega Evolve right now,
then what are you waiting for?!
Just in time!
They Mega Evolve,
then close in for a...
...Grow Punch!
What a shock!
He’s turned the tables and won!
A new monarch is born!
You’re really sure?
You should always start with high quality tools.
That’s my motto.
But...
You mustn’t make noise
while Mom’s working.
Roger!
Seeing Garoola Mega Evolve
was amazing.
How many times
have they Mega Evolved before?
Yesterday was their first time.
Their first time?!
How come?
It’d make them stronger.
Why didn’t you
Mega Evolve them before?
What a Pokémon wants to be
is all up to them...
And trying to get stronger
is just one path of many, I guess?
Even though you’re
a Pokémon Battle commentator?
Well, that is a good point...
And they’re off!
Quickly accelerating
as they head for the first set of bumps!
Forcefully leaping over it,
they maintain a beautiful mid-air form!
The techniques we’ve come to expect!
They even soar past the next set, too!
They’ve made a stable landing after such a high jump!
But this is where the real match begins.
Many indents lie ahead!
Weaving their way through
without losing speed will be important!
Twisting their body slightly,
Competitor Teura heads towards the next rough!
Bumps upon bumps await them!
Expending no excess effort, Competitor Teura
turns their body with the minimum possible...
There’s plenty more in the POKÉTOON series!
Subscribe to the channel and go find your favorite episodes!