This one’s...
Wooper!
And they’re Otachi and Ootachi.
Those are...
Hanekko.
Hiro!
Coming!
Hiro?
Uh...
Huh?
Home’s this way.
Right, of course.
Honestly, if he can remember
Pokémon names so easily...
He always was
an expert on them, after all.
A Midnight Adventure
With Yamikarasu
Right you are.
Airm'd—!
Huh?
Why... did that suddenly
bring back memories?
What are these memories...?
Who are you...?
Hiro.
Hiro, let’s go.
R— Right.
Be careful, watch your step!
H... Huh?
I’m home.
You must be...
...Hinoarashi...
...and Apalm.
Um...
Huh?
Um... Uh, sorry...
Don’t worry, Hiro.
See?
Come see, everyone.
Hiro’s back home.
Uh... Um...
Don’t worry!
It’s going to be okay!
You got better
and got to come home.
Take all the time you need
to remember.
This is... my room.
I have to remember...
Whoa!
A Yamikarasu?!
What’s going on?!
Why’s it want me?!
Whoa!
Huh?
What was that about...?
Sorry about earlier.
You see... When I ended up in the hospital,
I forgot a lot of things.
I’m trying my best
to remember, though.
We were friends, right?
All right!
And this was our greeting!
C’mon, food’s here.
It almost feels like
everything’s back to normal.
Think we worried too much?
The doctors did say he’d remember
more and more over time.
Right.
The Pokémon Champion Battle!
Johto Region Match!
The challenger facing the Champion today
has traveled all over and obtained many Gym Badges!
Will a new Champion
be crowned today?!
Or will...
Champion... Gym Badges...
That was your dream, wasn’t it?
My dream...
The Pokémon Champion Battle...
The Yamikarasu!
Those memories...
Yamikarasu...
Were those memories...
...of my... of our...
I-I’m not scared, I’m not scared...
I’m not scared, I’m not scared...
Not scared, not scared, not scared,
not scared, not scared, not scared,
not sca—
Whoa!
Hinoarashi, Apalm, thank you!
Yeah, let’s go.
Is that...?
This is the place
from those memories.
What is this...?
Yamikarasu?!
Um...
Yamikarasu...
Pretty... What is it?
Huh?
Who are you?
Wh-Whoa!
I found that!
Let go! Give it back!
Whoa!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
So this was a feather from Airm'd...
Never knew there was a cave here.
Now we match!
What do you think?
Let’s make this place our secret base!
Yamikarasu... You...
Someday, we’re gonna go for it!
Go all over, collect real Badges!
I remember!
When I met you...
And our promise... All of it!
Yamikarasu!
Yamikarasu, are you okay?!
I’m gonna save you!
Yamikarasu!
I’m sorry, Yamikarasu.
I remember all about you now.
You’ve been waiting for me,
all this time...
All this time,
ever since that day...
Whoa!
Got it!
Use Raising Wind, Yamikarasu!
Yamikarasu!
Thank you, Yamikarasu.
All set!
Whoa!
Next time, let’s go
on a real journey together.
Let’s have some adventures
that we’ll never, ever forget!
What do you say, Yamikarasu?
Three, two, one, and good night
three two one de good night
Breathe in the world turned silent
oto mo nai sekai o suikonde
Behind a line I can't cross
koechaikenai line de
The racing in my chest just won't stop
kono mune no takanari yamanai
With my worn-out Converse, I start the lights on this vending machine
hakitsubushita Converse de akari ga tomoru kono jihanki
Swerving to keep the roadside trees just at the edge of sight
mejirushi ni gairoju o yokome ni yuraide
Let's climb up that slope, and then toast to the view
ano sakamichi o nobotte mieru keshiki ni kanpai shite
A midnight runway just for the two of us
futari dake no midnight runway
(Ooh-ooh, ooh)
So stay just like this (ooh-ooh)
mada kono mama de (ooh-ooh)
I just want to be with you (ooh-ooh)
kimi to tada itai kara (ooh-ooh)
(Ah) Just like this (ooh-ooh)
(Ah) kono mama de (ooh-ooh)
For these free moments until the dawn
asa ga furu made no aima
There are more episodes
in the POKÉTOON series!
Subscribe to the channel
and support Pokémon!