OK!
OK! tsugi ni susumou ze!
OK! Let's move on!
OK! issho nara daijoubu!
OK! Together, we'll be all right!
OK! kaze ga kawattemo
OK! Though the wind may change...
OK! kawaranai ano yume!
OK! ...my dream is unchanging!
koko made kuru no ni muchuu sugite
We've been so focused on making it this far...
kizukazu ni ita keredo
...that we didn't even notice...
atarashii sekai e no tobira no kagi wa
...that we'd already obtained the key...
shiranai uchi ni get shite ita yo
...to the door leading to the new world!
Golden Sun & Silver Moon
ohisama to otsukisama
The sun and moon...
kawari banko ni kao dashite
...are always changing faces...
minna o mimamotte kureteru yo
...and watching over everyone!
dakara
And so...
OK! fuan nante tabechaou!
OK! Swallow your fear!
OK! jiman no waza "karagenki"
OK! Use your best move: "Bravado"!
OK! namae mo koe mo shiranai
OK! Though I don't know their names or voices,
aitsura ga matteru hazu!
they're waiting for me!
aitsura ni aitain da!
I want to meet them!
OK!!
Found you.
Target located.
Beginning analysis...
Mewtwo confirmed.
No confirmation needed.
I know full well that is Mewtwo.
Those children...?
We meet once again.
Is this fate?
MEWTWO!
I AM HERE
What’s that?
Aside from Mewtwo,
there are other Pokémon giving off similar readings.
As I expected.
Even Mewtwo cannot stand solitude.
It needed companions.
009, move in.
On it, sir.
What’s the big idea?
All Team Rocket elite squad troops
standing by: take off.
Team Rocket elite squad?
Where?
What, meow?
My...
Now that’s going all-out...
Those must be expensive, meow.
Give Pikachu back!
Domino, what is the meaning of this?
Now that you mention it...
Who are you?
When asked “who are you?”,
you’re never supposed to answer.
That is the rule a real
Rocket lives by.
But I don’t want idiot Team Rocket
operatives raining on my parade.
Team Rocket A-Class
Number 009, Domino!
Or as some call me,
“Black Tulip”!
You...
You, a sweet young lady
from the National Pokémon Research Lab...
Team Rocket spies are never far.
So perhaps...
The person smiling right next to you
could be a Team Rocket spy!
By the way, we’re in it, too.
We’re Team Rocket!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket members
getting in the way of Team Rocket...
...should make like good
little rockets... and blast off!
See ya, then!
Have a nice day! Bye!
Every car has
air bags these days,
so could someone explain
why our balloon has no safety gear?
Our budget, meow.
Well, look on the bright side!
At least we got Pikachu this time!
This is progress, you know?
Did he escape
in the confusion, meow?
It doesn’t look to me
like he got away.
Instead of getting away...
It looks more like...
Getting revenge!
L-Looks like we’ve been rescued.
But why?
Over there, meow!
Pikachu and...
Pikachu?
Translate, translate!
The other one said,
“so we meet again.”
Are they friends?
Meow, the mood seems really tense.
More like enemies, meow.
Really?
“I didn’t want
to have to see you again.
“Why did you come here?!”,
he’s asking, meow.
“We, the copy Pokémon,
were just living here in secrecy,
“and now you’ve brought humans here.
The humans we were hiding from.”
Huh? Is that a copy of Pikachu?
What’s going on, meow?
Apparently, our Pikachu
doesn’t know either, meow.
“Leave at once!
If you refuse, then...”
Doesn’t it look like
he’s in battle mode?
Pikachu versus Pikachu.
This could be the showdown of the season!
Stop this.
Halt this meaningless battle.
There is no difference
between the real Pikachu and the copy.
We may all be mere
copies of Pokémon...
However, just as real Pokémon,
we are alive.
Copies and real Pokémon?
I don’t get what that’s all about.
Um, pardon my asking,
but who might you be?
I hoped we would stay forgotten.
But you returned.
We tried to live here
in peace and quiet,
but you are upon us,
nonetheless.
Have we met before?
“All we can do now is fight.
“Claim our home for ourselves!”
he says, meow.
“This isn’t just some little battle, it’s a war!”
That sounds ominous, meow!
He says Pokémon
shouldn’t fight one another.
“Especially since the moon
is so round...”
That’s for sure, meow.
The moon reflects the light of the sun,
and so it can only shine during the night.
The world of sunlight is the domain
of those truly born upon this planet.
We copies
only exist as their shadows.
Our only choice is to live in the shadows.
We have no other place.
The moon really is round, meow.
“But why do we have to live
in the shadows?”
“I know the truth. There’s a big world
out there beyond this lake.”
“A vast world...”
“Pikachu, you know
about that world, don’t you?
“You’re living in that
vast world now, aren’t you?”
“Can’t we share
that world with you?”
“Can’t we live in freedom
like everyone else?” He’s right, meow.
You can say that again.
But don’t worry.
I used to be the same... Dreaming of the day
I would find freedom out in the great, big world.
I knew someday I would,
and now...!
Now, we can say it!
We’re free in this vast world.
Our future...
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding...
But...
I was a manufactured Pokémon.
As were all of you.
Do we have the right...?
Mewtwo, just you wait.
At dawn, we launch our attack!
Is everyone okay?
Barely.
Togepi seems okay, too.
Pikachu is...
Pikachu is still with them.
The balloon flew over
to that island, right?
We have to go there!
But how?
Don’t worry.
There’s a nice log over there.
Let’s make a canoe.
A canoe?
She means we’ll hollow out the log
and use it as a boat.
All right!
If we’re doing that...
Chicorita! Fushigidane!
I choose you!
Use Razor Leaf!
We’d better move quickly and quietly
so they don’t spot us.
Fight?
I cannot do that.
Humans...
They are the ones who spawned me.
If that is so...
Must we leave once again...
...on a blind search
for another refuge?
They’ll be here soon, right?
You know, to rescue us.
Do you really want that?
This is humiliating.
We can’t let Sakaki see us like this!
That Pikachu’s about to make
a big announcement, meow.
“Unless we do something, we’re bound to be
captured and dissected by the humans.”
“If we are going to escape,
it has to be now.”
“We will head out
into the vast world!”
If that’s what they’re doing,
let’s ask them for a favor!
Can you take us with you?
They took us somewhere, all right,
but what’s with this place?
It looks like a jail to me.
You guys sure are dense, meow.
There’s no way they’d take Team Rocket,
their enemies, along with them.
Then why are you free?
I’m a Pokémon who can speak
human language!
I’ll probably come in handy.
Yeah, but...!
Negotiations went as easy
as the moon is round, meow.
Hey, hold on!
You’re playing favorites!
It’s time to leave, meow!
Huh? It’s the brat boy’s Pikachu.
What’s he doing with them?
Don’t worry, meow.
I’ll get Pikachu and take him
to Sakaki in your place, meow.
So that means the credit...
...will all go to Nyarth?
Just leave everything to me, meow!
If everything works out, I’ll send you
some of my Pokémon food from outside, meow.
No, thanks!
While some may leave,
others stay behind.
As long as you stay here,
I can protect you.
However,
even if I brought them
into this world...
If they wish to seek freedom...
Stopping them would only be selfish.
What should I do...
...about their freedom?
Pikachu...
Where are we?
This water...
How is that possible?
Ms. Luna! This water is marvelous!
Undoubtedly the greatest water
on this planet!
The greatest water
on this planet?
Living beings, such as humans,
are primarily composed of water,
but that water contains a variety of nutrients
in a delicate balance.
Yes. And if that balance is thrown off,
their health suffers...
...impacting not just their bodies,
but even their emotions and personalities.
The water here contains a perfect balance
of everything an organism needs to live!
It’s a miracle that water like this
still exists in the world!
That’s it!
This is Clear Lake,
the source of Pure River’s waters!
Aw, how cute!
They don’t have any breeders,
but they all look so healthy!
With beautiful,
undisturbed nature like this,
and perfectly balanced water,
any being can thrive, all on their own.
But where are their parents?
They’re over there, watching.
All the creatures who were born here
are perfectly balanced, physically and mentally...
...and they will grow up to be
astonishing Pokémon!
And their parents
are eagerly awaiting that.
We’d better leave this place
before we disturb them.
After all,
it doesn’t seem like Pikachu is here.
Okay. We’ll go back
and look somewhere else.
Here at last, meow.
Are you all okay, meow?
Hey! Snap out of it, meow!
What? “Will the moon
be round tonight?”
We don’t have time for that now!
Worry about the round Monster Balls!
Let’s get out of here!
You!
So we meet again, Mewtwo.
My powers have greatly matured
since you last saw me.
Do you honestly think you will be able
to control me as you did before?
You certainly are stronger,
I’ll give you that.
But humans have the technology
to create a machine capable of sealing your powers.
How about it? You should think twice
before you patronize me.
Do you sincerely think
you can defeat me with heartless machines?
Having no heart just means
they are devoted to hunting you.
We shall see.
Raise the power.
I’m impressed, Mewtwo.
True strength cannot come
from those devoid of a heart.
I understand that.
But having a heart
is also a weakness.
You still desire
to best me in battle?
In a direct battle,
I’d have no chance.
But the real battle
will unfold on that island.
009, Domino speaking.
Commence operation!
Mewtwo, I know that the Pokémon here
are not your only companions.
Can you really bring yourself to abandon
your other companions back there?
You vile fiend...
What’s with this?!
Humans are not our targets...
But since you’ve seen this place,
we’ll make an exception.
I’m afraid we can’t let you go.
What?!
Say...
Hmm?
How much worse than usual
did you say today was?
Beats me. It’s just been
one long chain of feeling awful.
It’s all so awful
we never even said that, did we?
Well, let’s make up for lost time...
We’re down one member,
but we’ll have to make do.
Ready, set...
What an awful feeling!
Tensions have reached
a breaking point at Pure’s Rock.
Our story is still to be continued.
akai hoppe kiiro no shirt
Red cheeks, a yellow shirt
gizagiza moyou no boku no best friend
and a zigzag pattern, that's my best friend
shiroi page rakugaki shite
We scribbled on blank pages
dekitate no uta utatta yo ne
and sung newly invented songs
wasurenai yo kimi to no episode
I'll never forget my episodes with you
ryoute ippai no "arigatou"
My hands can't even carry all of my "Thanks"
yuuyami ni somaru oozora o goran
Look to the sky, tinged with sunset hues
pikapika atatakai hoshi ga warau yo
The stars smile back, sparkling and warm
atarashii kaze ga yondeiru kara
A new wind is calling
kimi to aruite yukitai
so let's keep walking together
dokomademo tsuzuku michi o
along this endless path...
Satoshi and his friends were captured.
And with his companions taken hostage,
Mewtwo once again falls into Sakaki’s hands.
To save his companions’ future,
and the purity of Pure’s Rock,
Mewtwo strikes back,
putting his life on the line.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
“Mewtwo! I Am Here - Part Three”
MEWTWO!
I AM HERE
Is this fate?
Look forward to the next episode!