OK!
OK! tsugi ni susumou ze!
OK! Let's move on!
OK! issho nara daijoubu!
OK! Together, we'll be all right!
OK! kaze ga kawattemo
OK! Though the wind may change...
OK! kawaranai ano yume!
OK! ...my dream is unchanging!
koko made kuru no ni muchuu sugite
We've been so focused on making it this far...
kizukazu ni ita keredo
...that we didn't even notice...
atarashii sekai e no tobira no kagi wa
...that we'd already obtained the key...
shiranai uchi ni get shite ita yo
...to the door leading to the new world!
Golden Sun & Silver Moon
ohisama to otsukisama
The sun and moon...
kawari banko ni kao dashite
...are always changing faces...
minna o mimamotte kureteru yo
...and watching over everyone!
dakara
And so...
OK! fuan nante tabechaou!
OK! Swallow your fear!
OK! jiman no waza "karagenki"
OK! Use your best move: "Bravado"!
OK! namae mo koe mo shiranai
OK! Though I don't know their names or voices,
aitsura ga matteru hazu!
they're waiting for me!
aitsura ni aitain da!
I want to meet them!
OK!!
You still desire
to best me in battle?
In a direct battle,
I’d have no chance.
But the real battle
will unfold on that island.
Commence operation!
Mewtwo, I know that the Pokémon here
are not your only companions.
Can you really bring yourself to abandon
your other companions back there?
You vile fiend...
What’s with this?!
Humans are not our targets...
But since you’ve seen this place,
we’ll make an exception.
I’m afraid we can’t let you go.
What?!
MEWTWO!
I AM HERE
My, how cute!
Don’t touch the Pokémon!
What’d you do that for?!
I’m no Pokémon Trainer.
Don’t expect me to show them mercy.
Don’t let even
a single one get away!
After we’re done using them
to lure Mewtwo out,
they’ll just be fodder for experiments,
so don’t even bother using Monster Balls.
Oh my, there’s more
rare Pokémon in here.
You callin’ us Pokémon?!
Oh, pardon me.
I didn’t recognize you.
Still, imagine finding morons
in Team Rocket...
That might even be rarer
than a phantom Pokémon.
You little...!
We have taken full control
of the island.
Aside from the Pokémon brought here
by a boy named “Satoshi,”
all the Pokémon
on the island are copies.
I have all your friends hostage.
Mewtwo, whether they live or die
depends on you.
I will go rescue my companions!
They’re all saying
they’ll go, meow.
I get it. You want to
head back too, meow. And you?
Me, too!
I can tell this guy’s
no ordinary alley-Nyarth, meow.
But don’t tell Sakaki
about this, meow.
We will live whichever way
we see fit!
My companions...
Let us return to the island.
009.
009 speaking.
Mewtwo is headed your way.
Roger.
I’ve been expecting you.
This Nidoqueen is so cute, isn’t she?
Return my companion at once.
Here’s the man
who’ll give you our demands.
Mewtwo, if you want to save your companions,
you will devote your life to me.
Given that as my only option,
I would rather die.
If you refuse
to cooperate with us,
then all of your companions will be dissected
and used for research. They will die.
Step back, all of you.
I am what he wants.
This light is not for subduing you.
It will control your mind,
and change your heart
so that you obey our every command.
It will change my heart?
No point destroying it, either.
We can make as many as we need.
But any show of resistance,
and your friends will pay the price!
Stop this!
That is enough!
Step into the light, then.
They’re all saying
he shouldn’t go...
But he’s going anyway, meow.
How’s that?
Now you belong to me.
You may take my body,
but you will never take my heart!
We shall see.
I will never...
...give up!
Which will hold out longer:
your will or my machine?
Only time will tell.
This is a nice place.
It’s certainly a hideout
worthy of Mewtwo’s attention.
I think I will turn it
into my secret base.
Then I will create
the world’s strongest Pokémon army.
Mewtwo.
You will lead the charge, as my pawn.
I look forward to that day.
Pikachu!
Pikachu! You got caught, too?
What in the world happened to you?
Ms. Luna, take the sample
of the spring water I collected.
Right!
Here, drink this.
Pikachu!
This water truly is amazing.
It really could be a miracle cure
for all sorts of living beings!
What’re you dawdling around for?
This isn’t your final destination, you know.
Domino!
Come on! Let us out!
You will never
see the light of day again.
Construction of the
secret base is proceeding well.
We’ve had no problems whatsoever.
How is Mewtwo?
Stubborn... There’s not even the slightest hint
of disruption in its brain waves.
If this keeps up,
its body will start to weaken.
If it dies,
then won’t all this be pointless?
I don’t care! This is a battle of wills
between Mewtwo and me!
Well, don’t take it out on me!
Hey, you two!
Mind mopping faster?
And don’t forget to change
the water in the bucket. Understood?
What an awful feeling...
What’s happened to everyone?
They’re coming, they’re coming.
They’re all mad.
Who’s coming?
The Bug Pokémon.
They’re all really mad.
They’re saying they won’t forgive
those who sullied their precious lake.
What is it?
What’s going on?!
Wh-What the...?
What’s going on?
Look!
All right! We can escape!
Let’s go, guys!
Ms. Luna, I’m going this way!
Why?
I’m worried about the water.
Then I’ll come with you!
Rapid Fire!
I’m Team Rocket Agent 009, Black Tulip!
Don’t mess with me!
No mess here! We mopped that spot so well
it’s like we licked it clean.
It’s slippery,
so do watch out.
No!
Oh, my. The water in that bucket
might be much too clean for your face!
What a pity.
What a relief.
The water is fine.
Right.
You are safe?
But I can’t...
Mewtwo...
My name?
We heard about you
from Nyarth.
He also told us
you rescued my Pikachu.
We have to do something
to repay you.
This light...
Isn’t there a switch anywhere?
Doesn’t look like it.
Fine! I’ll tackle it, then!
I’ll help!
Charge!
It didn’t work!
Never mind.
I will muster up
the last of my strength.
Will I be destroyed,
or will the machine?
This decides it
once and for all!
Hang in there, Mewtwo!
Keep going!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Are you okay, Mewtwo?
I have exceeded my limit...
There is no hope for me...
The water! They’re saying
we need the water, meow!
I see! The water
that healed Pikachu.
All right. Let’s go!
I cannot allow that.
Mewtwo belongs to me.
If it can’t be mine,
I’ll dispose of it.
We won’t let you do that!
You can’t have him!
Oh, no! It’s Sakaki!
If he sees us here
loitering around, he’ll...
You guys got out, meow?!
Nyarth!
Forget that, let’s hide!
Satoshi, hurry!
I know.
Get them!
What?!
Hmph. So they resist us still?
They leave me with no choice.
We will crush them all!
Thanks, guys.
Why? Why do you
try to rescue me?
You rescued Pikachu.
I’m just returning the favor.
Is that all?
Do I need more reason?
Perhaps you are a strange human.
You must be a unique trainer.
You’re a pretty unique Pokémon yourself.
Even to this day...
...I still cannot see who I really am.
Satoshi!
Who is that Pokémon?
He needs the power
of the spring.
But drinking some
won’t be enough to save him.
Wait! This spring is rich
with vital nutrients!
We could use it to create
lifesaving medicine for everyone!
All I care about right now...
...is saving him!
Saving his life!
Where am I?
I have seen this before...
This place...
But that was surely a dream.
What?
My powers are returning to me.
Mew?
This spring is...
Restoring me to how I was.
If it does the same
to other living beings...
Who am I?
At the least...
I know...
I have the right to live on this planet!
What’s that?
Where is Mewtwo?
Stop it! You’ll destroy the spring!
I don’t care.
This place belongs to me.
This place does not belong to anyone.
Nor do I belong to you.
I will not let you hurt anyone!
What?
What’s that?
What’s going on, meow?
Every fragment of my power...
Come forth, now!
Be unleashed, now!
What in the world just happened?
Mewtwo, where are you?
What happened to the water?
This is all that’s left.
Thank you! As long as I have this,
I can restart my research!
Right... But what happened
to all the other Pokémon?
Where are we?
Beneath Pure’s Rock. I transported the lake,
the spring, and everyone down here.
Wow, I didn’t know
you had that kinda power.
But it’s for the best
that everyone forgets about this.
I will erase everyone’s memories
and leave this place.
Erase our memories?
You can’t do that, meow!
Hey, Nyarth!
What’re you thinking?!
It’s not my message!
It’s what everyone’s asking me to say!
These kids’ mom and dad are pleading, too.
Take them as an example, meow.
One day, someone will ask these kids
who their parents are.
And you expect them to just say
they forgot, meow?!
Their parents might have been
created as copies,
but now they’re living creatures
who have created lives of their own.
They’re all living beings.
Even him and me, too!
I don’t wanna forget this, either.
Forgetting isn’t the solution
to every problem.
At some point, you’re gonna wonder
about what you forgot.
I’ll admit...
Whether copies or originals...
There is no benefit
in forgetting who you are.
You all have the right to live
wherever you desire on this planet.
Everyone...
Head out
into the vast world.
Spread your wings.
And what I will do...
...is erase the memories of only those
who sought to harm us and this spring.
Now... Forget everything.
Why are our agents
assembled at the launch pad?
Weren’t we here
on a secret mission?
Secret? What secret?
If this really is a secret mission,
we’re too conspicuous gathered here.
Yes. We should promptly retreat.
But... What was our mission
supposed to be?
The time for departure has come.
Tonight is a full moon.
Ideal for flying, meow!
This is farewell.
We may never meet again.
But I sure hope we do.
If ever you hear a voice
call your name somewhere,
glance back and look.
Perhaps...
...you may find me there.
Hello! The biweekly bus
has arrived! Huh?
Only one passenger today?
I’m not getting on.
I’m relocating here for research.
I am...
I am here.
What is it?
I’m not sure, but I just got the feeling
someone was there...
Yeah. It was probably...
Mewtwo.
Afterwards, that city
would become home to an urban legend...
...about a mysterious Pokémon
living somewhere in the city.
But nobody would ever discover
the truth behind this legend.
akai hoppe kiiro no shirt
Red cheeks, a yellow shirt
gizagiza moyou no boku no best friend
and a zigzag pattern, that's my best friend
shiroi page rakugaki shite
We scribbled on blank pages
dekitate no uta utatta yo ne
and sung newly invented songs
wasurenai yo kimi to no episode
I'll never forget my episodes with you
ryoute ippai no "arigatou"
My hands can't even carry all of my "Thanks"
yuuyami ni somaru oozora o goran
Look to the sky, tinged with sunset hues
pikapika atatakai hoshi ga warau yo
The stars smile back, sparkling and warm
atarashii kaze ga yondeiru kara
A new wind is calling
kimi to aruite yukitai
so let's keep walking together
dokomademo tsuzuku michi o
along this endless path...
Next episode
Pikachu got mistaken for a fruit thief!
We go racing around a huge orchard,
looking for the real thieves!
What we find is a nest of Pichu!
Then Team Rocket attacks too,
causing chaos in the orchard!
Leave this to me!
I’ll bring peace back to the orchard!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Pikachu and Pichu!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!
Next time
Pikachu and Pichu!
Look forward to the next episode!