OK!
OK! tsugi ni susumou ze!
OK! Let's move on!
OK! issho nara daijoubu!
OK! Together, we'll be all right!
OK! kaze ga kawattemo
OK! Though the wind may change...
OK! kawaranai ano yume!
OK! ...my dream is unchanging!
koko made kuru no ni muchuu sugite
We've been so focused on making it this far...
kizukazu ni ita keredo
...that we didn't even notice...
atarashii sekai e no tobira no kagi wa
...that we'd already obtained the key...
shiranai uchi ni get shite ita yo
...to the door leading to the new world!
Golden Sun & Silver Moon
ohisama to otsukisama
The sun and moon...
kawari banko ni kao dashite
...are always changing faces...
minna o mimamotte kureteru yo
...and watching over everyone!
dakara
And so...
OK! fuan nante tabechaou!
OK! Swallow your fear!
OK! jiman no waza "karagenki"
OK! Use your best move: "Bravado"!
OK! namae mo koe mo shiranai
OK! Though I don't know their names or voices,
aitsura ga matteru hazu!
they're waiting for me!
aitsura ni aitain da!
I want to meet them!
OK!!
This is a secluded area,
untouched by humans... Pure’s Rock.
It’s usually covered in clouds,
rarely seeing clear skies like these.
Mewtwo...?
How beautiful.
This lake is far more beautiful
than any other I have gazed upon.
But do I...
...have the right
to claim it as beautiful?
Who am I?
Yes. I am Mewtwo.
I was created by humans,
from the phantom Pokémon
known as Mew...
Created with the sole purpose to fight.
And then I created...
...all these Pokémon copies.
But after all that transpired,
it is best that no one
know of our existence.
Unknown...
And undisturbed...
We will live on.
Together with this beautiful lake.
MEWTWO!
I AM HERE
Aiming to enter the Johto League,
Satoshi and his friends continue their journey.
Beneath the clear, blue sky,
they traverse a deep, thick forest.
What’s that?
Wow!
That mountain’s the famous Pure’s Rock.
It truly is a wonder of nature!
The next town’s
on the other side of that mountain.
How are we getting past that?
Apparently, there’s a bus that goes
around the mountain once a week.
Its stop is at the foot of the mountain.
And when does it leave?
Lunch time.
Meaning today at noon.
Today?!
Then we’d better get moving!
What a pity.
I was planning on making pancakes
drenched in sweet syrup for today’s lunch...
Really?!
Look! Isn’t that the bus?
Looks like it is!
Th-Then we better hurry!
Rain? Aw, man.
My frying pan
can make a good umbrella in a fix...
...or, maybe not.
My, those kids
never learn, do they?
You never know what can happen
on a long journey.
An umbrella and extra food
are the bare essentials.
That’s the first thing
you learn about long journeys.
Wait, have we always been
carting those around, meow?
We’re just lucky we had them.
That’s all that matters.
But are you really sure
we’ll be fine, meow?
What do you mean?
“Pure’s Rock:
“The surrounding topography and airflow
create bizarre weather.
“When it rains,
there’s torrential downpours with mud slides.
“When it gusts, there’s 40 m/s gales,
with frequent tornadoes.
“Few tourists would ever come here.”
40 meters per second?!
Isn’t that basically a typhoon?!
I think it’s here...
Rather than try and pack
random junk...
...we’re better off
when we just wing it!
Okay then, everyone,
all together now...
What an awful feeling!
Big Sis, there’s still a little while
before the bus is supposed to depart,
but the bus is full and the weather is terrible.
You’d better leave while you can.
You’re right. I’ll set off.
Bye.
Hey! Wait for us!
A-Are you okay?
Wh-Where’s the bus?
We’re here for the bus!
You’re too late. It just left.
Madame! Would you like to shelter yourself
underneath this frying pan with me?
Now’s not the time for that!
Yes, ma’am...
We could still make it!
We’ll chase after it!
Don’t do that!
It’s too dangerous!
It’s pouring now,
and the wind could pick up at any moment!
Not to mention,
you’re all covered in mud.
You can all take a shower
at my place.
It’s... a miracle!
You ask me
why I rescued the humans?
If there is an accident,
many other humans will rush here to rescue them,
and they could discover us.
“That’s not the only reason”?
“I also did not want the humans hurt”...
Is that what you believe?
Do you believe I am a Pokémon
who can show such compassion towards humans?
Me? Mewtwo?
How absurd.
We barely even got here...
...and already,
what an awful feeling...
We never learn, meow.
Well, just make yourselves at home.
The next bus won’t be here
for another week.
I use this cabin as lodging
for people waiting for the bus.
We have to wait here a week?!
Isn’t there another way
around this mountain?
You could go down the river
leading into Pure River.
That might get you
to the other side.
Down the river?
In that case, leave it to me!
I’m a girl from a
Water-type Pokémon Gym!
Speaking of,
the river’s water has a wonderful flavor!
Go on, drink up.
This... this water...
It’s the best! It’s the best!
It’s so tasty I can’t stop myself!
It’s the best!
Ooh, ooh, let me try!
It’s like all the fluids in my body
are being washed clean!
It just looks like water to me.
Take a drink and you’ll see
what we’re talking about.
I think the chocolate milk
my mom makes is better.
You’re pitting water
against chocolate?!
You’re just ignorant!
Ig-nor-ant!
If you’re gonna ignore me
‘cause you think I’m an ant...
Pikachu, you’re no ant.
What do you think?
They can tell
how special this water is!
That so, huh...?
But anyway, let’s just put our faith
in these amazing waters,
and head down the river!
This is lovely.
So much nicer than taking that bus.
We’ll be fine, but I’m not sure
you’ll be so happy, Kasumi.
This river’s waters are very clean.
And Bug Pokémon love clean water.
If they’re fans of beautiful water too,
a couple bugs won’t bug me!
I sure hope so...
I’ll be fine, just fine!
Look at that!
It’s a Christmas tree!
Of course it isn’t!
But it’s pretty!
Those are Ledian.
They say that the spots on their backs
sparkle on starry nights.
Ledian, huh? I wish all bugs
could be so charming...
And these are Cocoon!
When Cocoon evolve,
they become Spear.
Wherever you find Cocoon,
you’ll find Spear.
No way, no way, no way, no way!
The river proved quite
treacherous, didn’t it?
Yes, ma’am.
Learned my lesson.
Isn’t there another way?
Where there’s a will,
there’s a way!
We’ll scale Pure’s Rock...
And head over the top!
That’s the most difficult approach.
What is at the top
of the mountain, anyway?
Guarded by sheer cliffs
that keep away humans,
it’s one remaining microcosm
of undisturbed nature.
There’s a vast forest,
with a hidden lake, Clear Lake.
That’s where this area’s water
comes from.
The water flows through Pure’s Rock
and into Pure River.
And, nourished by the water,
many different kinds
of wild Pokémon thrive.
I wonder what kinds of Pokémon live there...
I’d sure like to check it out!
What’s that?
It’s a swarm of Butterfree!
Butterfree use Pure’s Rock
as a birthplace for their offspring.
Living as desired.
Born with purpose.
That is being a Pokémon.
That is living.
But, we were different.
So how should we live our lives?
What should we do with our lives?
What do you think?
You say living here in hiding...
...is no different
to being locked in a cell?
Nyarth, what say you?
“No matter where you are,
the moon will always be round,” you say?
But we are artificial copies of Pokémon.
We are not real Pokémon.
“Whether we are Pokémon or not,
the moon is still round.
“Is that not the case?”
I see. You have a point.
So this is one of the places
where Butterfree come from.
Anyone there?
Coming!
A visitor?
This late at night?
Who is it?
Good morning, everyone... Kidding!
I know it’s, like, actually sleepytime.
I hate to impose,
but could we stay here for a while?
I am Penicillina.
Penicillina? You don’t mean
the famous medical professor, do you?
I do. You’re Luna Carson, right?
I’ve read many of your articles
about Pokémon.
So then, may we come in?
Ah, yes! Please do.
Pokémon articles?
Providing lodging for travelers
isn’t my only job.
I also conduct research
on the surrounding wildlife.
Domino’s totally wowed!
So are ya famous?
I think ya just made a fan
outta me!
You’re the biologist
Ms. Luna, right?
Uh... yes. And you are?
This is Domino, a student from the
National Pokémon Research Lab.
I’m Domino!
Domino! What a lovely name!
How about we topple
some dominoes— No!
I’d even fall like a domino myself
if it’s with you!
Okay, okay... You don’t need to
do the same bit twice in one day...
It will be a week
until the bus gets here.
We did not come here for the bus.
We came for the water.
The water?
I have been studying Pure River
for quite some time now.
And I discovered that the water
in that river possesses beneficial properties.
This is a sample.
I absolutely must study
the source of Pure River, Clear Lake.
Is that so...?
But the greater
the benefit of the water...
...the more people
will come seeking it.
If that happened,
what would become of all the wildlife here?
Well...
And besides, it’s far too dangerous
to climb the mountain.
If you tell us
“it’s far too dangerous”...
We’ll want to do it even more
out of sympathy for the world!
To protect the world
from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely,
charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
“Team Rocket”?
Never seen them before...
This time for real,
we’re taking Pikachu with us!
You think I’ll let that happen?
Oh, you will, indeed!
Electricity Insulating and Absorbing Wire!
Pikachu!
As long as we have
Pikachu by our side, we win.
Now, over valleys and mountains we go,
flying straight to the boss.
It’s pointless, meow. Not only does that rope
insulate electricity, it also sucks it up, meow!
Well then, click, meow.
You’re not getting away with this!
I’ll knock you out of the air!
That’s not gonna work.
Take a look at this!
Times have changed.
Team Rocket now has rockets!
That’s the same thing!
Not so fast!
The weather is unstable here!
It’s far too dangerous to fly in that!
Aw, you’re worried about us?
You’re such a nice guy!
You’re making me all excited.
But! You mustn’t stop me!
You mustn’t! You mustn’t!
How awkward. I am evil, you are good...
There is an impassable gulf between us!
So please don’t stop me!
You lovely man, you.
“Lovely man”?
Is that Musashi’s type, meow?
Hey, let’s just leave already.
Quiet! I’m not done yet!
...said the beautiful lady, reluctant to leave, as she
reined in the flames of love towards the lovely man,
and fired up the rockets instead.
Oh, how tragic!
Click.
Pikachu!
Farewell, lovely man. Oh, cruel rockets,
take me all the way up to the moon!
Fly me to the moon!
I can’t see the moon, meow.
But it was there just a second ago...
The winds have picked up again.
Those two are in danger.
How reckless!
More like senseless.
But they have my Pikachu!
Help!
No matter what you say,
I’m going to save him!
It seems there’s no stopping you.
I know more about Pure’s Rock than anyone else.
You’ll help, won’t you?
Of course!
I’ll accompany you, too!
Eek, I’m scared!
What should I do?
You didn’t have to join us,
you know.
But I would’ve been
even more scared all by myself!
Domino!
Up here!
That was a close one.
Seems at least luck’s on my side!
Is it my imagination,
or have we just been going round in circles?
Can’t we do anything about this?
It’s all up to the wind.
Nothing we can do, meow.
Everyone, hang tight!
Team Rocket!
Give Pikachu back!
Look out!
They’re headed straight for us!
We’re over capacity!
The gondola’s gonna break, meow...
If you come out,
it’ll be even heavier!
The wind stopped.
The winds have stopped.
A lake in a place like this!
There’s even an island, meow!
Found you.
Target located.
Beginning analysis...
Mewtwo confirmed.
No confirmation needed.
I know full well that is Mewtwo.
Those children...?
We meet once again.
Is this fate?
Mewtwo...
I swear, I will not let you go.
They were never to meet.
They were never to remember.
Yet, there they were...
And something monumental is in store.
akai hoppe kiiro no shirt
Red cheeks, a yellow shirt
gizagiza moyou no boku no best friend
and a zigzag pattern, that's my best friend
shiroi page rakugaki shite
We scribbled on blank pages
dekitate no uta utatta yo ne
and sung newly invented songs
wasurenai yo kimi to no episode
I'll never forget my episodes with you
ryoute ippai no "arigatou"
My hands can't even carry all of my "Thanks"
yuuyami ni somaru oozora o goran
Look to the sky, tinged with sunset hues
pikapika atatakai hoshi ga warau yo
The stars smile back, sparkling and warm
atarashii kaze ga yondeiru kara
A new wind is calling
kimi to aruite yukitai
so let's keep walking together
dokomademo tsuzuku michi o
along this endless path...
The peace at Pure’s Rock was broken.
Sakaki’s army approaches Mewtwo’s island.
Will they manage to escape?
Or do they have no choice but to fight?
Mewtwo’s heart is thrown into turmoil,
and Satoshi and his friends
are caught in the conflict once again.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
“Mewtwo! I Am Here - Part Two”
MEWTWO!
I AM HERE
Is this fate?
Look forward to the next episode!