All right, we’re recording!
Let’s start with the greeting.
Okay, here goes!
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
It’s a vid from the LikoRoy Channel!
Our project for today is...
“Special interviews about our
Terastal course Implementation tests”!
In order to keep on learning
about Terastal,
we’ll be taking Implementation tests
administered by Gym Leaders.
So we’re gonna interview each other
about how eager we are for them!
Good. Now, Liko...
Start us off by interviewing Roy.
R-Right!
Erm...
Roy, who were you assigned to battle?
I’m gonna be battling
Rhyme in Fridge Town!
Rhyme...
I wonder what they’re like.
Okay, so, Roy...
Tell us a little about how eager you are
for your upcoming battle!
Sure!
I’m gonna Terastallize Hogator
like Mr. Colza taught me,
add my evolved Taikaiden to the mix,
and make it the greatest battle
I possibly can!
Okay!
Next, it’s your turn to interview Liko.
Interviewee Liko!
I hear you’re facing Mr. Grusha
from the Mt. Nappé Gym!
How are you feeling right now?
Wha—?! Oh, uh...
I did meet Mr. Grusha at the academy...
...but he came off kind of harsh,
so I’m a little worried.
Still, I’ve got Nyarote and Tebrim,
so I bet I’ll be fine!
I’ll make sure to have fun and
do my best in my Implementation test!
I’m gonna have fun with
my Implementation test, too!
Well then, everyone...
Bye-bye!
All right! We’re all done filming.
Done at last...
Ahh... I was so nervous...
We got some good interviews, though.
Hey, actually...
Isn’t your Implementation test up first, Dot?
That’s right!
Dot, tell us how eager you are
for your battle with Mr. Aoki!
Huh? Why do I have to...?
I...
I’ll go for a clever battle, like usual.
Plus, we’ve got to use two Pokémon
in the Implementation tests,
so I’ll need a meticulously
thought-out strategy...
Kuwassu and Kanuchan...
I’m dying to see how your battle turns out!
Yeah, me too!
I can’t wait to see you laying on the glitz again,
like Ms. Nanjamo taught you!
Enough about me already!
W-Wait... Huh?!
I never stopped the recording!