Liko, think we’re good to go?
Just a sec...
Um...
Wh—! It’s already recording!
Huh?!
Y-Yo-ssu...
All you Pokémon Trainers out there!
It’s a vid from the LikoRoy Channel!
Our project for today is...
“We tried finding out about Terastal!”
All right Roy, please explain
the concept of Terastal for us.
Okay!
Erm...
Terastal is a phenomenon that makes
Pokémon sparkle like jewels.
They can turn into different types,
or have their moves get stronger, right?
Right!
For example, when Friede’s Lizardon
Terastallizes into its Evil Terastype,
Psychic-type moves
can’t affect it anymore!
Terastallized Lizardon
is so strong and cool!
The way it helped out in our battle
with the black Rekkuuza was amazing!
Ahh... I wish we could Terastallize too!
Yeah! I know what you mean, Roy!
And that’s why we’ll be taking Terastal courses
at Orange Academy... To learn how to Terastallize!
I can’t wait!
I’m gonna make my
Terastal Debut with Hogator!
I’ll work hard to make my
Terastal Debut with Nyarote, too!
Well then, everyone...
Bye-bye!