Pocket Monsters New Year Special!
TV Tokyo
Visiting TV Tokyo today...
...are Liko, Roy,
and Captain Pikachu.
And why are they here?
What a surprise! They’re here to have the stars
of popular shows take on a rap challenge!
What a surprise! They’re here to have the stars of popular shows take on a rap challenge!
Could this be it, Roy?
I hear there’s someone amazing here.
Yeah.
Let’s just go in and check it out!
Yeah!
Whoa!
Whoa, amazing!
Whoa, it’s a real Pikachu!
Hello!
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, pleased to be here.
Attempting to rap will be
Degawa Tetsurou-san!
And doesn’t that outfit look familiar?
I’m Liko!
Oh, Liko-chan.
Pleased to be here.
And I’m... Roy!
Roy-kun, Liko-kun.
Yep.
Liko-kun, Roy-kun.
Oh, it’s Liko-chan.
Oh, Liko-chan!
Liko-chan, Roy-kun. Pleased to be here!
Roy-kun.
And... Next to me is...
Captain Pikachu!
Whoa! Amazing! It’s a real Pikachu!
Thank you!
I’ve been wondering...
Right.
What’s that you’ve got?
That, uh... hat?
Oh, this? It’s my Watermelon Helmet...
Watermelon Helmet...
See, I always appear on this show
called “Could You Charge My Bike?”...
Where I wear this watermelon...
Ooh!
Ooh! It’s cute!
Right!
And I travel around
on an electric bike!
Ooh! That sounds fun!
Ooh! An electric bike!
Then when it runs out of power,
I borrow power from someone in town,
have them charge it up,
and continue my journey.
That’s what the show’s about.
Oh! How about you guest on it sometime?
What?! Can we?!
Can you ride an electric bike, Pikachu?
Couldn’t Pikachu recharge your bike?
Yeah.
Oh!
Pikachu’s a charger?!
Pikachu emits electricity,
so he could recharge it!
Oh! Really?!
Oh!
You’re perfect! Be a guest!
Pikachu!
You’d be a perfect guest for my show!
Pikachu, you should
come ‘round sometime!
“Degawa Tetsurou’s Could You Charge My Bike?”
is a popular show that’s been running for seven years.
Degawa-san, who’s quite popular with kids,
goes on a bizarre road trip!
And Liko, Roy, and Cap
have a request for Degawa-san!
Degawa-san, we’re here today to
help you learn to like Pokémon more.
We have a song called
RVR: Rising Voltteccers Rap.
What is that?!
Would you try our rap challenge?
Oh, so that’s the rap song?
Yes.
Gotcha, gotcha.
I can rap a little, you know.
Ooh!
Yeah.
And so, coming up...
A spectacular New Year lineup of
special guests try the rap challenge!
Psychokinesis!
Plus, a special edition of
Professor Friede’s Pokémon Seminar!
How many questions
can you answer in this special quiz?
All right,
go ahead with the opening theme!
Everyone watching
the Pocket Monsters anime.
I’m Yama.
I’m BotchiBoromaru!
Today, we’ve got a special live version for you,
different from the usual opening.
Everybody sing along and get fired up!
Well then, please enjoy...
Halo!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
The words that I couldn't say
surface and then hide back away
The uncertain drifting clouds
Push them aside and reach the blue sky
Someday, I'll look back
and recall that deep red sunset
I'll burn every detail into my mind
The unreachable truth of the world
or that girl's feelings
Even if I never get to know
let them gleam like rainbows
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
I have so much I want to say (Hello! Hello!)
The clock strikes (Hello! Hello!)
I stop the video, (Hello! Hello!)
brush my teeth, (Hello! Hello!)
and fall asleep (Hello! Hello!)
Are you doing well? (Hello! Hello!)
I bet you are well! (Hello! Hello!)
I can go on
with your song!
Now, head forth! Pierce through the clouds
Stumbling, staggering,
standing firm, and reaching farther
Now, run forth! Towards my future
I can still go even farther
Now, see the dream to its conclusion!
I know, someday, my ever-treasured
rainbow flower will bloom
To make sure I never lose it
let's walk together
Crossing beyond
the rainbow's glow
I found my dream
Next, Degawa-san attempts
the Rising Voltteccers Rap.
Captain Pikachu
does a whole bunch, too!
Look forward to it.
Don’t change the channel!
Pocket Monsters...
...is brought to you...
...by these sponsors!
Pocket Monsters New Year Special!
Degawa-san tries
the Rising Voltteccers Rap!
Everyone in front of the TV,
you try singing along, too!
Well then, Degawa-san, here we go!
Rap challenge, start!
Start!
Let’s learn about more and more!
Next, Pokémon that have regional forms!
Let’s have Roy show us how it’s done!
3! 2! 1! Go!
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it’s gonna explode!
Now, Degawa-san!
You only get one shot!
Let’s go!
Don-doo-don-doo, don-don-do-don-don,
All right, all right! Pikachu’s gonna guest star!
He’s finally gonna do it! What do I... Hey!
Could You Charge My Bike and Pikachu collabing!
Yay, yay, yay! Pokémon! All right!
Degawa-san!
Stop!
It’s the best! Oh, just the best! All right!
Degawa-san!
What is it? What, what, what, what?
Um...
You got the lyrics wrong...
Huh?
Um...
Wait, wait, wait, wait...
What do you mean?
They’re all names of Pokémon!
Huh?!
Oh, there’s a Pokémon
named Koratta-kun?
That’s right!
And one named Ratta-kun?
I see, I see. Got it.
Time for take two.
Right.
Degawa-san...
Please do it this time...
Take two!
Degawa-san!
Let’s do our best this time!
Oh, yay!
Now then... Start!
Yay, Pikachu!
Let’s learn about more and more!
Next, Pokémon that have regional forms!
Let’s have Roy show us how it’s done!
Oh, yeah!
3! 2! 1! Go!
Come on!
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumakka,
Biriridama, drop it and it’s gonna explode!
Oh, yeah! Okay!
Now, Degawa-san!
Nail it this time!
Let’s go!
Okay!
Kora—
Koratta, Ratta, Garagara, Darumatta,
Biribiribiri... drop it and it’s gonna explode! Yeah, yeah!
So close!
So close...
You were so close, Degawa-san!
This is hard!
I feel like you had the vibe down perfectly, though...
It’s hard!
Degawa-san, did you have fun?
Oh yeah, a lot of fun...
But are you sure?
If it was bad, I could do a take three.
Little kids watching Pocket Monsters!
Watch “Degawa Tetsurou’s
Could You Charge My Bike?” too!
It’s just as interesting
as Pokémon, so check it out!
I hear there’s someone amazing in this room!
Who could it be?
What if it’s a Gym Leader?!
Excuse us!
Nice to meet you!
Liko-chan! Roy-kun!
Hello!
Pikachu!
He’s so cute...
The next famous face is Wentz Eiji-san!
On “Learn The News In 60 Seconds,”
he’s the MC that makes
the latest news simple to understand!
I’m Wentz Eiji,
and I’ve started playing Pokémon lately.
Pleased to have you!
26 years ago...
I was a really busy elementary schooler,
so I never played it.
A pretty famous
busy elementary schooler, at that.
Huh...
I didn’t play it back then,
but I’ve picked it up now that I’m an adult!
Wow! That’s lovely!
Ooh! That so, huh?
Wentz-san,
have a look at our Pikachu!
He’s the ship captain
of our adventuring ship!
His name’s Captain Pikachu!
Captain Pikachu!
Pleased to have you.
So, if he’s the ship captain,
he gives the orders, right?
Yeah! Of course!
Then, if you would...
Decide the future of entertainer Wentz Eiji, too!
Huh?!
Give it to me straight.
What direction should I take myself?
Uh, that’s...
Are you up for it?
Huh, you will?!
That response seemed like a yes.
What? Cap, you can do that?!
Okay then, I’ll have to hear him out later.
Pokémon fan Wentz-san
also takes the rap challenge!
Wentz-san...
Yes?
Would you try our rap challenge?
Kōhaku singer.
Kō... haku... sing... er...?
Thank you for this opportunity
to show off.
Well, if you’re that confident,
one shot’s all you need, right?!
No, I wouldn’t rule out retakes.
No, no, no, no...
Do it in one shot!
Well then,
let the rap challenge begin!
This one is harder than last time!
Let’s learn about more and more!
Pokémon with “don” in their names!
Let’s have Roy show us how it’s done!
3! 2! 1! Go!
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it’s Lizardon!
Now, Wentz-san! Show us your skills!
Let’s go!
Heheh! Wentz Eiji, here I go!
Saidon, Yadon, Donmel, Groudon,
blazing on and on, it’s Lizardon!
Whoa! Amazing!
Whoa! A huge success!
Yeah!
Knew you could do it!
That was so cool!
Yeah!
My nose is dripping...
Oh, are you okay?
Yeah!
What do you think, Pikachu?
Did I do good?
Oh, he just gave me
a good slap on the butt!
You really put some muscle
into that! Thank you!
Did I do good? Was it okay?
You were really cool!
Yes!
Yeah!
Glad to hear it.
Honestly... Feel my heart.
Huh? Are you sure?
It’s pounding away fiercely.
Really?!
You’re right, it is!
I was really nervous.
Wentz-san, did you enjoy
our rap challenge?
I’m starting to enjoy it now!
Almost think I should’ve
rapped before we chatted...
It was great.
Feeling nervous,
but then overcoming it... That feels great.
Yeah!
This is Learn The News In 60 Seconds, so next, how about you
try and explain what makes Pokémon brilliant in 60 seconds?
Umm...
Makes you nervous, right?
Wednesdays at 9 PM.
Learn The News In 60 Seconds.
Yeah.
So far, there’s been
one success and one failure!
The last one is the hardest rap verse...
But before that,
we have another special segment for you!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Friede here.
It’s time for my Pokémon Seminar!
Today, it’s a special edition!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
We’ll be taking a look at our adventures
as the Rising Voltteccers,
and the Pokémon
we’ve met along the way.
Our adventure began when we met a Paldean girl
named Liko, who had enrolled at Sekiei Academy.
The mysterious pendant Liko got from her grandma
prompted a suspicious organization to chase after her...
That’s right. The Explorers.
Their goals are unclear,
but they’re after Liko’s pendant.
Found you!
We, the Rising Voltteccers, came to Sekiei Academy
to save Liko and her pendant from the Explorers.
Huh? Lizardon?!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
On our adventures, we met a boy
who dreamed of becoming a Pokémon Trainer: Roy!
And his personal treasure was none other
than an Ancient Monster Ball.
And now for a question!
A Pokémon popped out of that ball,
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
but do you know which Pokémon it was?
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
Liko’s pendant shone out,
resonating with the Ancient Monster Ball!
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
The orange Pikachu
The gold Iwark
The black Rekkuuza
Then, out of it came...
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
C: The black Rekkuuza
That’s right! The answer is...
the black Rekkuuza!
Yeah. It shocked me too.
What Pokémon came out of the ball?
C: The black Rekkuuza
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Well then,
let’s continue with our adventure.
We even went to the Wild Area together!
The Wild Area is home to many more Pokémon
than any other place in the Galar Region!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
And now, time for a question!
We ate a certain meal in the Wild Area,
and everybody loved it, but...
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
Do you know what that meal was?
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
There’s a lot of Momon Berries here.
...makes it taste a lot better.
Two: The berries!
Three: The heating!
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
Ramen
Curry
Hamburg steak
What meal did we eat in the Wild Area?
B: Curry
That’s right! The answer is... curry!
Liko and Roy put their hearts
into making it for Dot,
who’d never tasted curry
nor been interested in food.
Dot usually keeps away from others,
but eating curry together
strengthened her bond with her friends.
Seriously?!
Cap gives them a perfect score!
All right!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Yeah!
We, the Rising Voltteccers, are a team of adventurers
pursuing the mysteries of Pokémon and the world.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
And the captain of our airship
is none other than Cap, a.k.a. Captain Pikachu!
Now for a question! There’s something
Cap can do that other Pikachu cannot.
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
So, everybody, do you know what it is?
What thing can Cap do?
Fly
Surf
Change the weather
No way!
What thing can Cap do?
A: Fly
That’s right! The answer is...
He can fly!
That was how I met my partner Cap.
What thing can Cap do?
A: Fly
And it was also the moment
the Rising Voltteccers were born.
Whoa!
This really is the best!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Well then, let’s continue with our adventure.
When we headed to the Galar Mine
in search of the black Rekkuuza,
we met none other than Galarian Fire,
one of the Six Hero Pokémon!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Galarian Fire’s fiercely burning rage
had us in quite a bind!
But... It’s time for a question!
Liko’s pendant shone out,
and it transformed into a mysterious Pokémon.
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
But you know that Pokémon’s name, right?
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
Regigigas
Terapagos
Metagross
But the pendant turned into
this little one.
This little one looks like a Terapagos.
Terapagos?
What is the name of the Pokémon it transformed into?
B: Terapagos
The answer is... Terapagos!
I was shocked when that pendant
turned into a Pokémon!
Calming its anger,
Galarian Fire decided to come with us.
And the awakened Terapagos
came along on our adventure, too!
Diana-san is an adventurer,
and she taught us about the Ancient Adventurer Lucius,
and about Terapagos, too!
Terapagos’s wish is to go
to the paradise known as Rakua.
To fulfill that wish, we need to seek
the Six Hero Pokémon who traveled with Lucius.
The Pokémon from the Six Heroes traveling with us now
are Oliva, Galarian Fire, and Laplace.
Which leaves Basagiri, Entei,
and the black Rekkuuza as the remaining three.
Yeah! Just thinking about finding Pokémon
nobody’s ever seen before fills you with excitement!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
And if you’re getting excited
about Pokémon you’ve never seen before...
Then to conclude this seminar,
take a look at this Pokémon.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Your hint is this
characteristic silhouette...
What Pokémon's silhouette is this?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
But do you know
what this Pokémon is called?
What Pokémon's silhouette is this?
See the answer after the commercials!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
What Pokémon's silhouette is this?
And now, the answer is...
The Metalsmith Pokémon, Kanuchan!
Kanuchan
Answer
A Pokémon that creates
her very own original hammer.
Never stopping until she’s satisfied...
She’s got a craftsman’s mindset!
Will we meet one
in our future adventures?
I can’t wait.
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Whoops!
It’s about time we said farewell.
But you’ve all gotten closer to being
Pokémon Professors today, haven’t you?
Isn’t that right, Cap?
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Now, let’s plot a course
heading for new adventures!
See ya!
Professor Friede's Pokémon Seminar Special Edition
Friede and the Rising Voltteccers embark
on adventures seeking the rest of the Six Heroes.
And... Liko and Roy have delightful encounters
with Pokémon they’ve never seen before!
Not Nyahoja too!
Get a hold of yourself!
Sing out nice and loud!
Meguroco! Waruvile! Waruvial!
Who will we meet next?!
Right?!
I can’t wait to find out!
You said it!
Yeah!
So, you think they’re in here?
Yeah.
Should we open the door?
Let’s do it!
Whoa!
Whoa! What is this place?!
It’s amazing!
Amazing!
They’re here, they’re here,
they’re here!
Here they are!
Hello!
Nice to meet you!
Yeah, nice to meet you.
It’s Pikachu!
Pikachu!
Hey... You can’t say that
this early in the morning!
Huh?
You can understand
what Pikachu’s saying?
They dropped in straight after Oha Suta was broadcast live
What did he say?
What is it, Liko and Roy?
Um, could we ask your names?
You don’t know us?!
Huh?!
W-We’re sorry!
It’s... our first time meeting...
Our first time meeting, huh...?
Well then,
shall we introduce ourselves?
Yeah.
We’re Miki.
I’m the big brother, Mew.
Mew?
And I’m Mewtwo.
Mewtwo?!
Together, we’re...
Mew, Mewtwo, Mewtwo, Mew.
They’re Pokémon?
That’s us.
Pokémon?!
Here, of all places?!
Huh?!
Psychokinesis!
Well, that’s enough
joking around for now.
Sorry!
Sorry for dragging you into it.
Miki also appear
on the kids show Oha Suta!
The big brother Kousei-san and the little brother Asei-san
make up a comedian brother duo!
So, what brings you here?
We’re here today because
we want you two to try rapping for us.
Rapping?
Yeah!
Huh? Sounds pretty tough.
Rapping like in a song, right?
That’s right!
There’s this song called
RVR: Rising Voltteccers Rap.
No, big brother can sing
Ketsumei-shi’s Friends.
Wrong song! Wrong song!
You want me to sing that?
It’s the hardest difficulty!
Everyone,
give it a try along with Miki!
Well then, let’s get straight to it!
Right!
All right!
Rap challenge...
Start!
Yay!
Let’s learn about more and more!
Next up, cheerful bird Pokémon!
Let’s have Liko show us how it’s done!
3! 2! 1! Go!
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
She’s good.
You two, sing together!
Here we go!
Let’s go!
Hey! We’re Miki!
Kousei, Asei, that’s us!
Perap raps, Ikirinko Uproars,
Kuwassu dances and the carnival starts!
Yay!
Hold on, hold on, stop there!
I twowwy! I twowwy!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Huh?
Wait, Big Bro, were you singing?
Huh? I feel like I didn’t hear
the big bro’s voice...
Oh...
We’re brothers,
so our voices were so synchronised...
We were hoping you’d both try it together...
That was great and all, but...
Our voices sound too similar.
They’re too similar.
It was a real surprise.
Well, I could hear him
going “Ah” quietly next to me.
I heard him going “Ah, ah, ah”...
He probably was singing, right?
It was totally a “featuring” type thing.
Featuring... Featuring, yeah!
Asei featuring Kousei.
Well then, I guess it counts...
We’ll call it a success!
We’re good?!
Yeah!
Yay!
We did it!
We did it, right, Pikachu?
How could you say that?!
What is Pikachu saying?!
What is he saying?! I wanna know!
I wanna know!
What did you think of today?
Today was the best!
The best!
Now I wanna watch Pokémon
even more than before.
I wanna see your progress.
Ooh!
Thank you so much!
Next episode
Next time on
the Pocket Monsters anime...
The Rising Voltteccers
receive a job request.
Their job is to find a lost Pokémon.
Next episode
Anokusa!
...will hurt
all these Pokémon!
But oh no!
It turns into a kidnapping?!
Yet Friede and Cap
can’t stop bickering?!
Next episode
Friede and Cap: The Duo in the Wilderness
Look forward to it!
Pocket Monsters...
...was brought to you...
...by these sponsors!
That way!
The mysterious Pokemon
that awoke from the pendant, Terapagos!
If you meet the remaining Six Heroes,
I’m certain it will regain its original power.
That is when the path
to Rakua will open.
Liko and Roy trace a new course
toward their dreams!
Rising Voltteccers...
Go!
TV anime Pocket Monsters!
Airs weekly on Fridays at 6:55 PM!
With Pokémon by my side,
I’ll do just fine!