AniPoké Original Audio Drama
A Refined Lunch
With the Paldea Elite Four
Mmm! The food’s always great
here at Table City’s own Bar Kiebul!
Hassaku-san, would you mind
if I ordered the al ajillo?
Go ahead, Aoki.
Please, order whatever you’d like.
Oh, in that case...
Oh, waite—
Waiter—
Aoki-san, you gotta speak up a bit!
‘Scuse me!
One al ajillo please!
Poppy wants some more
mixed fruit juice!
The Terastal Course
is finally at an end.
Orange Academy is full of life,
preparing for the battle tournament.
I can’t wait!
Chili-chan’s been way too excited
to sleep, except at night!
After all, this time ‘round
I got someone to root for.
Liko-san, I take it?
Yeah!
Sounds like she failed
her implementation test with Grusha-san,
but being allowed to use Terastal
ain’t the only goal of the course.
It’s bound to make ‘em
stronger than ever!
Waiter, could I also get a tortilla
and an escalivada, please?
As for myself,
I have high hopes for Roy-kun.
That the kid Rhyme-san gave
her seal of approval to?
Indeed! His friendly match
against me was so marvelous,
simply remembering it
fills me with... emotion...
Bwuuuh-huh-hoi-hoi-hoi!
Grandpa Hassaku, don’t cry!
There, there, that’s a good boy.
Huuuuuh-huh-hoi-hoi-hoi!
Excuse me, could I get four orders of paella
as soon as they’re ready?
How much’re ya gonna order, Aoki-san?!
You can’t eat all that!
Oh, you need not worry.
I will be sure to enjoy it.
That’s our Grandpa Aoki!
He’s a gourmet!
What’d you make of
the girl you tested, Aoki-san?
Hmm... Dot-san...
A tactician with a keen mind.
Several interesting qualities as a trainer.
She even evolved her partner mid-battle.
You mean Kuwassu-chan evolved?!
I wanna have her play with
Poppy’s Pokémon again!
Anyhow, the battle tournament sure is stuffed
with promising trainers this time ‘round.
As the Elite Four, let us commit our full attention
to the finale of the Terastal Course!
Everyone...
Which parfaits
would you like for dessert?
You still want more?!