Ooh, it’s Liko-san!
AniPoké Original Audio Drama
After the Battle Tournament...
And Roy-san, too!
Nyarote’s so cute!
That Achigator was amazing!
Do you... get the feeling...
that we’re being watched?
We are, aren’t we?
We’re not just imagining it, right?
The way you two battled
during your friendly match was awesome...
No surprise you’re popular
around the academy now!
We’re popular?! Nice!
Oh... I just wish more people
could’ve seen it...
If only I had livestreamed it
on Gurumin’s channel!
That... would’ve been
kind of embarrassing...
Whoa!
Please shake my hand, Liko-san!
Who, me?! O-Okay...!
Roy-san, could I get
a picture with you?!
You bet!
Achigator, eyes on the camera!
Work up that energy
and strike a cool pose!
Ack! That thing on the top
of your head fell off!
That way! The stairs!
Let’s go after it!
Excuse me! Coming through!
Speaking of,
what is that thing anyway?
Not sure... An egg?
Huh? What if a new Pokémon
hatches from it?!
Apparently, it’s a fireball made from
Achigator’s overflowing energy and life force...
He nabbed it!
Nice work, Achigator!
You oughta be careful
so you don’t drop it.
Looks like Achigator
is happy he evolved!
Looks like Nyarote and Welcamo
are pleased about it, too.
Well, they’ve been
improving together all this time.
It’s from Friede!
“We’re just about to arrive.
Wait for us in front of Orange Academy.”
We get to go adventuring
with the Rising Voltteccers again...
I can’t wait!
Yeah!
Ack! You dropped it again!
Ahh! Pick it up, quick!