Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
The strange, strange creatures
who live on this planet.
In the skies...
In the seas...
In the fields...
Many different kinds of Pokémon
inhabit this world.
Among all these Pokémon, there is one hallowed
as a god for the belief that it created the world...
Arceus.
Today, as always, Arceus continues to
watch over people and Pokémon alike.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hallowed God, Arceus
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hallowed God, Arceus
Satoshi and Go! Let's Go to the Sinnoh Fest!!
Satoshi and Go have arrived at Sinnoh’s Mio City,
where the legend of Arceus is passed down.
Their objective is to investigate and experience
the ancient Sinnoh lifestyle as Research Fellows.
Apparently they’ve recreated
the way the streets used to look.
It’s like we jumped
into a movie!
Research like this
is a nice change of pace.
Satoshi! Go!
Hikari!
Hey! You’re here, too?
Sheesh! You should’ve told me you were coming!
Don’t surprise me like that!
We’re surprised to see you, too!
Right?
Yeah!
By the way...
What’s with the outfit?
Looks nice, doesn’t it?
I just rented it!
That’s so cool!
You guys wanna try this on?
I’m sure you’d look great!
Absolutely!
Let’s take some group photos!
Then follow me!
Sure!
Over here!
You can rent them here.
Oh?
Hello, Satoshi, Go!
Ms. Shirona?!
Ms. Shirona’s been helping out a ton
with the Sinnoh Fest this year!
Are you here for research?
Yup!
The museum should be
a real help to you, then!
Take your time
and look around!
Okay!
Ms. Shirona...
Satoshi and Go said
they’d like to try these clothes, too.
No problem!
What do you think,
Pikachu?
This is so cool!
They look great
on both of you!
Seems you’re all ready.
Well, then...
My three customers, step on in!
Saturn, Team Galactic Commander
Do it!
Dig!
G-1 calling G-2.
Capture complete.
This is G-2. Roger that.
Return to base.
That’s Mount Tengan, right?
Yes.
It’s believed that the harsh wilderness
even affected the biology of the native Pokémon.
Here.
Look at this painting.
That’s Guardie and Warrgle.
And this is Bassrao, and what is thought
to be an evolved form of Odoshishi.
Really?
I guess they’re
not around anymore...
I would’ve loved
to catch them if they were!
How’d people
catch Pokémon back then?
I was waiting
for you to ask that.
Here you go.
Monster Balls?
Check it out, Pikachu.
But they’re a little different.
They’re made of wood, huh?
That’s a form of Monster Ball
that was used back in the day.
Huh?
We recreated them using these
schematics our ancestors left behind.
Design documents still exist?
Do they really work?
Of course!
I wanna try!
Me, too!
Same here!
I knew you would!
So then, let me guide you
to the Pokémon Catching Corner!
Kinda looks like Sakuragi Park!
Can I catch these?!
Be patient, please.
Come out, everyone!
Mijumaru! Hinoarashi!
Mokuroh!
Hinoarashi comes from
the Johto Region...
Mijumaru is from Isshu...
And Mokuroh comes from
the Alola Region, yeah?
Why are they here,
Ms. Shirona?
Historical records show that these three
were brought here from other regions.
Wow, you’re right.
I wanted to study the influence foreign Pokémon
might have on Sinnoh’s ecosystem,
so I’m having these three
help me out.
I see.
Without further ado, the Pokémon Catching
Experience Corner entails...
...catching these three!
Hope we all
have fun together!
You get one Monster Ball each.
If you can catch one
within three minutes,
you’ll receive
a fabulous prize!
Three minutes?
No sweat!
Let’s make it a race!
Let’s! Whoever catches one first
gets all the prizes!
You’re on!
Of course,
you can have your Pokémon assist you.
Now, you three!
Go into the bushes!
It’s like playing hide and seek!
All right,
Satoshi, Go, Hikari!
Ready... Start!
C’mon, Pikachu!
We’ll be first, Sarunori!
No, we will!
There!
Oh, just a Koroboushi.
Find it?
Oh, just a Cherrim...
Where are you,
where are you?
Come out!
Pochama! Drill Beak!
I-Is that allowed?!
H-Hey, hey, hey?!
Outta the way, Pochama!
Wha...?
Mokuroh!
Satoshi! Over here!
Yeah.
Pochama! We’re catching Mijumaru
this time, no question!
Wait!
I said wait!
Then I’ll get Hinoarashi!
Oww!
You’re a pretty naughty one...
Good, Sarunori!
Now!
Let’s finish this, Pochama!
Go, Monster Ball!
Did we get ‘em?
They let out steam?
Is that how old
Monster Balls worked?
That’s right!
Isn’t it fascinating?
It is!
Mokuroh!
Hinoarashi!
Mijumaru!
We caught them!
Now, let the Pokémon out,
everyone.
Thanks, you guys.
That was an incredible
catching experience.
Wh-Why?
This one tends to launch Flamethrower
at people it likes.
Wait...
When did they get so friendly?
Since you all managed to catch them
before time was up, you all get the fabulous prize!
Been waitin’ for this!
Guess the race
ended in a tie...
Nobody gets to take them all.
Here you go.
“A History of Space-Time in Sinnoh,”
compiled by yours truly!
Amazing!
Thank you so much!
Mars, Team Galactic Commander
Jupiter, Team Galactic Commander
Do you have Heatran?
Great!
Now we can get to business.
The Fireball Plate...
Its beauty dazzles me every time I look at it.
Why bother stating the obvious?
They say this plate powers Arceus.
Of course
it would be beautiful!
Enough talk, let’s start!
Yes, yes.
Now... Time to begin
our experiment with Heatran.
All staff, stand by.
Begin Plate Hypervibration!
Heatran,
we require your power.
Magma Storm!
Energy generation confirmed!
Hypervibration rate
and energy expansion rate both rising!
Another step towards Team Galactic’s dream...
The creation of a new world!
Calm down.
We’ll need much more power
to open the space-time gate.
Crossing critical point!
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
Something’s strange here.
Let’s go take a look!
Yeah.
Phase one of the experiment
was a success!
We’ve verified how the released energy
affects the fabric of space-time.
Now we can open the gate
to Leader Akagi!
NEXT TIME
HEATRAN’S
EXPLOSIVE
ADVANCE
!