PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hallowed God, Arceus
The Heated Battle of Mount Tengan!!
A drastic increase in temperature
has been observed in the Mount Tengan area.
According to the
Sinnoh Meteorological Observatory,
the wildfire seen in these images
was determined as the cause.
It’s so hot...!
What is going on
with that Heatran?!
I can only assume some other,
greater force is at work here.
What now?!
It’s this sensation again!
Heatran was inside the flames.
You mean...
That was the real Heatran?
Yeah.
That gigantic form might be
some sort of energy clump made out of fire.
It looked unconscious.
Could it be going berserk?!
And there was something
that looked like a board. What was that?
Shoot down Agnome
and the other two!
Dokurog! Sludge Bomb!
Skutank! Flamethrower!
Bunyat! Shadow Ball!
Cut it out, Team Galactic!
What do you gain
from getting in our way?
We just want
the Pokémon to be free!
Agnome and the others
asked us for help!
We want to help them!
Look at you,
trying to act cool...
What was that board?!
Did you use it to make Heatran go crazy?!
Oh, no way!
You don’t know?
That was the Fireball Plate.
Plate?
They’re rumored to
increase Arceus’s power.
The Plate is trying
to return to the heavens.
To the Creation Pokémon, Arceus.
Because of that,
the space-time gate is opening.
It’s like a dream come true!
Th-The space-time gate?
Are you trying to summon
Dialga and Palkia?!
We only want Leader Akagi.
Nothing else.
Akagi?!
Team Galactic’s boss?!
The guy who disappeared
beyond the time-space gate?
There was no need to tell them...
Where’s the harm?
The new world has no need for them.
It really doesn’t matter
if they know.
We’ll simply dispose of them, no?
Naturally.
Shadow Ball!
Flamethrower!
100,000 Volts!
Bubble Beam!
We will save Heatran!
You’re making lots of Pokémon suffer
for your selfish goals!
We saw it ourselves!
The forest turned
to ash in an instant!
The Pokémon lost their homes!
Sarunori.
The heat’s too dangerous for you.
Get back in your Monster Ball.
Go, Aceburn!
Okay! Let’s go, everyone!
“Okay! Let’s go, everyone!”
Geez, you’re gonna make me puke.
Oh, but their energy
is quite charming.
Even if it won’t last for long.
Yeah. Nobody gets in the way of
our glorious new world and gets away with it.
We must secure Heatran’s path.
We must keep their attention
fixed on us,
and keep them away
from Heatran!
That goes without saying.
Now, all of you...
Attack!
Pyro Ball!
100,000 Volts!
Bubble Beam!
Satoshi! Go! Hikari!
I’ll keep Team Galactic busy here.
You go help Heatran
with Agnome and the others!
All right! Got it!
Let’s go!
Be careful, Takeshi!
Of course.
Stop them, Dokurog!
You’re fighting me!
It’s your turn,
Haganail! Happinus!
Haganail! Stone Edge!
Happinus, use Magical Shine!
Follow it up
with a Megaton Punch!
We can’t get close like this!
It’s too hot!
In that case...
Uonoragon!
I choose you!
Okay, then I’ll choose...
Inteleon!
Agnome! Uxie! M'rit!
Please help us out
and use Psychokinesis!
Uonoragon! Water Gun!
Inteleon! Snipe Shot!
Pochama! Whirlpool!
Amazing!
Do it!
Okay!
Great work!
Fools.
No way!
Against that intense heat,
water only makes things worse!
I expected no less of you, Heatran!
Now, go open the space-time gate!
Skutank! Flamethrower!
Bunyat! Iron Tail!
What?!
Gaburias?!
It couldn’t be...!
Ms. Shirona!
The Champion of Sinnoh?!
Another bother.
Ms. Junsa.
It really was Team Galactic.
Indeed.
This time, they won’t get away!
The Sinnoh Police
will be here shortly.
Keep us posted
on any developments.
Takeshi.
Take my Gaburias to Satoshi and the others.
I will deal with Team Galactic.
The only way to stop that Heatran
is to collapse its footing.
Gaburias should be able to help.
Got it.
I’m counting on you,
Gaburias.
Gureggru. Happinus.
You mean you’re staying here?
Then you help Ms. Shirona
in my place!
Haganail! Dig!
Bloom, Roserade!
Takeshi!
Ms. Shirona said to
collapse its footing!
So we make a pitfall?
Yeah!
If we get it stuck,
we can extinguish it!
Okay! Let’s focus our attacks
on the ground under Heatran!
Exactly!
Now, let’s do this!
Now’s our chance!
Dig!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Mammoo, come out!
Primal Power!
We did it!
What?!
Petal Blizzard!
Is that...?!
No way!
The space-time gate!
Leader Akagi!
We win!
The space-time gate has opened!
How could this be?
It’s back up?!
Even that wasn’t enough?!
Hikari!
Hang in there!
Yeah!
It’s getting bigger!
And it’s changing shape...
Could it have taken energy
from the space-time gate?
Yeah. Soaking up that energy
probably amplified the pressure inside it.
Left like this, it could cause an explosion
strong enough to blow away Mount Tengan.
That would obliterate Heatran instantly,
and us along with it.
We must go
and meet Leader Akagi!
Skutank! Smokescreen!
This is bad!
It’s gonna blow up
at this rate!
What’s that?!
Arceus!
That’s Arceus?!
NEXT TIME
A WONDROUS RADIANCE
!
THE LEGEND OF SINNOH