The Crown Snowfield?!
The Crown Snowfield is a frigid area in Galar
with jagged, snowy mountains.
It’s beautiful!
And we’ve heard that someone there
“spotted a mysterious Pokémon.”
A mysterious Pokémon?!
What is it?!
That much,
we have yet to determine.
Which is why I’d like to have you start
by hearing from the man who saw it.
Got it!
Come with us, Koharu!
Come on!
Sure!
Okay then, Director...
We’ll be off!
Be careful out there!
And so, Satoshi, Go, and Koharu make their way to
the Crown Snowfield, a place they have never been before.
Meanwhile...
Lilie, a friend of Satoshi’s from Alola...
...searches for her missing father, Mohn,
along with her mother and brother.
...look after Lilie for me.
Please protect...
my little princess.
Father.
Snowball?
The direction of that light...
So it is...
The Crown Snowfield!
It lines up with what we got
from all the data we’ve gathered!
That’s where Father is...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Mohn and Lilie,
A Reunion in the Snow!!
Crown Snowfield, Galar Region
The mysterious Pokémon you saw...
What shape was it?
Mmmm...
It was just this sudden “fwoosh,”
crossing my sight...
I couldn’t exactly say...
And... its color?
What color was it?
Oh! Ohh!
Its color! It was white!
So it was a white Pokémon.
Or was it?
“Or was it?”
No, yellow!
Yellow?!
Or was it?
“Or was it?”
I know!
It was both!
Both?
Or was it...?
It was in the middle of a blizzard,
after all.
Oh, there’s a blizzard today, too.
When did it...?
It’s pure white!
I can’t see a thing.
See?
Most people would’ve missed that Pokémon!
I only saw it ‘cause I’m used to blizzards.
Doubt it’s gonna clear up
anytime soon.
You should stay the night here.
Are you sure?
Of course!
Thank you!
The sun was shining until just a moment ago.
What is this?!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Yeah!
Ice types sure can tough it out.
Magearna?!
Wait!
Zoroark!
Chase them with your Agility!
Are you okay, Magearna?
Thank you, Zoroark.
Let’s camp here for tonight.
Huh? Out in this blizzard?
This is a new product developed by
the Aether Foundation!
I hope it’s sunny tomorrow.
If it’s sunny, you’ll go looking
for the Pokémon the old man saw, right?
Not just looking.
We’re gonna catch it!
You bet!
I knew you’d say that.
Father is...
just over there...
Lilie!
Please excuse me!
Is there nobody in?
Father!
Huh?
Um...
Who might you be?
It’s me, Lilie.
I expect you would only
know me as a baby,
but I am your daughter!
Dad!
There, there...
Is this your Pokémon?
It’s Zoroark!
Zoro... ark?
Your old partner, Dad.
Dad?
That’s right,
this girl was calling me that, too...
What is all this about?
Mohn...
How do you know my name?
We’ve been searching
for my missing husband...
...the father of my children...
We’ve traveled so far to get here.
Missing?
We thought we’d finally see him again,
here in the Crown Snowfield...
Oh, so that’s why your kids
mistook me for their father.
I understand now.
If you’d like,
you can come in for some tea.
You must be tired
from your long trip.
Thank you very much.
We’ll accept your kind offer, then.
Please make yourselves at home.
Mom.
What do you think?
If he doesn’t recognize us...
He might have lost his memory.
His memory...
Thank you for waiting.
Be careful, it’s hot.
Here.
Thank you.
Here you go.
I hope you like these.
I need to introduce you
to my daughter.
Your... daughter?!
Still, what a coincidence.
My daughter’s name is Lilie, too.
Lilie!
I’ll go and call her.
U-Um...
Huh?
May we come with you?
Lilie?!
Of course.
I’m coming in!
Utsu... roid?!
Stand back, Lilie, Gladio!
We have visitors, Lilie.
Zoroark!
Let’s go!
Wait!
Huh? Lilie?
I’m sorry.
My daughter’s quite shy.
Well, I’m sure
she’ll show herself at some point.
Our teatime was interrupted.
I’ll brew us some more.
Why did you stop me?
He thinks the Utsuroid
is his daughter.
If you suddenly attacked it,
how do you think he’d react?
There has to be
some reason for all of this.
First, we need to find it out.
Let’s look for some clues.
I’ll try talking with Mohn.
If you see the Utsuroid,
tell me straight away.
And be very careful.
Right.
Are we nearly there?
We should be near the spot
where the old man saw the Pokémon!
Or are we?
What happened?
They found something!
Something?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Lilie...
The mirror...
This one’s been removed, too...
A mirror...
Utsuroid hid it away.
Iron Tail!
You okay, Lilie?!
Satoshi!
What’s wrong?!
Satoshi?!
Gladio?
Why are you here?
When I went chasing after Pikachu,
I saw Utsuroid about to attack Lilie.
Pikachu!
It’s been such a long time!
Lilie?
That girl who was traveling around
looking for her father?
Her father?
Yes.
That is what led me here.
Big Brother,
please look at this.
This is my husband.
This man...
I don’t see
much of a resemblance.
You really...
You really can’t remember anything?
Mohn...
Still...
He looks very happy.
I hope you manage
to find him soon.
Mohn...
The one that you...
...called your daughter...
...called Lilie, is...
Mom!
Lilie, what are you doing?
Wait, Utsuroid!
Thank you.
You rescued my father,
isn’t that right?
What... do you mean?
Lilie, Gladio!
We brought them.
We found this
in the piano room.
What’s this?
This is just my guess,
but I think the accident...
...blasted you off
to some other world.
Accident?
What are you talking about?
Mohn...
You had an accident
while experimenting with Ultra Holes.
Ultra...
...Holes.
In that world, you made contact with that Utsuroid,
and you returned to this world together.
Except you didn’t return to the Alola Region,
but here, to the Crown Snowfield.
And then,
you began living together in this house.
As father and daughter.
Lilie...
I don’t know why the Utsuroid
wanted to become Lilie.
But you’ve lived
a happy life here, right?
That’s why Utsuroid feared the possibility
of your memories returning if you saw your reflection.
So it removed all of the mirrors
and made the windows dirty.
If your memories returned...
...it wouldn’t be able
to live with you anymore.
When I saw that the mirror and clothes
had been carefully stored away...
...I could tell
you cherish my father.
That’s what I realized.
Even though you could have simply
thrown them away...
Dad.
Hmm?
I remember...
everything.
Gladio.
Dad!
Lilie.
Father!
Lusamine.
Mohn...
Welcome back, Mohn!
Welcome back!
Welcome back, Dad!
I’m home.
To think Magearna is working...
I can’t believe it.
Lilie made it happen.
My little princess did?
I could only do it
thanks to your Magearna journal.
Stay, Lilie.
I want that too, Lilie.
If not for you,
I’d never have reunited with my family.
If you’d like to,
why don’t we keep on living together?
That’s a great idea, Mohn!
I’m all for it, too.
We’re both Lilie.
Isn’t that right?
Let’s go home, together.
And so, Mohn, Lusamine,
Gladio, and Lilie’s family...
...became united once again,
and they set off into a brand new future.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
A Battle Royal?!
What’s a Battle Royal?
It’s this awesome type of
Pokémon battle they do in Alola!
“Awesome”? Awesome how?
They have this ring,
and they go “wham, boom, bam-bam-bam-bam-bam,”
and then “grrrr, fwoosh, mrraaaaggh, hiy—”
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Homecoming!
The Champion of Alola!!
A Triumphant Return!