Man, I’m so bored!
Haven’t we gotten any orders
from Sakaki?
Not a word, meow.
In that case,
wanna do some training?
Let’s do it!
Capsule machine, c’mon!
It’s not coming.
‘Cause we’re indoors, meow.
Who’s that?
From here?!
Well done, meow!
Then let’s turn the wheel
like always!
Rocket Capsul-et Secret!
Straight from HQ!
Some real kingly Pokémon,
come forth!
The Fish Pokémon,
Koiking!
The Royal Pokémon,
Yadoking!
Those sure are
some real kingly Pokémon, meow.
Let’s see,
and their moves are...
What the—?!
Wh-What?
What’s it say, meow?
Today’s episode is a two-in-one!
“Flop! Koiking” and
“Crown Yourself! Yadoking”
Here we go!
Rockebiin!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Flop! Koiking
We’re the Ko-ings!
Go ahead and challenge me,
if you dare!
Flop, Goldking!
The tenth Koiking High Jump Tournament
has begun!
May your Koiking soar high, too!
Challenge the nine-time champion,
Kasuking’s Goldking!
We’re the Ko-ings!
You’re entering this?
Yeah! I’m aiming to win
with this guy!
Come out, Koiking!
Is this the Lord Koiking
from the other day?
He’s gotten crazy fat...
Don’t worry!
I got a master plan!
We’re the Ko-ings!
Hope your abs are still ripped!
Kasuking isn’t just
the Koiking High Jump Champion.
He’s also a popular muscle trainer!
Now, don’t give up!
You can still do it!
Your abs can get
even more ripped!
Hey, Goldking!
Show ‘em your ripped muscles!
Kasuking really is an expert!
Hey, don’t you wanna be
as cool as Goldking?
You wanna beat Goldking, yeah?
Oh, you’re fired up?
All right!
Then we’ll train, too!
Right, Pikachu?
From that day on,
we were training fiercely
for the Koiking High Jump Tournament!
The sweat and tears shed
were countless!
Your greatest foe
is the weakness in your own heart!
The efforts piled up
to conquer this weakness...
...do not lie!
We’ve done all we can,
yeah, Koiking?
We’re gonna win!
We’ve reached the semifinals
of the Koiking High Jump Tournament!
Competitor Go’s Koiking has
demonstrated some impressive jumps!
Its remarkable physique seems to have been
tailored with this tournament in mind!
His opponent is Koi Kingen,
last year’s runner-up!
Which of the two
will reach the finals?!
Hang in there, Go!
You got this, Koiking!
Ready... Get set...
Jump!
Flop,
Koiking!
Off they go!
How will this turn out?!
Awesome!
21.02 meters!
Competitor Go wins,
beating his record in the process!
All right!
You’re in the finals
at last, Go!
Yeah! But next is...
The second match of the semifinals!
The nine-time champions,
the team of Kasuking and Goldking!
They are showing their
kingly dignity!
We’re the Ko-ings!
Ready... Get set...
Jump!
Flop, Koiking!
Flop, Goldking!
Incredible!
Champion Kasuking’s Goldking
displays immense power!
He makes it into the finals!
Onigohri!
You got this, Go!
Of course!
I know this guy will pull through!
The Koiking High Jump Tournament
has reached the finals!
Competitor Go challenges
Kasuking for his crown!
You think you can
beat my Goldking?
That’s why I’m here.
Then let me show you...
...the king’s true power!
Goldking has been restraining himself so far,
to liven up the tournament...
But this tournament will be
our tenth win in a row!
Today, we will become legends!
Release all restraints,
and go at full power, Goldking!
Oh, my! Competitor Kasuking declares
that he hasn’t been serious until now!
What kind of jumps
can we expect?!
Scared?
No, I’m excited!
Really...
The Champion is something else,
all right.
Right, Koiking?
We couldn’t ask
for a better opponent!
Now it is time for you
to claim your wings!
Oh, my! Competitor Go’s
Koiking’s fins...!
What is this?
My Koiking has been Flopping
with weights on all this time!
A stunning confession!
When’d he put those on...?
Um, please wait a moment.
We are clearing the aren—
Kairiky injured its back!
Competitor Go’s Koiking has been equipped
with immensely heavy weights!
What kind of jumps
can we expect from him?!
The climactic High Jump
is about to take place!
Which Koiking will win?!
Ready... Get set...
Jump!
Flop, Goldking!
What’s this? Competitor Go’s Koiking
has yet to jump!
What could be wrong?!
Did you get scared
and throw the match?
Not at all.
What?
My Koiking is still storing power...
...so that he can leap to any height!
Flop, Koiking!
Competitor Go’s Koiking
flies like a rocket!
My Goldking?!
Come on!
This is amazing!
What will the result be?!
I can’t believe I would lose...
He’s not coming back...
Huh?
Hello?
Excuse me...
The judge has just told me
his verdict.
Verdict?
Um, since tournament rules state that
one’s results are only measured after landing,
Competitor Go’s Koiking’s jump
will not get measured.
And as such, Competitor Kasuking’s
Goldking is the winner.
We’re the Ko-ings!
Unreliable... Pathetic...
Incredibly famous... Incredibly weak
Koiking...
He put so much blood, sweat and tears
into winning, and ultimately became a star...
Once upon a time it was super strong
I will never forget him.
Or so the rumors say, anyway
Farewell, Koiking!
Thank you for the memories!
But now it’s really—
Hey! Why are you
reciting the closing words?!
We’re the Ko-ings!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Koiking
Water
Crown Yourself! Yadoking
Whoa... My info was right!
Yadon... Yadon...
and more Yadon!
What’cha doin’, Yadon?
Had a dream ‘bout wakin’ up with the sun
As it slept ‘til noon, that Yadon
Its pink skin isn’t due to being overboiled
It always looked like that, that Yadon
Its large mouth is like a convenience store;
Open 24/7
Yadon! Dopey Pokémon!
Water/Psychic type!
Its long tail often breaks off!
It doesn’t really feel any pain, though, and the tail
grows back, so Yadon isn’t particularly bothered!
Its tail is said to be sweet!
Its tail, huh...?
I wonder if it tastes nice.
Delicious!
What are you doing?
Well, I was just hungry.
Come on... We’re all the way out
on the Yadon island.
At least act like you’re in awe.
I am, though!
Whatever.
Time to catch a Yadon.
Which one should I get...?
Is that...?
Udon!
Not the food!
Yadoking! Royal Pokémon!
Water/Psychic type!
If its tail is bitten by a Shellder,
Yadon evolves into Yadoran!
But when its head is bitten instead,
it evolves into Yadoking!
It possesses
the intellect of a genius!
Huh? Of a genius?
All right!
I’ll start with Yadoking!
That’s Psychokinesis!
You want this? Sure.
I know, right? It’s great!
It came off?!
What?!
Satoshi, are you okay?
No problem!
I’m excellent!
Understand?
Satoshi...
You’re acting kinda weird.
Weird?
Why, I haven’t the faintest clue
what you mean!
I am Satoshi. No...
I am Satoking!
I have become a Yadon Master!
An influencer striving
to improve the Yadon!
No, this is totally weird, yeah?
Could that thing be why?
All right...
Cease that, my dear Go.
That would be a severe compliance breach.
Wh-What is that?!
Look, just take that thing off your head!
I cannot do that!
I need it to remain myself.
This is a critical factor to
the Yadon’s future success!
A most big issue for us!
I don’t understand you at all!
It appears, my dear Go, that you cannot comprehend
the success I am attempting to reach.
I have to put Satoshi
back to normal!
Rabbifoot, use Double Kick
on that thing on Satoshi’s head!
Pikachu, help us!
100,000 Volts!
Stop, my dear Pikachu.
It takes a bit of time
for Yadon to feel pain!
You and the Yadon
are both part of my beloved family.
There is no reason whatsoever
for there to be any conflict between us. Be at ease!
Satoshi...
My dear Go,
will you not walk alongside me?
The synergy between you and I
shall surely point the Yadon’s future in a positive direction!
There’s no way!
Welcome, my Yadokingdom!
I absolutely refuse!
What are you trying to do?!
Here you are, my dear Go.
As of today, you shall be a Yadoran.
Never! You’re gonna be
a Pokémon Master, right?
I am now the Yadon Master,
Satoking!
Double Kick!
Huh? What am I doing?
All right! You’re back to—
Go!
My name is Goking!
I shall capture every Yadon!
What’s happened to you, Go?
Huh? What was I doing?
Pikachu!
Rabbifoot?!
Compliance!
I shall capture them!
Critical success factor!
Complete!
I’m excellent!
Success!
Capture!
Com—
Capt—
Compli—
What was that?
Look!
Yadoking!
Is that...?
Koiking!
Go’s Koiking,
thought to have become a star...
...has safely returned to him!
All’s well that ends well... I suppose?
Man, I’m so bored!
Anything from Sakaki?
Not a sound.
Not even the slightest whisper, meow.
In that case,
wanna do some training?
Guess we might as well.
Capsule machine, come on!
We’re indoors,
so it won’t come, meow.
Someone’s here.
Coming.
We’re the Ko-ings!
Onigo—
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Go! Let’s go check out Mr. Dande’s
official Master Class battle!
I will catch
every Pokémon in Galar!
H-Hey, what’s that?!
Is that... a Kamonegi?!
Let the winds blow!
Stream forward, Sandstorm!
Now, enjoy the climax!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Heroic Legend!
Dande's Ultimate Battle!!
Dande’s Ultimate Battle!!