Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
A research request?
Yeah.
A guy from Hoenn named Hoji
contacted us.
We became friends when we battled
in the Glass Flute Cup!
What was his request?
Apparently, the water suddenly stopped flowing
at his uncle’s hot spring.
Here’s a photo he sent.
The water?
And right around that time,
an Absol was seen nearby.
An Absol?
The townspeople suspect the Absol
is why the water stopped.
Absol! Disaster Pokémon!
Evil type!
It appears when it senses
an impending natural disaster!
As a result,
it was mistaken as a doom-bringer!
So, he wants us to
look into the Absol!
In ancient times, Absol was considered
a doom-bringing Pokémon,
and some people still believe
in that old superstition.
So we thought we’d find
the real cause! Right?
Yeah.
I see. Well then, you two better go
and help this Hoji!
Right!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Hated Absol
Fuen Town, Hoenn Region
Satoshi, Go, Pikachu
and Sarunori
have arrived at Fuen Town
in the Hoenn Region.
The town’s hot springs are
a famous tourist destination.
Hey!
There’s Hoji!
It’s been a while!
You’re here!
That’s a rare one
you’ve got there, Go.
It’s called a Sarunori.
All right, nice to meet you!
That didn’t hurt! Not one bit!
Good to see you’re both
doing well!
All the stores are closed...
Awful, right?
Nobody’s gonna come here
without the hot springs.
That sounds rough
for a tourist spot...
Everyone here’s saying
“This is all Absol’s fault!”
They’re all furious.
Isn’t that just a superstition?
I’ll show ya. C’mon.
What’s this?
Uncle says this tablet’s
been here for generations.
Absol?
Ever since ancient times,
whenever Absol showed up here, disaster followed.
Our ancestors carved this to make sure
the message would be passed down.
See, look at that.
The hot springs must’ve dried up
after Absol appeared in the past, too.
So that’s why everyone’s
convinced it’s Absol’s fault...
I don’t really get it,
but everyone’s worried.
So I thought if I asked you,
maybe you could do something.
You’re really kind, Hoji.
S-Save it!
This is my Uncle’s inn.
Uncle!
What are you doing?!
Oh, Hoji.
We’re going Absol hunting.
You should join us!
Hunting?!
We’ve all had enough!
We’re gonna give that Absol a real clobbering,
and bring peace back to our town!
Yeah!
Hold on a sec!
Who are these kids?
My pals, Satoshi and Go.
And Sarunori and Pikachu.
I had them come here to investigate.
Huh?
I don’t see what
you kids could do to help.
What?!
Well, the more hands, the better.
You can come, too.
Maybe Absol is just showing itself
to warn you of some danger!
Catching it and getting rid of it
would be wrong!
What?!
Why should we listen
to outsiders?!
You got any proof,
any evidence?!
What, you came here to criticize us?
Give us some time!
We’ll investigate,
and uncover the real reason!
What you’re doing is just cruel to Absol!
Listen to me at least, Uncle.
They know a lot about Pokémon.
They’ll be able to help!
You have two hours. Take any longer,
and we’ll go out hunting!
It really is empty.
Hoji...
When did the water stop?
About half a month ago, I think?
After Uncle saw
Absol on the mountain,
the water suddenly
cooled down,
then before long,
it was just gone.
Fuen Town’s hot springs
come from Mt. Entotsu?
Yeah. The water’s piped from
the source inside the mountain.
Everyone here’s afraid of
running into Absol,
so they don’t go near
the source spring.
The water cooling down
is kinda suspicious, too...
Satoshi! Let’s take a look
and see if we can find any clues!
Okay!
While you’re at it,
I’ll try and convince Uncle.
Have him give up that ridiculous idea
of a hunting squad.
We’re counting on you, Hoji!
Yeah, leave it to me!
There’s a road winding right to
the spring on Mt. Entotsu.
As long as we follow it,
we can’t get lost.
This is getting kinda fun.
This is pretty rough.
Yeah...
All right, we’re nearly there.
Absol?!
Look out!
Are you okay?
What are you doing, Absol?!
Sarunori!
You okay?
Rest up for a bit.
It got away.
Ugh...
What’s wrong with Absol,
attacking us out of nowhere...?
What now, Go?
We’ll just have to look for
another path, I guess.
Yeah.
Pipes!
If we follow these,
they’ll take us to the spring!
There!
We finally found it.
What a relief!
It’s frozen solid.
Then the water stopped
because it was frozen?
But why is it frozen?
No matter how cold it is,
hot spring water wouldn’t freeze.
The water is heated by magma
underground before it surfaces.
Does that mean
something’s going on underground?
But how can we
investigate underground...?
I thought this might come up, so...
Go!
Nuckrar! Dig!
Looking good!
Nuckrar?
Hey! Did something happen?!
Sorry, Nuckrar...
That must’ve been cold...
It’s frozen...
Something really is wrong!
Brrr!
What?!
An Onigohri?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Absol
Evil
Onigohri! Face Pokémon!
Ice type!
It has a body of ice that won’t melt,
even with fire!
It can instantly freeze
moisture in the atmosphere!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
Brrr!
Pikachu, now try―
Hold on!
Huh? Why?
Don’t you think the Onigohri
could be behind the ground freezing?
There could be more of them.
Let’s follow it stealthily.
A Yukiwarashi!
There really were more of them.
Yukiwarashi! Snow Hat Pokémon!
Ice type!
They can only survive in cold areas!
They eat snow and ice to survive!
Did that Yukiwarashi
get completely lost and end up here?
This mountain is
too hot for Yukiwarashi.
So they froze everything
to make it more comfortable.
That means if we
deal with the Onigohri,
the hot springs should
go back to normal!
All right!
I’ll solve this by catching them!
Absol?!
Wh-Why are you getting
in our way, Absol?!
Just when we got to
the bottom of things...!
Why is Absol attacking us?
Does it have some sorta reason?
I want to trust Absol, too.
I feel the same way you do.
But...
Absol’s eyes earlier...
Maybe Absol appeared
to try and tell us something?!
Hey, Go.
I’m having a hard time here.
You doing any better?
Yeah.
The hot spring stopped because
Onigohri arrived and froze the water.
Oh, that’s great!
So it really wasn’t Absol.
About that...
I’ve got a favor to ask.
Sure, what is it?
Can you check if that tablet
depicts anything like what’s happening?
Got it, leave it to me!
Sorry, Uncle. We’ll talk more later.
I gotta step out for a bit!
Go...
Why did you ask Hoji to do that?
That tablet depicted all sorts of disasters
that Absol previously warned about.
If it shows anything like
what’s currently going on...
Maybe we can figure out
what Absol’s trying to tell us!
Yeah!
Hello?
Go, bingo!
There’s a drawing of
a frozen hot spring on the tablet!
What is it?
I don’t get why,
but it shows the mountain erupting, too.
Does that mean they both
happened at the same time?
Thank you, Hoji!
What is it?
What Absol was trying to tell us...
...was this!
Huh? An eruption?
300 years ago, Onigohri wandered up the mountain
and the hot spring froze.
After that, the ice heated up
all at once, made steam...
And the mountain erupted!
Huh?
You know, if steam builds up underground, the pressure rises, right?
Like... If you shake a can of carbonated juice,
it gets full of gas!
What?! That’s awful!
If the ice all melted at once,
the same thing might happen.
That’s why Absol stopped us
from catching the Onigohri!
Yeah! We can still make it in time!
What?!
Steam venting!
That could be a sign it’s erupting.
Let’s hurry!
Yeah!
Go... What can we do
to stop the eruption?
We crack the rock open,
and let the steam vent!
Okay, got it!
Aceburn, go!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
It’s crazy hard!
One more time!
All right!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Nothing...
Absol!
We should help!
Yeah!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Okay!
But at this pace...
Absol!
It wouldn’t...
You did it!
Absol!
Absol’s data will be
added to the Index!
Absol, I’m glad you’re okay.
The steam’s stopped venting,
so it looks like everything’s settled down.
So, no eruption?
Nope.
Should be good now, yeah?
Absol. Thank you for
warning us about the disaster.
Feel free to go now.
Huh? What is it?
Wait, is there going to be
another disaster?!
Huh?
Absol’d rather go along with you!
You... want to come along with me?
Great, huh, Go?
Nice to meet you, Absol!
This feels great.
It’s heavenly, heavenly...
The temperature’s perfect!
It’s good to see
you’re all better, Sarunori.
Thanks.
The hot spring’s back,
all because of you.
And we’ll take the Onigohri
somewhere colder.
They’d have a hard time
living on Mt. Entotsu, anyway.
Yeah, go ahead.
How’d things go with your uncle?
He’s given up Absol hunting, right?
Oh, well, about that...
He insisted on doing this.
Please accept my apologies.
Huh?
Water?
Yeah. And the Onigohri have been in there,
so it’s freezing cold.
Wh-Why?
I was wrong about Absol,
and about you two.
You worked so hard to save our town.
This is the least I can do to apologize!
I’m sorry!
I was wrong!
Thank you for your help!
Th-That’s enough!
You’ve made your point!
Hurry up and get in the hot spring!
You satisfied now, Uncle?
Yeah.
Let’s call it hot water under the bridge,
for the hot spring.
A dad joke he put his heart into.
Laugh for him, will ya?
Hot water, hot spring, I get it now!
Huh? What is it?
That hurt!
No, that didn’t hurt.
Satoshi and Go resolved the mix-up regarding Absol,
and prevented a disaster.
Now, peace is sure to return
to Fuen Town.
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Pikachu! It’s the Isshu Region!
Time to catch loads of Pokémon!
Monster Ball, go!
Oww...
Ugh... Who did that?
O-Oh, sorry!
I thought you were a Pokémon...
Go, she’s my next opponent.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi VS Iris!!
Dragon Battle!
Dragon Battle! Satoshi VS Iris!!