This is Masara Town.
And here lives...
Mom!
I can go too, right?
To Professor Okido’s Pokémon Camp!
It’s a camp where you get to observe
wild Pokémon with Professor Okido!
Wow!
They have camps for that?
All right, I’ll sign you up.
Yay! All right!
But I have things to do
that morning.
You’ll have to get up
on your own.
I can’t wait!
Satoshi, are you listening?
I wonder what kind
of Pokémon I’ll meet!
Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
Strange, strange creatures
with countless secrets.
Some Pokémon live happily
alongside humans...
But in the grass...
In the air...
and in the water,
you’ll find wild Pokémon, too!
And in this forest...
Pichu is a Pokémon who can
discharge electricity.
It still can’t use it well, though.
There are many Pokémon
who live in packs in the forest,
but it appears that
this Pichu is all alone.
The lonely Pichu...
...began living with the Garura family.
Several weeks later...
...the day had come
for Professor Okido’s camp.
Professor Okido!
Aren’t we leaving yet?
Well, you see...
There’s supposed to be one more coming.
But we’re past the meetup time...
He’s an energetic little boy
who lives nearby...
He probably went all like,
“I’m going on a trip tomorrow, so I’m too excited to sleep!”
I bet he’s careless and simple-minded.
Can’t wait...
for the Pokémon... Camp...
That does describe him pretty well...
But, um... Who are you?
I’m Go!
She invited me here!
Oh, you’re Koharu’s friend?
That’s right! Go comes to play
at Dad’s lab all the time!
Is Professor Sakuragi doing well?
He is!
Much like me, Koharu’s father
is a Pokémon researcher.
He shows great promise, too.
He’s been deemed a genius since he was young.
So, how long are we gonna wait
for the careless and simple-minded guy?
We don’t want to be late back, either...
Oh, well.
I suppose we’re setting off.
The... sun?!
Professor Okido! Everyone!
Wait for me!
All right, it’s time to explore the forest
and observe the Pokémon living here!
All right!
A real live Caterpie!
Go, Monster Ball!
All right! I got Caterpie!
As you just saw, you can catch wild Pokémon
by throwing Monster Balls at them.
When you turn ten,
you can become Pokémon Trainers,
get your own starter Pokémon,
and embark on an adventure
with Pokémon!
But before that, you should steep yourselves
in plenty of Pokémon knowledge!
All right! We got it!
I’ve already got more Pokémon knowledge
than I’ll ever need, though!
Go?!
That’s great to hear!
Do you know what this Pokémon is?
It’s Cocoon,
the Cocoon Pokémon, yeah?
Oh! Correct!
Well, do you know
that Pokémon, then?
That’s Kamonegi, yeah?
The thing in its mouth is a plant stalk.
The stalk is used like a sword to cut all sorts of things!
Amazing!
Awesome!
I can’t believe you knew that!
That’s Digda! A Pokémon that
feeds on plant roots!
Here’s Digda’s evolved form, Dugtrio!
It’s amazingly strong!
It can dig to a depth of 100 kilometers!
Go! Professor Okido is supposed to
provide the Pokémon explanations!
You really do know a lot about Pokémon,
don’t you, Go?
Just like Go just said,
Pokémon evolve.
The conditions for them to evolve vary,
but Pokémon are creatures who
change their appearance and shape.
But Kamonegi don’t evolve!
Th-That’s right...
Not every Pokémon evolves!
But some Pokémon do, right?
Go!
It’s quite all right.
Now let’s look at the Pokémon
living in the water.
Come on, Go!
This is why you can’t make any friends!
I don’t want to get friends...
I want to get an amazing Pokémon someday!
One that nobody’s ever seen!
Hey, are you mocking me?!
I mean, that’s just a dream...
It’s not a dream! It’s the future!
And that future lies in my hands!
Huh?
It’s a Nidoking!
It vanished?!
No way!
It used the same move as Nidoking!
The same move again?!
It’s playing by using
the same moves as its opponent!
Who’s that Pokémon?!
Go, wait!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pichu
Electric
Go! I said wait!
Where’d that Pokémon go?!
Oh, come on, Go!
Boobur!
Go!
It turned into a Kentauros?!
And now a Laplace?!
I’m not giving up!
Go!
Meanwhile, in the same forest,
Pichu had become good friends with the Garura family...
These Pokémon are called Lucky.
They’ll share their eggs
with their friends.
Lucky’s eggs are highly nutritious,
and the Pokémon love them.
I’m sure it flew this way...
Go, let’s go back to the others.
I’m sure Professor Okido is worried!
Oh, no!
Professor Okido!
Oh, there you are!
I looked all over for you!
That might have been Mew.
Mew?
It’s said to live deep in the jungle...
But since it can freely hide itself,
it’s very hard to spot.
It seems to contain
the genes of every Pokémon.
It’s known as a Mythical Pokémon.
A Mythical Pokémon?
Awesome... Mew is amazing!
I wanna turn ten already!
Turn ten, become a Pokémon Trainer...
Then I’ll catch that Pokémon...
I’ll catch Mew, for sure!
A new meeting...
A small missed opportunity...
Then, some time later...
Pichu and Garura’s child
had both grown a bit bigger.
One parting...
...leads to another meeting.
Several years later...
Satoshi, the young boy who
lives in Masara Town...
...had turned ten.
The... sun?!
On the day he was finally set to embark
on his journey as a Pokémon Trainer,
Satoshi overslept again,
but he was still able to
get his first Pokémon.
It’s called Pikachu.
So cute! He’s perfect!
Really?
Yeah!
Pikachu!
It’s so nice to meet you!
What’s...?!
It’s also known as
the electric mouse.
It’s quite shy,
and doesn’t take to people very well.
This is what happens if
you touch it carelessly.
Pikachu, huh?
I’m Satoshi! Nice to meet you!
This meeting was the start of
Satoshi and Pikachu’s story.
The two have shared
many adventures,
and now the curtain rises
on yet another one!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Oh, yeah... Go barely ever
goes to school, right?
That’s right...
It’s like researching and observing
Pokémon is all he ever does.
The future...
...already...
...lies in my hands!
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
An exceedingly rare Pokémon
will appear at Kuchiba Port!
What?! Lugia?!
Let’s all fight it together!
It’s a Raid Battle!
Wait!
I’ll be the one to battle Lugia!
No! The future lies in my hands!
Who are you?
Who are you?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi and Go,
Aboard Lugia They Go!