Here you go!
The Pokémon World Championships?
They’re tickets to the finals, even!
Awesome!
I know, right?
What’s this?
Satoshi, you don’t know?
There have been plenty of Leagues
and tournaments in other regions,
and they all have
their own Champions...
But the Pokémon World Championships
are where they crown the Supreme Monarch.
Supreme Monarch?!
And these tickets are
for the finals!
So, that means...
We’ll get to see the Pokémon battle
that’ll decide who’s the strongest in the world?!
Indeed!
Awesome!
It will be held in the Galar Region.
I’m sure the stadium where the battle takes place
will be filled with surprises!
I’d like you to go see and
experience it for yourselves!
We will!
Thank you, Director Sakuragi!
And I’ll catch myself plenty of
Pokémon while I’m at it!
All right! Set off for Galar!
Let’s go to the
Pokémon World Championships!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be friends!
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Daimax Battle!
Dande, the Strongest of All!
How much longer?
The plane has just entered
Galar airspace.
We’re almost there!
Check the power transmission system.
Of course.
Don’t worry, everyone.
Please keep your seatbelts fastened.
What’s up?
Something’s coming.
What?
Nothing’s there.
It will be! I can feel it!
Pikachu!
Cabin lights are back on.
What was that?
You okay, Pikachu?
Hey, what did we just see?
A Pokémon!
Must be...
It was real impactful!
I’m getting really excited!
Seems there’s still loads of
mysteries to uncover in Galar!
Yeah!
I’m getting excited, too!
We’re back in the Galar Region!
It’s been a while since you were
in Shoot City, huh?
So, which way to the stadium?
It’s right in front of us!
Huh?
Where?
Look!
Shoot Stadium, Galar Region
It’s massive!
Awesome!
It’s huge! So awesome!
We’ll go catch some Pokémon first!
Go, let’s enter the stadium!
No, I’m going to catch Pok—
C’mon, hurry!
Stop pulling me!
Look at all these people!
Yeah, there’s even more
than I imagined!
Oh, wow, the brat boy is here.
I’d like to say
“Let’s get Pikachu!”, but...
We have our orders
from Sakaki, meow.
Those gigantifying Pokémon
in Galar or whatever...
Operation Catch ’em!
And for that purpose, we’ve been provided
with a new item, too, meow!
Ladies and gentlemen!
The time has come at last!
The world’s biggest and best
Pokémon battle fest to crown the world’s best!
Its name?
The Pokémon World Championships!
The top eight battlers certified
by the Pokémon Battle Commission,
the Masters Eight, have duked it out
in a fierce tournament.
Who will claim the title of
the Supreme Monarch?!
Now, then, the finalists
are entering the arena!
First off...
Competitor Wataru!
It’s Wataru!
Representing our
very own Kanto Region!
One of the Kanto League’s Elite Four,
the winner of the Elite Four Cup,
and the winner of the dream showdown,
the Hodomoe City Pokémon World Tournament!
He is also an active member of the Pokémon G-Men,
who takes down his foes with overwhelming force!
His elegant battles using
Dragon-type Pokémon are truly art!
A Pokémon Trainer who prides himself
on his world-class strength! This is Wataru!
Next up, the other finalist is...
...Competitor Dande!
Born and raised in Galar, the first time he participated in
the Seed Challenge to determine Galar’s strongest,
his overwhelming power
netted him a flawless, undefeated victory!
Ever since then, he has continued to
extend his flawless winning streak,
and has declared that,
as Champion, he will battle any challenger!
This king of kings effortlessly took down 100 challengers
from all over the world who answered his call!
That is Galar’s very own superstar:
The invincible Competitor Dande!
Competitors Wataru and Dande
are standing by on the battlefield.
It’s finally time.
Yeah.
We will now commence the
Pokémon World Championships finals!
Both competitors, step forth!
The battle will be a single match.
The first to incapacitate
his opponent’s Pokémon wins.
Looking at your battles up till now,
I can tell that you are a trainer
of considerable skill.
So of course, I figured
you’d make it this far.
Can you feel it, Wataru?
The tense, still air
on the battlefield...
And the exact opposite from the audience,
cheering and yelling...
They’re both fantastic,
wouldn’t you say?
But remember,
the audience is also a bit cruel...
They want nothing more than
to see one of us lose, after all!
I absolutely love pushing past that fear.
I love giving it everything I’ve got as a trainer
to seize another victory!
It’s the greatest feeling in the world,
and I can’t get enough of it!
You think you’ve won already?
The reason I’m unbeatable is because
I learn from every battle I see or take part in.
I will learn from this battle...
No, this victory, too!
There’s no need for words now.
We will battle to determine
who is the stronger of the two of us!
Both competitors,
send out your Pokémon!
Awesome!
It’s an alternate-color Gyarados!
Competitor Dande sends out
his absolute ace, Lizardon.
And Competitor Wataru sends out
the evolved form of the golden Koiking,
the red Gyarados!
Let the match begin!
Here I come!
We’re going to have
a real champion time!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Lizardon
Flying
Fire
Let the match begin!
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Gyarados! Counter with
Destroyer Beam!
The Destroyer Beam
overpowered the Flamethrower!
Dodge!
Gyarados, you’re as strong
as I expected!
Lizardon! Air Slash!
Stop it, Gyarados!
Oh? Despite the recoil from having fired a Destroyer Beam,
Gyarados blocked the Air Slash!
Competitor Wataru’s training is
in a league of its own!
Flamethrower!
Go!
Can they dodge this time?
Dragon Dance!
Gyarados boosts its attack power and speed
with Dragon Dance!
But the Flamethrower
hits its mark!
Move in close!
Knock it down with Aqua Tail!
So much power!
I see! Even though the Flamethrower hit Gyarados,
it wasn’t very effective.
So he figured it was worth getting hit if it meant
increasing his speed and power with Dragon Dance!
It’s super effective!
Lizardon, are you all right?
Keep up the pressure!
Ice Fang flurry!
Ferocious!
Having raised its speed and power,
Gyarados wraps around Lizardon and attacks non-stop!
Shake it off, Lizardon!
Fire Spin!
What’s this?! Gyarados is
locked in place by Fire Spin!
You’re kidding!
What now, Wataru?!
Gyarados!
Sever it with Aqua Tail!
All right!
Go! Use Ice Fang!
I was waiting for this!
Lizardon! Thunder Punch!
What?!
Lizardon used an
Electric move?!
They were saving it until now!
That’s gotta hurt!
Thunder Punch flurry!
Wataru’s going to lose
if this keeps up!
Counter it with a flurry
of Aqua Tails!
Awesome...
I’m not finished with this battle.
And I won’t let anyone finish it for me!
Of course not.
I was thinking the same thing!
Oh! Is this...?!
Here we go, Gyarados!
Daimax!
Here comes Daimax Gyarados!
Daimax...
They even use it in battles here in Galar?
This must be what Director Sakuragi meant
when he said “full of surprises”!
That’s great!
Bigger is better, meow!
So that’s what Sakaki meant
by “gigantifying Pokémon”!
I want one, too!
That Daisocks!
“Daisocks”? Gigantic socks?
It’s “Daimax”, meow.
Daimax... That’s great.
I’ll show you what Lizardon
can really do!
It’s Kyodaimax time!
It’s Kyodaimax Lizardon!
Kyodaimax?!
So cool!
The battle has turned from a regular battle
into an intense Daimax battle!
Dai Stream!
The Water-type Daimax move, huh?
Of course you’d use that move.
Lizardon! Counter with Dai Thunder!
Competitor Dande uses
the Electric-type Daimax move!
Aiming for super effective hits
is a surefire way to claim victory!
Bring them down
with Dai Attack!
Lizardon! Dai Jet!
They dodged it?!
Dai Jet hits its mark!
I’ll show you a true champion time!
Kyodai Hellfire!
Gyarados, use Dai Wall!
Gyarados’s Dai Wall
blocked the Kyodai Hellfire!
Oh, did it, now?
Now, enjoy the climax!
Gyarados!
Gyarados is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is Competitor Dande!
The winner is Competitor Dande!
Wataru lost...
Lizardon, well done.
Now we’re Supreme Monarchs!
They sure were tough...
Yeah, that Champion Dande
was crazy strong!
You did well.
Take a nice, long rest.
...It’s over.
Your Daimax was superb!
I once trained
at Galar’s Dragon Gym.
And I was influenced by their uniform,
with its rich history,
and based this outfit off of it.
I see. I’m sure they’re happy.
It’s an odd feeling.
I’m not angry that I lost.
In fact, I feel happy that I witnessed the rise
of a great new Supreme Monarch!
Thank you.
That was a magnificent battle!
The Supreme Monarch
has been born here today!
Pokémon will respond to a
trainer’s strong, upstanding nature.
That is how trainers continue to
grow stronger with their Pokémon!
Like Dande and Lizardon have!
Then, let me introduce you
once again...
The winner of the Pokémon World Championships!
He who holds the ultimate title of honor!
The Supreme Monarch, Dande!
That’s the world’s strongest
Pokémon Trainer, huh?
I wanna battle Mr. Dande!
Wow, that was fun!
That was quite the spectacle!
But we should get back to
catching Pokémon, meow.
A Pokémon I’ve never seen before!
It’s my turn, meow!
Kajirigame. Biting Pokémon.
Water/Rock type.
Etcetera, etcetera!
“Etcetera, etcetera”...?
But it’s a Galar Pokémon, meow!
Then I’m sure it can turn giant!
Okay! Let’s catch it!
Vending, come on!
Rocket vending secret!
Huh? Just one?
If there’s just one, it might be a huge Pokémon,
like the Whaloh from last time!
All right! Come on!
The Flower Pokémon...
Madatsubomi?
Oh, fine! Show us what you can do!
Power Whip!
What power, meow!
Keep beating it into the ground!
What is that...?!
What?
Musashi, catch it, meow!
Go, Monster Ball!
Were you even trying?!
Take it down, Madatsubomi!
Wait... Where are you? Huh?
You sure are quick to flee!
Kajirigame is an
extremely ferocious Pokémon.
There is no escape
once it gives chase.
No way!
A Kyodaimax Kajirigame is
on a rampage at the stadium!
What will happen next?!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U’u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Satoshi and Mr. Dande
are gonna battle?!
I’ll show you
a true champion time!
Pikachu, here it comes!
Enjoy the climax!
Kyodai Hellfire!
No way!
Pikachu!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi VS Dande!
The Path to Power!!
Satoshi VS Dande! The Path to Power!!