Sakuragi Institute’s research fellows,
Satoshi and Go,
headed to Galar to investigate
the mysteries of Daimax.
They were separated in the Slumbering Weald,
and each met a mysterious Pokémon.
Meanwhile, Pokémon began Daimaxing on their own and rampaging.
Satoshi worked with Dande
to stop their rampages,
while Go went with Sonia
to try and solve the legend of the hero.
At the same time, Rose was attempting to
revive the Pokémon which once nearly wiped out Galar.
What is his goal?
Then, when Go and Sonia were investigating a mural,
they were attacked by a mysterious group.
Impossible!
There were statues behind the mural?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Sword & Shield III
"Mugendaina"
Two humans,
and two Pokémon?
Those Pokémon...
Hey! You can talk
all you want later!
Knock them all down
with Dai Steel!
Rabbifoot! Are you okay?
All right! Dai Knuckle!
Hey! What are you doing?!
Finish them with Kyodai Stench!
We’ll finish you first!
Rabbifoot, Dai Burn!
How’s that?
Want some more?
You’ll regret this!
Go, that was great!
Guess it went well for being
my first Daimax battle.
Rabbifoot, good job!
You really are my Pokémon!
Oh, right! The statues!
Now then, time to meet up
with Go in Lateral Town!
Go for it, Kairyu!
Galar itself is what
let me reach my current life.
And I intend to do everything
within my power,
in order for this marvelous view
to last a thousand years.
A thousand years...
I can’t even imagine
that far ahead!
When I was in the Slumbering Weald,
I met a Pokémon that
looked a lot like this statue.
Though it didn’t have
the sword and shield...
When I tried to catch it,
my Monster Ball went through it,
and the fog got worse...
I fell asleep out of nowhere...
Is that why it’s called
the Slumbering Weald?
And then?
When I woke up,
the Pokémon was gone.
What a bizarre experience.
What’s this?
It looks like their names...
It says the one holding the sword is Zacian,
and the one with the shield is Zamazenta.
Now we know for sure!
The legendary hero
wasn’t one person, but two!
And they both
had a Pokémon with them.
Which were Zacian and Zamazenta!
The black vortex that once covered the sky
was a Pokémon called Black Night.
It nearly wiped out Galar.
But the two heroes, and their partners
Zacian and Zamazenta quelled the calamity.
Yes, that about summarizes it.
Okay, there they are!
Catch them this time!
Those guys again?
They don’t give up...
What do we do?
Times like these...
...you gotta bowl straight through ‘em!
Where to?
The Slumbering Weald!
To do what exactly?
If the legendary heroes
really quelled Black Night,
Zacian and Zamazenta
might lend us their help!
Okay!
Oh, come on...!
Go, hold on tight!
Hey! After them!
Sir!
M-Mr. Dande! You can’t go through here
without Chairman Rose’s permission!
Chairman Rose called me here.
Okay, I’ll confirm it with him,
so please wait outside the elevator.
Sorry, but I don’t have time.
Go?
Satoshi, where are you?
On the way to Lateral Town.
Sorry, we aren’t there anymore.
Huh?
Kairyu, stop!
Hey, Satoshi...
When we got split up
in the Slumbering Weald,
did you happen to meet
a strange Pokémon?
I did, I did!
How did you know that?
I saw one too.
It looked like this?
Yeah, just like that!
Their names are
Zacian and Zamazenta.
Zacian? Zamazenta?
Those Pokémon are linked with
the legend of the hero.
The legend of the hero?
Yeah.
The black vortex was Black Night,
a Pokémon.
And it was quelled by Zacian, Zamazenta
and two heroes.
At least, that’s our deduction.
Black Night... Two heroes?
And right now, Pokémon are
Daimaxing on their own and rampaging, yeah?
If our deduction is right,
that’s because of Black Night.
Which means it might’ve been
revived somewhere.
The way things are going,
Galar is headed for the brink of destruction again.
Quick! Stop the injection
of Galar particles!
We won’t make it in time!
What the...
It’s overloading!
What’s wrong?
There’s this red light...!
Where’s it coming from?
Uhh... Rotom, where is that?
Knuckle City.
Black Night might be there, then.
If Pokémon are exposed to that light,
they’ll start rampaging again!
I have to do something, Go!
Got it! I’ll go search for
Zacian and Zamazenta!
Let’s talk later!
Okay!
Kairyu, let’s go!
So this was the light that was
making Pokémon rampage?
If we don’t do something,
Mugendaina’s going to escape the hangar.
Mugendaina?
Contact Chairman Rose!
Understood.
I knew it.
It’s finally happening!
Hurry on out,
strongest and evilest Pokémon!
We’re gonna catch you, meow!
Yeah!
No way!
This is... Mugendaina?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
You still can’t get in touch
with Chairman Rose?!
What are you doing?!
It’s going to get out to the surface!
Mr. Dande?!
Why are you here?!
It doesn’t matter!
Don’t you have any way of stopping it?!
But... Anything related to Mugendaina,
we need to confirm with Chairman Rose...
Let’s go, Lizardon!
That was awful, meow.
What’s that?
We gotta get outta here, meow!
Hold it!
Our prey just came straight to us!
We’ll catch it here!
Yeah!
Team Rocket is on the scene!
Nyarth, do it!
You got it, meow!
Huh?
Nyarth?
That’s perfect!
Go catch that strongest and evilest Pokémon!
Nyarth?
Hey! What’d you do that for?!
Team Rocket?
What are you doing here?
The brat boy?!
Nyarth?
This weird light hit him
and he went crazy!
The strongest and evilest
Pokémon’s to blame!
Go do something about it!
He’s here!
It really... was in here...
Zacian! Zamazenta!
Show yourselves!
The fog!
It’s just like before.
Pokémon are involuntarily Daimaxing and
going on destructive rampages all over Galar once again!
Satoshi?
The red lights that trigger the rampages
are being fired out of Knuckle City Stadium–
That’s Black Night?
It really was revived!
We need to hurry and
find Zacian and Zamazenta.
Come on! Zacian! Zamazenta!
Black Night has been revived!
Galar is going to be wiped out
if we don’t do something! Please!
Come on out again!
Zacian... Zamazenta...?
You showed up!
Hold on!
We need your help!
They vanished...
Rabbifoot?!
I never knew this was here...
A sword and shield...
The sword and shield
from the legend?
Yeah, they must be.
That’s... Black Night?
Dodge it!
Kairyu!
Are you okay?
Have a rest.
Mr. Dande!
Satoshi!
That’s Black Night, isn’t it?
Correct!
The people who once feared it
named it so.
Chairman Rose!
But I lovingly renamed it
Mugendaina— “Infinite”!
After all, it’s a valuable Pokémon
which creates infinite energy.
The enormous power it’s displaying
is even beyond my expectations.
I never knew the audience safety barrier
could help in such a way.
Dande. We’ve often discussed
the future of Galar together.
Now’s not the time!
No, this is all for Galar’s future!
What do you mean?
I found that in the near future,
Galar’s energy will be exhausted.
I racked my brains on
how I could solve this issue,
and discovered Galar particles
could serve as a new energy source.
Galar particles?
Yes. And more than that...
I learned Mugendaina was the Pokémon of my dreams,
infinitely creating Galar particles!
But those beams cause Pokémon to
Daimax and go on rampages!
It’s very troubling.
That’s why I’ve guided
talented trainers like you.
Yes... You shall catch
the revived Mugendaina, and control it!
As I desire!
What’re you doing?
If the sword and shield
belong to Zacian and Zamazenta,
they may have some hidden powers.
I get it.
Maybe they can help us
stop Black Night.
Let’s hurry to Knuckle City!
Yes!
My father, he worked in the mines.
He worked day and night,
to extract the energy source
we once used,
and to support our family.
But after an unforeseen accident,
he never came back.
But what do you think?
As long as we have Mugendaina,
nobody will ever need
to suffer as I did,
and we’ll have infinite energy.
See...
I’m thinking of the Galar
a thousand years from now!
Dande...
I’ve watched over you and nurtured you
since you were young, all for this very moment.
You can’t turn me down now.
I’ll catch Mugendaina.
You’ll be a true hero of Galar!
But... only to calm it down.
It’s already caused immense damage!
I don’t want to witness
any further tragedies!
How naïve you are.
It looks like Mugendaina’s
full revival is near.
Go on, Dande! You’re up!
Even if it creates Galar particles,
Mugendaina is too dangerous!
I’ll catch it, and seal it away!
Satoshi, let’s go.
Right!
Stop!
You’ve disappointed me.
Daioudou! Power Whip!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Satoshi?
Mr. Dande,
please go catch Mugendaina!
Got it.
You intend to make all of my effort
be for naught?
I won’t let you cause any more
innocent Pokémon to rampage!
What insolence.
Nutrey!
Lend me your help, Riolu!
How long’s he gonna keep rampaging?!
Just go back to normal already!
We’re nearly at the stadium!
What do we do?
Times like these...
you gotta go straight through ‘em!
Get moving, Go!
But...
I’ll be fine.
Get in there and help Satoshi!
Right.
Rabbifoot, let’s go!
I’ll be your opponent.
You wanna be crushed?!
What’s all the noise?
I can’t let you trouble a beautiful lady.
Not on the home turf of the mighty Kibana,
Dragon-type Gym Leader.
Oh, it’s you.
That boy playing at solving riddles
with Magnolia’s granddaughter.
Something wrong with that?
This will not do at all.
I cannot have you
disturbing Chairman Rose.
I’m just here to stop Black Night
threatening Galar—
That’s disturbing him!
Black Night...
No, Mugendaina.
How much time and money do you think
Chairman Rose has spent to revive it?
So you were the ones
trying to catch us!
As his secretary,
Chairman Rose’s dream is also my dream.
And I won’t let anyone disturb him!
Rabbifoot, here we go!
Mugendaina was finally revived.
Will Satoshi and Go
be able to save Galar from this crisis?
To be continued!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’ll seal Mugendaina away for sure!
Pikachu! Riolu!
Let’s hurry and catch up to Satoshi!
Go! Satoshi!
For all the humans
and Pokémon of Galar...
...we’ll protect them!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Sword and Shield
Sword & Shield IV
"The Ultimate Sword and Shield"
“The Ultimate Sword and Shield”