Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Oh, Koharu!
This is where they hold
the Pokémon Circus.
Wow!
It’s the very image of a circus!
Yeah. Ready to go, then?
I’m feeling nervous...
This circus hosts very popular, spectacular performances
featuring Pokémon and their partners.
Satoshi and Go were chosen by lottery
to be guest stars in a circus show today.
Hello!
They’re so high up!
Wow!
It’s an Eevee!
Now!
Nice jump, Karen!
Let’s go!
Come on!
Whoa!
That was amazing, right, Eevee?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Pokémon Circus!
Booster and Thunders!!
Circuses are enchanting!
Welcome, on your fleeting visit
to a world of dreams!
You are Satoshi and Go,
correct?
Huh? Expedition leader?
No, it’s the president from
the Fossil Museum!
Non, non!
I am the ringleader of this circus!
Call me “Ringleader!”
Nice to meet you!
N-Nice to meet you...
How was it
watching them rehearse?
It got me really pumped!
It was thrilling!
Yes, yes.
Thrills and chills
are what make circuses...
...enchanting!
Um...
My name is Koharu.
I’m a friend of Satoshi and Go’s.
May I watch the rehearsals, too?
Of course!
I read the circus was going to star
Thunders and Booster,
and I was hoping I might
get to meet them.
What a happy coincidence!
You see, those two Eevee
are just about ready to evolve.
Allow me to introduce you!
These are Honoka and Billy,
members of my circus.
They’ll be the final act of the circus,
the flying trapeze.
Nice to meet you!
My name’s Honoka!
A performer who loves
Fire types!
She’s my partner, Karen.
I’m Billy.
A performer who loves nothing more
than Electric types.
This is my partner, Rhyme.
Fire-type acts are cool, and get you fired up!
Nothing’s more popular!
Fire types are past their prime.
Electric types are
the future number one.
The two of them are always going at it
over which of them is the top star.
So they’re rivals?!
That’s why sparks are flying
between them...
You two, will you let Koharu here
watch you evolve your Eevee?
Course! No problem!
I just got the evolution stone
I needed for this show, after all.
The evolution stone I asked my friend
to get me just arrived, too!
I’ll evolve Eevee into Booster
with this Fire Stone,
and put on an even more
powerful show!
I’ll evolve my Eevee into Thunders
with this Thunder Stone,
and put together a show
like nothing you’ve ever seen!
Hey! I’m going first,
so don’t you go butting in!
You’re the one in my way!
I’ll go first!
I’m going first!
No, I am!
What’s wrong with you?
What’s the problem?
Okay, Karen!
Here goes, Rhyme!
N-No way...?!
Thunders! Lightning Pokémon!
Electric type!
They send out electrical charges
of about 10,000 volts!
Because they are high-strung,
it can be difficult to grow close to them!
Booster! Fire Pokémon!
Fire type!
It stores some of the air it inhales in its internal flame pouch,
which heats it to 1,700 degrees!
My Karen... turned into
the Electric-type Thunders...
My Rhyme... became
the Fire type, Booster?
Y-You have to be kidding me!
What am I gonna do now?!
This is your fault, you know!
You kidding me?! You did this!
Let’s try again
with the spare stone...
Once over, from the top!
It’s not working?! How come?!
No way! This can’t be real!
What do I do now?!
Now what do I do?!
Pull yourselves together!
But we can’t do the
flying trapeze of fire like this!
I’d been planning an
Electric performance, too!
Hmm...
If you can’t do the act,
that is troubling...
Oh, I know!
We don’t have much time
until the show,
so why don’t you
swap your Pokémon?
What?!
Swapping their partners?!
Think about
how the Pokémon’ll feel!
If it’s just for this show,
then so be it.
We’re professional performers,
after all.
The show must go on.
We have to give it a try.
Hmph!
Are they gonna be okay?
Who knows...
I must apologize
for all this arguing.
Now, let’s get you practicing!
Right!
Let’s see,
the two of you could...
Pikachu!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Sarunori! Branch Jab!
That looks hard...
No, no! Start over!
It’s 3, 2, 1, jump!
Are you listening? Rhyme!
Really...
You have to concentrate!
Karen, you’ve gotta use Thunder Shock
when I give the signal.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
This is useless.
She won’t listen to a word I say.
We can’t rehearse anything like this.
Even when you evolve,
you’d want to stay by your partner’s side...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Thunders
Electric
Fire team, assemble!
Everyone, use Ember!
Wha—?
Karen...
Why are you here?
What’s wrong?
Shouldn’t you be rehearsing
with Billy?
Come on! Thunder Shock!
What?
If it isn’t Rhyme...
What’s up?
Aren’t you supposed to be
rehearsing with Honoka?
Hmm... Is that so...?
So Karen and Rhyme aren’t
accepting the partner swap?
Right.
Hey, Karen...
I’ll be putting on
a Fire performance.
Please be understanding...
Rhyme...
I’m doing an
Electric performance here.
Okay, I’ve got it.
I don’t know if this will work,
but try rehearsing with
your original partners.
It’s bound to be enchanting!
I understand.
I’ll give it a try.
Hello!
We hope you’ll look after us
again today!
Oh, welcome!
Huh?
Ms. Honoka has Karen
with her, not Rhyme...
You’re right.
I decided they should practice with
their original partners, after all.
But, you see...
Now!
Electricity is pretty too,
but well...
Come on!
Fire is impressive too, but...
It’s not going very well.
If they can’t work something out,
we might have to cancel the flying trapeze...
Whaa?!
Cancel it right before
the show?!
There’s no other option.
I wouldn’t be satisfied, either,
if I had to put on a half-baked performance.
I’m sorry.
None of this is your fault.
I’m going to take a break.
Ringleader.
I couldn’t help hearing...
Right...
With the way things are going...
That might be the only choice.
This isn’t your fault.
Sorry, I need a moment...
Eevee!
Where could they have gone?
Are they training?
Of course...
Huh?
They want to work together
to put on the show.
I wonder...
Does Eevee want to perform with them, too?
Looks like it.
That’s a great idea!
Hey! Let us join in too!
Let’s practice together!
Aw.
A certain somebody
just had to ruin everything.
That’s my line.
If only my Rhyme
had become a Thunders...
Same for Karen!
If only she evolved into Booster...
Excuse me!
Could you come with me?
There’s something
I’d like to show you.
Let’s go!
Now, it’s my turn!
Come on!
Karen...
Rhyme...
We’re not done yet!
Here we go!
Awesome!
Rhyme...
Karen...
What’s going on?
Why are you
practicing together?
I think they’re doing it
for their partners.
They want to be able to
perform for you,
so they’re working together,
and practicing as hard as they can.
Won’t you think of them, too,
and figure out a way
to keep the act in?
Karen... Thank you!
You too, Rhyme... Thank you.
These two are working so hard...
...that we need to turn over
a new leaf, too!
Let’s work together...
...and put on a great show!
Now, our special guests today,
Satoshi and Pikachu,
Go and Sarunori...
...make a sparkling entrance!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Sarunori, go! Branch Jab!
We’ve got this, yeah!
All right!
Pikachu!
The four of them were marvelous!
Now, for the finale,
we have Honoka and Thunders,
and Billy and Booster,
with their enchanting
flying trapeze act!
And helping them out today,
we have Koharu and Eevee!
Here goes!
Rhyme!
Karen!
Beautiful!
Amazing!
Eevee, if you please!
That was incredible!
Bravo!
Yes, yes!
Enchanting...
Wasn’t that fun?
I wanna see it again!
The show was a great success.
We had loads of fun!
Thank you very much!
Sorry for having you join us
on short notice, Koharu.
But the flying trapeze act
went wonderfully, thanks to you.
Yeah.
Don’t worry.
I’m glad I got to perform!
I think Eevee enjoyed it, too!
It’s not much,
but as a token of our gratitude...
...we want you to have these.
Huh?
Are those...?!
This is a Fire Stone...
...and this is a Thunder Stone.
Use them when it’s time
to evolve your Eevee.
Thank you!
And by all means,
make her a Thunders!
Electric types can be
surprisingly cool.
I can recommend you
Booster, too.
Fire types are amazing,
as well.
Huh?
Something strange?
Our horizons have been broadened,
thanks to you.
I wonder what Koharu’s Eevee’s
gonna evolve into!
I can’t wait to see!
Eevee...
Whatever you evolve into,
let’s always stay together!
Koharu has learned of another kind of relationship
between Pokémon and Trainer.
What kind of future could lie in store
for Koharu and Eevee?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Championships!
My next battle’s in Galar!
They’re rehearsing right now.
Nobody may enter.
Huh? Wasn’t this supposed
to be a Gym?
I got skin in this game
too, y’know!
I ain’t about to be goin’ down!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Mary from Spike Town!