The world’s biggest and greatest
Pokémon battle festival to crown the world’s strongest...
...is finally here.
That is... the Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
Shoot Stadium, Galar Region
Satoshi and Pikachu have arrived
at the place these fateful battles will be held.
There he is!
You’re Satoshi from Kanto, right?
Huh? Yeah, why?
I request a battle from you!
Right here and now!
C’mon, battle me!
Do you think he knows
you’re one of the Masters Eight?
I can hear you.
Of course I already knew that.
I’m going to test your strength!
Sure, you’re on!
Sell me on a battle and you know I’m buying!
It’s go time, Pikachu!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Curtain Rises!
The Masters Tournament!!
Wooloo! Sheep Pokémon!
Normal type!
Its curly fleece
is a very effective cushion!
It could fall off a cliff
and be unharmed!
Wooloo, huh?
It probably has good defenses.
Move in, Wooloo!
Use Double Kick!
Iron Tail!
Wooloo!
Huh?
That was it?
That attack...
You really are strong!
I see why my bro
has his eyes on you!
Huh? Your bro?
Yeah! I’m Hop!
Dande’s little brother!
Mr. Dande’s?!
Little brother?!
Mr. Dande talks about me?!
Don’t know why,
but that makes me so happy!
But let me warn you!
I’ll be the one
to take down my bro!
Until then,
he’ll never lose to anyone!
Okay, we’re on!
Wha-bam Z!
As always, your hosts are
Princess Number Thirteen!
Dolled-Up Blue Hair!
And Charm Head Deluxe, meow!
Today, we’re not in the studio, but broadcasting live
from the Pokémon World Championships!
Look at all this!
Everyone’s super excited!
Shoot Stadium
is packed full of crowds!
You just know it’s a festival
with tons of strong Pokémon, meow!
We’ll be showcasing them
one after another, so stay tuned!
...and “showcasing them”
is our cover story, meow.
We can’t pass up
so many strong Pokémon.
We’ll catch them all
in one fell swoop!
Cutting it close, Satoshi!
Oh! Iris!
We both made it
to the Masters Eight!
Yeah! I’ve been looking forward
to seeing you today!
Same here!
I’ve made it this far...
I’m gonna win!
Now, Shoot Stadium
is crammed full with spectators.
You can already hear cheers
in anticipation of the heated battles.
Hey!
Hi.
Can I sit with you?
We could watch together!
Yeah, that’s fine!
I’m Go.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah! Let’s make some noise!
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The biggest tournament in history,
where the highest-ranked eight, the Masters Eight,
determine the greatest Pokémon battler.
And so, which of them
will be crowned...
...Championships Monarch?!
Now, let’s introduce the Masters Eight.
First, ranked eighth...
The shining first Champion
of the Alola Region’s first-ever League.
Hailing from Masara Town in Kanto,
Competitor Satoshi!
All right!
Let’s do this!
Satoshi!
Ranked seventh...
Aiming to be a Dragon Master,
and still growing ever stronger.
The young Champion of Isshu,
Competitor Iris!
Iris!
I’m cheering for you, too!
Wait, you know Iris too?
Everyone! Thank you!
Ranked sixth...
An adventurer renowned
for excavating Mega Stones.
The winner of the Kalos League
Miare Tournament,
Competitor Alain!
Ranked fifth...
A world-renowned actress
enters the stage.
Just as skilled in battle as on camera,
she is the Champion of Kalos,
Competitor Carne!
Ranked fourth...
The new Champion
of Kanto and Johto.
One of the Pokémon G-Men
fighting evil far and near.
Competitor Wataru!
Ranked third...
The heir to Hoenn’s Devon Corporation
and Champion of Hoenn,
Competitor Daigo!
Ranked second...
The authority on Pokémon archaeology
and Champion of Sinnoh,
Competitor Shirona!
And ranked first...
The Champion of Galar, and the reigning Monarch of the Pokémon World Championships,
The world’s strongest...
The unbeaten...
Competitor Dande!
Big Bro!
I’m so happy
to see this in person!
What a miraculous moment, to see these eight,
Champions from far and wide, gathered in one place.
This is the true thrill
of the Pokémon World Championships.
In the Masters Tournament, even the undefeated Monarch, Competitor Champion Dande,
will be starting from the first round,
on equal footing with the other seven here.
Competitor Dande,
could you give us a few words!
Bring it on!
Me and my Pokémon
will take down all comers!
And with that, it’s time to announce
the match-ups for the first round.
The first match:
Competitor Dande versus Competitor Alain!
Alain’s up against Mr. Dande...
The second match:
Competitor Wataru versus Competitor Carne!
The third match:
Competitor Shirona versus Competitor Iris!
Ahh, it’s Ms. Shirona...
Go easy on me, okay?
The fourth match...
Competitor Daigo versus Competitor Satoshi!
My first opponent is...
...Mr. Daigo.
So I finally get a chance
to battle you.
Those will be the match-ups
for the Masters Eight’s first round.
Man, doesn’t this
get you pumped up?!
Pumped, pumped!
I can’t wait to see
what Pokémon they’ll use, meow!
Where’s Satoshi?
Oh, Satoshi said
he’d watch it with Go.
He said he wanted to feel
the heat of the stadium up close.
That’s just like Satoshi.
You’re not going to join him?
Oh, um... Actually, I had something
I wanted to ask you two...
Could I take a photo with you?!
So that’s why you stayed.
Of course!
It sounds like
you know that Alain well.
As the stones guide me.
Yet, to face Dande right away...
I hope he doesn’t get overwhelmed.
Okay, say cheese!
Now, the first match of the first round...
The competitors are entering the stadium.
Watching from the stands is the best!
Yeah!
Competitor Alain even works as
an assistant to Kalos’s Professor Platane.
I bet that the Professor
will be watching this battle from Kalos.
The regulations today: you may each use
three Pokémon in the first round!
There is no limit on match length
or switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all three of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, you are allowed a single use of only one
of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolution.
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Come out, Gorillander!
Come out, Brigarron!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Brigarron! Spiny Armor Pokémon!
Grass/Fighting type!
When it takes a defensive posture
with its fists guarding its face,
it can withstand any impact!
So it’s a battle between Grass types...
Everyone watching the stream...
The battles are finally starting, meow!
That trainer with the fluffy neck thing...
I’ve seen him somewhere before.
The first match in the first round is a showdown between Dande and Alain, meow!
Better check out his Pokémon, too...
Let the battle begin!
Now, it’s Champion time!
Arm Hammer!
A fierce Arm Hammer!
But Gorillander endures it!
What?!
Already?!
Now that’s what I want to see!
Kyodai... max!
Here it is!
Competitor Dande’s Kyodaimax!
I’m not a drum!
Come on,
follow my bro’s beat!
Brigarron!
Brace for attack!
It’s one of the duties of a Champion
to get the crowd fired up!
Kyodai Drum Bash!
Needle Guard!
Even Needle Guard won’t be enough
to completely block Daimax attacks.
But I can withstand them.
That’s what Brigarron is here for!
How about this one, then?
Dai Jet!
Gyro Ball!
Brigarron shrugs off the Dai Jet...
...and hits with Gyro Ball!
All right!
That was good.
Amazing!
He’s doing well,
considering his opponent.
He mustn’t let his guard down.
Dai Jet will have raised
Gorillander’s speed.
Needle Missile!
Dai Earth!
And that’s the end
for Gorillander’s Kyodaimax!
Gyro Ball!
Acrobatics!
Brigarron!
Magnificent Acrobatics!
His aerial attack landed!
Brigarron is unable to battle!
Competitor Alain
has lost his first Pokémon!
Good job, Big Bro!
Mr. Dande beat him at
Grass against Grass, huh?
That was an incredibly fast attack...
So Dande was a step ahead.
Yes. For it to know Acrobatics...
You did well. Take a rest.
Come out, Lizardon!
His second Pokémon is Lizardon!
We’ve battled Alain’s Lizardon
lots of times before.
Huh...
You’ve got a good glare.
I’ll make you show me
how strong you are.
Drum Attack!
Flare Drive!
It’s super effective!
Gorillander is unable to battle!
Lizardon takes down Gorillander!
Now they’re even!
Good work, Lizardon!
Bro...
Well, well...
It’s not looking so sure now...
Yeah!
Gorillander... That was marvelous.
You’re strong!
My second Pokémon...
Come out!
That’s it! My bro’s ace!
Competitor Dande’s strongest partner,
Lizardon, has arrived!
Dragon Claw!
Air Slash!
So, I can’t get close enough...
Well, in that case...
Return, Lizardon!
Oh, Competitor Alain
is switching Pokémon!
Come out, Calamanero!
Your powers will turn
the tide of the battle!
Competitor Alain’s third Pokémon
is Calamanero.
Calamanero! Turnaround Pokémon!
Evil/Psychic type!
Gazing at its luminescent spots
will quickly induce a hypnotic state,
putting the observer
under Calamanero’s control!
Psycho Cutter!
Great Blaze!
Rush in! Use Hell Thrust!
Air Slash!
Great Blaze!
Calamanero is unable to battle!
Competitor Alain
has lost his second Pokémon!
I couldn’t give you
a chance to shine. I’m sorry.
He’s strong...
The pendulum’s swung
all the way in Mr. Dande’s favor.
Head forth, Lizardon!
I will keep going with Lizardon!
It was my dream
to battle against your Lizardon.
And to surpass it!
Heed my heart’s call,
Key Stone!
Transcend evolution...
Mega Evolve!
Yes! Mega Lizardon X!
Dragon Claw!
Ancient Power!
Flare Drive!
Dragon Pulse!
Dragon Pulse is super effective!
Competitor Alain’s Lizardon is unable to battle!
Competitor Dande’s Lizardon wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Dande!
The first match
of the first round has concluded.
Competitor Dande
advances to the semifinals!
That was an awesome battle!
Mr. Dande’s so strong...
Big Bro! Lizardon!
Competitor Alain was forced into a tough battle
by Competitor Dande’s skillful attacks,
but he put up a great fight!
You fought well.
Hey! Hey!
Wasn’t that battle amazing?!
Look forward to the next match!
The second match is—
I’m tired.
Break time.
Don’t fall asleep, meow!
Keep working! Work!
This is hopeless.
I’ll retrain myself,
and then I’ll be back.
Right. I’ll be waiting!
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament...
...has begun with a victory for Dande.
And the next match is between...
Now, then...
Please, don’t hold back
on my account.
I would ask the same.
...the Dragon Tamer Wataru,
known throughout Kanto and Johto...
...and the Champion of Kalos, Carne.
Whoever wins battles Mr. Dande!
Yeah!
Which of the two will emerge victorious in the
second match?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament!
It’s the best, meow!
The second match is between
Competitors Wataru and Carhrhrhr!
What did you just say?
Competitor Carhrhrhr!
That’s the star actress,
Carne, meow!
Humph! Never heard of her!
Guess she’ll just have to show us
how a “star actress” battles, then!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Champions’ Pride!
Wataru VS Carne!!
The Champions' Pride!
Let’s all tune in, meow!