Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
My next opponent’s been decided!
Satoshi has climbed his way
to 64th place in the Hyper Class.
His next opponent was none other than
the Galar Gym Leader, Saito.
He had battled Saito twice before,
in the Super Class.
Aqua Break!
Riolu!
Losing the first match...
Go!
...and drawing the second match.
Now, their third showdown
has arrived.
The decisive battle will take place
on Saito’s home turf,
in Galar’s Lateral Stadium.
Satoshi and Go have come to see the arena,
to prepare for tomorrow’s battle.
Lateral Stadium, Galar Region
Ms. Saito...
Halt!
I have not heard from you in some time,
trainer of Riolu.
No, my name’s Satoshi!
And it’s not a Riolu anymore!
So it has evolved.
Trainer of Lucario, then.
...Of course.
Oh, right!
Come on out, everyone!
These are my friends.
These six here are my Pokémon.
Six Pokémon each...
So you’ve both seen each other’s hand.
We should train together.
How about it?
Oh... Sorry.
We’re supposed to
be meeting Corni here.
Corni!
Satoshi...
What if Corni and Ms. Saito...?
She is rather soft,
don’t you think?
What’s that supposed to mean?
There is no need
for me to say more.
Ms. Saito did say that about her...
Corni said she wanted to see your battle,
but maybe she really intended...
Corni!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Rival Showdown!
Satoshi VS Saito!!
Corni!
Saito...
...kins!
Saito... kins?
I’m so, so sorry!
They were all sold out
of the Miare Galettes you love!
So... I brought my latest obsession.
Please forgive me!
Oh, was that all?
You’re not mad?
That was quite thoughtful of you.
Let’s have some together.
What a relief!
Hey, weren’t you here
to meet them?
Oh, hiya, Satoshi!
Hiya...
Hey, Lucario!
Now’s not the time for battling...
Thanks, Corni.
They all look delighted.
I can’t just bring treats from Kalos
without bringing some Pofflé!
And these are my current obsession...
Kunoe Chocolat!
They look great.
Here, you guys try them, too.
I’ll have one!
Me, too!
Time to eat!
Delicious!
It melts in your mouth...
I could keep eating these forever...
We never would’ve thought
you two were friends.
What? Why not?
The first time we battled, Ms. Saito
said you were “rather soft.”
“She is rather soft,
don’t you think?”
With this strict look.
Saitokins is such a sourpuss.
She says battles are to be enjoyed.
But I do not share that sentiment.
See?
But I don’t mind that side of her.
She’s kind to her Pokémon,
and she’s an expert martial artist...
There’s so much I could learn from her.
I could say the same about you, Corni.
I love the way you show me
all these tasty sweets!
Wha... The sweets?
I really enjoyed the Kunoe Chocolat.
Hey, this is going to be
the third time you battle, right?
Yeah! I’m looking forward
to our battle, too!
I see this as a trial.
A trial...?
Trainer of Lucario, who has
crossed my path three times...
Tomorrow, I believe I’ll find out
what you’re here to show me.
Yeah. Let’s have a good fight!
Yes.
This is gonna be great!
A showdown between rivals...
I can’t wait!
Can’t tomorrow be here any sooner?
I’ll be cheering you on
with everything I’ve got!
Cheering for who exactly,
me or Ms. Saito?
Both of ya!
This is gonna get tiring...
Ms. Saito was really
fired up back there.
I wonder what Pokémon she’ll pick...
Whoever she picks, I’m gonna win!
Give it all you’ve got, Satoshi!
Yeah! Thanks for the support, Go.
The Pokémon World Championships
Hyper Class.
Striving to be the world’s strongest Pokémon Trainer,
here we have today’s contenders!
Ranked 30th, a Galar native,
Competitor Saito.
Equipped with her Daimax Band,
as always!
Saitokins!
So she’ll be using Daimax...
Of course! Lateral Stadium’s
a Daimax Power Spot.
And when Saitokins uses Daimax,
it’s a real sight to behold!
And the trainer who,
in a recent Hyper Class match,
took down Sinnoh’s Competitor Denji
with an astounding Z-Move...
The one everyone has their eyes on,
Competitor Satoshi from Kanto,
currently ranked 64th!
Satoshi!
Go for it!
And what’s this?
The gleaming stone on
Competitor Satoshi’s left hand is a Key Stone.
He’s picked Mega Evolution
over Z-Moves, then.
Note that in this tournament, you are allowed
one use of either Daimax, Mega Evolution, or a Z-Move.
Mega Evolution...
Daimax, huh...?
Today’s battle is a 3v3.
Mega Evolution and Daimax...
When are they gonna use them?
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3! 2! 1!
Go!
Pikachu... I choose you!
Otosupus!
Battle, start!
Lightning Speed!
Detect!
Electroweb!
All right, it’s trapped!
Straight for the attack!
So he managed to get
the first hit on Saitokins...
The Lightning Speed was just a feint
for the Electroweb.
It had to be!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Infight!
What?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pikachu!
An unexpected Infight!
Completely ignoring the Electroweb,
Otosupus’s display of toughness leaves the crowd gasping!
The Electroweb...
Nothing fazes that Otosupus.
You okay, Pikachu?
Come back for now!
Go, Lucario!
Even before it evolved,
it fought Otosupus to a draw
the last time.
So this is their fateful showdown?
Lucario! This time we’re gonna
beat that Otosupus!
Aqua Break!
Shadow Clones!
Satoshi’s wary of
a close-range battle.
I can see why he’d be wary
when Otosupus has Octolock.
Spin, Otosupus!
The Shadow Clones vanish!
Otosupus used the water spray
from Aqua Break to full effect!
But where’s the real Lucario?!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Detect!
Return, Otosupus!
Holding off the end for later, huh...?
Oh, they’re just barely getting started.
That was just checking each other out, no?
Go...
Luchabull!
Luchabull next, huh?
Competitor Saito’s second pick
is Luchabull.
What kind of battle will it show us?!
Lucario, rush in!
High Jump Kick!
The High Jump Kick hits!
Wing Attack!
Lucario!
Knock back its attacks!
A marvelous exchange of blows!
Their speed and power
are evenly matched!
Go!
God Bird!
Force Palm!
Lucario!
God Bird lands a spectacular blow!
It must’ve felt that!
She really isn’t giving me
any chance to attack...
That Luchabull’s
even faster than last time.
Well, that’s Saitokins for you.
Better today than yesterday,
better tomorrow than today...
She’s constantly leveling up.
The same goes for Satoshi!
All right, you can keep going!
Lucario stands back up!
What incredible toughness!
Come back, Luchabull.
Go...
Kairiky!
Competitor Saito’s
third pick is Kairiky!
And it arrives with an
oppressive show of determination!
Kairiky, huh?!
Kairiky! Superstrength Pokémon!
Fighting type!
With four arms that react more quickly than it can think,
it can execute many punches at once!
Saitokins is really staying
on the offensive today.
She’s already sent out
her true ace!
Her true ace?!
Of course...
The Daimax Band!
Bullet Punch!
Force Palm!
A fierce assault by Kairiky!
Rush in again!
Force Palm!
Bullet Punch!
Kairiky uses its four arms
to deliver blow after blow!
This is nothing...
This is nowhere near Kairiky’s full strength.
Kairiky immobilizes Lucario!
Cross Chop!
Kairiky is truly fearsome!
Does Lucario not stand a chance?!
Bullet Punch!
Lucario!
What will you do now?
Lucario! Competitor Satoshi!
So strong...
I’d better...
Huh?
What’s this?
Competitor Satoshi brandishes his Mega Glove.
He’s trying to escape his bind
by Mega Evolving?!
Lucario, let’s go!
It doesn’t want to Mega Evolve?
You think so, too?
Yeah...
Right, Lucario?
Lucario manages
an amazing escape all by itself!
Lucario...
Lucario’s strong will
suppressed the light from the Key Stone...
That can happen...?
I got it, Lucario.
Competitor Satoshi and Lucario
seem to have fallen apart.
I lost my temper...
I panicked and wasn’t thinking ahead.
Pokémon and trainer on equal footing...
The ideal I aspire to.
Mega Evolution failed to activate!
Was your bond not deep enough,
Competitor Satoshi?!
Far from “not deep enough,”
their bond was perhaps too deep.
That’s why this happened.
Champion!
I was getting worried!
Sorry for being late.
Man, I really got lost out there...
What?
What’s going on?
Whaa?! Mr. Dande?!
No way! The Champion?!
Mr. Dande!
Their deep bond means
it’ll happen precisely when it’s necessary.
That is Mega Evolution.
But now was not the time.
The Lucario knew,
and stopped its trainer.
Can’t you feel how close they are?!
Starting now,
I’ll be joined by today’s special guest,
the Pokémon World Championships
Monarch, Mr. Dande.
Mr. Dande is watching...
I’m gonna be the one
who battles him!
No, it will be me!
Now, the battle resumes!
Superstrength!
Reversal!
The Monarch, Dande, has arrived.
With the trainer they seek
watching over them...
Who will win, Satoshi or Saito?!
Next time, their battle will get
even more heated!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
This is bad, Satoshi!
Mr. Dande’s here and watching!
Yeah...
So I can’t lose this!
Fine then,
let’s just destroy everything!
Your skill is worthy of respect—
and Kyodaimaxing!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Mega Evolution Versus Kyodaimax