Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
It’s gone!
Gone, gone, g-gone...
The cake I was saving is gone!
My snacks are gone too, meow.
Did that thing
hork our stuff down again...?!
Well, I hid mine somewhere
completely safe.
Huh?
N-No way...!
B-By all means,
go ahead and keep eating...
If you like it,
we’re happy, meow.
We can buy more
if you need more...
It’s been eating even more
than usual lately, meow...
All the money from our part-time jobs
goes to feeding Morpeko...
We can’t do our part as
Team Rocket members with this going on!
Why’d that thing
settle down here, anyway?!
It’s not like I have any idea...
Better to just catch it
so it listens to us, meow.
No way!
All that worthless thing does is eat!
Hold on...
We never actually caught it, so...
So?
It goes back to the wild.
Huh?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Please!
Catch Morpeko!!
Kojiro has headed to the mountains
with Morpeko.
How will he return it to the wild?
Why do I have to...?
Oh, it’s nothing.
What am I going to do?
That’s for me? Are you sure?
It’s actually pretty cute
when it’s not hungry...
It’s good!
So that’s why they smell so nice.
Keep going, keep going...
Is it gone?
Okay!
I-It’s nothing...
Th-Thank you...
What should I do...?
Y-You wouldn’t...
I’ll take everything you’ve got!
Everything?!
Tasty, aren’t they?
Good to hear it.
You can take your time
and enjoy them.
Stay strong out there...!
Farewell, Morpeko...
Now we can finally eat in peace!
Was it a good idea to let Kojiro
handle it on his own though, meow?
I’m back!
Oh, good to see you.
You made sure it went back
to the wild, meow?
Of course!
Hah... What a relief. Now...
Why is that here?!
I did what you asked...!
Those are our snacks!
It really followed us...
It’s asking us “Food?”
We wouldn’t be out shopping right now
if you hadn’t eaten it all...
How are we getting rid of it?
Monster Ball, go!
It’s the brat boys, meow.
Ratta’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
I caught a Ratta!
Great work, Go!
Ratta! Mouse Pokémon!
Normal type!
A surprisingly violent Pokémon!
With its long fangs, it can gnaw away
even thick concrete with ease!
Look at how carefree they are,
when we’re suffering so much...
Oh, I know!
We can stick them
with Morpeko—
No, no...
Have them catch Morpeko!
That’s it!
Nice idea!
With that decided,
let’s get right to it.
Operation: “Have Them Catch Morpeko”
is a go, meow!
Morpeko, you wait here, meow.
They won’t be able to resist
trying to catch Morpeko.
How about going that way next?
Yeah! Hope we get to see
some new Pokémon!
I’ve already caught most of the Pokémon
around here, so I’m not so sure...
Why did you come up here?!
I told you to stay there, meow...
Just settle down, okay?
The brat boys are gonna get away...
It tastes great!
See?
Here, you can eat this.
Just do it quietly.
The brat boys are here, meow!
You better catch it this time!
Oh, a Pidgeon!
Huh? Where?
Over there!
Wait for me!
Come on...
I almost had that Pidgeon...
Really stinks.
You there.
Huh, me?
I see in you a sign that you will meet
your fated Pokémon.
My fated Pokémon?!
Do you mean Mew?!
I see it!
Your fated Pokémon is...
My fated Pokémon is...?
There!
It’s a Pidgeon!
Umm...
No! This way, this way!
Thanks, old lady!
Wha—?! Old lady?!
H-Hey, wait, this way,
this way, this way...!
How come the brat boys
never notice it...?
Please hurry up and catch it, meow...
They’ve had really bad timing...
Here’s your delivery
of Pokémon foods!
Thank you!
Huh? Where’s Morpeko?
Over there, meow.
Morpeko!
Stop!
They don’t need to stop.
This works, meow.
Oh, of course.
Take care of yourself!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pidgeon
Flying
Normal
We’re back!
Welcome back, Satoshi, Go.
How’d it go?
I caught a Ratta!
One step closer to Mew, yeah?
But still no luck with Pidgeon.
Just wait until next time!
I reckon the Pokémon
should be hungry by now.
Oh, right! Satoshi, let’s go!
Yeah!
The new Pokémon foods came in,
so I left them in the usual place.
Got it!
Thanks for waiting, guys!
Time to eat!
I’ll get everything ready now.
A Morpeko?!
Morpeko! Two-Sided Pokémon!
Electric/Evil type!
Constantly hungry!
As it eats the seeds stored up in its pocket-like pouches,
it generates electricity!
When hungry, a hormonal change
makes it turn violent!
Don’t worry, Lucario, Aceburn.
It must’ve wandered into the box
somewhere along the way.
Hey, calm down!
Okay then...
Neither of them is
giving an inch...
Yokubarisu, Morpeko,
there’s still plenty more!
Raichu knew just what to do!
All right, while it’s distracted...
Monster Ball, go!
I lost to its appetite...
Just wait ‘til it calms down,
then you can catch it!
Raichu,
can you take this to Jimeleon?
They might get along
better than I thought!
Morpeko...
I hope you’re not hungry out there...
Hey, you listening?
That pest of a Pokémon
is gone now.
Time to get back to work!
Our plan for tomorrow is to catch as many Pokémon
as we can here in this shopping mall, meow.
Right.
It really has a big appetite...
It already ate so much
yesterday...
Well, a big appetite’s
a good thing!
You can say that again!
All right, today I’m gonna
catch a Pidgeon!
Yeah!
Where should we go today?
Good question...
I lost track of that Pidgeon
around here...
I hope you find it.
Let’s go!
Right!
Keep it coming!
We’re in peak form!
What a haul, meow!
What are you doing?!
If you ask us “What are you doing?!”
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
Give those Pokémon back!
Fat chance!
We’re in peak form today!
So stay out of our way.
We’ve eaten well
for the first time in ages!
And we bought lots of
snacks too, meow!
No chance of them
disappearing meow!
I have no idea what
you’re talking about,
but you’re not
getting away with this!
Aceburn, go!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
You asked for it!
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
What’re we gonna get?
The Tiny Bird Pokémon,
Naty!
The Tiny Raccoon Pokémon,
Zigzaguma?!
These are kinda bland.
H-Hey, don’t stare at me...
Anyway, gonna have to make do!
Zigzaguma! Take Down!
Umm...
Pull yourself together...
Naty! Peck!
Are you okay, Aceburn?!
It’s actually working?
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Why is...?!
Why is...?
Morpeko?!
I have a bad feeling
about this, meow...
J-Just settle down... okay?
Aceburn!
Pikachu!
That was Stomping Tantrum!
It’s super effective on
both Pikachu and Aceburn, meow!
Good going,
just keep doing that!
Why?!
All that, just for this to happen, meow.
What an awful feeling!
What was that about?
No idea...
Go, look!
Monster Ball, go!
Pidgeon’s data will be
added to the Index!
I did it!
I caught a Pidgeon!
Great work!
Gah...
What’s wrong with that thing?!
We left behind all the snacks
we bought, meow...
But...
Just let it pass by.
Yeah, meow.
You went looking for us...?
Morpeko, we’re here!
Hey!
Kojiro, stop, meow!
Let’s stick together,
Morpeko.
You just had to catch it, meow...
Well, I guess it’s strong?
Let’s see if we can’t
find some use for it.
Now, let’s head back... Huh?
I knew it!
Team Rocket have gained
a new member, Morpeko.
Will it someday become
a valuable asset for them?
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’m the leader of
Project Mew, Hodaka.
Huh?
We will have you catch
an Alolan Kyukon in this area.
Mr. Tsurugi...
You can go ahead
and forget that name.
Kyukon!
We want to take you
back to your home!
So let us catch you!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Let's Go! Project Mew!!
Let’s Go! Project Mew!!