The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
At long last, Dande and Satoshi’s
finals battle has begun.
A fierce fight right out of the gate,
with Dande losing Inteleon and Satoshi losing Gänger.
They both have five Pokémon left.
Their battle continues to heat up!
Psycho Field on top of
the frozen ground, huh...?
Come on, Satoshi!
What Pokémon will you use next?
Negigaknight! I choose you!
A Fighting type?
Barrikohru is part Psychic type,
so the Fighting-type Negigaknight is at a disadvantage.
Satoshi! Negigaknight!
Go for it!
Negigaknight!
There’s something only you can do!
I’m counting on you!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Finals II - "Toyed With"
Consecutive Cut!
A ferocious assault from Negigaknight!
But Barrikohru also wields its staff masterfully!
Go, go, go!
Send it flying with that big leek!
Avenge Gänger, meow!
Consecutive Cut hits!
It’s super effective against Psychic types!
Brutal Swing!
Barrikohru! Catch it!
Wide Force!
This time, Negigaknight takes
a super effective hit!
Psycho Field and Wide Force
make for a terrifying combination!
You okay, Negigaknight?!
Good job holding out.
He has Negigaknight’s
chivalrous spirit to thank for that.
Triple Axel!
Wide Force!
Detect!
Go get your shield!
And he leaps!
Whoa!
A pole vault?
Then we’ll use...
Triple Axel!
Let’s make this work!
Consecutive Cut!
Here he comes, Barrikohru!
Cut...
...the field!
The Psycho Field energy...
...has vanished!
Great job, Negigaknight!
So that was your goal!
Because it was a Bug-type move,
it could destroy the Psychic-type move?
So moves aren’t just
for attacking Pokémon...
Right! This is how Satoshi battles.
Negigaknight, return!
I’ll finish this with you.
Watch out.
There’s no telling what he’s planning.
Let’s do it, Lucario!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
Competitor Satoshi follows his Kyodaimax
with Mega Evolution!
Guiding Waves!
I’m really feeling ‘em!
Wow...
You can feel Lucario’s determination!
Incredible Guiding Waves from Lucario!
Bullet Punch!
Triple Axel!
It dodged!
Even without Psycho Field,
the frozen field still gives Barrikohru the advantage!
Triple Axel hits!
Lucario!
Barrikohru!
Another Triple Axel!
Still going, huh?
Can’t underestimate Mega Evolution.
Lucario! Use the Guiding Waves!
Sense Barrikohru’s movements!
Hmm?
Charge up a Guiding Wave Sphere!
Very well!
Just try using your Guiding Waves to follow Barrikohru!
Triple Axel!
Now! Fire!
Mega Lucario counters!
It really could sense Barrikohru’s movements!
Barrikohru is unable to battle!
We did it, Lucario!
Competitor Dande
loses a second Pokémon.
A stellar performance, Barrikohru!
Return!
You’re quite something,
Satoshi, Lucario.
Well, that’s because
I believe in Lucario!
This one’s next!
Come out! Drapult!
Lucario! Shadow Clones!
Follow up with Bullet Punch!
Flamethrower!
Return, Lucario.
You’re up next, Uonoragon!
Ooh, it’s turned into a showdown
between Dragon types!
Dragon Dive!
Dragon Arrow!
Catch it!
The second
Dragon Arrow missile fails!
What?
I’ll take that back.
One more Dragon Arrow!
You okay, Uonoragon?!
What is happening
to Uonoragon?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
You okay, Uonoragon?!
What is happening
to Uonoragon?!
Uonoragon...
Uonoragon’s body is changing?!
What is going on?!
Forget it!
Let’s do this, Drapult!
The clash of Dragon moves must’ve awakened
some long-dormant power within Uonoragon.
I wonder how Satoshi
will make use of this metamorphosis.
100,000 Volts!
You didn’t get to
let it shine after all.
Finish it! Move in!
Uonoragon!
What?!
Okay!
What are those spikes?!
All right! It caught it!
Now, Uonoragon! Jaw Bite!
It bit on!
Uonoragon counters!
Drapult can’t get away!
What power...
It squeezes even tighter!
This is like Otosupus’s Octolock.
But, Satoshi, you shouldn’t
underestimate Drapult.
Dragon Tail!
Incredible!
Drapult’s tail stretched out!
Don’t let go! Ice Fang!
Kairyu!
There it goes! Sending a Pokémon flying
and forcing a swap to a reserve Pokémon!
That’s the effect of Dragon Tail!
Can that happen?!
And right when Uonoragon
had awakened, too!
Good going, Big Bro!
Drapult!
You’re facing another Dragon type!
Dragon Arrow!
Fly, Kairyu! Dragon Dance!
Kairyu speeds up with Dragon Dance!
But the Dragon Arrows
are locked on to their target!
Dragon Claw!
After them, Kairyu!
Dragon Tail!
Dragon Tail again!
This time,
it dragged out Mega Lucario!
Satoshi must be finding this hard.
Satoshi may have scored more wins,
but Competitor Dande’s
still setting the pace.
Don’t worry, Pikachu.
Lucario!
I’ll finish this with you!
Bullet Punch!
A swift assault from Lucario!
100,000 Volts!
Reversal!
Bullet Punch!
Lucario?!
Oh! Mega Lucario was paralysed!
Flamethrower!
Lucario is unable to battle!
Competitor Dande’s second win!
It’s a 4v4 now!
Good work, Drapult!
Return, Lucario.
You did well out there.
Mr. Dande really is strong...
He’s quick to close any gap...
Dande’s smile
shows he’s not worried.
Satoshi...
It’ll be fine.
He’s going to be fine.
That Drapult’s unbelievable!
Is the brat boy gonna be okay...?
Pull yourself together!
We’re here watching you!
What’s wrong, Satoshi?
My Drapult is still raring to go!
Competitor Dande taunts
Competitor Satoshi!
How will Competitor Satoshi
respond?
Kairyu! I choose you!
This time,
Competitor Satoshi sends out Kairyu.
Let’s go! Hurricane!
An intense Hurricane
buffets Drapult!
All right! It’s working!
Use a massive 100,000 Volts!
The 100,000 Volts
destroyed the Hurricane?!
What do you think?
It was simple!
Then...
Fly up high, Kairyu!
Dragon Arrow!
Dragon Meteor Shower!
Drapult, dodge them all!
The Dragon Arrows are shot down!
But Drapult closes in on Kairyu!
Kairyu, grab Drapult!
100,000 Volts!
Let’s go! Kairyu Meteor Shower!
Kairyu Meteor Shower?!
She made herself the meteor?!
Go, go!
Drapult is unable to battle!
Competitor Satoshi
struggled against Dragon Tail,
but he managed to pull out
a third win!
Now that shocked everyone!
His finishing blow was the Kairyu Meteor Shower
he invented right here!
Thank you, Kairyu!
Return, Drapult!
You were really cool out there.
Satoshi... You really are the best!
But have you noticed?
All your remaining Pokémon
are already worn out.
Come out, Gorillander!
A true seesaw struggle.
Satoshi faces Monarch Dande.
Their fierce fight
continues!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The back-and-forth continues
in the finals battle!
His Kyodaimax is finally here!
The sublime power of Kyodai Hellfire
engulfs the field!
Competitor Satoshi
starts feeling cornered!
Don’t worry!
Pikachu’ll work something out!
Go get him!
That’s our Pikachu!
That’s right!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Finals Three - “Supreme”
The Finals III - "Supreme"
Correction: “The Finals III,” meow.