Shoot City, Galar Region
This is Hotel Lond Rose,
where Satoshi and Go are staying.
It looks like
they’re both out right now.
Hmm?
Did they forget something?
Incoming call from Mr. Tsurugi!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
GO FOR DREAM!
Go's Road to Mew, His Dream!!
Incoming call from Mr. Tsurugi!
Incoming call from—
Please enter your password!
Wrong password!
Unlocked!
Opening album!
Should I look up information
about this Pokémon?!
Inteleon! Agent Pokémon! Water type!
The final evolution of Messon and Jimeleon!
Its signature move is Snipe Shot!
The water from its fingertips
is fired at Mach 3!
It picks out weak points
and hits them precisely!
Would you like to watch
a related video?!
This was back when Go’s Inteleon
was still just a Messon...
Oh, no!
Now! Delvil,
use Ember on them!
Poochyena! Shadow Ball!
What?!
Great going!
Messon’s really
looking up to Inteleon.
Getting stronger will take time.
So what do you think?
Would you like to train with me?
To become more like the Inteleon he admired,
Messon began training with Go.
Even after evolving into Jimeleon,
he kept on training in silence and solitude.
Then, one day, the Sakuragi Institute
had an intruder...
Something’s there!
A Kakuleon?!
It’ll get away with
the institute’s priceless data!
Jimeleon tried to catch
the fleeing Kakuleon, but...
Jimeleon!
Are you okay, Jimeleon?!
Don’t worry! I’ll protect you!
You evolved...?
Now you’ve gone and made me...
...run for it, shi!
Snipe Shot!
Wh-Wh-Wha...?!
Wild! This is wild!
Shi?
All right!
He evolved into Inteleon,
as if answering Go’s call.
He finally pulled off
the Snipe Shot he had admired.
And the case was solved.
Incoming call from Mr. Tsurugi!
Incoming call from—
This is your regular check-in
from Project Mew.
I’m only saying this once,
so listen care—
A message has arrived from Ms. Asahi!
Asahi here.
I think Tsurugi will have
told you already,
but I’m sending you extra material
for the Mew search mission.
Make sure to
commit it to memory.
Project Mew.
Its goal is to search for Mew,
a mythical Pokémon that holds the genes of all Pokémon,
and is thought to be ancestor to all Pokémon.
A select few will conduct a search under the direction
of Project Leader Professor Hodaka.
These are the five Chasers this time.
Tsurugi, Shigeru, Tokio, Go,
and me, Asahi.
Teamwork will be invaluable
in our search.
In this extra material,
I’ll share data about the Chasers with you,
so you can better understand them.
Go, Wulaosu!
First, Tsurugi.
He passed the previous round
of Trial Missions with the highest score.
He’s skilled at survival, and specializes
in fieldwork under harsh conditions.
He’s far from cooperative,
so relay any complaints to our mediator...
In other words, to me, Asahi.
Next, Shigeru.
He passed the current round
of Trial Missions with the highest score.
Even if my goal seems impossible,
I’ll press on ahead without giving up.
A researcher who travels
various regions to study Pokémon.
He has a wide and deep range of knowledge
on a variety of fields.
He exhibits a well-balanced style
which allows him to adapt to any situation.
His Pokémon are also well-trained,
and as a trainer he has achieved excellent tournament placements.
Next is Tokio.
He’s a trainer pursuing Celebi, another Pokémon
considered a myth, similar to Mew.
He’s well-versed in
Grass types and Psychic types.
I thought that if I track down
every Psychic type, including Mew,
that might lead me
to Celebi, someday.
His battle style specializes in support moves;
on defense and recovery.
Mew’s capabilities are completely unknown.
If a battle with Mew proves necessary,
we can count on him
to provide combat support for the team.
Lastly, Go.
He travels various regions as a research fellow
for the Sakuragi Institute,
and has caught
over one hundred Pokémon.
He’s one of the few trainers
to come into contact with Mew.
I want to know
so much more about Pokémon.
That’s why
I really want to see Mew again!
His investigative skills in finding
his target Pokémon...
...and his resourceful battle style
are his unique traits.
We expect surprising situations
to be a constant in the search for Mew.
We hope his analytical skills
and inventiveness will help us open a path to Mew.
Those are the five Chasers
who will attempt the search for Mew.
I’ll leave the strategy details
for another da—
Incoming call from Mr. Tsurugi!
Incom—
What did you hang up
out of nowhere for?
Hey!
Are you listening?
Is that Sarunori?
Don’t tell me you’re the one
who hung up on—
Afterschool Blaze Kick
Heyo!
A radio show for all you
potential future champions out there...
Afterschool Blaze Kick
starts now!
I’m your upperclassman, Narratah,
reciter of everyone’s dreams. Nice to meet you!
How’re you doing?
Enjoying your youth?
Got a Snipe Shot locked onto
winning the girl on your mind?
I bet you’re hesitating,
fearing she’ll Aqua Break your heart!
If you’re frozen stiff like Harden,
here’s a Blaze Kick to the rear!
There’s been a lot of new shows lately.
Our theme today is “childhood friends.”
Friends you’ve known
since childhood really are great.
First up is a message from
“The Port Town Flower Tender.”
“I’ve started listening to the radio lately,
thanks to my dad.
“If you read this out, it’ll be my first message read!”
Oh, thank you!
And thanks to your dad, too!
“My childhood friend
just loves Pokémon so much,
“and he’s so confident.
“He’s always going on saying
‘The future lies in my hands! I’ll catch Mew, for sure!’”
Ooh, big dreams are the best ones!
“He has a bit of a stubborn side,
and he even argues with his Pokémon.”
Huh...? Why does Hihidaruma
look so smug?
Hihidaruma provoked Hibunny
into trying to use Ember,
but it can’t really pull it off...
You should stop.
That’s enough.
Stop, Hibunny!
Your Lightning Speed and Double Kick
have gotten really strong.
It doesn’t matter if
you can’t use a Fire move.
Looks like Hibunny
doesn’t agree with you.
Well...
You can’t do
what you can’t do.
I told you, you don’t have...
Listen to me!
That’s just not good enough!
Ow!
Just accept that
there’s some things you can’t do!
Oh, what now?
Fine, then! Have it your way.
Hibunny!
What’s gotten into it?!
I tried so hard to bring out
Hibunny’s strength in battle.
Really?
Yeah!
Oh, I see.
But that battle was...
How do I put it?
You and Hibunny
weren’t really one.
“One”?
Yeah! Like how when Pikachu and I battle,
it’s like we merge into one being!
And then it’s like our chest
starts boiling and blazing up...
and we go all “Ba-Ba-Ba-Bang!”
I have no idea what you mean...
Then you’ve gotta stick
with Hibunny until you do get it!
Hibunny!
That was...
Hey, wait, Hibunny!
Hibunny!
There might be a Fire move
you can use.
Wanna try your Fire move?
Then stand in place
and use Lightning Speed!
Faster!
And then kick this!
This is our Ember!
“Putting the feelings of his Pokémon first,
they managed to pull off their very own Fire move!
“And with that move aiding him,
I hear he’s been on all these adventures.
“This one time, he even told me
how he challenged a legendary Pokémon.”
Oh, you can’t believe that!
“I plan to keep cheering him on,
until the day he finds Mew!”
Thanks for your message!
Seeing their growth from up close...
Now that’s a perk of being childhood friends!
You are enjoying your youth!
Well then, onto the next message.
Radio Name “A Timeless Bayleaf.”
Thanks again!
“Recently, I finally reunited with a friend
I lost contact with when I was young!
“Now, we’re allies working together
to reach the same goal, and he motivates me as my rival!”
It’s cold...
Get back!
Eerie Light!
Absolute Zero?!
A one-hit KO move...
It’ll sweep you up
if you stick too close!
Try to battle from a distance!
Reflector!
Good choice!
Thanks, Tokio!
Don’t look away!
Focus on the battle!
Windie!
Pyro Ball!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Moonforce!
Reflector!
Aceburn and Lucario,
grab onto Freezer!
Don’t just order them around!
Go, let’s do it.
Aceburn, grab onto Freezer!
You too, Lucario!
Flamethrower!
Blaze Kick!
Go, Lucario!
Healing Pulse!
Thank you, Tokio.
Don’t let your guard down!
Yeah, I know!
Satoshi,
let’s pile on the pressure!
Yeah!
No! Freezer’s not some
easy little pushover!
Aceburn!
Use Blaze Kick again!
Lucario, use Guiding Wave Sphere!
Sirknight, use Light Screen!
Windie! Flamethrower!
Aceburn!
Cheer up, Go.
There’ll be more missions.
If you keep at it,
I’m sure you’ll make it!
Thanks.
Sometimes,
kindness can be a cruelty.
I cooperated with you today
because the mission was a Raid Battle,
but we Challengers don’t need to
play nice and pretend to be friends.
It’s fine! We can help
each other out as friends!
You’re as naïve as ever.
I agree with Mr. Tsurugi’s
strict mentality.
Without that strictness,
we’ll never encounter Mew.
“I used to think that we should all just work together
as friends, since we were allies with the same goal,
“but watching him
and my other rivals...
“...has given me the chance
to learn about how others view things.”
Shigeru, let’s work together!
I’ve been waiting for you
to say that!
Use Pyro Ball on Regieleki!
Use Rocket Headbutt
on Regidrago!
Kamex, use Rapid Spin!
Aceburn, get on Kamex!
Then use the Twister
to gain height!
Now!
Use Blaze Kick on Regieleki!
Charge in with Rapid Spin!
Come on, Monster Ball!
Monster Ball, go!
Go. Without your help,
I would never have caught it.
It’s teamwork
that gave us victory.
Shigeru...
If you team up with someone unskilled
simply out of friendship, they’ll only let you down.
But even if you’re rivals
with someone...
...if your goals align,
you can still work together.
Stubbornly clinging to your pride
will only slow you down.
Acting alone
can prove fatal.
That’s something I learned
from Mr. Tsurugi on a mission.
“We are walking
a long and steep path together.
“Which is why I think we shouldn’t just be friends,
but also rivals pushing one another forward...
“...so that we can one day
reach our dreams, together!”
So you met long ago
and now you’re back together as rivals!
The flow of time is such a mystery!
Now, here’s a trendsetting song
that’s ahead of its time!
Storybook segment after the commercials!!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
“The Cheerful Sarunori.”
“This is my first errand!
It will be easy!”
The plodding Sarunori.
“Adventures are fun!
There are so many strange things!”
The fearful Sarunori!
“Huh? Where am I?
I’m exhausted...”
The weary Sarunori...
“I made a promise!
I have to see it through!”
The advancing Sarunori!
“Ah! There’s everyone!
I’m so close!”
The tearful Sarunori!
“My errand went perfectly!
Didn’t I do great?!”
The cheerful Sarunori!
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
At last,
the finals are tomorrow!
So today, let’s have a feast
and get some good rest!
Huh?
That scone shop...
Do you remember this place, Aceburn?
This is where we met!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Go and Aceburn!
The Place It All Began!!