The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament Finals.
In Dande and Satoshi’s struggle over
the summit of Pokémon battling,
Dande currently has
three Pokémon left,
while Satoshi is one step ahead,
with four.
However, all of Satoshi’s Pokémon
have already taken heavy damage.
Though he appears to have the lead,
Satoshi has actually been driven into a corner.
How will Satoshi fight back in this,
the single biggest Pokémon battle in history?
Kairyu, watch out!
You can do it, Kairyu!
Go for it, Satoshi!
Big Bro! Fight!
Drum Attack!
Hurricane!
He starts an intense Hurricane!
The Flying-type move is super effective
on the Grass-type Gorillander!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Finals III - "Supreme"
An astonishing Drum Attack
reduces Hurricane’s damage!
All right!
You can do that?
That’s more like a Gentle Breeze
than a Hurricane.
That won’t do any damage, meow.
Go snap those roots
like they’re twigs!
Do it!
Kairyu, you okay?!
Her speed dropped... Drum Attack’s doing, I take it?
When I send out a Grass type,
my opponents tend to attack it with Flying-type moves,
so that was my counter.
“The best defense
is a good offense...”
Mr. Dande’s kinda like Satoshi.
Huh?
Don’t you think
their battle styles are similar?
Now, show me more, Satoshi!
Then...
Let’s do it!
Dra-Kairyu Meteor!
There it is! The move that took down Drapult,
Gorillander!
Use Drum Attack!
Break through!
What?!
Too bad, Satoshi.
I knew you’d play it like that!
Ooh, it’s just like Vine Whip.
Finish it, Kairyu!
Use Dragon Claw!
Acrobatics!
So fast!
What the...?
That’s a move?
It’s way too nimble
for its size, meow.
Kairyu!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
His type disadvantage
did not matter one bit!
Is this how a Champion battles?!
Big Bro!
And with that, it’s now a 3v3.
Who will Satoshi pick?
Return, Kairyu.
You put up a great fight.
Have a nice, long rest.
Come out, Negigaknight!
It’s Negigaknight!
Star Assault!
100,000 Horsepower!
And they clash!
Are they evenly matched?!
Hold out!
Push!
All right!
Gorillander stands back up!
But the recoil from Star Assault
leaves Negigaknight unable to attack!
100,000 Horsepower!
Negigaknight,
ride your shield!
Drum Attack!
Consecutive Cut!
Acrobatics!
Negigaknight is unable to battle!
That’s my big bro!
Back-to-back losses
for Competitor Satoshi!
Competitor Dande and Gorillander
emerge victorious from the incredible aerial battle!
Return, Negigaknight!
Thanks for everything.
Good showing, Gorillander!
Now you’ve done it,
supreme jerk!
Gah! Why’d he have to
pick up steam?!
It’s not over yet!
He still has
Pikachu and Uonoragon, meow!
Satoshi! You’ve given me and my Pokémon
a chance to show off our full potential.
And yet, I’m sad.
You have two Pokémon left.
This incredibly exciting battle...
...is almost over.
It’s not over ‘til it’s over,
Mr. Dande!
Come out, Uonoragon!
Uonoragon!
Its spikes are still morphed!
Ice Fang!
Drum Attack!
What’s this?!
The Drum Attack was smashed to bits!
Now, Uonoragon!
Dragon Dive!
100,000 Horsepower!
Gorillander is unable to battle!
All right! We did it!
And suddenly,
Competitor Satoshi closes the gap!
Return, Gorillander.
You fought well.
Uonoragon,
don’t let your guard down!
Come out, Aceburn!
Aceburn arrives!
So it’s back...!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aceburn, the Pokémon
he kicked off the finals with.
It has the ability Libero, which changes its own type
to that of the moves it uses.
High Jump Kick!
It became a Fighting type!
High Jump Kick lands!
Water Gun!
Pyro Ball!
Pyro Ball cancels out
the Water Gun!
Jaw Bite!
Iron Head!
Now it’s a Steel type!
Nice header!
Competitor Dande’s
completely setting the pace.
Uonoragon, you okay?
We’ll land the next hit!
Dragon Dive!
High Jump Kick!
Uonoragon is unable to battle!
Aceburn overwhelms Uonoragon!
Return, Uonoragon!
You did great.
Is Satoshi going to be okay?
It’ll be fine!
Satoshi and the team will be fine!
You battled well. Return!
Satoshi, this is my sixth Pokémon.
Come out, Lizardon!
Competitor Dande’s
supreme partner, Lizardon!
Mr. Dande wants to finish the battle
with Lizardon.
I’m counting on you, Pikachu!
Left with only Pikachu,
will Competitor Satoshi
be able to take down Lizardon?
Or will Competitor Dande
bring the battle to a close?
Satoshi.
Lizardon was my first Pokémon.
My irreplaceable partner,
who’s always traveled with me.
My first battle, my first catch,
my first evolution...
He’s been there
for everything and anything.
We’re the same, Mr. Dande!
Me, I’ve always traveled
with Pikachu.
And that’s why I wanna beat
Lizardon with Pikachu!
That’s why...
I’ll win with Lizardon!
Kyodaimax!
All right! Do it, Lizardon!
It’s huge!
It’ll squash Pikachu flat!
Wait— I... I can’t process this!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Dai Rock!
Jump, Pikachu!
Dai Rock’s effect
whipped up a sandstorm!
Despite its depleting stamina,
Pikachu rises above Lizardon!
Iron Tail!
Dai Dragoon!
Pikachu!
It landed!
Good job hanging on.
Kyodaimax’s power
really is something else.
This is the only way
I can stand up to it.
Pikachu!
Let’s use our full power!
I’ve been waiting for this!
Competitor Satoshi
activates his Z-Move!
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Pikachu! 10,000,000 Volts!
It’s Champion time!
Kyodai Hellfire!
This is perfect, Satoshi!
I’ve always wanted to try this...
Kyodaimax versus Z-Move!
Me too, Mr. Dande!
Kyodai Hellfire versus
10,000,000 Volts!
The tremendous energy
leaves the whole of Shoot Stadium shaking!
What is this
Galar particle reaction?
An event like this
has never been observed before.
Mugendaina...
It couldn’t be—
The Black Night is happening again?!
Sonia, look...
Right... The Kyodaimax
and Z-Move colliding...
Plus, the enormous power of
Mega Evolution...
Maybe having them shake this stadium—
this space— has caused this...
What is the meaning of this?!
Though the Kyodaimax has ended,
black clouds continue to swirl above us!
That cry...
In the midst of their white-hot battle,
Mugendaina has come flying in out of nowhere.
What is it after?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The fiercely fought finals battle
concludes at last?!
But suddenly, racing through the sky,
Mugendaimeow arrives!
Wha—?! What about the battle?!
Dunno why you’re here,
but you better not butt in, stupid Mugendaidai!
Get out!
It’s “Mugendaina,” you know...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Finals IV - “Partners”
The Finals IV - "Partners"
“Let’s all tune in, meow!”