The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The eight mighty trainers
aiming for the summit...
...have begun battling.
At Shoot Stadium,
the site of these fateful battles,
Satoshi and Go met Dande’s brother, Hop,
and they ended up spectating together.
The first match of the first round
was Dande VS Alain.
Dande’s skillful battling struck down Alain,
advancing him to the semifinals.
Following it is the second match...
...between the new Champion of Kanto and Johto, Wataru,
and the Champion of Kalos, Carne.
Competitor Wataru and Competitor Carne
have arrived on the field.
Which of them will end up battling
Competitor Dande in the semifinals?
Ms. Carne and Mr. Wataru, huh?
Which one should I cheer for?
Satoshi, you know both of them?
Yeah! One time
I even got to battle Ms. Carne.
That’s incredible!
Even my bro
thinks highly of you...
You must have some knack
for getting Champions to notice you!
Wake up, meow!
More importantly, look at Carne!
She’s sparkling!
She’s dazzling... too dazzling!
The very image
of a star actress!
Humph...
A “star actress,” huh?
Well, why don’t we just see
how well she performs?
The time is come!
Trainers of Kanto!
Trainers of Johto!
Bear witness to my battle!
And to you, Carne!
As a dragon tamer, may this battle be one
my dragon brigade can be proud of!
You’ve said it well!
We are linked together by Pokémon!
And by this battle!
I, too, shoulder hopes and dreams...
Those of the trainers of Kalos...
...as I stand here today!
Mr. Wataru...
You and your Pokémon...
How marvelously will they shine?
I can’t wait to find out!
Then let us begin!
Sparks are flying from the get-go!
This is gonna be
a really awesome battle!
You may each use three Pokémon
in the first round.
No limit on
switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all three of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, you are allowed a single use of only one
of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolution.
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Head forth!
Let’s do this!
And the battle has begun!
Competitor Wataru chooses Kairyu!
His opponent, Competitor Carne,
chooses Amaruruga!
Amaruruga! Tundra Pokémon!
Rock/Ice type!
When gripped by rage,
it will emanate freezing air,
covering everything around it in ice!
Let the battle begin!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Champions' Pride!
Wataru VS Carne!!
Let the battle begin!
Light Screen!
Destroyer Beam!
Light Screen reduced
the Destroyer Beam’s damage!
Also, firing Destroyer Beam...
...immobilizes the attacker
for a short while!
Blizzard!
It’s super effective!
Bravo.
Good! Well done holding on!
Kairyu can move again!
Body Press!
Once again, it’s super effective!
Amaruruga, stay strong!
Once more! Body Press!
Reflector!
Another defensive move!
Amaruruga held out
thanks to the Reflector!
It’s like an aurora!
Light Screen and Reflector...
She fortified herself
with two defense moves.
Still, the effect of the moves
will dissipate in time.
They’re not all-powerful.
She must be hoping
to put pressure on Mr. Wataru, too.
Ms. Carne now clearly
holds the upper hand in the battle.
It’s too early to call it yet.
Wataru won’t be fazed by this.
Kairyu! Twister!
Rock Slide!
Underestimate me
and you’ll be in for a shock!
Have a taste of my
well-trained Dragon moves!
Your part is over, Amaruruga!
Amaruruga is unable to battle!
Competitor Wataru takes the first win!
The terrifying power of Kairyu!
Placing walls before us
will only make us strike even harder!
Amazing!
It even endured that Rock Slide!
But is it going to last much longer?
Return, Amaruruga.
Thank you.
Kairyu! Return!
Oh! He called it back!
I’m counting on you,
Pumpjin!
Competitor Carne’s
second Pokémon is Pumpjin.
And the effect of the walls is still in play!
Pumpjin! Pumpkin Pokémon!
Ghost/Grass type!
It enwraps its prey in its hairlike arms!
It sings joyfully as it observes
the suffering of its prey!
Pumpjin, huh?
Musashi caught one of those
in Kalos, meow.
Pumpjin, eh...?
Wait...
Pumpjin?!
That actress lady’s got good taste!
You guys!
It’s a Pumpjin! A Pumpjin!
That’s right...
Come out, Gyarados!
Competitor Wataru’s
second Pokémon is Gyarados!
A red Gyarados!
Gyarados!
We’ll break through those walls!
Pumpjin!
Halloween!
What is that?!
Pumpjin’s signature move.
It adds the Ghost type to its opponent!
Then, if he gets hit
with a Ghost-type move...
It’ll be super effective!
Tch...
A troublesome move.
Aqua Tail!
What power... Without the Reflector,
we might have been in trouble.
The Light Screen will vanish soon.
That moment will decide it!
Gyarados! Dragon Pulse!
Shadow Strike!
She attacks first with Shadow Strike!
Dealing huge damage
because of Halloween!
But!
The Dragon Pulse is a direct hit!
The Light Screen finally vanished!
Still standing.
In that case...
Ice Fang!
Ghost Dive!
Dragon Pulse!
Gyarados is unable to battle!
This time,
Competitor Carne takes the win!
Awesome!
They’re both awesome!
Incredible, Pumpjin!
I’m moved to tears, meow!
Even though it’s not on our side, meow!
That’s the first one
we’re nabbing!
Good work, Gyarados.
Come out, Sazandra!
Competitor Wataru’s
third Pokémon is Sazandra!
I have a strategy
for Sazandra, too.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The second match,
Competitor Wataru VS Competitor Carne.
Competitor Carne uses Pumpjin.
Competitor Wataru uses Sazandra.
Sazandra! Brutal Pokémon!
Evil/Dragon type!
It bites anything that moves!
There are a slew of stories about villages
that were destroyed by Sazandra!
Pumpjin...
Halloween!
I care not! Evil Pulse!
The Reflector’s effect has ended!
And because of the super effective Evil Pulse,
Pumpjin is flinching!
No way!
Pull it together, Pumpjin!
Once more! Evil Pulse!
Pumpjin is unable to battle!
We did it, Gyarados.
We owe this victory to you.
It’s finished...
Hey!
Plug the next Pokémon!
You’re still doin’ this?
Now, Competitor Carne
is up against a wall!
Thank you, Pumpjin.
Ms. Carne’s third Pokémon
has to be...
It’s your time to shine...
Sirknight!
I knew it! Sirknight!
She’s finally using her ace?
Fairy types have an advantage over
Evil/Dragon types, after all!
I’ve been waiting for you,
Sirknight!
Let us show you
our greatest performance!
Sirknight! Mega Evolve!
All right!
It’s Mega Sirknight!
Shadow Ball!
Tri Attack!
Offense is the greatest defense!
The first strike takes the win!
Luster Cannon!
Psychokinesis!
What?!
Moonforce!
An intense Moonforce!
Can Sazandra hold on?!
Sazandra is unable to battle!
Now Competitor Wataru
is down two as well.
What a back-and-forth!
The next showdown will decide the battle!
You fought well.
Leave the rest to Kairyu.
Come out!
The final battle is
Kairyu VS Mega Sirknight!
Sirknight, you mustn’t let your guard down
until the very end.
Kairyu!
We have not yet demonstrated
all that we can do!
Here goes, Kairyu!
Daimax!
Competitor Wataru
activates Daimax!
Kairyu Daimaxed?!
It’s huge!
Unlike Mega Evolution,
Daimax has a time limit.
The whole battle
hinges on that.
Daimax allows Kairyu’s stamina
to go beyond its limits!
So you had a trick
up your sleeve...
But will it stand up
against my Fairy moves?
Moonforce!
Dai Ice!
It held on!
It endured the Moonforce!
It’s hailing on the field
from the Dai Ice!
That’ll eat away
at their stamina bit by bit.
Quite the risky tactic.
Or are you simply confident that Kairyu is
strong enough to hold on, even through hail?
Take this! Dai Attack!
Shadow Ball!
Dai Dragoon!
But Dragon moves
don’t affect Fairy types!
No, he’s not aiming at Sirknight!
Incredible! The Dai Dragoon
swallowed the Shadow Ball!
Your plan...
I’ve figured it out.
Of course...
Mr. Wataru’s hanging on with his Daimax,
then he’s gonna strike
the moment it wears off!
Oh, and his Daimax has—
Destroyer Beam!
Checkmate!
Moonforce!
Kairyu!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
Sirknight wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Carne!
Competitor Carne lands a seat
in the semifinals!
Thank you.
You had me at your mercy.
Your victory was magnificent.
I, too, greatly enjoyed
our time together.
I look forward to seeing
how you’ll battle against Dande.
Indeed.
A battle between Champions...
That was amazing!
So Mr. Dande’s facing Ms. Carne.
Ms. Carne, and her skillful
support move combos...
But! Big Bro will win!
Ms. Carne truly is an enigma.
Her battles change
with the Pokémon she uses.
She’d call them performances
and not battles, right?
I can’t wait to perform
alongside her.
Okay!
Here’s Competitor Carne!
Bringing you live comments
ahead of everyone else, meow!
So, how are you feeling
right now, meow?
Everyone in Kalos,
thank you for your support!
Finish the next match
with Pumpjin, ‘kay?
You hear me?
With Pumpjin!
Mr. Wataru!
Hey, Satoshi.
My battles end here.
Hang in there.
Satoshi.
Iris!
You’re finally up!
Right now, I’m just so nervous...
And I’m so fired up...
...and I just wanna get out there
and let loose!
You’re up against Ms. Shirona.
Go at her with everything you’ve got!
Yeah! I’m gonna win a match
before you, Satoshi!
Ooh, now you’ve said it!
Okay, I’ll be back soon!
Pikachu, you cheer for me, too!
The third match of the first round.
The Champion of Sinnoh,
Competitor Shirona, is on the field.
Her opponent is the Champion of Isshu,
Competitor Iris.
This is a clash between the dignified
queen of Sinnoh and a young Champion.
This battle is a 3v3! Both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Come out, Doryuzu!
Emerge from the waves, Tritodon!
Ms. Shirona’s using Tritodon?
And the other Pokémon is...
It’s Doryuzu!
The Masters Tournament...
The third match of the first round is Shirona VS Iris.
How will their battle
play out?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The Pokémon World Championships!
Masters Tournament!
Looks like the third match is
the Champion of Sinnoh VS the Champion of Isshu!
By the way, I feel like I’ve seen
that Champion of Isshu somewhere before...
Meow, too!
These awful-feeling memories...
Are they real, or are they not...?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
VS Shirona!
Iris, the Path to be Dragon Master!!