Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Over 10,000?
There’s that many participants?!
I’m fired up!
They’re not called the Pokémon World Championships
for nothing! They’re insanely popular!
That’s what I wanna hear!
The more rivals, the more excitement!
More and more
keep signing up after me!
I see... Everyone starts out
in the Normal Class, huh?
And above that is the Super Class, Hyper Class,
and then the Master Class!
Everyone shares
the same starting line.
Your momentum greatly depends on
whether you win or lose your first battle.
The first battle is vital.
Got it!
All right, let’s do this, Pikachu!
What are you gonna do?
If I wanna battle Mr. Dande,
then first of all I gotta enter the Super Class!
Meaning there’s only one thing to do!
Win, win, and win some more!
You pumped up too, Gänger?
Looks like the best way
to climb the ranks fast...
...is to fight someone
ranked much higher than yourself.
So basically, strong trainers?
I wonder if there are
any participating trainers nearby...
As strong as I can find!
You sure are impatient.
Look into it yourself!
Search for “Kuchiba City.”
Oh, I see!
“Kuchiba City”...
Ooh, found one!
I choose this trainer!
Ranking number 2,109...
Oh?
Isn’t that the substitute
Gym Leader in Kuchiba Gym?
Kuchiba Gym? Wasn’t Mr. Matis
the Gym Leader there?
Right you are.
But I hear he’s out training right now,
trying to refine his mastery over the Electric type.
Out training...?
His substitute, Ms. Visquez,
is quite formidable as well!
Are you sure you should start
with such a high bar?
Now I’m really fired up!
Satoshi is finally starting his
Pokémon World Championships challenge.
His target is Dande!
All for the sake of
becoming the strongest!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi Joins In!
The Pokémon World Championships!!
Hey, do you have
Kuchiba Gym’s Badge?
Sure do!
I got it from Mr. Matis
after fighting his Raichu!
It was my third Badge!
This world has Pokémon Gyms
built in all sorts of places.
Gym Leaders await within,
serving as role models to many trainers.
Challengers are tested
in their Pokémon Battling skills,
and receive a Badge
if they are victorious.
But in the Pokémon World Championships
Satoshi is now entering,
Gym Leaders and regular trainers alike
all start in the Normal Class,
regardless of their prior careers.
It’s an Onisuzume!
Sorry, Satoshi!
I got things to do!
Rabbifoot!
H-Hey, hang on!
Hang in there, Go!
Kuchiba Gym, Kanto Region
You are strong!
I commend you!
But you lack something vital
if you want to surpass us!
What do I speak of?
Answer me!
What?
Well...
Spirit!
The spirit to conquer yourself!
Gym Battles are all about
you challengers...
...showing us Gym Leaders the strength that
you and your Pokémon built up through battle!
The Badge is the proof
that you have taken us down!
But I wish to commend
your battling prowess!
And so, we will bury you
with our strongest move.
Voltteccer!
Sleeper is unable to battle!
As such, substitute
Gym Leader Visquez wins!
I... I accept defeat!
Good. Train hard,
and challenge us again!
Your battling showed real promise.
Well done, Deputy Captain!
That was the last
Gym challenger for the day.
I see.
You fought well today.
You never let me down, Raichu.
You still haven’t fought enough?
It would be nice if a trainer in the Championships
would show up right now.
Your current rank is 2,109...
No change.
Is this...?
A Championships
participant is nearby!
Excuse me!
This is an official
battle announcement.
I see. So it’s you.
Would you like to battle?
Or not?
Of course I’ll battle!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
I’d like to battle you, Ms. Visquez!
Very well!
Official battle appointment made!
Deputy Captain, this trainer is...
I didn’t expect
Satoshi from Masara Town...
I wanted to meet you,
and your Pikachu as well.
Captain Matis told me about...
...the young boy who once overcame
him and Raichu in a spectacular battle;
Satoshi from Masara Town
and his Pikachu.
This Raichu is my comrade,
trained by the captain himself!
Satoshi!
I made it in time!
Go!
Who are you?
This is my friend, Go!
He came to cheer me on
during the battle!
Nice to meet you!
Got the Onisuzume?
Cool, you did it!
Yup!
And now it’s my turn to shine!
Ms. Visquez! I just entered the Championships,
and this will be my first battle!
I’m honored that you’d choose me
as your historic first opponent!
Welcome! Welcome!
Welcome!
The Pokémon World Championships
has approved this Normal Class battle!
The battle will be between Kuchiba Gym’s Visquez
and Satoshi from Masara Town!
Happy to have you as judge again,
Drone Rotom!
Ooh, a Drone Rotom?
Never seen one before!
Nice to meetcha!
This battle will be a 2v2.
Now, allow me to explain
the official rules!
You are free to switch Pokémon
during the battle.
When all of a trainer’s Pokémon are incapacitated,
that trainer loses, and the trainer remaining wins!
And the battle judge will be myself,
as approved by the Championships!
What are those?
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3!
2!
1!
Go!
Pikachu, I choose you!
Go, Raichu!
Raichu! Mouse Pokémon!
Electric type!
Pikachu’s evolved form!
As electricity builds up inside its body,
it becomes more aggressive!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Battle start!
This is my squadron’s welcome!
100,000 Volts!
We’ll use 100,000 Volts too!
Satoshi and Pikachu are both
going at full throttle!
Voltteccer!
A Voltteccer already?!
They plan on finishing this
right away?
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Stand on your tail!
That’s...
The tactic the captain
was praising!
He’s discharging the power of Voltteccer
into the ground!
And the power of Iron Tail is helping him
withstand the impact from Raichu’s tackle!
Don’t give up, Pikachu!
Disperse all the electric power
into the battlefield!
Raichu!
Show them our power!
Pikachu!
Brute force wasn’t enough, huh?
Catch him!
Amazing!
Is that even possible?!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Now, Raichu!
Iron Tail!
Reflector!
An impressive call...
Raichu would have taken a lot of damage
if we hadn’t put up the Reflector in time.
Turn every bad situation into a chance!
That’s how we’ve always fought!
Don’t push yourself, Pikachu.
Return!
You did great.
Gänger!
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Raichu
Electric
It’s all on you, Gänger!
You can beat its tail!
Can you go on, Raichu?
Gänger, huh?
How will this battle go?
Now! Night Head!
100,000 Volts!
Ice Punch!
How can it move like that?!
Use your tail, Raichu!
What?!
I see! He took advantage of
Gänger’s intangibility!
Good, Gänger!
That tail’s not scary at all!
Well then... Voltteccer!
Psychokinesis!
What?!
Raichu!
Raichu is unable to battle!
The Raichu?!
You did it, Gänger!
I knew you could do it,
Satoshi!
You used Gänger’s unpredictable movement
to your advantage!
Come back, Raichu.
You fought well.
I will avenge you.
I have my own way to
counter tricky movement!
Go, my squadron’s
ultimate lethal weapon!
Yes! Marumine!
Marumine! Ball Pokémon!
Electric type!
It explodes in response
to even minor stimuli!
It is feared, with the nickname of
“The Bomb Ball”!
This shape...
EM Levitation!
That’s not the only thing we can do
with our EM Levitation!
What is this?!
Most challengers counter the Electric type
with Ground-type moves!
The EM Levitation we’ve developed
to counteract that can even control space!
Meaning... Marumine has no rival!
Commence bombardment!
Gänger! Watch Marumine’s
movements carefully!
Those imprints on the wall
were from this attack!
Good! Gänger can’t get out
of Marumine’s electric cage!
Above you!
Psychokinesis!
Gänger! Night Head!
Discharge!
Gänger!
Gänger is unable to battle!
Take a nice, long rest.
Counting on you, Pikachu!
Now it’s one on one...
Let’s end this!
Marumine, use Rollout!
Pikachu!
Watch its movements carefully!
Do something, Satoshi!
You’ll lose at this rate!
My Marumine’s attacks deal more damage
the more it gets to accelerate!
How long can Pikachu last?!
In that case...
Pikachu! Get on top of Marumine
and use Iron Tail!
He stopped it!
Good, Pikachu!
Now, spin it in reverse!
How is this...?
That’s insane, Satoshi...
He took control of Marumine!
What an insult!
Finish it off! Iron Tail!
No way!
Induced Explosion?!
Wait, Marumine!
Electric Net!
I... I can’t believe it...
Well done, Pikachu!
Marumine is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
As such, the winner is
Satoshi from Masara Town!
All right!
They triggered your ability,
Induced Explosion...
You must have battled
past your own limits.
I stand defeated.
Ms. Visquez!
I’ll report this to Captain Matis!
I’m sure he’ll want to battle
this new and stronger you, too!
I’d love to battle Mr. Matis...
To battle the captain again, too!
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
So quick!
Satoshi!
Go!
Congratulations!
Thanks!
That was incredible!
I never could’ve come up with any of your tricks!
But that battle was intense!
I owe it all to Pikachu and Gänger!
I’ve climbed way up in the ranks!
You’re right!
Since you defeated Visquez, who had a high rank,
your own rank skyrocketed!
How do I explain this
to the Captain?!
Deputy Captain!
Satoshi has triumphed in his first
Pokémon World Championships match!
But his challenge to reach
Supreme Monarch Dande...
...has only just begun!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
We should make this Metamon
our partner, meow!
I agree! It would enable us to
carry out new kinds of schemes!
But it’s a failure of a Metamon
who just got fired from its TV gig, right?
That thing has a long way to go before it’s worthy of
acting alongside a world-class actress such as myself!
Next time...
I Am Metamon!
...on Pocket Monsters: