This is the Sakuragi Institute.
Satoshi and Go now greet
their first morning here.
Satoshi, it’s morning.
Wake up...
You too, Go...
Oh, it’s just Barrierd.
We can eat as much as we like?!
Of course! After all, we’re...
...research fellows here!
Being research fellows is amazing!
Yeah!
They’ve got Pokémon food, too!
So, I was thinking of
using Electroweb,
but then I realized I should go with
100,000 Volts instead!
Right, Pikachu?
Director Sakuragi!
Good morning.
Good morning!
Morning, Koharu.
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Perfectly!
You even have a food corner...
This is the best!
Satoshi’s been stuffing his face
since he got here!
Yeah, stuffing my face since...
Wait, so have you!
I guess.
Wanpachi, I’ll put your food
and water here.
See you later.
All right. Take care.
You should eat with us, too.
I already ate.
And I don’t want to be late for school.
Well, see you later.
I’ll go!
Me, too!
I’m so sorry!
The bus got... stuck in traffic...
Oh, that’s right.
I hadn’t introduced you yet.
I’m Renji, an assistant here.
And my other assistant...
I’m Kikuna.
The cause of the traffic jam
is up on the news sites.
Fushigisou!
A city-wide outbreak of Fushigisou?
Fushigidane. Fushigisou.
Fushigibana.
True to the “fushigi” in their names,
they’re full of mysteries.
mystery
Let’s go investigate!
This’ll be our first job as research fellows
of the Sakuragi Institute!
Yeah! Let’s give it
all we’ve got, Pikachu!
By the way, Satoshi,
do you have a smartphone?
Smartphone?
Have this, then.
Thank you!
Go, you take out yours.
All right.
Rotom!
Raise up your smartphones,
both of you.
All right!
It went in...
What’s this?
It’s called a Smartphone Rotom.
It functions as a Pokémon Index, too.
Thank you, sir!
All right, now...
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Oh-Sou Mysterious
Fushigisou!
I ask of you: what is Team Rocket?
An evil organization spearheading
the Pokémon world, now and forever.
What evil do we commit?
We steal each and every
strong or rare Pokémon.
To what end?
To create the mightiest Pokémon army
using the Pokémon we stole.
For that purpose, I have prepared
the ultimate secret weapon.
Go! Make the whole world learn to fear
the name of Team Rocket!
Your wish is our command,
Sakaki, sir!
That’s weird...
It should be around here...
Please stop!
Over there!
Ms. Junsa!
Did something happen?
As you can see...
Fushigisou!
Fushigisou! Seed Pokémon!
Grass/Poison type!
Exposure to sunlight
adds to its strength!
Sunlight also makes the bud
on its back grow larger!
I wonder where
the Fushigisou are going.
Oh, that’s right.
This might not have anything to do
with the Fushigisou,
but look at this.
Team Rocket?!
I’ve read about them online.
Apparently they’re bad guys who
steal people’s Pokémon...
But the bit about the talking Nyarth
has to be a lie, yeah?
People would think that, huh?
We’re on guard because
they were reportedly seen around here.
You take care, too.
All right!
Pikachu!
What’s wrong?
Seems like it wants to
keep moving, but can’t.
Let’s help it!
Don’t!
Why?
We’re here to investigate
the Fushigisou outbreak, yeah?
If we help them, we won’t be able to
solve the mystery.
It’s in trouble,
so we should help!
It’s a mistake to try and help
anyone and everyone!
If a Pokémon can’t overcome problems on its own,
then that’s the end of the line!
What do you mean,
“end of the line”?!
If we helped it,
we’d rob it of its strength to live, yeah?!
That doesn’t make any sense!
If I want to help someone, I will!
Helping them on a whim
because you think they’re cute,
or because you feel bad for them,
is just human selfishness!
I don’t care if it’s selfish or whatever!
I’m helping it!
Don’t worry. I’ll get you up.
All right...
Told you so.
Leave me alone, will you?
Oh, I see how it is.
Sheesh... Back with Lugia,
I accepted you as my friend,
but it seems I misjudged you.
I don’t need you to be my friend!
So you’re one of those guys, too...
You say something?
Forget it!
I’ll investigate on my own!
Oh, will you, now?
Well, suit yourself!
Yeah, I will!
All right! Me, too!
Don’t copy me!
Right back at you!
Rotom, what’s that?
A Pokémon Gym under construction.
There’s a sweet scent in the air...
I see!
The Fushigisou might be
going there to evolve.
Evolve?
Them letting out a sweet scent
from their bud like that...
...is a sign that they’re about to evolve
and have their flowers bloom!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Fushigisou
Poison
Grass
They keep coming
from that way, too.
There’s Fushigidane, too!
They’re so cute!
Rotom, do you have any info
on that place?
This is a photo from
when construction was starting!
Oh, Wanriky!
Before construction began,
it was a sunny grassland!
Wild Fushigidane and Fushigisou
would gather there to bask in the sun!
The Fushigisou are disappointed.
Huh? You can tell?
It’s obvious from
the look on their faces!
I can’t tell at all...
Are they climbing up,
since the sun shines brighter up top?
Let’s go, Pikachu!
You mean we’ll know
if we go up there?
Awesome!
Grab on!
Easy now...
Now up there, huh?
Get on.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Thanks!
And... Hup! Hup!
Here.
We made it!
They’re all basking in the sun!
The Fushigidane’s bulbs are
taking in sunlight and growing bigger!
What a sweet scent...
Does this mean they really did come here
seeking stronger sunlight?
I know!
We might understand them better
if we become Fushigisou ourselves!
That’s it...
Pikachu, you be the bud.
I’m starting to feel like a Fushigisou.
This feels so nice...
Oh, man...
It really does feel nice...
The wind’s so pleasant.
This spot is famous in Kuchiba
for its strong winds.
Is this evolution?
What’s that?!
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket?!
It’s my first time seeing them!
Sure, pleasure meeting you, meow...
The Nyarth really is talking!
I don’t mesh well with
people like that, meow...
Give the Fushigisou back,
Team Rocket!
With so many of them gathered in one place,
it’s like they’re saying “Please steal us”!
And so, of course we will do just that!
Farewell, brat boy!
Wait!
“Brat boy”?
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
I’m glad you’re all right!
How dare you take my Fushigisou?!
We’re going down, Nyarth!
Roger that!
You have some nerve,
you know that?!
This is the secret weapon, meow?
Looks like a capsule toy machine to me.
Well, then we’ll have to put in a coin!
But do we even have one?
We sure do!
Here goes!
Rocket...
Capsule...
Secret!
So these Balls have awesome Pokémon
that Sakaki picked out, huh?
Come on!
The Atrocious Pokémon, Gyarados!
The Armor Pokémon, Banguirus!
Way to go, Sakaki!
These are some energetic
and strong Pokémon!
Commence attack, meow!
Gyarados, go!
Banguirus, use Fire Fang!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Something powerful!
Evil Pulse!
Electroweb!
Lightning Speed!
Good!
Awesome...
Another!
Pikachu!
Stone Edge!
This doesn’t look good!
I know that!
Pikachu, are you all right?
Let’s finish them
with a dual attack!
Yeah!
Solar Beam?
Thank you, everyone!
Hey, Gyarados, are you okay?
Can you go on, Banguirus?
Well then, let’s dish out some pain
on the Fushigisou first!
And then we’ll catch them!
Destroyer Beam!
I won’t let you!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Go!
That Pikachu really is incredible.
So we’d better stick to
our original plan.
We will get
that Pikachu, meow!
But now we’re blasting off...
What an awful feeling!
They’ve started evolving!
Fushigibana!
Fushigibana. Seed Pokémon.
Grass/Poison type.
Its flower is said to take on vivid colors
if it gets plenty of nutrition and sunlight.
The flower’s aroma
soothes the emotions of people.
The Fushigibana came here to
use the wind to spread their pollen!
Yeah. Guess this is the “strength to live”
you were talking about?
Pokémon really are awesome!
Yeah, they sure are.
As are the two of you, though.
No, never mind.
The mysterious strength hidden
in Fushigibana’s pollen...
Another grand discovery!
Well, when up against
the ultimate duo of Satoshi and I,
it was an easy job!
Today was a lot of fun!
We got to see
the moment they evolved,
and became friends with
the Fushigisou!
First it was Lugia,
now Fushigisou...
That’s great, Satoshi!
Yeah!
Well, then... While you’re at it...
Could you be my friend—?
What are you talking about?
We’re already friends, right?
Oh, of course!
I’m home.
Welcome home.
What took you so long?
All the flowers at the school
bloomed at once...
I was in charge of cleanup...
It was so much work!
What’s with you?
How creepy...
In any case,
my exceptional research fellows...
...have solved the mystery of
the Fushigisou march.
Thank you!
We can still keep going!
Yeah! I can’t wait to see
what adventure lies in store next!
Learning a new fact about Fushigisou
has allowed Satoshi and Go to make up.
Tomorrow, more dreams and adventures await
in the world of Pocket Monsters!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
There’s a phenomenon in the Galar Region
that makes Pokémon grow giant!
Really?
That sounds cool!
I wanna go there!
Gimme back my backpack!
Were they working together?!
No data found for this Pokémon!
Does that mean...?
It’s a new Pokémon species?!
Let's Go to the Galar Region!
A Meeting With Hibunny!!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Let’s Go to the Galar Region!
A Meeting With Hibunny!!