Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon Battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
Trainers from all over the world
are taking part.
They battle other trainers
in their class,
and the results of those battles...
...determine their
current ranking in the world.
Satoshi is currently ranked 415th,
which places him in the Super Class.
His path to the Monarch Dande
remains a long one.
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Today, he is once again
training for battle.
You’re really pumped, Kamonegi!
That was some crazy power...
I really felt that...
Satoshi!
What’s up, Go?
Check it out!
There’s an Ishitsubute outbreak!
If I can catch Ishitsubute,
then I can evolve it and register both
Gorone and Gorogna in one fell swoop!
Where’s it happening?
Here.
Rock Tunnel, huh?
Kamonegi, this’ll be a perfect chance
for you to train.
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kamonegi's Great Trial!
Rock Tunnel, Kanto Region
Here we are at Rock Tunnel!
Where’s that Ishitsubute outbreak?
Huh? I don’t see them.
Did they already leave?
Watch out!
Go, are you okay?
Yeah. Thanks, Aceburn.
Be careful, Kamonegi.
Looks like its training
is going well.
Yeah. How’s your search going?
I don’t see any Ishitsubute...
There!
Monster Ball, go!
Ishitsubute’s data will be
added to the Index!
I got Ishitsubute!
Ishitsubute! Rock Pokémon!
Rock/Ground type!
Commonly found near
mountain trails and the like!
If you step on one by accident,
it gets angry! Beware!
Another new friend!
Thank you, Kamonegi!
I owe you one.
All’s well that ends well,
I guess.
Talk about power!
Yeah. My Kamonegi is aiming
to be a Leek Master!
Leek Master?
Yup.
The mightiest Kamonegi,
expert at fighting with the leek!
Let’s chase after
that goal together!
Good... You’ve got
some intense power...
Leek Master... Really?
This is an official
battle announcement.
Hard at work, I see!
Is that guy participating
in the Pokémon World Championships, too?
Very good! It’s well trained!
It’s irresistible!
Um...
Kamonegi!
Perfect timing, Dotekkotsu!
I was watching your Kamonegi, kid!
It wields its leek well!
Your Dotekkotsu handles
that steel beam well, too!
Right? So then there’s
only one thing to do!
You’re in the Super Class,
right, kid?
Yeah. You, too?
I am Genba!
Dotekkotsu and I have trained hard together!
You can call me Genba the Self-Made Man!
The Pokémon World Championships
has approved this Super Class battle!
The match-up is Competitor Satoshi
VS Competitor Genba.
This battle will be a 1v1.
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3!
2!
1!
Go!
Go, Kamonegi!
Go, Dotekkotsu!
Dotekkotsu! Muscular Pokémon!
Fighting type!
It skillfully wields its steel beam!
It excels at demolition;
construction is not its forte!
Battle, start!
Here we go...
Crossroad Kill!
100,000 Horsepower!
Kamonegi!
How’d you like that?
Our 100,000 Horsepower!
Tremble at our skill
with the steel beam!
Good, Kamonegi!
Use Crossroad Kill again!
Counter with Fighting Spirit Blast!
Argh...
Consecutive Cut!
On your feet, Dotekkotsu!
Fighting Spirit Blast again, and make it count!
Keep pushing them back,
Kamonegi!
It’s predicting Kamonegi’s moves...
Dotekkotsu is more skilled!
Use Crossroad Kill!
Now!
Get back up!
Brutal Swing!
Kamonegi!
Verifying condition.
Scanning... Scanning...
Scanning...
Kamonegi!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Dotekkotsu
Fighting
Battle, resume!
Kamonegi!
Build Fighting Spirit!
It’s fully charged!
You good to go?
Very good... Looks like
things are gonna keep heating up!
Wait, Kamonegi!
You can’t just charge in carelessly!
Well, then... Crossroad Kill!
Bring it!
Fighting Spirit Blast!
Fire!
Yeah! That landed!
Okay!
Gah... That really stung!
Kamonegi! Let’s win this battle
and get a streak going!
I can’t lose here!
We’ve been itching to battle
strong trainers!
So let’s give it our all!
Build Up!
Build Fighting Spirit!
Brutal Swing!
We’re not even close to done!
Keep swinging!
You seriously believe a steel beam
can lose to a leek?! Send ‘em flying!
Push back, Kamonegi!
We’re comparing strength?
Sounds wonderful! I accept your challenge!
What?!
Dotekkotsu is unable to battle!
Kamonegi wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
All right!
Kamonegi, you did it!
That steel beam slice was amazing!
We went and lost...
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
It went up!
You’re 381st!
Your name was Satoshi, right?
I suppose we still have
a long way to go.
We’ll have to start training again,
Dotekkotsu.
Here.
Don’t be so down, Dotekkotsu.
I’ll make you a new steel beam.
Until then, you can use this!
Good for you, Dotekkotsu!
Hey!
It’s got a look that screams
that it’s hungry for more battle!
Where are you going?
Kamonegi!
Kid, it’s got the eyes
of a real warrior!
I can tell.
Warrior?
Kamonegi?
Its resilience is quite alluring.
It’s a Pokémon well worth raising!
You think so, too?
You see?
Wait, Satoshi!
See ya, kid!
It just finished a battle.
Isn’t it tired?
But it’s gotten closer
to being a Leek Master.
It sliced a steel beam!
Ellade?!
A wild one?!
Ellade! Blade Pokémon!
Psychic/Fighting type!
When trying to protect someone,
it extends its elbows
as if they were swords and fights savagely!
All right! I’ll catch it!
I’m afraid he’s my partner.
You’re rather inadequate.
I was observing your battle.
The one just now?
Your Kamonegi...
It was rough and unrefined,
and didn’t seem at all aware of its surroundings.
But due to sheer power,
it won in spite of its inadequacy.
Are you here to offer advice?
Perhaps...
Even I don’t know why I felt compelled
to come lecture you.
I just couldn’t let you be.
Hi there, Kamonegi.
My name is Rinto.
I am this Ellade’s trainer.
How would you like to battle us?
You up for it, Kamonegi?
Kamonegi doesn’t seem to understand
that which is most essential.
Most essential?
Part of battling
is learning what that is.
Here we go, Ellade.
Kamonegi, show them how strong you are!
Crossroad Kill!
Keep it up, Kamonegi!
Use Brutal Swing!
Blunt Edge Strike!
Kamonegi!
It’s over.
Hang in there, Kamonegi!
Your Kamonegi...
I believe it holds immense potential.
A shame about its inadequacy.
Should we ever meet again,
I hope to see you
battling in unison.
Shall we go, Ellade?
Okay, let’s do this!
Huh? Leeks?
Kamonegi!
We won’t let up!
We’ll definitely beat that guy
the next time we meet!
Let’s train together!
But why leeks?
Rinto said he wanted us
to battle in unison.
So if we train using leeks,
maybe I’ll understand Kamonegi better!
Is that how it works?
Aim to be a Leek Master!
What will the meeting with
the mysterious trainer Rinto and Ellade...
...bring about in
Satoshi and Kamonegi?
Become stronger before your
next encounter, Kamonegi!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
You’re kidding!
There’s Digda all over the field!
There’s Dugtrio, too!
Seems they’re causing trouble
by eating the vegetables.
Wait... Where’d they go?
We can’t catch them
if they tunnel underground!
Hands-On Agriculture Studies!
Where is Digda?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Hands-On Agriculture Studies!
Where is Digda?!