It should be
somewhere around here...
Ooh, I can see it!
There it is!
Sea Kinsetsu!
Once used to extract resources from the ocean floor,
it has since been abandoned!
Sea Kinsetsu, Hoenn Region
Because it had become home to sea Pokémon,
it was left as a nature preserve!
It’s really huge!
There’s Ms. Asahi!
In order to attempt
a new Project Mew Trial Mission,
Go and Satoshi have arrived at Sea Kinsetsu,
an ocean facility in the Hoenn Region.
Good work, Whaleko.
See ya again when we’re done!
Now, let’s get going.
This is the entrance.
All right! Let’s go!
Stop!
Sorry, but this mission is
only for the challenger himself.
So this is as far as you go.
Wha...?! No way!
Don’t worry, Satoshi.
I’ll clear it for sure.
Okay.
Give it your best shot, Go!
Go, show me the Pokémon
you brought with you.
Sure. Here he is!
Inteleon, huh?
Then if you head down to the lowest deck
from here, you’ll be at the meet-up spot.
The other challengers
are down there, too.
Right!
Um, is Shigeru already...?
I think he was...
...competing at a different site.
He shouldn’t be coming here.
Huh?! I-Is that so...?
I wanted to face him today...
You make it sound like
the other Challengers are nothing to you.
Oh, that’s not...
The mission won’t be that easy.
You’ll have plenty of strong rivals,
so watch your back.
Go!
Y-Yeah!
Let’s go, Inteleon!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Battle Royale of Betrayal!
This would be
the lowest deck, right?
But nobody’s here...
Where’s this meetup spot?
It looks like all of you
have reached the lowest deck.
Your mission this time is survival.
Have Pokémon battles with the other Challengers,
and come out on top.
Survival...
The last person remaining
will receive three tokens.
Well then,
let the mission start!
Hey, wai—
This is... a floor map?
That means...
the red lights are Challengers,
and the blue one
is me, then?
There!
Granbull, use Ice Fang!
Inteleon, use Mud Shot!
Granbull!
Inteleon!
Go!
Tokio?
You’re here, too?
I’m glad I found you, Go!
The battling started so abruptly...
It disappeared.
Does this mean we won’t see
the map for ten minutes?
Rock Slide!
Gamenodes,
use Stone Edge!
Dodge and use Mud Shot!
Here’s our chance!
Zangoose!
Consecutive Cut!
Sirknight! Moonforce!
Inteleon, use Snipe Shot!
Granbull, Zangoose, Gamenodes:
unable to battle.
Eliminated challengers,
please return to the entrance.
Over already, eh?
That sure was fast...
What a relief!
We won!
Battling together worked great.
Hold on...
Hey, why don’t we
keep battling together?!
I had the same idea!
All right!
Go and Tokio formed a team!
Realizing they can battle as a team
means they’ve cleared the first hurdle.
Think they’re gonna
clear the mission?
Well, I can’t know for sure.
Kuwagannon!
Use Scissor Cross!
Discharge!
Dodge it!
He’s strong...
We’re finished...
Don’t take it personally.
Why, you’re pretty good.
Hey, you.
Name’s Layla.
Wanna team up?
I’m Shun'ya.
What will I gain
from teaming up with you?
How about a trial run,
just to see?
It’s dark in here...
Inteleon,
can you check out our surroundings?
Wow!
He’s like a spy!
Sirknight, you can let us know of any dangers
with your predictive powers.
Getting attacked
by someone in hiding would be bad.
We need to make the first move!
Um...
Why don’t we just
hide somewhere?
If we survive until the end,
we’ll clear the mission, right?
We wouldn’t have to battle anyone...
Of course...
Even if we hid,
this would give away our location.
Yeah.
This means we actually have to come up
with a strategy, and defeat our rivals.
Still...
Don’t you think there are
too many paired-up challengers?
They...
don’t seem to be battling.
They even move together.
That means... The surviving challengers
are the ones that realized teams have the advantage.
Hey! Hello!
2v2, huh?
Looks fun, no?
Dirtengu and Jupetta...
Well, well...
I’ll take care of the Inteleon!
I’m gonna beat
the Sirknight, no?
Razor Leaf!
Shoot them down
with Mud Shot!
Jupetta! Ghost Dive!
Reflector!
Shadow Strike!
We’re at a type disadvantage!
Inteleon! One more—
Go! Don’t try to do it alone!
Right...
Just like that time...
Leaf Blade!
Reflector!
Leave defense to me!
Got it!
Mud Shot!
I’m the one you’re fighting, no?!
Shadow Ball!
Inteleon!
Shoot it down with Mud Shot!
What?!
All right!
I’m not finished here!
Razor Leaf!
Sirknight! Use Heal Pulse!
He recovered?!
Aqua Break!
Jupetta, Dirtengu:
unable to battle.
Eliminated challengers,
please return to the entrance.
Gah... This stinks...
It’s over, no?
We did it!
Yeah!
Warrgle, Sawamurar:
unable to battle.
Aw, these guys are
complete pushovers.
I was expecting a tougher mission.
Are you sure about that?
Anyone could be an easy mark
if they let their guard down.
Go and Tokio
are doing a good job keeping ahead!
Maybe it’s about time.
Huh?
These are the only challengers left?
This might be over
sooner than we thought.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Watakko?!
Why?!
Huh?
Go! Don’t fall asleep!
This is Sleep Powder!
Is this also part of the mission?!
Let’s run for it!
Yeah!
Now there’s Dogas?!
This way!
What’s happening?!
What is this?!
Go!
Hey—
Did... you do that?
If they hope to be Chasers,
they need the skills to deal with a surprise like this.
Who knows what will happen
during the actual search?
If someone panics and falls apart,
they’ll hold the others back.
They need to make the right calls
at times like these.
Looks like they’re gone.
Hiding was the right idea!
I’m amazed you noticed
there was a room here.
When I saw the map,
I quickly committed it to memory.
I also remembered
where the other challengers were, but...
They must’ve moved a lot
in that commotion.
Do we really have no choice
but to battle?
I don’t really like it.
I’d rather make friends
than have to battle.
But you can’t clear the mission
by doing that.
But we’re all allies
in looking for Mew, right?!
Can’t we all work together?
Well...
Eek! Help!
Let’s go see!
Yeah.
What?
Oh! Help me!
What happened?
He promised we’d team up,
and then he suddenly attacked me!
What?!
I simply took the chance.
Her fault for letting her guard down
in a mission.
Leopardas is already unable to battle!
It’s cruel to keep attacking it like that!
Hey, please,
can you help me out here?
S-Sure.
Wait, Tokio.
We can’t trust her...
Where’s the Drone Rotom
to give the verdict?
You’re so cruel!
You think I’m a liar?!
Yeah, Go.
We have to trust her.
Tokio!
If you want someone to fight,
we’ll take you on!
Leopardas.
Surprise Attack.
Now, Kuwagannon!
Discharge!
Sirknight!
Is that paralysis?
I’m amazed that your plan worked.
I thought maybe he was catching on...
Good thing his partner’s so gullible!
Let’s go, Shun'ya.
It’s 2v1 now.
We just need to beat that Inteleon.
We used the commotion earlier
to take out all the other challengers.
You’re the only ones left!
Inteleon, hide in the water!
Snipe Shot!
Dodge it!
Sirknight...
I’m sorry, Go...
This is my fault...
Don’t worry!
Leave it to me!
One more Snipe Shot!
We’ll smoke you out!
Kuwagannon! Discharge!
Another Discharge!
Leopardas! Crossroad Kill!
Inteleon! Camouflage yourself!
No, you don’t!
String Shot!
I’ve got you!
Sirknight!
Evil Pulse!
Inteleon!
It’s over!
We’ll be taking the tokens.
Sirknight! Eerie Light!
You’re kidding!
You shouldn’t be able to...
Go! It’s now or never!
Yeah!
Shake free, Inteleon!
Snipe Shot!
Leopardas!
That Sirknight from before...
Scissor Cross!
Aqua Break!
Leopardas, Kuwagannon:
unable to battle.
We’ll get our payback
in the next mission.
It’s just...
me and Tokio.
We survived...
We did it!
Yeah!
Good job, Go!
Don’t go and celebrate just yet.
Only one person may clear the mission.
You two need to decide the winner.
Huh?!
But that’s...
I guess there’s no choice.
But I’m glad
you’re the one remaining, Go.
Ms. Asahi, I’m withdrawing.
Tokio?!
Withdrawing?!
Are you serious?
Yes.
I won’t fight Go.
I won’t fight a friend.
I can wait for another chance—
You can’t!
Go?
You don’t know
if there’ll be another chance!
Chasing after Mew to reach Celebi...
Wasn’t that your precious dream?
It’s a chance at catching Mew...
A chance at
making your dream come true...
You can’t just abandon that!
I want to support you, Tokio!
But I can’t give up, either!
So let’s have a battle!
Go...
We’ll both go all out!
No holding back!
Got it.
Let’s do it.
Go...
Sirknight and Inteleon
are both at their limits.
One hit will decide the battle.
Camouflage yourself, Inteleon!
Sirknight! Predict danger!
Mud Shot!
Dodge it and use Moonforce!
Snipe Shot!
Eerie Light!
Moonforce!
Inteleon!
Inteleon: unable to battle.
Tokio has cleared the mission.
Everyone,
please return to the entrance.
This can’t be...
You did great, Inteleon.
Take a nice long rest.
You did it, Tokio!
Congrats!
Thank you!
I owe it to you,
for showing me I was being naïve.
I see.
Well, shall we head back, then?
I-I...
Go on ahead of me.
Sure.
Tokio, congratulations on
clearing the mission.
I’m sending you three tokens.
Thank you very much!
Also, I will grant the 2nd place
challenger two tokens,
and the 3rd and 4th place
challengers one token.
All right!
Tsurugi, is your event over?
Yes.
Who cleared it?
Shigeru.
I see. I thought so.
Rainy season is ending
sooner than we thought.
We don’t have time to waste
selecting Chasers.
As such, anyone with
less than four tokens as of now...
...can be disqualified.
Good point.
Which means...
These are the remaining Challengers.
I’m still only in 7th place...?
The Chaser selection
is finally reaching its climax.
Will Go be able to reach the passing line
of being in the top three?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Let’s follow Pikachu!
He might’ve found
that mysterious Pokémon!
Running in the snow
is so hard!
Huh?
What’s wrong?
I can hear...
something...
A piano?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Mohn and Lilie,
A Reunion in the Snow!!