Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Here we are!
Isshu Region
The Isshu Region!
The hottest spot in Isshu right now:
the Resort Desert!
All right! There it is!
The newly uncovered ruins;
the Ruins of the Titan!
Try your hand at solving
their ancient riddles!
That “Titan” has got to
be a Pokémon!
Yeah! I think so too!
Wait for me, Isshu Pokémon!
So... how do we get there?
I thought you’d worked that out...
Wait, you don’t have a plan?!
You don’t either!
Pikachu!
This desert is way too hot!
Hibunny, you can take the heat?
Guess that’s a perk
of being a Fire type.
How do we cross?
Don’t underestimate
the Resort Desert, you two!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
My First Time in the Isshu Region!
A Raid Battle in the Ruins!!
Whoa, an Asanan!
Lucky you...
I want one, too!
Do you have any flying Pokémon?
Sure do! Come out, Kairyu!
What’s with this one?
There, there, there...
Calm down, now...
What a cutie!
And I brought...
A Spear, huh?
This one’s mine!
Ooh! A Warrgle, huh?
If you want to cross
the Resort Desert,
this is by far
the most fun way to do it!
Counting on you, Warrgle!
See ya! You try it too!
So cool...
Let’s give it a try!
Yeah!
We’re so quick!
Spear, go, go!
Don’t let them beat you, Kairyu!
Full speed ahead!
Kairyu?!
Stop!
That was great!
You don’t have to pretend.
Look!
We made it!
It’s the Ruins of the Titan!
Hey, wait! Slow down!
You gotta be tired from flying, right?
Take a rest.
Watch out!
It’s Overheat!
Hihidaruma’s data will be
added to the Index!
Hihidaruma! Blazing Pokémon!
Fire type!
Its internal fire burns at
1,400 degrees,
making enough power that it can
destroy a dump truck with one punch!
That was pretty surprising,
huh, Pikachu, Hibunny?
Hello?
Are you two all right?
The Hitomoshi spoke!
Of course it didn’t.
I’m the chief of
the excavation team!
Hitomoshi is my excavating partner,
who lights our path!
I see...
That was really surprising.
Enchanting, isn’t it?
This area used to be a city long ago.
It’s said that the people created the Titan
to protect the city!
Awesome!
Yeah!
And this is its key!
Enchanting, isn’t it?
I feel like I’ve seen that before,
but I’m not sure...
Chief! We’ve found
another inscription!
Very well! I’ll be right there.
I feel the call... Twinkle!
The call of something
new and enchanting!
You two!
Proceed carefully through the ruins!
There are some enchanting
surprises in store!
Be careful, Pikachu.
Don’t rush either, Hibunny.
A Meguroco!
Meguroco! Desert Croc Pokémon!
Ground/Evil type!
They live hidden under hot desert sands
in order to keep their body temperature from dropping!
Pikachu! Electricity won’t work
on Meguroco!
Hibunny, use Double Kick!
Monster Ball, go!
You did it!
Meguroco’s data will be
added to the Index!
My second Isshu Pokémon!
Was this what the chief meant
by “surprises”?
A Koromori!
All right! I’ll get that one!
This is what he meant
by “surprises”!
Maybe they’re warnings to
stay away from the Titan!
Did you just hear a click?
Don’t tell me...
These ruins are way too intense...
Oh, a Deathmas...
But I’m getting fired up!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
We’ll race to the Titan!
And he’s getting
all hyped up, as usual...
Pikachu, watch out
for the surprises!
Satoshi!
Asanan! Psychokinesis!
Pull him up!
Over here, young man!
It’s you!
All right...
Oh, it’s you two!
Thank you.
I’m Keira! Wherever there’s mystery and adventure,
you’ll find Asanan and I!
Or something!
This inscription seems to be
talking about this emblem.
I came because I wanted to find out
what the Titan was, too.
But you came without any equipment?
Don’t underestimate the ruins!
So, Keira, the surprises...
I mean...
The traps didn’t get you
on the way here?
Of course not! I mean,
they had switches, you know?
These.
Oh, yeah...
If you step on or move these,
the traps will activate.
No!
That’s a switch to a trap!
Quiet!
What’s up?
We didn’t touch anything!
Shh!
Deathkan...
My third Isshu Pokémon!
Wait!
There’s someone inside.
They’ll be turned into mummies!
Mummies?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Golugh
Ghost
Ground
Wait!
Fighting-type moves won’t work
on the Ghost-type Deathkan!
Leave it to us!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
They’re free!
Wham!
Oh, you truly are my savior!
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!
Satoshi, that’s...
A blue Koduck!
I’ve never seen one before!
How do you do? My name is Colovari!
Isn’t my Koduck adorable?
I want to fill out my Pokémon Index with
nothing but alternate-color Pokémon!
Only alternate-color ones?
I have more! Look!
Whoa! They are all
alternate-color!
But it’s a pretty empty list...
I’m just getting started...
There’s more to come!
Koduck is the first Pokémon
I ever caught!
Having your first Pokémon be alternate-color...
feels like destiny, doesn’t it?
So I made up my mind!
I would fill out my Index in a way
nobody has ever done before!
Alternate-color Pokémon
are really rare, you know.
Doesn’t matter! No matter how many years
it takes, I will see it done!
Hey, how’d you know
there was someone in there?
Because the Deathkan’s bodies
were hanging close to the ground.
When they’ve swallowed a person,
the weight makes them droop.
Huh...
There’s nothing here!
Wasn’t this supposed to be the goal?
Perhaps there’s some hidden setup?
Everyone!
What’s up?
See any more of this emblem around?
Here’s one!
I found one too!
There’s one here too.
Five in all...
There’s five circles, too.
Satoshi, push the mark!
But what if another pitfall opens?
It’s fine! Trust me!
Let’s give it a try, Satoshi!
Don’t blame me
if things go wrong!
It started moving!
Was it a trap after all?!
No.
All of you, push them!
I knew it!
This is the emblem of the ruin!
Awesome...
We did it at last...
That’s the Titan!
Golugh is the Titan?!
It’s huge!
Golugh are 2.8 meters tall...
But this one’s easily more than 5 meters!
I deciphered the inscription!
Enchanting...
It’s not “Enchanting”!
It’s a Golugh!
The Titan was a Golugh!
Wh-What’s going on?!
Stop! Stay away!
This is what the inscription said:
“Golugh was a city defense system
the ancient people created”!
It only awakens to battle.
It attacks anything in sight!
Those ancient people were nuts!
Golugh! Golem Pokémon!
Ground/Ghost type!
Some say that ancient people invented Golugh
to serve as a laborer!
It follows its master’s orders faithfully!
How do we...?
They may call it a Titan,
but it’s still a Pokémon!
Interesting... Let’s battle it!
Satoshi! Let’s fight a Raid Battle!
All right, I’m in!
If you’re doing a Raid,
then I’m joining in!
Then I will, too!
It’ll be an enchanting catch!
I think I’ll skip this one...
Fight with us!
I’m an alternate-color
Pokémon collector!
My friend has one of those!
I’ll introduce you!
I will aid you!
Koduck!
Let’s do this, Asanan!
I’m counting on you,
Hitomoshi!
Now things are
really heating up!
Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
H-Huh?
Hey, hey, calm down!
Golugh’s a Ground type,
just like Meguroco!
Oh, right! What a slip-up...
Hibunny,
it’s got the Ghost type too,
so your moves won’t work on it.
Hibunny! Are you okay?
Hitomoshi! Fire Vortex!
Asanan! Psycho Shock!
Koduck! Hydro Pump!
So strong...
Asanan, come back!
Battling is too hard!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
You okay, Pikachu?!
Rest up here.
We still have Kairyu!
Go, Kairyu!
Kairyu! Use Dragon Claw!
Hibunny,
you watch from here!
Next up, I’ll use Spear!
Double Needle!
Spear! Come back!
Go, Warrgle! Air Slash!
Lampler, I’m counting on you!
Flame Burst!
Lampler!
Well then, I’ll use the new partner
I just caught! Hihidaruma!
No hard feelings...
...no matter who catches it!
No way!
It transformed?!
Oh, no! It can’t be!
What?
This might be the ultimate attack
the inscriptions described!
Unleashing light from its body,
the Titan would burn all its foes to ashes!
Burn to ashes?!
I can see why they’d
call it a Titan!
Let’s have Kairyu and Hihidaruma
do a combo attack!
Before it can fire its move,
we’ll finish it off with our attack!
All right!
Kairyu! Hurricane!
Hihidaruma! Overheat!
It’s acting strangely...
It might not be able to go back to normal
after sustaining all that damage!
Golugh!
Sorry for cutting ahead!
Monster Ball, go!
Golugh’s data will be
added to the Index!
Oh, I’m so jealous,
but Golugh is yours, Go!
That was amazing, Go!
Nice, Go!
Kairyu’s battling was amazing!
Your Hihidaruma did great too!
Oh?
Is this...?
This is the ancient city
the Titan was protecting!
Ruins are enchanting!
Perhaps I’ll find an alternate-color
golden Pokémon!
Adventure! Adventure!
Hey, Go!
Shh!
They’re kinda like the guardian deities
of Sakuragi Park, yeah?
Ooh...
So cool!
The adventure in the Isshu Region ended
with an unexpected Raid Battle!
What sort of Pokémon will
Satoshi and Go meet next?
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
There’s some trouble at the institute!
All right, it’s been a while,
so home we go!
For him to come home so suddenly...
Did he cause some sort of trouble?
He was so obsessed with Pokémon,
he was always cooped up at home...
That bone must have been important.
On a Snowy Day,
Where is Karakara's Bone?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
On a Snowy Day,
Where is Karakara’s Bone?