Project Mew, an operation to search for Mew,
is underway.
Go, who hopes to join the search,
must clear various Pokémon-related Trial Missions.
Every successfully cleared mission
nets the participant a token.
The three candidates who obtain
the most tokens will be accepted.
Will Go be able to join the official Mew search team,
and become a Chaser?
It’s here!
A Trial Mission!
Let me see...
“Reach the goal by using
your ingenuity and imagination.”
I can choose from
three missions again, too!
What’re you gonna pick?
Hmm... Good question...
This one!
“Catch a wild Kingdra!”
A Kingdra, huh?
I can catch Pokémon
better than anyone, yeah?!
You’re very confident today.
Go, take a look at
the main monitor.
Kingdra. Dragon Pokémon.
Water/Dragon type.
Kingdra lives at extreme ocean depths
that are otherwise uninhabited.
It is said to create whirlpools
by yawning.
When a Kingdra and a Kairyu meet,
a fierce battle ensues.
Catching a wild Kingdra
is known to be pretty difficult.
Which is why the most common method
of getting one is by trade evolution,
by having a Seadra
hold a Dragon Scale and trading it.
Sounds like it won’t be
a straightforward task.
You sure about this?
Uhh...
You’ll be fine!
You can catch Pokémon
better than anyone, right?
Y-Yeah!
Then, let’s get to it...
Seadra habitats could also be home
to their evolution, Kingdra.
That’s right!
Here we go!
The seas near Hoenn’s Kaina City!
There have even been whirlpool sightings!
Okay, then, off to Hoenn...
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
A Trial Mission!
The Deep Sea Diving Research Team!!
Hoenn Region, here we are!
Hoenn Region
We can go the rest of the way
on our Pokémon!
Okay!
Come on out!
Satoshi, it’s straight ahead!
Tamanta, Dugong, you’re up!
All right!
Let’s take a look around here.
Okay!
One, two...
Lovecus! Rendezvous Pokémon!
Water type!
Lovecus makes its home
in coral reefs in warm seas!
It especially likes sleeping in
the space between Sunnygo’s branches!
Never mind Kingdra...
There’s not even any Seadra.
Guess we’ll have to dive deeper...
Yeah.
One, two...
What are you doing
messing around out here?!
Is that...?
Mr. Gonji!
It’s Genji!
Mr. Genji...
From the Hoenn Elite Four?!
Mm-hmm.
And your name, was it...
Sabashi?
Satoshi...
Oh?
A wild Kingdra?
Yes. Have you seen any
around here?
I have!
Really?
Where?!
One time when I was already deep underwater,
I was caught in a whirlpool, and dragged down even deeper.
That’s the one and only time
I’ve seen a wild Kingdra.
Sounds like it’s way deeper than
we ourselves could dive, then...
We’ve just gotta try harder,
and dive down deeper!
No matter how hard you try,
some things just aren’t possible!
Gonna give up, then?
No way!
I just need to think
if there’s some way to...
Huh?
What is it?
The preface to today’s mission.
“Reach the goal by using
your ingenuity and imagination.”
Yeah, that was it!
So, then...
Mr. Genji,
when you dove down before...
I’ve heard enough.
Very well.
I can lend you my equipment.
You did it, Go!
However!
You have to help out
with my work.
Work?
Treasure hunting!
Keep it coming, keep it coming...
Ahem, ahem...
Mr. Genji...
How’s it going?
No problems yet.
An ancient submarine
from thousands of years ago, huh?
It’d be incredible if we found it!
Yeah!
It feels like we’re wasting time
just standing around here.
Satoshi, get Lucario out!
Huh? Sure, I guess...
Chonchie can send
Supersonic Waves into the sea.
So I’d like you to use Lucario’s Guiding Wave
to investigate what it picks up.
I get it!
Pokémon Radar!
Lucario, you up for it?
The sun’ll be setting soon.
Should we call it quits for today?
Yeah!
What is it?
Did you find something?
Mr. Genji! Keep heading toward
the setting sun!
There might be something there!
Mm-hmm. Got it.
Anything there?
No, nothing of note.
Hmm...?
Hold on...
Oh! Here it is!
It’s the ancient submarine.
What?!
Plus, it’s shaped like a Kingdra.
A Kingdra?
It definitely wasn’t here before...
But it’s too dangerous to stay out
if it gets any darker.
Let’s hold off until tomorrow.
Bring me back!
Right!
That was a great meal...
That was delicious...
It’s so sweet and tasty!
Naturally.
That’s my Hot Moomoo Milk.
But forget about that.
Give this a look.
So that’s the ancient submarine...
But why is it shaped
like a Kingdra?
No idea.
But it seems the ancient civilization
behind the submarine idolized Kingdra.
What’s that?
Oh...
When I was walking Komoru,
I happened to find this vase on the beach.
I looked into it, and found
there’s a legend told about these waters.
Apparently, an ancient submarine sunk here,
with treasure aboard.
Since then, I picked up treasure hunting as a hobby,
whenever I’m not busy with Elite Four duties.
You don’t say...
Once, I had a huge sailboat...
But this small ship works just as well.
Oh, that reminds me...
I found this in the sea...
Mm-hmm.
That’s it, exactly.
You’re pretty lucky yourselves.
You even found
the whole sub, after all.
But, Mr. Genji... What’re you gonna do
after you find the treasure?
Look for the next one.
Huh?
You’d just move on, that easily?
Hmph!
What I’m really looking for
are dreams and adventures.
That’s so cool!
Okay, we have an early day in store.
Let’s get to sleep!
Right!
Huh?
You want me and Satoshi to dive?
I do.
But... are you sure?
You’ve been looking for the treasure
for so long...
It’s your turn to
have your dreams come true.
Go catch that wild Kingdra!
Right!
If the ancient people
used Kingdra as their crest,
we might find some hint
in the submarine!
All right! Let’s start
by searching the sub!
Yeah!
Take these with you!
Even if your hose should fall off,
these will let you breathe for ten minutes.
Thank you!
There it is...
The ancient submarine!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
We’re heading for the submarine.
Be very careful out there.
What’s wrong?
There’s a really strong current...!
A current?
I get it...
The submarine wasn’t always there.
I suppose the current must have carried it here.
That can happen...?!
Go, let’s go!
Right!
A Huntail!
And there’s a Sakurabyss!
And now, a Seadra.
Seadra!
H-Hold on!
What is it?
I saw a Seadra, but I lost it...
A Jilanth...
You okay?
Yeah!
What’s that...?
A treasure chest?!
Maybe you’ll find a hint inside.
It’s just mud...
We shouldn’t give up yet.
A scale?
It’s blue, and it’s really pretty.
That might just be a Dragon Scale.
That reminds me,
if you have a Seadra hold a Dragon Scale...
Seadra?
Okay, time to catc—
Samehada’s data will be
added to the Index!
Whaaa?!
Do you want this?
You could evolve
into a Kingdra, after all.
Here, a present.
You sure?
Yeah.
My mission was
to catch a wild Kingdra.
Hey, do you know
where I might find this guy?
Are you showing us the way?
Mr. Genji!
We want to dive down deeper!
It can’t go any deeper.
Go, look!
Is it in that cave?!
What’s wrong, Seadra?!
What now?
It’s a whirlpool!
I’m pulling you back up!
Please, hold on...
Kingdra could be doing this!
What?!
The Index even says Kingdra
creates whirlpools by yawning!
True...
I’m going to take a look.
Satoshi, you wait for me here!
Huh? Wait for you?!
I thought if I let the whirlpool draw me in,
it might take me to Kingdra.
Do I wait for another whirlpool?
No, I don’t have time...
Oh, when a Kingdra and a Kairyu meet,
a fierce battle ensues!
There it is, a Kingdra!
What now...?
Throwing a Monster Ball
doesn’t work underwater...
I know! You’re up!
Snipe Shot!
Keep firing Snipe Shots!
Dragon Breath?!
Am I no match for it underwater...?!
Satoshi! Uonoragon!
We’re here for you!
Don’t give up!
Right! I have my friends with me!
Come on out, Tamanta!
Use Ice Beam around Kingdra!
Okay, Inteleon!
Let’s use the move
that we’ve been practicing!
Aqua Break!
All right...
Snipe Shot!
We did it!
Kingdra’s data will be
added to the Index!
Oh no, my oxygen...!
I need you to help me out!
Satoshi, hold onto Kingdra!
Okay!
We’re gonna make
a quick escape!
Kingdra! Dragon Breath!
Seadra?
I’ve verified your capture
of a wild Kingdra.
Well done.
Thank you!
Asahi, hurry it up!
Don’t you boss me around.
It’s coming.
So, we finally meet.
I’ve been waiting for this.
The Legendary Pokémon,
Regirock.
All right! The token is here!
Now you’ve got two!
I’ve finally got two, you mean!
So Go, you’re collecting those token things
and trying to join a Mew search project.
Right.
And Satoshi, you entered the Championships,
aiming to become the world’s strongest Pokémon Trainer.
Yeah?
Now there’s dreams and adventures.
You kids’ve gotta hold onto those!
I’ll be chasing dreams and adventures
for the rest of my life, too!
Go passed his second Trial Mission
with flying colors.
However, his next mission has
an even tougher task in store.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Hikari’s Pochama was kidnapped?!
Satoshi! Let’s check it out!
Let’s go!
Commence attack.
Evil Pulse!
Capture them.
Lucario!
Inteleon!
You and I are the same person,
living in different worlds.
That could be an entrance
to another world.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Dialga & Palkia!
The Space-Time Cataclysm!!