Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The ever-recognizable
Sakuragi Institute.
What mysteries could
they be unsealing today?
Renji, what’s that?
It’s finally back from
being repaired...
This is Françoise’s favorite lamp!
Come on, it’s lunchtime!
Does that taste good,
Françoise?
Coil! Magnet Pokémon!
Electric/Steel type!
It subsists on electricity!
As Coil flies, it emits electromagnetic waves
from the units on each side of its body!
Françoise sure is weird...
Yesterday it was eating a fan,
and before that... Was it a phone?
Yeah. Who could imagine it only eats
from retro appliances...
Well, Françoise is a picky eater.
It was a lot worse
when we first met.
Oh? I’d like
to hear about that!
Then I’ll tell you the tale!
This was when Françoise and I–
Huh? A blackout?
It came back on.
The blackout seems to have been
caused by a magnetic storm.
A magnetic storm?
It’s a phenomenon caused by explosions
on the surface of the sun.
They can damage the power grid,
or ruin delicate instruments.
Huh...
Kikuna, everything okay?
That’s what I wanted to ask you!
Is Françoise okay?!
Huh?
Did something happen?
I’ll send you a video.
There’s big trouble
in the city right now.
What happened to you?
What’s going on...?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Your Name is Françoise
What is this...?
It’s receiving
a strange transmission...
That might be the reason
the Coil are behaving oddly.
What is it, Pikachu?
Françoise?!
It’s not listening?
You should put it
in its Monster Ball for now.
Françoise, return!
But why?
Is the strange transmission
causing that, too?
Drastic times call for...
Renji, what is that?!
Tinfoil!
That should block
the transmission!
Tinfoil is amazing!
Still, it’s not like it
can block it out completely...
Hmm...
It looks like strange Coil behavior
has only been reported in central Kuchiba City.
You should be able to avoid the effects
if you head to the outskirts.
Great idea, Director Sakuragi!
How about evacuating
for the time being?
It doesn’t want to?
Well, it’s been getting pickier
and pickier lately.
Now it even wants all its things
to have a retro feel...
Its things too, huh...?
I know!
What?
I covered up
the tinfoil with a hat.
What is that thing?
A doorknob cover.
I guess kids these days
haven’t heard of them.
Then let’s go!
Come on out, Kairyu!
Flygon!
All right!
Get on, Renji!
Huh? Ride that?
We’ll get to
the outskirts in no time!
Huh? Ride that?
I didn’t know you were
scared of heights, Renji...
I thought I’d be
able to tough it out,
but I’m so scared
I’m starting to feel faint...
If it’s getting to you,
you should think about something else.
Something else?
Tell me that tale from earlier!
Oh, how Françoise and I met...
It all began the first
time I went into that café.
Welcome!
This is a very calming place.
Thank you.
I love antiques, and can’t
resist collecting them.
A Coil... Is it yours?
No. It’s just started coming
to this café lately.
For whatever reason,
it seems to love that chandelier.
Huh...
Wild Coil usually eat
from power lines.
You’re pretty unique.
Guys!
It’s a Coil...
Think it’s gonna attack?
We better not provoke it.
Hey, Go! Look to your side!
When did they get here?!
Hold on, this might not be
the best time for talking...
Let’s get out of here!
Right!
Françoise!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
You okay?
They ate the Electric Net!
There’s more coming
from behind us!
Ahh! They look really mad!
They want Françoise!
Huh? Why?
They might be trying
to force it to join them.
Not a chance! I’m not letting
Françoise end up like that!
Okay.
Kairyu, use Hurricane!
Satoshi!
You go on ahead!
I’ll hold them back!
Got it!
Let’s go, Flygon!
Kairyu,
use Hurricane again!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
We stand out
too much in the air.
Thanks, Flygon.
We can’t make any dumb moves...
Okay... Renji!
Hey!
Follow me!
Thank you, Go.
Let’s go, Françoise!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Coil
Steel
Electric
I can’t find any
other similar cases.
How about you, Kikuna?
Right. I nearly have
this narrowed down...
Found it!
The strange transmission is coming
from above the city...
Wait, it’s coming from...
...space!
Go, Aceburn!
We’ll be too exposed
if we keep going.
What do I do...?
Hey, stop that!
It’s really made
this place its home.
I could say the same thing
for you, Mr. Renji.
Well, it’s so comfortable here!
Don’t you agree?
Oh, now that’s unusual.
Hey, welcome.
What do you think of this?
Oh...
No interest, huh?
It’s not too cramped in there,
is it, Françoise?
We’d stick out
if we started running.
Let’s just walk past them.
Oh, no!
Hurricane!
They just keep coming...!
But we can’t let ‘em pass!
After them, Flygon!
This is hopeless...
Françoise...
Okay!
Supersonic Waves!
Are they gone?
That café...
And so, please forgive me.
But I have to
close down the café.
Is that so...?
But I worry about
that little one.
If only I had the means
to look after it myself.
In that case,
may I take it in?
That’s... My, thank you.
Oh, of course. If you’d like,
you may take that lamp too.
Since the day
you offered it that lamp,
it’s taken a liking to it.
Please use it
to make it a new home.
You need to start
eating something...
What a mess...
I know you loved that chandelier,
but I never imagined you’d
refuse everything else...
It’s such a lovely lamp, though.
Just give it a try...
Look, it’s snowing.
Hey, wait!
Oh, come on...
Just a little bit further now...
Oh dear...
Françoise!
Don’t worry about me!
Just run for it!
Françoise...
No...
Renji!
Sorry we’re late!
Where’s Françoise?
Up there?!
Give Françoise back!
They’re sticking together!
Are their magnets going haywire?!
No...
They’re evolving!
Huh? But...
Coil’s only evolutions are Rarecoil
and Jibacoil, yeah?!
As far as we know.
But there’s so much we don’t know
about Pokémon’s capabilities.
Absolutely anything could happen.
Huh?
Then it could be some
never-seen-before Hyper-Rare–
No, Ultra-Rarecoil?!
Director Sakuragi.
We found the source
of the transmission.
A man-made satellite malfunctioned
in the magnetic storm earlier,
and started transmitting
at the Kuchiba City area all on its own.
A man-made satellite?!
The Space Center is trying
to shut it down right now.
We might not have time
to wait for that!
Huh?
The Coil forced Françoise
to join them!
They’re turning into
a Hyper-Ultra-Rare-Rare-Rarecoil!
What could that mean?
Perhaps the transmission happened to be something
that induces Coil to evolve, by chance.
But it overloaded them...
So they sought out even
more peers than usual,
and they’re trying to fuse
into an ultimate form.
But if that happens,
Françoise will never come back.
I’ll stop them!
I need to get Françoise back,
somehow...
Renji...
Satoshi! Have Pikachu
use 100,000 Volts!
Huh?
Evolution requires energy.
When the Coil see Pikachu’s tasty-looking
electricity, they’ll jump at it.
Except for one picky eater
who only likes retro appliances...
I get it!
Okay! Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Right now, all I can do
is trust Françoise.
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
We did it!
They’re still not stopping?!
Renji!
Hey! Hey!
It couldn’t be...
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Where could you be?
There you are.
Look at the state I’m in
from searching for you.
You really must’ve loved
that chandelier.
And if it was within my power,
I’d love to grant your wish.
But for now, do you think you
can make do with this lamp?
Focus on eating and
getting your strength back,
then we can look for
that chandelier together.
Hey... Would you mind
if I called you Françoise?
F-Françoise...
You... are Françoise...
It’s back to normal.
It’s a miracle.
Welcome home.
Was it a miracle?
Or was it the exact moment
the transmission shut down?
Either way, the rampage of the Coil
had come to an end.
And...
Welcome back, manager!
Thanks to your support,
I was able to open this place again.
More than anything,
I’m glad to see you’re doing well.
Oh, Françoise!
Françoise?
Oh, I do apologize.
I borrowed the name
of your café...
I see...
Well then, I hope the two of you enjoy your stay
here at Café Françoise.
We will!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Kaiross is acting weird?
Yeah...
She’s been really depressed
since a romantic rival showed up...
I want to cheer Kaiross on!
Hey! Have you heard
of Pokémon Flower Arranging?
You can beautifully decorate
Pokémon using flowers!
Decorating Pokémon
with flowers...
That’s it!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Heracross Loss,
Lovey-Dovey Kaiross