The final Promotion Battle before the start
of the Masters Tournament is nearly upon us.
The match-up is between
the following two...
Currently ranked 8th,
the strongest Gym Leader in Galar’s Pokémon League,
and a user of Dragon types: Competitor Kibana.
His opponent
is currently ranked 9th...
...and climbing the ranks with incredible momentum.
The promising new star from Kanto: Competitor Satoshi.
Satoshi’s amazing!
Look at all the attention he’s getting!
‘Course he is!
The Championships are
a worldwide tournament, after all.
This is really cool.
Imagine if he ends up winning the whole thing.
It wouldn’t exactly be easy.
After all,
he’s facing the Masters Eight.
The Champion, Competitor Dande,
had some words to say about their battle.
They’re both strong trainers,
with strong Pokémon.
I’m sure we’ll get to see a heated battle
far beyond our expectations.
Their battle will be...
...one we should all make
every effort to enjoy!
I’m getting really excited!
By the way,
where is Satoshi?
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Great work, Negigaknight!
Gänger! Shadow Ball!
Uonoragon, use Jaw Bite!
Lucario! Shadow Clones!
Kairyu, use Hurricane!
He’s hard at work!
That’s really intense...
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Hey!
We brought you some snacks!
How about a break?
Oh, thanks!
Nice timing!
Let’s have a break, everyone!
Lucario’s really raring to go!
Yeah!
I know exactly what
Lucario’s thinking!
He still wants to get stronger!
Eevee?!
What?
Even Keromatsu
is battling, huh?
It’s evolving!
Gekogashira’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Ooh...
Lucario!
Let’s go see him!
Let’s go see Gekkouga!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Lucario and Gekkouga!
The Guiding Waves of Destiny!!
Satoshi and Go
decided to visit Gekkouga,
so that Lucario may yet
improve himself even more.
Their destination:
the Kalos Region.
Gekkouga! Shinobi Pokémon!
Water/Evil type!
It creates shuriken
out of compressed water!
When it spins them and throws them at high speed,
they can split metal in two!
That’s so cool!
So... I get that you traveled
across Kalos with Gekkouga,
but why take Lucario to him?
Back then,
when I got all fired up battling,
it was like I became Gekkouga
and Gekkouga became me!
Huh?
And the way Lucario’s Guiding Waves feel
kinda reminds me of that.
So I wanna have them meet up!
What do you think, Lucario?
Whoa, it’s the real Kibana!
Knuckle City, Galar Region
Ah...!
Thank you so much!
Mr. Kibana!
It’s my dream to be a trainer just like you!
Is it, now?
Keep at it!
I will!
We’ll come and cheer for you
at your next battle!
Win the match for us, please!
You think I’d ever lose?
That trainer who wowed Dande...
Never thought
he’d rise up this quickly.
“Win the match for us, please!”, huh?
That was a great battle!
Let’s have another one sometime!
What a pathetic face...
How could I let myself...?
I can’t forget that regret.
That’s why I started taking selfies.
I’ll be the one to topple Dande.
I’ve come too far
to lose now.
Let’s go! Duraludon!
Kalos Region
So... Where is Gekkouga?
Somewhere in this forest!
H-Hey, hold on!
After all that,
we didn’t find him.
Is Gekkouga really even here?
He is!
I know he is!
Gekkouga and me...
We’re always connected,
even if we’re apart.
Keromatsu was the first Pokémon
I caught when I arrived in Kalos,
and we got stronger together
as we traveled.
At one point we even fought,
‘cause I was too focused on winning a battle...
But we made peace again.
After that, we made it all the way
to the Kalos League finals.
Then, Gekkouga stayed here
to protect Kalos.
I bet he’s gotten
a lot stronger since.
I hope we find him soon.
Yeah!
It’s Gekkouga!
Lucario, did you feel that, too?
Huh? What?
Lucario!
Satoshi! Wait for me!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Satoshi!
What is all this?!
Go!
Gekkouga!
Let’s go, Gekkouga!
Shadow Clones!
Whoa...
I can feel it...
There!
Water Shuriken!
Gekkouga!
How’ve you been?!
Gekkouga...
He really is cool...
Have a battle with us!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gekkouga
Evil
Water
We wanna get stronger!
Gekkouga! If we can battle you,
I just know we’ll learn something!
You’ll do it?
All right! Here we go, Lucario!
How’s this battle going to go?
Lucario! To your right!
Your left!
I didn’t see a thing...
Shadow Clones!
They both used Shadow Clones?!
Lucario!
Stop, Lucario!
You want to Mega Evolve?
All right...
Lucario!
Lucario...
Gekkouga...
Satoshi, you’re not going to
chase after Lucario?
Nah!
We can leave this to Gekkouga!
...Lucario and Gekkouga are similar?
Yeah.
They’ve both been all about getting stronger
since I met them.
I heard their feelings loud and clear.
Huh...
And not through words...
They rang out loud,
deep in here!
I wonder how far they went...
They’ll come back soon.
There are more?!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Aceburn, use Pyro Ball!
100,000 Volts!
It’s bigger than the one from before!
Not good...
Gekkouga! Lucario!
All right! Shadow Clones!
Gekkouga, you use Slicing Draw!
Go!
I can feel them!
Lucario’s Guiding Waves!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Not enough!
Let’s go, Lucario!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
Shadow Clones!
Incredible teamwork!
Gekkouga, go for it!
Lucario, we can do this!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
That’s it, Lucario!
More... Give it more!
Now!
Wh-Whoa...
You did it!
Wai— Lucario!
Thank you, Gekkouga.
See you again someday.
Take care of yourself ‘til then!
He’s already gone...
Even if we’re far apart...
I’m always connected
to Gekkouga.
Same for you, Lucario!
Satoshi has witnessed Lucario
improve himself even more.
And his opponent is...
I’ll be the one to topple Dande
and become Champion!
Satoshi and Kibana!
They’re about to clash
for a seat in the Masters Eight!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Masters Eight Promotion Match!
It’s here!
You’re facing Mr. Kibana.
You do have a plan, right?
Yeah!
I’ll go “Boom!”, and I’ll go “Bash!”,
and “Whoosh-whoosh-whoosh!”...
You’ll need more than that to beat—
“Bam! Ba-bam! Shiiing!”
...and I’ll win for sure!
S-Sure...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
VS Kibana!
The Battle for the Masters Eight!!