Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Don’t let any Pokémon Hunters
capture you again.
I’ve never seen
that look on your face before.
The Alolan Kyukon
should be fine now.
Any leads on the Hunters?
We’ve found them.
We’ll head their way next.
Aren’t you curious about the trainer
who caught that Kyukon?
It was your choice to pass him
after he got disqualified, right?
So, what?
Nothing. He’s about to start
his first Trial Mission.
Whatever.
Oh, please.
He’s obviously curious.
Ooh! It’s here, it’s here!
My first Trial Mission
from Project Mew is here!
So? What’s it say?
Umm... “Reach the goal by making
full use of a variety of Pokémon.”
Huh? There’s three of them!
Huh?
Three?
It says I can choose
whichever one I like.
Hmm...
Okay, I pick this one!
“Gather Ulgamoth’s golden scales!”
Ulgamoth, huh...?
Wait...
But what’s it mean by
“golden scales”...?
That would appear to be
the key to this mission.
Kikuna, display its Index data
on the main monitor.
Right away.
Ulgamoth. Sun Pokémon.
Bug/Fire type.
It hatches from a cocoon
formed of raging flames.
It uses its six wings to scatter its Ember scales,
igniting a sea of fire that engulfs its surroundings.
So those Ember scales
are golden?
Or maybe it really does scatter
scales made of gold sometimes.
They must want you
to figure that out, and clear the mission.
Okay!
The place with the most
info about Ulgamoth...
It’s the Resort Desert in Isshu!
Oh, isn’t that where...?
Yeah! Where I caught Golugh
at the Ruins of the Titan!
And there was a golden room there!
So there could be an Ulgamoth
with golden scales, too!
That’s great!
Then let’s head straight to Isshu!
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
A Trial Mission!
Ulgamoth's Golden Scales!!
Resort Desert, Isshu Region
Go and Satoshi have arrived
at the Ruins of the Titan in Isshu...
...to attempt Project Mew’s
first Trial Mission.
It’s gold and shiny!
Ruins truly are enchanting!
Chief!
We’re looking for Ulgamoth!
Go looked it up and saw that
there were tons of sightings around here!
Hmm... All of that ended
a few days ago, though.
Huh?
Did something happen?
Pokémon Hunters.
They’ve been using cruel methods
to capture Pokémon nearby.
Ulgamoth seems to have
stopped visiting because of that.
That’s awful!
But my excavation team have made
an enchanting Ulgamoth-related discovery!
A mural with Ulgamoth...
I wonder what it says...
“When the rage of the mountain
swallows the sky,
“the god of fire shall appear,
to save those suffering from cold.”
The god of fire...
Does that mean Ulgamoth?
I think so.
And if the “rage of the mountain”
means an erupting volcano,
then maybe Ulgamoth
is in a volcanic area!
Indeed.
Past these ruins, there’s a town founded in the gold rush,
which was sealed off when a volcano erupted.
You might find something
enchanting there!
Let’s check it out!
Yeah!
The whole town is falling apart...
Is there really anything
“enchanting” here?
There’s just a huge volcano...
Is this a tunnel
they used to mine gold?
Let’s move, Go!
Naturally!
Oh, it’s just some Koromori...
A-Anyway,
I thought this might happen!
So I came prepared, yeah!
Is something there?
A Dangoro?
Dangoro! Mantle Pokémon!
Rock type!
It was discovered a hundred years ago in
an earthquake fissure in a layer of exposed rock!
The material that makes up its body
is dirt from several hundred years ago!
You can leave this battle to me!
Stop! I’ll do it.
Dangoro is a Rock-type,
so I’ll use you, a Water-type!
Inteleon! Snipe Shot!
It worked!
Monster Ball, go!
Dangoro’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Something’s coming!
It’s a horde of Dangoro!
Run for it!
Satoshi!
Okay!
The rails are gone!
Inteleon,
aim for the points lever!
Y-You saved us...
Good work, Inteleon!
It looks like an elevator.
Maybe if it still had electricity...
In that case...
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Just what we needed,
Pikachu!
It took us to a big, open place.
What’s that?!
Nutrey! Thorn Pod Pokémon!
Grass/Steel type!
Its spikes are harder than steel!
If I’m fighting a Grass/Steel type...
I’ll use you, a Fire type!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
It’s super effective!
Go! Monster Ball!
All right!
That’s your second catch today!
Yeah! Thank you, Aceburn!
Oh, thanks for the help.
I’m studying the wild Pokémon
living in this area.
We’re research fellows
at Sakuragi Institute.
I’m Satoshi!
And I’m Go!
So you’re here to investigate too?
Yes. We’re looking for Ulgamoth.
Oh... Actually,
I’m looking for Ulgamoth too.
What do you say?
Why not come with me?
Sure!
That’s okay, right, Go?
S-Sure...
Okay, it’s a deal.
Where are we...?
It’s like a train station...
It’s a mining railway station.
Back during the gold rush,
these tunnels led to the next mine over.
You really know a lot.
Wha—? Oh, not at all...
What are these?
Eggs!
I wonder what eggs these are...
Lemme have a look.
These are probably Melarva eggs.
Melarva will hatch from them
and evolve into Ulgamoth.
Are the eggs gonna be okay
just left here on their own, though?
Oh! Then Ulgamoth
might be here!
So it can protect the eggs!
Of course!
Yeah. So before it comes back...
...I better get outta here
with these eggs!
Sticky Web!
What’re you doing?!
While I was catching
all the Pokémon ‘round here,
Ulgamoth managed to get away.
But if I sell all these eggs,
I’ll make plenty of money!
You’re a Pokémon Hunter?!
You just sit tight there...
...‘til I’ve taken all of these eggs!
We’d never let you!
You...!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Stop!
Shut it.
You just wait patiently there
‘til I’m finished.
There could be
more eggs down there...
Melarva!
Two of them!
They’ll fetch a good price...
Dentula! Sticky Web!
Argh, dammit!
How do you like this, then?!
There’s another one?
Gah! I give up on the Melarva!
Give those eggs back!
Don’t you see
the Melarva are mad?!
These are valuable!
Who’d give them up?
The eggs are gonna
end up burning!
The Melarva are
going crazy with rage!
We’re in danger, too!
No, this could be good!
I get it!
Nearly there...
Satoshi, get the eggs.
I’ll stop the Melarva!
Okay!
Stop, Melarva!
If you keep going,
you’ll burn the eggs!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
You still wanna fight?!
You’ll regret this!
Go!
Look! They’re right here!
Your eggs are safe!
So please, stop!
Don’t!
Stop! You have to stop, Melarva!
Watch out, Go!
You understood?
Here, we’re giving the eggs back.
Sorry about this, Melarva.
But... Go...
If this keeps burning...
Right!
You’re up!
I choose you!
Inteleon, use Snipe Shot!
Crab, use Bubble Beam!
Uonoragon! Water Gun!
It’s not working...?
One more try!
That’s the one from the tunnel!
It’s alternate-color...?!
It’s evolving...?!
A golden Ulgamoth!
The flames are being sucked
into the Fire Vortex!
Wow!
It’s gone...
Are these...
the golden scales?
Go!
Right!
I got Ulgamoth’s golden scales!
You did it, Go!
That’s a strong wind...
Good work.
You again...!
You were still here?!
Of course!
The eggs, the Melarva, and a super-rare golden Ulgamoth...
I’d never give up on those!
How do you...?!
I was watching.
That would sell for a fortune.
So I waited here.
Even called in some friends.
Hand over all
the Pokémon you have.
I’ll make sure they all get sold.
You’re awful...
You’re not getting away with this!
I’m not, am I?
Sludge Bomb!
What’s wrong?
Weren’t you gonna stop me?
You’re so pitiful.
Ms. Asahi!
But the most pitiful things here
are the Pokémon doing your dirty work.
Right.
The Pokémon aren’t to blame.
Mr. Tsurugi!
And who are you?
Their friends?
Zip it. Your words foul the air.
What?!
Let’s get this started.
I’ll take those three.
Don’t you belittle me...
Hit ‘em with Crunch!
Use Poison Jab!
Go, Wulaosu!
You, too!
Pouring Strikes!
Wulaosu! Dark Blow!
Two Wulaosu!
And that one’s different from
Mr. Tsurugi’s Single Strike Form!
Wulaosu! Rapid Strike Form! Martial Arts Pokémon!
Fighting/Water type!
It’s believed that this Pokémon modeled its fighting style
on the flow of a river—sometimes rapid, sometimes calm!
You’re both okay?
Yeah!
Go, you chose
the golden scales, right?
Did you get them?
Yes... Here they are!
Confirmed.
You’ve cleared the mission.
Really?!
That’s great, Go!
The token arrived!
That’s only one single token.
As you know, you’ll need to
collect a lot more in order to pass.
I’ll do my best!
But we needed you guys
to save us again...
I don’t remember rescuing you.
We dealt with hunters
who only think of Pokémon as goods to sell.
That was all.
Right!
Go! Satoshi!
Professor Hodaka!
We’ll take charge of delivering
the hunters to Ms. Junsa.
What about their Pokémon?
We’ll look after them temporarily,
and later return them to the wild.
That’s great.
Yeah!
Go, you just get ready for next time.
And don’t worry about anything, okay?
Right!
Go has spectacularly cleared
his first Trial Mission for Project Mew.
Now then, what sort of challenge will he
face in his next mission?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Roentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Roentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Roentorar
Electric!
Showers
Roentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Blue Pokémania?
Do they like blue Pokémon?
Hey, guys! You should do Aokatsu!
Aokatsu?
It means blue Pokémon-related activities!
Stop right there!
You haven’t done nearly enough
to call yourself a maniac!
Another one turned up!
What is all this?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Clash?! Blue Pokémania!