Today, Satoshi and his Pokémon...
...once again continue their training
for the Masters Tournament.
Looking good, everyone!
You’ve got it!
Looks like
it’s all coming together.
Still more to go!
I’ve gotta help them
get a lot faster and even more powerful!
I see.
But what specifically
do you plan to do?
I’m gonna get all fired up,
and so are they!
Huh?
But... how exactly?
Like I said, we’ll get fired up...
Incoming call from the Professor.
Hello.
Hey, Satoshi!
Professor Okido!
You should come by sometime.
All of your Pokémon are—
That’s it!
I know where we can go
to get fired up!
Okido Laboratory, Kanto Region
Go! I heard from Shigeru.
You managed to get into Project Mew?
Congratulations!
That’s right, thank you!
We better keep up!
Oh, Bayleaf!
You been doing good?
Thanks for the grand welcome!
All right!
Come on out, everyone!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
A Fire Training Battle!
Satoshi VS Shinji!!
Everyone,
I’ve got something to announce!
There’s this huge tournament coming up
called the Masters Tournament,
and we’re gonna battle in it.
We’re gonna win, win, win,
and win our way
to battling the Champion, Mr. Dande!
So I want you guys to
share your power with us!
Amazing!
Such passionate cheers!
I took in your power,
you guys!
Gänger!
Elecible!
That was your Gänger?
Shinji!
Huh? What?
You okay?
It’s hot!
Huh? How come?
Gänger’s always cold to the touch...
Huh? It is cold...
Huh?
H-Huh? You’re right...
You’re hopeless.
At least try to understand
your partner’s condition.
I do understand!
Satoshi, do you know him?
Yeah, he’s a rival I battled again and again,
back when I was on my journey around Sinnoh.
His name’s Shinji.
Nice to meet you...
My name’s Go.
Is it just me,
or is he kinda scary?
He’s always like this.
Satoshi! Go!
Professor Okido!
Professor!
Shinji’s here!
You see,
I thought to surprise you.
Huh?
Shinji happened to turn up yesterday,
just out of the blue.
Professor Okido is the leading authority
on Pokémon research.
Anyone wanting to learn all they can
about Pokémon would visit him.
There’s nothing strange about it.
You gonna train together?
We should, too...
Leave it to your Pokémon.
That’s what this place is for.
I’ll go watch over them!
Satoshi, you must have plenty
to catch up on with Shinji!
Yeah!
Goukazaru, you go with them.
Take care of Gänger,
Goukazaru.
Goukazaru listens to
Shinji’s orders, too...?
Yeah, he used to be
Shinji’s Pokémon.
What?!
Shinji, a trainer that Satoshi met
in the Sinnoh Region.
He put his Hikozaru through harsh training
time and time again,
but eventually
abandoned him as a failure.
Satoshi befriended
that same Hikozaru,
cared deeply for him,
and led him to evolve into a Goukazaru.
What a history...
Yeah.
Goukazaru’s sure gotten stronger.
Hey, Sarunori!
Elecible, go play with them.
Gamagaru and Fukamaru
really like cuddling up to you.
Ooh! Are the Fire-type Pokémon
teaching Gänger a new move?
Quite a novel discovery!
You didn’t participate
in the Championships, Shinji?
I’m not one for festivities.
Then why don’t we
take advantage of the moment?
Battle me!
Oh, there he goes!
3v3 with no switching.
Okay!
But...
Only use Pokémon you’re using
in the Masters Tournament.
Okay!
I’ll call everyone over!
Good, good.
Hey! Gänger!
Thanks, Goukazaru!
Gänger, that was
Will-O-Wisp, wasn’t it?
Satoshi...
He accomplished it thanks to
Goukazaru and the others’ advice.
They are truly
dependable mentors.
I see.
Thanks, Goukazaru.
And thank you, everyone!
Let’s go, Shinji!
Lucario! I choose you!
Stand by for battle!
Gyarados!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mijumaru
Water
Lucario! Shadow Clones!
Ice Fang!
Not even close!
Destroyer Beam!
Now’s your chance!
He won’t be able to move for a while
after Destroyer Beam.
This is Satoshi’s chance.
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Charge in!
Lucario!
Ice Fang!
What’s that?
Lucario, is that...?
That’s it... Come on!
Destroyer Beam!
Now! Bullet Punch!
All right!
You did well.
Thank you.
Your Bullet Punch was awesome.
Professor, what was that?
Its Steel-type energy blazed up
from being backed into a corner,
and let it activate Bullet Punch.
Next up, Kairyu!
I choose you!
Stand by for battle,
Gaburias!
Gaburias next, huh?
Dragon Claw!
We’ll use Dragon Claw, too!
Equally matched...
Are you sure?
Stone Edge!
Hurricane!
Such incredible power...
Draco Meteor!
We’ll use Draco Meteor, too!
Kairyu!
Charge in with the Draco Meteor!
Here come his crazy tactics!
Dragon Claw!
Kairyu!
He lost...
Nevertheless, that Draco Meteor
was quite an interesting strategy.
Kairyu, you were
really cool out there.
Take a rest!
Did you see that, Shinji?
I call that Dra-Kairyu Meteor!
How tacky.
It’s cool!
‘Cause I think it’s cool!
Stand by for battle,
Metagross!
Metagross, huh?
Huh? Shinji’s Pokémon...
Gyarados, Gaburias, Metagross...
This time...
Gänger, I choose you!
They’re really excited.
They’re about to see
the results of their training.
Gänger! Goukazaru and the others
are watching! Give it your all!
Agility!
Shadow Ball!
Psychokinesis!
Gänger!
You call yourself
one of the Masters Eight?!
If you’re struggling against me,
then you’ll have no hope of winning.
Comet Punch!
Can you keep going, Gänger?
That’s right, Gänger!
We have everyone from the lab on our side!
Let’s show it to Shinji!
Will-O-Wisp!
Ooh, it’s started!
I get it! It felt hot before
because it was awakening a new move!
Do it!
All right! It worked!
Comet Punch!
Is the burn affecting us?
Now! Shadow Ball!
We did it!
All right, Satoshi won!
You did it, Gänger!
Goukazaru, Lizardon, all you guys...
Thank you!
You did well.
Um...
Your three Pokémon were all aces
of the Masters Eight, weren’t they?
Gyarados is Mr. Wataru’s...
Gaburias is Ms. Shirona’s...
Metagross is Mr. Daigo’s...
Was that really a coincidence?
Professor,
thank you for everything.
With that, I’ll be off.
You can come back whenever.
Right. Then excuse me.
See you again, Goukazaru.
Let’s go, Elecible.
Shinji!
Let’s battle again sometime!
He’s way too cool, yeah.
Apparently, Shinji has been asked
to become a Gym Leader.
A Gym Leader?!
And that is the reason
he wanted to learn more about Pokémon.
Professor...
I’m glad I came back.
Thanks to everyone,
I’m all fired up now!
I’m gonna go all the way
and even beat Mr. Dande!
Go! Let’s head to
the Masters Tournament right now!
Yeah!
Satoshi!
Mom!
When’d you get here?
Partway through your battle.
Huh? You saw it?!
You must be tired
from all your battling.
You should sleep at home tonight.
You’re welcome too, Go. Okay?
I-Is that okay, Satoshi?
For me to intrude...
It’s fine, it’s fine!
Thanks, Mom.
His traveling companions
he hadn’t seen in a while...
...and his battle with his rival Shinji
have stoked the fire in Satoshi and company even more.
Next time, the curtain finally rises
on the Masters Tournament!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Masters Tournament
is finally starting!
I’m surrounded by all these amazing people...
Next stop:
Our battle with Mr. Dande!
Pikachu, let’s go all out!
Go for it, Satoshi!
I’ll be cheering for you!
Yeah!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Curtain Rises!
The Masters Tournament!!