Hey...
You get the feeling we’re lost?
How’d we even end up like this?
Was this our fate... all along?
Kojiro... Nyarth... Fare—
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Farewell! The Team Rocket Wanderers!
One week earlier...
This is a factory in Kuchiba City.
Y’know, I really hate these
fiddly little jobs we take...
Our operation funds
have hit rock bottom.
We don’t have a choice.
Sometimes I wonder, meow... What’s our career?
Part-time work, or Team Rocket, meow?
Oh... I’m so tired.
Huh?
Hey! Pikachu!
The brat boys!
Now’s our chance!
You’re mine, meow!
Pikachu!
Ta-daah!
Team Rocket!
Pikachu, we gotchu!
Not on my watch!
Lucario, I choose you!
Aceburn, go!
Straight from Team Rocket HQ...
Vending, come on!
Rocket...
Vending...
Sakaki’s grinning...
Secret!
What’re we gonna get?!
The Slacker Pokémon, Namakero!
The Lazy Pokémon, Kekking!
Hold on a sec!
“It’s fittingly titled the Slacker Pokémon”?!
And this one’s
the world’s laziest Pokémon!
Don’t worry, meow!
Hmm?
When they unleash all the energy
they’ve stored up while lazing around,
it’ll be super powerful, meow!
I like the sound of that!
So, what moves can they use?
Slack Off!
What’s your deal?!
You were supposed to attack!
Attack!
Huh?
We’re gonna go first, then!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
What an awful feeling!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow...
Does this mean Matori’s going to
lecture us again?
I’m so sick of
writing apologies, meow...
“Why do you continue to fail?
“Go reflect on why you failed.”
Shut up,
you bowl-headed four-eyes!
Come to think of it, our vending Pokémon
were completely useless today.
Right, meow!
We failed because of
the vending Pokémon, meow!
Hey, you.
Whaddaya got to say for yourself?
Why didn’t we get cooler Pokémon?
“The machine comes down to luck.
“Sometimes you get good pulls,
sometimes you get bad ones.
“To change your luck
is to change your life.”?
“Everyone has equal opportunities.”?
Where’d all this deep
smarty-pants junk come from?
What’s wrong with you?!
Wait, meow!
I know!
If we follow it, it might lead us
to whoever fills that machine at HQ!
I’m not gonna be happy
till I give ‘em a piece of my mind!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
Ahh, if only I could soar on the wind
and roam as free as these clouds...
Thinking about it, all we’ve done recently
is missions, missions, lectures, lectures...
Apologies, apologies...
And it wears you out,
doesn’t it...?
What a great feeling...
Huh?
The Cotton Bird Pokémon,
Tyltto, meow!
The blue bird Pokémon
that brings happiness!
That sounds great!
We’ll catch that Tyltto
and catch us some happiness!
This is bound to improve our luck!
Here goes!
It’s using Dragon Breath, meow!
What an awful feeling!
At least the sea broke our fall...
What a great feeling...
Huh... Should’ve known
the Water Bird Pokémon Pelipper could swim.
Who cares?
Just chase it, meow!
Go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
It’s a Whaloh, meow!
Musashi!
Nyarth!
Sonansu!
So, we’re inside Whaloh right now?
I don’t want to think we are,
but... probably.
We’re lucky to still be alive
after being swallowed up like that, meow.
How come you’re having fun
swimming around?!
Ing around!
Huh? What?
What!
Is somebody there?
Body there!
Who’s that?
The Music Note Pokémon,
Perap, meow.
Music Note? Perap?
Perap says it’s been living here
ever since it got swallowed, too, meow.
Ever since?
How long’s it been here?
As long as this ship has?!
Wha...?!
This rusted heap?
That had to have been ages ago!
If worst comes to worst,
we might end up looking like this...
No! Anything but that!
There’s gotta be something
we can do...
That’s it!
Pelipper still has
the Rocket Vending in its mouth!
I get it! There have to be some
super cool Pokémon in there, meow!
So we use those Pokémon to escape!
You wanna get outta here too,
don’t you?
Open up, you stubborn...!
“My mission is delivering
the Rocket Vending to agents who need it!
“Until then,
I’m never letting it out of my mouth.”?!
Drop the cool guy act, will ya?!
We’re agents who need it!
Open up!
All right!
We made it out!
What a great feeling, meow.
Great feeling, meow!
So, where are we?
All I see is ice...
I’m freezing, meow...
Freezing, meow!
Bet you’re glad
you finally got out!
Pelipper!
We couldn’t have done it
without you! Thanks a ton!
Huh?
Weren’t we following Pelipper...?
Right, meow!
Hold it, meow!
Wait for us!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow...
A Mammoo, meow!
How did things
end up like this, meow?
Just hang on,
this won’t take long.
Well, we lost Pelipper...
But I can see a village, meow.
But I’m so hungry
I’m losing my grip...
A-A warm firepla—
Freshly baked brea—
S-Some nice, hot sou—
Where are we?
What’s wrong, Musashi?
What’s that?
So much food!
Let’s dig in!
This tastes great!
It’s warming me up!
You don’t have to be
in such a hurry to eat.
There’s plenty more
where that came from.
Oh, this is the best!
I don’t know who you are,
but we owe you our lives!
Huh? Where have I...?
Even if you asked,
usually I would never answer...
...but why don’t I consider this
an exception?
Even if you ask us
about “this” or “that”...
Usually, we would never answer.
But let’s consider this an exception!
To protect the Earth from devastation.
To preserve the Earth’s peace.
Championing love and sincere evil.
We’re the cute, naughty villains.
Yamato!
Kosaburo!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the universe!
Like shocking pink,
a rosy tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding!
Yamato?!
What are you doing
all the way out here?
Oh, I know!
You’re carrying out a Team Rocket mission
at this very moment, right?
Oh, you dummies.
I quit all that.
You quit? Never!
Team Rocket’s
not all there is to life.
Team Rocket’s...
...nyot all there is to life?
I was an elite,
nothing like you three,
but eventually I just got tired of the daily routine
of missions, lectures, and apologies.
Just like me, meow...
Now I’m running a café
and doing wood carving as a hobby.
Well, you can rest up here
until you’ve recovered your strength.
No way we’re doing that!
We’re gonna work hard to repay you
for saving us, till we can call it even!
If you really want.
A meal after a hard day’s work...
What a great feeling!
I wouldn’t mind
living like this.
Yeah.
But how did we end up here
in the first place?
Hmm...
Right, meow!
We were chasing Pelipper, meow!
We’ve repaid Yamato enough by now,
so let’s get after it!
Hold on!
We’re not even saying goodbye?
Huh?
Oh, it’s just...
After she took such good care of us,
it seems rude to just abandon her...
Kojiro. If you want to stay here,
don’t let us stop you.
Huh?
I saw you and Yamato
carving one of the crown caps you love.
I’ve never seen you
look so happy before, meow.
Oh, no, that was...
Team Rocket’s
nyot all there is to life.
You’ve worked so hard
for so long.
Kojiro! Farewell!
Musashi! Nyarth! Sonansu!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pelipper
Flying
Water
What’s this?
“Here, where the Ground-type ends
and the Water-type begins.”
So this is land’s end, meow?
I wish my hunger would end, too.
I smell something good, meow.
Huh?
This is it, meow!
Oh, so it was the scent of bread!
Meow?!
She looks just like my first love,
Madonnya, meow!
Oh, we have customers?
Huh?
You!
Who are you?
Even if you asked,
usually I would never answer.
But why don’t I—?
Ahh!
Kosanji!
It’s Kosaburo! Kosaburo!
What is this?
It’s so tasty!
It’s amazing, meow!
Oh, it’s nothing...
You know, I—
Yeah, we know.
You got fed up with the missions, lectures,
and apologies and quit Team Rocket, right?
Hey, that was supposed to be a big reveal!
Let me say it myself!
Yamato told us everything, meow.
Huh? You saw her?
Now...
Time to repay the favor
with some hard work, Kosaburo.
It’s Kosanji!
Huh? You got it right...
A meal after a hard day’s work...
What a great feeling!
I wouldn’t mind living like this.
You’ve said it, meow.
But... How did we end up here
in the first place, meow?
Ahh!
We’ve repaid him by now,
so let’s keep chasing Pelipper!
Huh?! But...
Nyarth. If you want to stay here,
don’t let me stop you.
I saw you having fun
with that Madonnya lookalike.
I’ve never seen you
look so happy before.
Oh, how should I put it?
That was...
“Team Rocket’s
nyot all there is to life.” Right?
You’ve worked so hard, too...
You’ve worked really hard too, meow!
Nyarth! Farewell!
I stayed up late
sewing this, meow!
Take it, meow!
How far’s it gonna fly?
Huh?
What are you doing, Tyltto?!
Aren’t you supposed to be the
blue bird Pokémon that brings happiness?!
What an awful fee— ling...
Hey...
You get the feeling we’re lost?
How’d we even end up like this?
Was this our fate... all along?
Kojiro... Nyarth... Fare—
Musashi!
Get it together, meow!
Huh? Why...?
Saving a friend in need...
...is what a true friend
does, meow!
Kojiro... Nyarth...
That hurts, that hurts!
I said that hurts!
Huh? A Sand?
Then what was that?
A dream?
Sonansu! Wake up!
This ain’t the time to slack off
and drop dead, you hear me?!
We’re following that Pelipper,
no matter what it takes!
No! No!
No! Somebody help me!
I can’t, I can’t...!
I can’t do it...
I’m out of energy...
That’s right,
what was it Pelipper said?
“To change your luck
is to change your life.”
Then I guess we were just
unlucky to the bitter end...
Musashi!
Kojiro? Nyarth?
What a stroke of luck it is
to see you again!
You guys...
Why are you here?!
It’s a long story.
Have you heard about this, meow?
The moment I took my eyes off it,
Morpeko ate the café out of all its food.
Even when a cloudy night hides the stars and the planets
Yamato tossed me out,
and when I saw Pelipper again, I chased after it!
There’s still one, and only one you can still see
And for me, that Madonnya lookalike turned out to be
good friends with the Persian who rules the town, meow...
With a broken heart,
I bid the town farewell, meow.
It’s right nearby, it’s just beneath your feet
That’s when I saw Kojiro
chasing after Pelipper, meow.
Save the details for later...
Just do something already!
R-Right!
How’re you supposed to help
if you get stuck, too?!
Luck is still on our side!
Pelipper, help us, meow!
What? You don’t have room
for anything else?
Then just spit out
the thing in your mouth!
No, it’ll never let it go!
What an awful feeling!
Y-You saved us...
I don’t quite get it,
but do we owe it all to Pelipper?
The machine comes down to luck.
Sometimes you get good pulls,
sometimes you get bad ones.
Sometimes they’re good,
even if you think they’re bad.
And sometimes they’re bad,
even if you think they’re good.
And life rolls on
like a vending machine, meow.
So...
How are we getting back home?
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
The brat boys?!
Team Rocket!
I’ve got a good idea.
Hey!
Say, “What are you guys up to?!”
Huh...?
What’re you guys up to?!
If you ask us
“What’re you guys up to?!”
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Romanticism”!
Just kidding, meow!
The “ke” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Keenness”!
The little “c” in “Team Rocket” between the two stands for...
“‘Course, we’re villains!”
Team Rocket
really is my life, after all!
“Come on, come at us!”
“Clearly, Pikachu’s too strong, meow!”
We’re taking that cool Pikachu!
Right!
“What an awful feeling!” we scream as we blast off again,
Not if I can help it!
Pikachu, 100,000 Volts!
and beneath us we see a little, tiny earth,
forests, mountains and Pokémon...
Here it comes,
here it comes, here it comes...!
They all blend together! What a great feeling!
What an awful feeling!
Wherever we land,
we’ll have a meal to prepare ourselves for tomorrow
Wh-Why were they smiling...?
We look up and see the shining moon
Who knows?
We look each other in the eye and laugh together
All in all, what a great feeling!
We’re the invincible Team Rocket!
Sometimes you’re lucky,
and sometimes you’re unlucky.
Scaring crying children into silence...
But you can never truly know
if you really are lucky or not.
Team Rocket!
Either way,
Team Rocket....
Keep moving ahead, towards
tomorrow!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Satoshi! Go!
It’s been a while!
Māmane!
So this Denryu
is part of the project?
Yes!
The Asteroid Explorer
Fiarrow2 Retrieval Project!
Ooh!
Let’s go, Denryu!
Send the light of hope into space!
Light, on!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Reach Into Space!
Denryu's Light!!
Reach Into Space! Denryu’s Light!!