What about you, Satoshi?
Me?
My dream is to be
a Pokémon Master!
I’ll catch every Pokémon
and work my way up to Mew!
That future, too,
lies in my hands, yeah?!
Satoshi, who dreams of
becoming a Pokémon Master...
And Go, who aims to
catch every Pokémon.
What kind of Pokémon
will they meet today?
Awesome! It really is
a massive pack of Menokurage!
Told you so, didn’t I?
It’s so soft and squishy!
All right! I’m gonna
catch one right away!
Hmm... Better go for
one of the strong ones.
I choose you!
Monster Ball, go!
Huh?
Menokurage’s data will be
added to the Index!
Well, it worked out anyway!
Huh?
Something’s coming.
Look at it go!
A Samehada?
No, maybe it’s a Gyarados!
All right! It’s a big one,
and I’m gonna catch it!
Huh?! Pochama?!
What?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Don't Lose, Pochama!
The Sinnoh Region Drift Ice Race!!
Pochama. Penguin Pokémon.
Water type.
Very proud, and a skilled swimmer.
Its thick down guards it from cold.
I wonder where it swam from...
It sure is eating a lot, though.
It must have something going on.
I’m home.
Oh, welcome home.
What are you doing?
We were watching
Pochama, Koharu.
Pochama?
Where?
What do you mean? It’s right...
H-Huh? It’s gone.
Don’t tell me...
Could you all please
come to the main room?
Pochama!
You’re okay!
What a relief!
Who’s this?
I was searching for
information on Pochama,
and then I got in touch with this lady,
who had put out a missing Pokémon report online.
You saved Pochama?
Thank you!
I’m Misaki from Kissaki City.
Kissaki City...
in the Sinnoh Region?!
No way!
It swam all the way from there?!
I was worried since it disappeared
all of a sudden...
It was a real shock to hear
you found it in Kuchiba City!
Hey, aren’t you glad
we found your trainer?
Huh? Are you embarrassed?
Now that we know,
we should return it as soon as possible.
All right! I’ll go give it back!
Me, too!
I gotta catch some
Sinnoh Pokémon, yeah?
Counting on you.
In Kissaki City,
the city of snow and glittering ice,
you should see, interact with, and catch
plenty of rare Pokémon!
All right!
It’s the Sinnoh Region!
So cold...
Look at all these people, though.
Is there a festival or something?
Hey, look!
The Drift Ice Race?
A Pokémon race, huh?
Sounds fun!
Let’s go check it out
after we’re done with the mission!
Nice! Chasing after the brats...
...led to us hearing something real good.
Change of plans, meow!
Let’s nab Pikachu...
and all the Pokémon in that race!
But the way to Sinnoh...
sure was long...
We should have installed
an electric assist...
Or really, why not make
this whole thing run on electricity?!
We couldn’t afford it, meow...
Kissaki City, Sinnoh Region
Now accepting sign-ups for Pokémon
participating in the Drift Ice Race!
Ms. Misaki said she’d be waiting for us
at the port, didn’t she?
Huh?
Where’s Go?
Do it, Hibunny!
Now! Go!
Nice!
Tamanta’s data will be
added to the Index!
Yeah! I got Tamanta!
Caught something
right off the bat, huh?
Yup! My first catch in Sinnoh!
Oh, there you are!
Ms. Misaki!
I’m terribly sorry.
I dropped my glasses on the way here.
It took a while to find them.
Pochama,
I’m so happy to see you.
Satoshi and Go, was it?
Thank you so very much!
Oh, my glasses again!
Where are they?
Oh, they’re here...
Thank you.
It’s really dependable!
Now, Pochama,
let’s go home.
What’s wrong, Pochama?
Why are you angry?
What’s up with Pochama?
It’s not happy to be back?
It’s a Gureggru!
Gureggru!
Huh? This Gureggru’s yours?
Yes.
Gureggru! Poison Jab Pokémon!
Poison/Fighting type!
Inflating its poison sacs, it fills the area with an odd sound
and hits flinching opponents with a poison jab!
It came with me because
it was so worried about Pochama!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pochama
Water
Looks like sparks are flying...
Could this Gureggru have had something to do
with Pochama disappearing?
Ms. Misaki, why did Pochama leave?
What?
Well, I don’t really know, either...
I first met Pochama about a year ago,
when I lost my glasses in the ocean.
My glasses! My glasses!
You sure do drop them a lot...
But this one picked them up for me.
Thank you!
You really do love to swim!
Say, would you like to
join the Drift Ice Race?
The winner is Pochama!
Amazing! You’re amazing, Pochama!
Pochama won?!
Awesome!
So, how about Gureggru?
I met Gureggru...
last month, I believe.
I was taking a walk
with Pochama, when...
...I dropped my glasses and
Gureggru picked them up for me.
Again?
Figured as much.
We started living together
after that.
Gureggru, you’re such a baby.
Here, open up!
Is it good?
Oh, look at you go!
That’s amazing, Gureggru!
Oh, you’re so quick!
Amazing, Pochama!
Amazing! I didn’t know
you could swim that fast!
You’re even faster than Pochama!
That’s incredible!
Pochama! Where are you going?
And there you have it.
I see.
Pochama wanted your praise
for its swimming!
But it lost to Gureggru...
It may have swum to Kuchiba City
to train so it could beat Gureggru!
It was swimming
at the institute, too!
What? Is that true, Pochama?
Hm? Pochama?
Those are Drift Ice Race
entry stickers!
Does this mean it wants to settle the score
with its rival, Gureggru, in the Drift Ice Race?
Oh, no... Rival?
I just wanted us all to be friends...
Sign-ups will close soon!
Any participating Pokémon, please hurry!
I know! I’ll sign up with Tamanta!
You wanna join too?
All right!
Looks like Pikachu
is participating, too.
Everything’s falling into place.
Commence Operation:
Catch of the Day, meow!
The time has come again
for the annual Pokémon Drift Ice Race!
Competitors must swim between the two icebergs
and back here to reach the goal!
But many drift ice pieces
lie in the Pokémon’s way!
This year’s race is
harsher than ever before!
Which Pokémon will come out on top?
Go, go, Tamanta!
You hang in there too, Pikachu!
Pochama... Gureggru...
The Chonchie have lit the course.
We will begin momentarily!
And they’re off!
Leading the pack are last year’s runner-up,
Emperte, and the winner, Pochama!
They are followed by Gureggru,
appearing for the first time this year!
Good, Emperte!
Keep it up and win!
Pochama! Gureggru!
Oh, who should I root for?
Tamanta, Tattsu and Keikouo
are frantically chasing after them.
You give it your all,
Dugong and Beadaru!
Oh, my! Pikachu is almost
out of the race!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
What are you doing?!
Tamanta’s helping Pikachu?
Oh! What a great guy!
Just as expected of my Tamanta!
They have very nearly reached
the iceberg where they’ll turn around!
Emperte is the front runner, but...
Oh, my! Pochama and Gureggru
have finally swum past Emperte!
Don’t give in, Emperte!
Pochama... Gureggru...
Do your best, both of you!
What? What is that?!
If you ask us
“What? What is that?!”
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket! You guys again?!
We would go to the ends of the earth
or the ends of the sea for Sakaki!
We’ll be taking Pikachu
and the other Pokémon in this race!
And push, meow!
They’ve ruined the race!
I’m not sure what to say...
The situation has gotten out of hand, but...
...the front runners, Pochama and Gureggru,
are continuing the race!
Neither will yield an inch
as they dash for the goal!
What? What’s going on?!
Pikachu!
Use Iron Tail on the net!
You cheeky little...!
We won’t let you get away!
Capsules, c’mon!
All right!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
What’s it gonna be?
Yeah! A really strong-looking
Pokémon, Kairiky!
Superstrength Pokémon
Kairiky
One more!
What’s it gonna be?
All right! The Freezing Pokémon,
Tunbear!
Freezing Pokémon
Tunbear
Get ‘em, Kairiky!
Tunbear! Icicle Drop!
Tamanta! Agility!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
You have some nerve!
Tunbear!
Use Thrash on that ship!
Pochama! Gureggru!
Ms. Misaki!
We have to help her!
S-Somebody, help me!
I... can’t...
Pochama... Gureggru...
You came to save me?
Thank you!
All right! Ms. Misaki’s safe!
Hibunny!
Use Double Kick on Tunbear!
All right!
We’ve got them cornered!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
This is unbelievable!
Due to Team Rocket’s interference,
we can’t continue the Drift Ice Race!
I’m afraid this race
ends in cancellation!
It’s canceled, huh?
And after we worked so hard...
Right! We’ll shoot for
victory next year!
Yeah, Tamanta?
Right, Pikachu?
Huh? Looks like Pochama and Gureggru
are friends now!
You’re right!
Nothing beats friendship.
Goodbye!
See you later,
Pochama, Gureggru!
The Drift Ice Race
may have been canceled,
but Satoshi and Go got to meet
the people and Pokémon of Kissaki City.
A new adventure awaits them
across the sea.
Let’s go!
Now, shall we go home?
Oh, my glasses!
Thank you.
You are a really fast swimmer,
aren’t you?
Amazing!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Satoshi, big news!
What’s up?
It’s Houou! Houou appeared!
All right!
Let's head straight for Enju City!
I wanna battle Houou!
I want to catch it!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Hibunny, go!
I told you, Houou doesn’t exist.
Grandpa...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Vow From That Day!
The Johto Region's Legend of Houou!!
The Johto Region’s Legend of Houou!!