Masara Town, Kanto Region
I... choose you!
Satoshi!
You’re still asleep?
You’ll be late to Okido Laboratory!
Okido... Laboratory...
Mom! Why didn’t you
wake me sooner?!
You said you could get up
on your own, didn’t you?
See ya later!
This young man is
Satoshi from Masara Town.
He battles and catches Pokémon
together with his partner, Pikachu.
His Pokémon Trainer studies continue.
Professor Okido!
Oh, Satoshi!
What did you want me to do?
You see, this younger colleague of mine
is opening a new laboratory in Kuchiba City today.
A new laboratory?
That’s right. So I figured I’d invite you
to its opening ceremony.
You are going, I take it?
Yeah! And you, too, Pikachu!
“Of course!”
Mom?!
I just came to bring your lunch,
but what a great thing I just heard!
There are plenty of delicious sweets
and stylish shops in Kuchiba City!
W-Wait, you’re coming too?
Let’s go, right now!
Digda!
Butterfree!
Ever the Pokémon lover, I see.
Are you still working towards
becoming a Pokémon Master?
Yeah! Of course!
I’m definitely gonna be a Pokémon Master
together with this guy!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi and Go,
Aboard Lugia They Go!
Kuchiba City, Kanto Region
Here we are.
I’ll park the car,
so you just go on ahead.
Sure!
It’s a Pokémon
I’ve never seen before!
You’re so cute!
Where are you from?
What’s your name?
Lemme touch you just a little!
C’mon?
Caught you!
All right,
see you tomorrow!
Bye bye!
Wanpachi! I’m home!
Satoshi.
You’d better hurry
or you’ll miss the opening ceremony.
Right!
Thank you for your patience.
My name is Sakuragi, and I am the director here
at Sakuragi Institute, which is opening today.
I am most grateful to see so many of you
come here from so far away.
Now, then... Pocket Monsters,
or Pokémon for short.
As you all know, they are the strange, strange creatures
that live on this planet.
In the forests, in the skies,
in the seas...
You can find them
all over the world.
Humans and Pokémon live together in this world,
forming diverse kinds of bonds.
Here at the Sakuragi Institute,
we wish to observe and analyze
everything about these mysterious Pokémon,
so that we may deepen
our understanding of them.
To know Pokémon is
to know the world.
I believe this will help
make the world a better place!
That Go...
I brought the school handouts
because he said he’d be here today...
“I’m about to have
a fateful encounter, so I’ll be late”?!
Sheesh...
His messages are always like this.
Just as I predicted...
Those clouds make it look like
it could appear at any moment!
This’ll be easy!
What is this?
From this air flow, temperature,
humidity, and altitude...
This is just
my prediction, but...
In roughly 20 minutes, an exceedingly rare Pokémon
will appear at Kuchiba Port!
A rare Pokémon?!
What do you think?
It does seem pretty big...
Professors!
I’ll go have a look!
What if it’s
a Legendary Pokémon?!
All right! I’m first!
Kabigon?!
Please, move!
Here it comes!
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Go!
Huh? That’s strange...
Wh-What?!
Over there?!
There it is!
It’s Lugia!
It was well worth the wait!
Kameil! Ice Beam!
Thunders! Thunder!
Gänger! Night Head!
Wait for me, Lugia!
All right!
Let’s fight it together!
It’s a Raid Battle!
Yeah!
Yamirami! Evil Pulse!
Usokki! Rock Slide!
Gaburias! Dragon Claw!
Kirikizan! Crossroad Kill!
Armorgaw! Steel Wing!
Found you!
Lugia...
Let’s battle!
Pikachu!
Use 100,000 Volts!
Wait!
The future lies in my hands!
Lugia!
Gonna fall!
Who are you?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Lugia
Flying
Psychic
Lugia...
Amazing!
I’m riding on Lugia?!
So this is how it moves its fins...
And...
Its skin is rougher
than I thought it’d be.
But...
It’s really warm!
Well, of course!
It’s Lugia, after all!
Onidrill!
Onidrill flying at
the same height as Lugia...
They’re really strong fliers!
We’re gonna crash!
Here we go!
That was close...
But, you know...
Meeting so many different Pokémon
is the best!
You’re a real character!
What, really?
I accept!
Accept what?
Accept you as my friend!
What’s that about?
I’m Go from Kuchiba City!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
This is my partner, Pikachu!
It’s nice to meet you!
You all right?
Yeah...
Thank you, Lugia!
Let’s meet again!
Later!
It’s gone...
Pokémon sure are nice.
Yeah.
Lugia reminded me...
...just how big the world is.
And that if you just want it bad enough,
you can go anywhere...
...and meet whatever
Pokémon you want!
Yeah, of course you can!
You can meet ‘em, for sure!
Well, I guess it’s time to go back.
But where...
...are we?!
We finally... made it...
Go, you’re late!
Listen to this, Koharu!
We just had a fateful encounter...
...with Lugia! We met Lugia!
Did you, now...?
Anyway, here’s the
handouts from school.
Oh, sure...
Not that I really need them...
Oh, by the way,
where’s Director Sakuragi?
Dad’s inside with Professor Oki—
What?! Professor Okido is here?!
Professor!
Director Sakuragi’s your dad?
Nobody’s ever caught footage of
Lugia’s fins mid-flight this close up before!
That’s not even
the biggest surprise!
Is this underwater?!
Amazing, Go!
And what did you
take from the experience, Satoshi?
I think we kinda, maybe
made friends with Lugia!
Friends?
What makes you say that?
I, like, felt a jolt
when I locked eyes with Lugia!
What’s that supposed to mean?
Sure you didn’t just imagine it?
I did not!
Um, how do I put it...?
It’s like an electric shock
just ran through me around this part...
Come to think of it, Lugia did lessen the impact
with a Hydro Pump for us, didn’t it?
Yeah, yeah! And when it
plunged into the water,
I heard a voice saying,
“Here we go!”
Huh?!
That’s incredible, Satoshi!
Huh? What is?
Satoshi, and Go.
I’m profoundly grateful
for your initiative.
You’ve allowed me to learn
untold secrets about Lugia!
And so, I have a request for you.
Would you become research fellows
at my institute?
“Research fellows”?
It means special lab assistants.
I want you to meet, touch,
and speak to all the Pokémon of the world,
and then...
...we will deepen our
knowledge of Pokémon!
Together!
I had been waiting to hear that.
That is the new future
I should take in hand, yeah?
Director Sakuragi! I’ll do it!
Oh, you both accept?!
Sure! I won’t lose
to Satoshi, though!
I won’t lose to you, either!
No, I won’t lose!
Are you sure, Satoshi?
Commuting from Masara Town
to here will be tough.
If so...
Is this our own dorm?
All right! A dorm! A dorm!
I’ll have the top bed!
Wait!
I’ll sleep up top!
You probably toss and turn,
so you get the bottom bed!
No! I bet you do that!
I’ll sleep on top since I’m taller!
No, I’m taller!
Well, in that case...
Bari-chan, look after Satoshi
for me, okay?
See ya, Mom.
Oh, that’s right.
Make sure you eat properly.
That includes the vegetables.
Oh, and brush your teeth! And...
I got it...
Go, look after my son.
Leave it to me!
Oh, cut it out!
All right! See you soon!
I will be waiting for you,
Professor Okido!
Dad! Still not ready?
Oh, I’m so sorry!
Just wait a little longer!
There’s one more
important thing I’d forgotten.
It’s Hitokage, Fushigidane,
and Zenigame!
I still hadn’t given you your starter Pokémon
for your trainer debut, had I?
So, who do you choose?
I...
I choose...
...Mew!
I’ve decided that Mew
will be my first Pokémon!
The Mythical Pokémon?!
That future already lies
in my hands, too, yeah?!
You really are
an interesting guy, Go.
Not as interesting
as you, though.
Then I win!
What?!
In that case,
I’m more interesting!
No, me!
Oh, who even cares?
Then, I’ll be waiting...
...to learn Mew’s secrets!
Yes, sir!
A world of dreams and adventures
with Pocket Monsters awaits!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
A mysterious city-wide
outbreak of Fushigisou?
Let’s go investigate!
Forget it!
I’ll investigate on my own!
Oh, will you, now?
Well, suit yourself!
Is this evolution?!
Team Rocket?!
It’s my first time seeing them!
Pleasure meeting you, meow!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Oh-Sou Mysterious
Fushigisou!