Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon Battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
Kalos Region
All right, it’s time for...
Pokémon Battles!
Pokémon catching!
I’ll go on ahead
to Miare Gym, then!
Yeah! I’ll be right there
once I’ve caught something!
Right!
Satoshi has arranged to meet up
with Citron and Eureka,
with whom he once
traveled through Kalos.
Huh?
The Pokémon World Championships
Hyper Class!
Tomorrow’s battle is between one of the Kalos Elite Four,
Competitor Dracaena, currently ranked 12th!
And...
Wha— That’s me!
The New Star of Kanto,
who is quickly rising up the ranks,
Competitor Satoshi,
currently ranked 15th!
So, Competitor Dracaena...
The day is nearly here.
Satoshi is strong, isn’t he?
Quite, quite strong indeed!
It fills me with joy!
Thank you for those words.
That was Competitor Dracaena!
Pikachu! If we can’t get past her,
we won’t have any hope of reaching Mr. Dande!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi and Citron!
The Great Friendship Training!!
What is it?
A Keromatsu!
Monster Ball, go!
What is this stuff?!
It’s Keromousse!
Keromousse?
Yeah!
A talent only Keromatsu has!
Huh...
All right! Keromatsu!
Let’s battle!
Miare Gym, Kalos Region
Wild Bolt!
Ahh!
Berobelt is unable to battle!
Roentorar wins!
As such, the winner is
Gym Leader Citron!
Citron!
Satoshi! Pikachu!
I’ve been waiting for you!
Your next opponent
came as quite a shock.
A battle against Ms. Dracaena
of the Elite Four!
Yeah! My Pokémon are
really hyped up, too!
Then how about I join you,
like old times?
Come on out,
everyone!
Ahh!
Kairyu?!
What’s that Pokémon?!
It’s called Uonoragon.
It’s a rare Pokémon,
revived from fossils from Galar.
Nice to meet you,
Uonoragon.
Huh?
Horudo?!
Yes, my Horubee evolved!
Horudo. Digging Pokémon.
Normal/Ground type.
With power equal to an excavator, it can dig through dense bedrock.
I’ve never seen a Pokémon
like him before, either.
He’s Negigaknight.
Galarian Kamonegi’s
evolved form.
Wow...
Hmm?
Huh?
What?!
You can’t pull it out?
Come on...
Ahh!
That was a surprise...
That Uonoragon’s surprisingly quick,
considering its size.
It’s never done that before!
Why did it suddenly go
for Negigaknight?
Who knows...?
Again?
Uonoragon!
That almost looks like fishing...
Come on. Open your mouth,
Uonoragon.
Whoa!
Man...
He might be on the verge of
pulling off a new move.
Huh?!
Monster Ball, go!
Keromatsu’s data will be
added to the Index!
I-I caught a Keromatsu!
Good job!
Keromatsu! Bubble Frog Pokémon!
Water type!
It protects itself by covering its body
in delicate bubbles!
Beneath its happy-go-lucky air, it keeps a watchful eye on its surroundings!
That took a long time...
Let’s see, what way takes me
to Miare Gym...?
I was just going to the Gym!
Really?
It’s my bro’s Gym!
Oh...
Your bro’s?!
Yeah!
Hmm...
That move was Star Assault.
A move that only Negigaknight can learn.
Star Assault!
He hasn’t quite perfected it yet,
but that was still an impressive move!
I hope he can learn it somehow...
I wanna use it in my battle
with Ms. Dracaena!
I thought you might say that!
Then...
The time has come for science
to usher in our future!
Citronic Gear, on!
I imagined something like this could happen
and prepared this nice machine!
I call it the Pokémotion Capture!
Ooh!
Another lame name.
Eureka!
Huh? Go?
Yeah! I was surprised to hear
you know one another!
She gave me some advice
when I was trying to catch this!
Ooh, a Keromatsu? Good job!
Yeah!
Nice to meet you!
I’m the Miare Gym Leader, Citron.
Hi. My name is Go.
I hear you’re an incredible inventor.
Oh, no, far from it.
I just hope to invent things
that can make people and Pokémon happy.
Then you made this robot, too?
Yes.
I am Citroid. Nice to meet you.
Amazing!
Here, take this.
I got you some souvenirs.
They’re Miare Galettes!
Oh! Thank you!
Let’s eat them together later!
Oh, that sounds good.
It’s so cute!
Tickle-tickle-tickle-tickle!
Is this one of Satoshi’s Pokémon?
Yeah. It’s called Uonoragon.
It’s apparently a very rare Pokémon
from the Galar Region!
I’m Eureka!
Nice to meet you!
Tickle-tickle-tickle-tickle!
Satoshi! Let’s get started.
So cute!
All right!
Negigaknight! Let’s do it!
Well then, Pokémotion Capture...
Let’s get capping!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Roentorar
Electric
I see...
I’m beginning to see the problem.
Ooh...
Star Assault involves gathering the energy
given off by his body into his chest.
It takes time to charge.
That’s step one.
Mhm, mhm.
Step two is sending that charged energy into his sword,
and then thrusting it forward.
Ahh...
How come?
Good question.
Which brings us to the third step.
Normally, he would hit the enemy
with that energy stored in the tip,
but for Satoshi’s Negigaknight, the core of his body
wobbles in the transfer from charge to thrust.
The tip of the sword fails to stabilize,
and the focused energy falls apart.
Eliminating that wobble will be
the key to perfecting the move.
Ooh!
And this is what I’ve simulated.
Stillness into motion,
motion into stillness.
If you can pull that off fluidly,
and stably,
Star Assault is sure to exhibit
incredible strength.
The power of science is amazing!
But why does he wobble?
Looking at the data,
compared to when he was a Kamonegi...
Between his sword and shield,
he’s carrying far more weight now.
I believe that extra weight
is what’s making his body sway.
But just before, it was strong enough to
blow away Uonoragon...
I think that being bitten by Uonoragon
stabilized Negigaknight’s stance
and let him concentrate
on the move.
Uonoragon, you’re amazing!
Thank you, Uonoragon.
If only there was some way
he could control the charge and thrust...
Okay, Negigaknight!
Train with me!
Citroid!
Lemme borrow these flags!
Understood.
What now?
What’s he gonna do?
Listen up, Negigaknight.
Focus your feelings here,
then thrust them toward your opponent!
One...
Two...
Three!
This “snap” is
the most important part!
If you can do that,
your sword won’t wobble!
One... Two... Three!
That’s a very Satoshi
way of teaching.
Yeah.
They’ve trained together
ever since he was a Kamonegi.
I know they’ll be able to
pull it off next time!
You know... When I’m battling...
If I’m watching my opponent...
I go “vwoosh” and focus in on them!
Times like that...
I don’t even notice anything else around me!
Yeah, Satoshi really is incredible
when he’s focused.
Indeed!
So I bet... If you...
...keep focusing on
your opponent, too...
Your sword and shield
will feel like they weigh nothing!
Know what I mean?
Ack!
This again!
What? What?
What happened...?
Oh, this always happens...
It looks happy!
I thought so!
Being bitten by Uonoragon stabilized the sword
and let him concentrate on the move!
Oh, so that means Uonoragon is like
training wheels on a bike!
They help you ride
when you’re starting out.
But once you get the hang of it,
you can keep your balance just fine without them!
That’s a good example, Go!
Y-You think so?
So that’s it!
Negigaknight!
Your focus got a lot better
thanks to Uonoragon!
Focus on the opponent in front of you!
You’re gonna win!
Those feelings are gonna help you
perfect your Star Assault!
Yeah.
Battle problems will have
battle solutions.
How about a practice battle
with me?
All right!
Let’s make it a Double Battle!
Huh? A Double Battle?
Yeah! Uonoragon’s speed
when biting the sword...
Its power to withstand
Negigaknight’s attacks...
I wanna try ‘em out!
Ms. Dracaena is a Dragon user.
I can see why you’d want to fight her
with a Dragon type.
Got it!
In that case... Roentorar! Horudo!
Please lend me a hand!
Commencing practice battle
between Satoshi and Citron!
Roentorar!
Use Wild Bolt on Negigaknight!
Horudo,
Dig towards Uonoragon!
Negigaknight!
Use Star Assault on Roentorar!
Uonoragon,
you use Jaw Bite on Horudo!
Uonoragon! Wait, wait!
Uonoragon!
So I bet if you keep focusing on
your opponent, too...
Your sword and shield
will feel like they weigh nothing!
He stopped wobbling!
Go!
A perfect Star Assault!
The training wheels are off!
Uonoragon looks happy, too!
You finally did it,
Negigaknight!
He can’t move from the recoil?
What now?
Its power is rising...
Uonoragon...
Horudo!
Use Arm Hammer on Uonoragon!
The practice battle is concluded!
Thank you, Citron.
I’m glad I could be of help.
That looked like
Dragon Dive just now!
Dragon Dive?
Maybe it tried to copy Star Assault
but it turned into a Dragon Dive!
Huh?
That can happen?!
I get it...
You got a power-up too, Uonoragon!
Huh?
They look like they get along.
At this rate,
tomorrow’s battle...
...is looking promising!
Yeah!
All right!
Negigaknight! Uonoragon!
I’m picking you two tomorrow!
Negigaknight and Uonoragon...
An unexpected tag team.
And Satoshi finally heads to challenge
Dracaena of the Kalos Elite Four!
Chevargot!
Use Consecutive Cut!
Wide Breaker!
You are as sharp as I thought,
Mr. Gampi.
I would say the same for thee!
I cannot relax for a moment!
I have you! Finishing Stinger!
Heat Wave!
Marvelous!
Your sharp moves are captivating!
Tyltalis and thou
truly move together as one!
Thank you.
Let’s show Competitor Satoshi
just how strong the Kalos Elite Four are.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
We finally get to battle!
Dracaena of the Elite Four!
Negigaknight and Uonoragon...
Go for it!
I had a look at your battle record.
However...
Your forward march ends today.
It’s your turn, Tyltalis!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Hyper Class!
VS Elite Four Dracaena!!