Wulaosu!
Thunder Punch!
Infight!
This will finish it!
Oh! Here it is!
A Trial Mission!
What’s this one like?
“Choose one of the following two”...
One is...
“Follow the three Sacred Footprints.”
The other one is...
“Catch Regieleki/Regidrago.”
Both sound awesome.
“Additionally,
this will be the Last Mission.”
Huh?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Last Mission!
Catch Regieleki/Regidrago!!
The final Trial Mission
for Project Mew has finally arrived.
Those who clear it
will be awarded three tokens,
and the three with the highest totals
will be accepted.
Currently first is Shigeru,
with 12.
Second: Layla, with 9.
Four people are in third with 8,
including Tokio and Shun'ya.
Go, with 7, is seventh.
Even if I clear this mission,
it all depends on the other Challengers’ results.
For now,
you just gotta do all you can.
Yeah!
So what’re you gonna pick?
All right, this one!
“Catch Regieleki/Regidrago.”
I’ve heard of Regice and Regirock,
but those...
These are Pokémon
we don’t have much data on yet.
If it’s called Regieleki,
is it an Electric type?
And Regidrago sounds like
a Dragon-type, right?
Apparently they’re somehow connected
with the Ruins of Decision in Galar’s Crown Snowfield.
The Ruins of Decision...
This is getting me pumped up!
Let’s get going, Go!
No. I’m going alone this time.
Huh?! How come?
I’m going to work hard
at my own goals.
So Satoshi,
I want you working hard at yours.
Go...
Got it.
I’ll go train for
the Masters Tournament.
So make sure
you clear the mission, Go!
Right!
Crown Snowfield, Galar Region
The future lies in my hands...
Let’s do this!
Project Mew, Last Mission!
And if I pass through here...
The Ruins of Decision!
Huh?
Shigeru?
You took your time, Go.
You were waiting?
For me?
Would I do that?
Don’t you think
these ruins are strange?
Yeah.
The colors being split like this...
Hmm.
Go. There’s ancient symbols.
Huh?!
Oh...
There’s probably
a seal on this door.
I wonder what it says...
“A giant of rock. A giant of ice.
A giant of steel”...
“When mustered are the giants three,
opened shall the door of destiny be.”
Mr. Tsurugi!
Can you tell what it means?
If we gather three giants,
this door will open.
What are the three?
“Rock, ice, and steel” can only mean
Regirock, Regice, and Registeel.
Aren’t they... Legendary Pokémon that are important
for studying the origin of Pokémon as a whole?
Precisely.
Come on out!
Ooh!
You finally got them all.
On top of these three,
it’s said there are two unknown giants inside.
Go investigate.
But from here on,
you may only use two Pokémon.
Right!
You’ve learned a little bit
about cooperation, haven’t you?
Yeah.
Still, having you battle Tokio
one-on-one at the very end...
Ms. Asahi has a mean streak
of her own.
H—?
You were watching that mission?
Maybe I was.
I want to confirm whether you’re worthy
of working by my side.
Wh—?
What are you trying to say?
Why are you trying to meet Mew?
Remember what
Professor Hodaka said?
What are Pokémon,
and where did they come from?
The solution lies with Mew,
who holds the genes of all Pokémon,
and is thought to be
ancestor to all Pokémon.
And I even met Mew
when I was young.
Huh.
I want to know
so much more about Pokémon.
That’s why
I really want to see Mew again!
Just like me, then...
I think you said you were researching
everything to do with Pokémon.
Yes.
And Mew is
a necessary part of that.
I also believe that meeting Mew will bring us closer
to solving the mysteries of Pokémon.
Oh, how I want to meet Mew...
I’m sure you will!
Statues on the left and right...
Round patterns on the floor...
This room is pretty suspicious.
Yeah.
There must be some trick to it.
Now that you mention it...
Maybe the patterns
at the entrance are a hint...
In which case...
If I step on the same pattern
as those...
Bingo!
All right...
I’m not gonna lose to you!
Seems like only one set of floor switches,
left or right, will light up at once...
Sorry, but I’m going first!
What now, Shigeru?
This is getting us nowhere...
How about we battle
to decide who takes priority?
Oh...
You want one?
Mm-hmm!
But first,
there’s one thing I’d like to try.
Rather than
one or the other...
I’m wondering if there’s a way
for us to catch both.
Not just one, but both...
At the same time...
I get it!
Collaboration
instead of obstruction!
If we sync up and step on both
at the same time...
Let’s give it a try.
Ready, and...
We did it!
Just as we predicted.
Next is the last one!
We don’t know what’ll happen
once we step on it.
Keep your cool.
Back at you!
Mosnow, use Icicle Spears!
Hihidaruma, use Icicle Drop!
Layla and Shun'ya?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Next is the last one!
We don’t know what’ll happen
once we step on it.
Keep your cool.
Back at you!
Mosnow, use Icicle Spears!
Hihidaruma, use Icicle Drop!
Layla and Shun'ya?!
I owe you big time for
Sea Kinsetsu, Go.
There’s Go, seventh
in the interim rankings...
...but the real prize we caught here
is the frontrunner, Shigeru!
So you’re going to just
steal our idea, is that it?
That’s a dirty trick!
Well, we’re Challengers.
We’ll do whatever
it takes to win.
Correct.
Which is why I had to come prepared
for any and all complications.
Me, too!
Brimuon! Psycho Cutter!
Aceburn, use Blaze Kick!
Shigeru, let’s work together!
I’ve been waiting for you
to say that!
So we’re settling it
with a tag battle?
Yes.
Considering
we’ll need them for later,
we should limit our Pokémon usage
as much as possible.
What would you say to one Pokémon each,
with no Pokémon change-outs?
Sure.
I don’t see any reason to refuse.
Sadaija and Deathban, huh?
I expected Go
to use his Aceburn...
...but I didn’t expect
Shigeru to bring out Kamex.
I predicted you’d pick Rock or Ground types,
which have an advantage over Fire types,
so I chose a Water type
to counter that.
I can see why you’re
provisionally ranked first.
But we didn’t come here
just to lose!
Use Sand Hell on Aceburn!
Aceburn!
Blow it away
with Hydro Pump!
Shigeru...
You can thank me later!
They’re about to attack again!
Ground Stomp!
Go! Get on Kamex!
Aceburn,
ride on Kamex’s back!
Shoot a Water Pulse
at the ground!
Our Ground Stomp...
They dodged it!
Now, Go!
Blaze Kick!
N-Next!
Give it up.
Layla!
A promise is a promise.
If you won’t keep your promise,
I’ll take you on.
What sportsmanship.
But that’s not all, is it?
Hmph.
You saw right through me, huh?
If we fail at catching
Regidrago and Regieleki,
it becomes your turn to try.
Of course, Regidrago and Regieleki
will be weakened after our battle!
Which will make our battle
all the easier.
Amazing, Layla!
You’re so sneaky!
Don’t get your hopes up
while you wait.
Discharge?!
So this one’s Regieleki?
Then this is Regidrago!
You handle Regieleki!
Got it.
Flygon, go!
Brimuon!
Don’t let your guard down!
Back at you!
It’s fast...
Hit it back with Mud Shot!
What is that move?!
Block it with Magical Shine!
An electrical cage?
Go!
Dragon Breath!
Brimuon!
Divine Speed?!
Here it comes!
Arm Hammer!
Flygon!
Brimuon!
You did your best, Flygon.
Take a good rest, Brimuon.
They’re working as a team.
Yeah.
Well, bring it on!
Let’s go!
Aceburn, go!
Kamex, you too!
Use Pyro Ball on Regieleki!
Use Rocket Headbutt
on Regidrago!
Gah...
Are they trying
to take us both down at once?!
Shigeru!
Use the Twister!
Go! Do it like you did
to dodge our Ground Stomp!
Thanks for the advice!
Kamex, use Rapid Spin!
Aceburn, get on Kamex!
Then use the Twister
to gain height!
All right!
Now!
Use Blaze Kick on Regieleki!
Charge in with Rapid Spin!
Come on, Monster Ball!
Monster Ball, go!
Regidrago’s data will be
added to the Index.
Regieleki’s data will be
added to the Index!
Aww, we lose.
We never got to play a part.
No, thank you for the advice.
It saved us.
Go. Without your help,
I would never have caught it.
It’s teamwork
that gave us victory.
Shigeru...
If you team up with someone unskilled
simply out of friendship, they’ll only let you down.
But even if you’re rivals
with someone...
...if your goals align,
you can still work together.
Stubbornly clinging to your pride
will only slow you down.
Acting alone
can prove fatal.
That’s something I learned
from Mr. Tsurugi on a mission.
You’re disqualified.
Were it not for me,
you’d be dead.
Both you and your Pokémon.
So you did...
the same thing?
Yeah.
I nearly got myself disqualified.
But that experience
helped me grow.
Is that so...?
So that’s why
you kept goading me...
No.
Everything I did
was for my own sake.
Ms. Asahi?
So the other mission
is over, then.
Well, yeah.
Oh?
You caught both of them?
So these are
Regidrago and Regieleki.
The legendary quintet is complete.
What a glorious sight...
Oh...!
A pillar... of light?
Regigigas...
And...
...it’s Daimaxed!
Did Regidrago
and the others call it here?
What... was that?
Incoming call from Professor Hodaka!
Now, all of the
Trial Missions are over.
As the head of Project Mew,
I thank all the Challengers
who participated.
I hope you make use
of what you learned in these missions...
...and keep pursuing
the mysteries of Pokémon.
Now, I will announce the results.
As you know,
the top three will be accepted.
First place is Shigeru
with 15 tokens.
Second place is Tokio
with 11.
Tokio...!
And finally,
third place is...
Incoming call from Go.
Go, how’d the mission go?
Satoshi, I...
...passed!
Really?!
Congrats, Go!
It’s all because of you!
It’s ‘cause of your hard work!
Thanks so much!
Okay, I’ll see you later!
You’re merely standing
at the starting line.
So let’s both do our best, Go.
Shigeru...
Yeah!
Alongside Shigeru and Tokio,
Go was accepted,
and has finally
become a Chaser.
What sort of adventures will Project Mew
have in store for him?!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Masters Tournament
is almost here!
You guys, let’s get all fired up
and get training!
You’re hopeless.
At least try to understand
your partner’s condition.
Shinji!
That guy has a scary look in his eyes!
3v3 with no switching!
Stand by for battle!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Fire Training Battle!
Satoshi VS Shinji!!