Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Satoshi, come and help me!
Coming!
This one, too!
Sorry! I should’ve warned you
they were broken.
I’ve already called the handymen.
Handymen?
We’ll fix it right away.
Thank you.
A Plusle and a Minun!
Plusle! Minun! Cheering Pokémon!
Electric type!
They cheer on their friends
with pom-poms made of sparks!
If their friends are losing,
their bodies let off more and more sparks!
Oh, they’re really cute.
Plusle and Minun are
our mascot Pokémon.
Here!
From plumbing...
...to Pokémon-sitting...
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
Zero problems?
Yep, zero problems.
Mulply.
Here, Big Brother.
Umm...
I’m sorry!
I forgot the extension cord!
Plusle!
Use Discharge on the dryer!
Go for it.
All right! Thanks, Plusle, Minun.
Thank you very much.
If you ever need
the Plusle and Minun Handymen again...
Give us a call!
Thank you!
Okay, now for the next job—
Big Brother!
B-Be careful!
Oh, no!
Are you okay?!
Big Brother...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
There’s Zero Problems We Can’t Solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!!
Satoshi and Go have taken Divi,
the injured handyman, to the hospital.
I’m sorry...
It’s fine, it’s fine.
I’m glad you’re not hurt, Mulply.
Don’t worry, I’ll be okay.
I’m really, really sorry!
But... You’re going to have
to handle any jobs on your own.
Huh? On my own?
No way, I can’t do that!
I can’t handle both our tasks!
If you just relax and try it,
you’ll be fine.
You’ll have Plusle and Minun, too.
Minun’s angry...
That’s right...
Minun is particularly
attached to you...
I’m sorry, Minun.
If you start panicking,
even easy jobs will seem impossible.
Just relax.
Yes, the Plusle and Minun
Handymen here.
Got it! Zero problems we can’t solve!
Mulply, we have a job.
But...
Um... I can help her!
Me too!
Huh?
We’re always
taking care of Pokémon!
We should be able to do something!
From... plumbing...
to Pokémon... sitting...
Th-Th-Th...
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
That’s it, you’ve got it.
Thanks! I’ll try my best!
From plumbing to Pokémon-sitting,
there’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
Sorry for the wait!
To get straight to the point,
can you help groom my Pokémon?
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
Ooh! Kentauros!
And there’s so many!
Okay then, should we split up
and start brushing them?
Yeah!
Here you go. Just keep still...
Does that feel nice?
I’ll make your fur all silky!
Ooh! They’re so silky!
Thank you! I’ll call you again!
Please do!
You were both great!
It was easy!
Naturally, yeah.
Plusle, thanks for cheering us on.
You too, Minun.
Yes, the Plusle and Minun
Handymen here!
Got it! Zero problems we can’t solve!
That’s our next job! Let’s go!
Yeah!
From plumbing to Pokémon-sitting...
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
Sorry for the wait!
Oh, I’ve been waiting for you!
I lost my Kentauros
going through the tunnel!
Kentauros again?
You need us to find it?
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
Whoa, it’s pitch black.
You can’t see anything.
Plusle, help us out!
Thank you, Plusle!
Okay then, let’s go.
Kentauros!
Come on out!
There it is!
So that’s where it was hiding.
Come on,
let’s head outside together.
Don’t be scared.
All right,
let’s cheer it on, too!
Hey!
I-I’ve gotta stop it! No!
Run for it!
It’s okay now...
You must’ve been scared...
Thank you!
Call us again!
Sorry, everyone...
Why do I always start panicking...?
You just need to get used to it, yeah?
Try taking deep breaths!
Thanks, Go, Satoshi...
You too, Plusle.
Minun...
I’ll do better on the next job,
so just watch me, Minun!
What’s with all the Kentauros?!
He’s showing off.
I wish he’d share a few with us.
Not just “a few”...
I’d like to take ‘em all!
But how?
There’s the question.
I’ll go have a drink.
H-H-Hey! Hold on!
The side, the side’s leaking too!
This is bad, meow.
This isn’t my fault!
That’s it, meow!
Yes! Understood!
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
Emergency, emergency, meow!
Broken pipe! Emergency, meow!
Um, um, um...
What— what do I do?!
What do I do?
We’re back.
W-Water?!
What am I gonna do?!
Ack! The brat boy...
Huh? What happened?
The d-drinking fountain
went crazy...
Whoa, we gotta fix it!
Mulply, get a hold of yourself!
R-Right...
I’ve got to get a grip!
Um... Get my tools ready.
Right!
Since when are
the brat boys plumbers?!
When I called that handyman over,
they came too, meow.
We fixed it somehow...
Yeah...
Thank you, both of you!
It’s nothing.
You did most of the work, Mulply.
Really? You think so?
Yes, the Plusle and Minun
Handymen here!
Oh, thank you!
Understood.
One hour from now, right?
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
Was that a job?
Yes, from that Kentauros lover
from earlier.
He wants us to look after
his Kentauros.
The job’s in one hour,
so let’s have lunch in the meantime!
Okay!
Gotta have a good meal
to keep us going!
You hear that?
Sure did.
Excuse me!
Ack!
From plumbing to Pokémon-sitting.
If you ever need help, you can count on
the Plusle and Minun Handymen!
This is it.
We’ll get right to work, too!
You mean we should make money
by fixing pipes?
Not that!
The Kentauros, the Ken-tau-ros!
I get it! We get there first
and take them all, zero problems, meow!
Oh! Nice idea!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Minun
Electric
Huh? You already gave them to us?
They said they were handymen,
so I thought they were your staff.
We don’t have any other staff.
Maybe it was some other handymen?
Then they took the wrong Pokémon?
When did you hand them over?
Just a moment ago.
That means they should still be close by.
Did anything stand out
about them?
Now you mention it...
They had a bicycle cart.
A bicycle cart?
That went well, meow!
If we keep this up,
we can get loads of Pokémon!
Sakaki’s going to
be feeling great!
Excuse me!
Ack!
You’re handymen, right?
There’s something
we’d like to ask you.
Did you pick up
the wrong Pokémon?
Apparently you got the Pokémon
we were supposed to be taking care of.
Ack, ack!
Did you take the job?
Huh? They look kinda familiar...
Whatever could you
be talking about?!
We are the Anyway and Anyhow
Handymen!
These are our Pokémon we caught
by anyway and anyhow, meow!
“Meow”?
Ack!
They seem kinda suspicious.
Who exactly are you?!
If you say “Who exactly are you?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
The Nyarth is talking!
Yeah, that is what stands out.
They’re always doing this stuff!
Well, sorry for doing this stuff, meow!
We’re not giving these Pokémon back!
That said...
We’ll leave while we’re ahead, meow!
See ya!
Wh-What?!
Nyarth!
Move, meow, Kentauros!
What do we do, what do we do,
what do we do?!
For crying out loud...
Let’s save him, Go.
Hey! Are you okay?
Whoa... It’s stuffed full
of Kentauros...
Mulply, do you have
any ropes or anything?
Huh? Um, er...
Ropes... Ropes... R-R-Ropes...
They’re too heavy, meow!
From plumbing...
to Pokémon-sitting...
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
Go. Satoshi.
There’s a winch on the van.
A winch?
Let’s begin by
pulling up the Kentauros.
You two get the rope
and bring it to the hole.
Right!
Then, lay one of those steel pipes across the hole,
and stabilise it with the sandbags.
Right!
Like that?
Hang the rope over the pipe,
then lower it.
Right!
We’re gonna save you now!
Someone needs to go down there
to wind the rope around the Kentauros.
Okay, I’ll do it.
Hold on. I’ll go.
Mulply...
This is my job.
I can’t let you
put yourselves in danger.
That’s what my brother would say,
if he was here.
When the Kentauros reach the top,
you two should lead them somewhere safe.
Got it.
You over there.
Can I ask you to operate the winch?
Me?!
Hmph. Don’t go
ordering people around.
However, I just so happen to be
in the mood for using a winch.
What a coincidence.
Everything’s fine.
I’ll get you out now.
Okay! Pull it up!
Right!
Switch... On!
Stop!
Right!
Okay, over here...
Easy does it...
Rescue complete!
Now for the next one!
Pass the rope down!
Right!
H-Hurry it up, meow...
Hold on a bit longer.
You’re safe now.
Don’t worry.
The next one is the last one?
Yes! This is the last Kentauros!
All right!
Pull it up!
Right!
Gently, meow...
Huh?
The battery!
Mulply!
Are you okay?
S-Somehow...
I can do this!
Let’s all pull together!
Yeah!
We’ll help!
Heave... ho!
Minun?
Minun...
I won’t give in!
Winch... please work!
They’re too heavy...!
Ah, Minun!
Oh! Will that work?!
No good!
There’s not enough power!
Power? In that case...
Pikachu! Use 100,000 Volts
on Plusle and Minun!
Okay! Use Discharge together!
This... might just work!
Meow... I’m saved, meow...
Nyarth!
What a relief!
Minun.
I heard you cheering for me.
Thank you too, Plusle.
Honestly, you put in
far too much effort.
Now that you’re all tired out,
we’ll make off with them all, zero problems!
You creeps...!
You still haven’t given up?!
Just kidding.
We’ll let you off, just for today.
We’ll leave, out of respect
for that handyman.
Thank you for rescuing me...
...is something
I won’t be saying, meow.
Hah, what a waste of effort.
What an awful feeling!
Mulply was amazing!
Everyone worked together
under her lead!
I’m glad to hear it went well.
Yeah! It’s all thanks to everyone there,
and Plusle and Minun cheering me on!
I can’t wait to get back to work.
I’m counting on you!
Yeah!
From plumbing...
...to Pokémon-sitting!
There’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
Mulply managed to
face up to her faults.
Together with Divi, Plusle, and Minun,
they have a bright future
as handymen.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Jimeleon’s data will be
added to the Index!
My Messon evolved into Jimeleon!
Awesome!
Congrats, Jimeleon!
What’s wrong, Jimeleon?
Hey, Jimeleon...?
Where are you going?!
Jimeleon!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Depression of Jimeleon