Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
There it is!
Okido Laboratory!
Professor Okido!
Race ya there!
Wait for me!
Okido Laboratory, Kanto Region
My, it has been a while.
Have you two been well?
Yeah!
Go, I don’t believe I’ve seen you
since the Sakuragi Institute inauguration event.
Yeah, and we didn’t get
a good chance to talk that day.
Oh, here are some documents
Director Sakuragi had me bring.
Ooh! Sorry for the bother.
Go, is this your first time here?
No, I came here for a Pokémon Camp
when I was six.
That reminds me, we were all held up
because someone was late.
Yeah, some people are like that!
Guess they overslept or something...
Huh? Wait a sec...
Oversleeping... When you were six...
Maybe it was you all along, Satoshi.
On that day I went to
Pokémon Camp, I met Mew.
And that’s what inspired my dream!
Hmm? What sort of dream?
To reach Mew, which is said
to have the genes of all Pokémon...
...by catching every Pokémon!
Ah, that’s a marvelous dream.
How many Pokémon
have you caught so far?
H-Have a look!
My, my, this is quite impressive.
Suikun?!
Yeah! I caught it!
Very impressive!
Ah, that’s right...
Go, have you heard of Project Mew?
Project...
...Mew?
Yes. A team to meticulously search for Mew
is being set up, and they’re recruiting.
But you must complete all sorts of Trial Missions
if you wish to become a member.
Huh.
What do you think?
If you’re interested,
I can recommend you.
Thanks for the offer...
...but I have to pass.
What?!
Why, Go?
I don’t really like being
part of a team...
Those missions or whatever
don’t sound appealing, either...
Hmm...
I thought it would present a good opportunity
for you to meet trainers sharing your dream.
Well, I won’t twist your arm.
Oh, right, Satoshi.
Your Pokémon have been waiting to see you.
Project Mew, huh?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Rivals for Go?!
The Path to Mew!!
Lizardon! Fushigidane!
I haven’t seen you in ages!
Everyone!
I’ve missed you!
Huh, so those are
Satoshi’s Pokémon.
Kentauros!
Stop!
Satoshi?!
Betobeton!
A-Are you okay?!
Yeah! Totally fine!
Glad to see you all
look so happy!
There was one point of concern,
however...
“Point of concern”?
What is it?
I haven’t seen Goukazaru
for the last two or three days.
Huh?
Is that one of your Pokémon?
Yeah.
I’ve raised him since he was a Hikozaru.
I was worried when he
failed to turn up for meals,
so Kenji and I looked for him,
but we couldn’t find him anywhere.
I wonder why...
Professor Okido, did Goukazaru
do anything unusual recently?
Hmm...
Now that you mention it...
Before he disappeared, he battled Lizardon.
And before that, he battled
Magmarashi, Chaoboo, and Fiarrow, as well.
Those are all Fire types.
Was he training or something?
That wouldn’t be a reason
to leave though, yeah?
For now, I’ll go look for him!
I’ll come with!
Goukazaru!
Say something if you can hear me!
I guess he’s not here...
Up there!
Huh? Where?
Look, up there!
Pidgeon! Bird Pokémon!
Normal/Flying type!
Really..?
Yes, really!
I’ve tried and failed to catch
lots of Pidgeon!
Monster Ball, go!
Failed again!
I’m not giving up!
A-An Iwark!
What a stroke of luck!
Monster Ball, go!
Kamex! Hydro Pump!
W-We’re safe...
But isn’t that Kamex...?
Of course,
who else could it be but Satoshi?
Shigeru!
I haven’t had a chance
to say that in a while.
Long time no see,
Satoshi and Pikachu.
Yeah, it’s been forever!
But why are you here?
Weren’t you supposed to be
researching Pokémon in Sinnoh?
That’s old news.
Now, I’m traveling all over the world
to research Pokémon.
And, while traveling,
something sprung up that brought me to Kanto.
What was it?
Well, never mind that...
Aren’t you going to introduce us?
Oh, sorry!
He’s a research fellow
at Sakuragi Institute, just like me.
I’m Go.
Hmm...
That’s a cute Sarunori.
This is Shigeru.
A childhood friend,
and longtime rival!
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Oh, right! Shigeru’s grandpa
is Professor Okido!
Huh?! Professor Okido?!
I was intrigued when I heard
Satoshi’d found himself a buddy.
Wondered what kinda guy he was.
“What kinda guy”...?
I’m just who I am.
It’s not your personality
I’m interested in.
What I want to know
is how skilled a Pokémon Trainer you are.
If I’m supposed to accept
that Satoshi has a buddy,
he’d better be
at least as good a trainer as me.
...What do you mean?
I’m saying you’re not qualified
to be Satoshi’s buddy.
Gaaaah!
Satoshi! What’s wrong
with this guy?!
Oh, he always did
this sorta stuff to me too...
By the way, Shigeru,
what was that thing you mentioned?
The Legendary Pokémon, Fire.
Fire?
I analyzed the temperature, humidity, wind direction,
and past appearances,
and judged that Fire
is likely to appear...
...in a valley near here.
Huh, that’s amazing!
I could have done that,
too, you know...
So why are you here, Satoshi?
Oh, my Goukazaru,
who I left at Okido Laboratory, went missing...
Your Goukazaru, huh...
I remember seeing him battle
in the Sinnoh League.
Do you have any clues?
Seems before he left,
he battled Lizardon.
Magmarashi, Chaoboo,
and Fiarrow, too.
I see.
Perhaps Goukazaru
went to the valley I’m heading to.
There’s no time to waste.
Let’s go.
Yeah.
It’s a pretty dangerous place.
Will you be able to keep up?
Of course!
It’s not you
I’m concerned about.
If Satoshi can do it,
then so can I!
Don’t disappoint me, now!
Hey, what sort of adventures
have you had since Sinnoh?
No mere rundown
could ever do them justice.
What about you?
Me? I, uh...
I’ve done loads!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Goukazaru
Fighting
Fire
Look at this.
This valley was formed from magma
that once flowed through here.
Huh.
Go, do you notice anything?
In other words,
this used to be a volcanic area.
The perfect sort of place
for Fire to appear.
Correct.
But your analysis missed something.
Huh?
Fire. Flame Pokémon.
Fire/Flying type.
If it is injured, it is said to dip its body in the
molten magma of a volcano to burn and heal itself.
And one more thing.
It is said that its appearance
indicates the coming of spring.
Spring?
Correct.
Flowers have bloomed early here.
Combining that with some other data,
I narrowed down the time and place it would appear.
But I now have a new piece of data.
Satoshi, your Goukazaru.
Goukazaru?
I’ve seen that Goukazaru many times
when visiting Okido Laboratory.
He was always working hard
to become stronger.
So if that Goukazaru was aiming
for ever greater heights,
and left to challenge
someone to a battle...
His desired opponent may be
the Legendary Fire-type, Fire.
Go, have you figured out
what I’m saying yet?
Since Goukazaru’s also a Fire type,
he sensed that Fire would appear here.
What? Really?!
So if we were to find Goukazaru here,
it would be even more likely
that Fire will appear.
That voice...
He’s calling for Fire.
Goukazaru!
We were worried about you!
You look like you’re doing good...
Did you come here to battle Fire?
Look, this is Fire.
Shigeru, you called it!
Oh, I called more than just that.
Have a look!
It looks like it’s responding
to Goukazaru’s wish.
Fire!
Yeah, I get how you feel!
Fire! Battle us!
Let’s go, Goukazaru!
Flamethrower!
Fire Vortex?!
Dig!
Mach Punch!
It dodged?
That’s Air Slash!
Don’t give up, Goukazaru!
Flare Drive!
Goukazaru!
You still wanna fight, don’t you?
But..
Satoshi, look out!
Let’s go!
Hydro Pump!
Rapid Spin!
Rocket Headbutt!
I knew I couldn’t block it completely...
So I used the recoil from the collision
for a Rocket Headbutt!
Now! Water Pulse!
Amazing...
That move...
It couldn’t be...
Is that Burn Up?!
Kamex!
Meet it with Hydro Pump!
What’s Burn Up?!
A move that burns up
all the fire in your body.
The user won’t be
Fire type anymore.
Won’t be
Fire type anymore?
That can happen?!
Pokémon biology
is an incredibly complex field of study.
It’s using the Flying-type move
Hurricane?
Defend with Rapid Spin!
Kamex!
You battled well,
considering that Fire was your opponent.
Have a nice, long rest.
Me next!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Elecible! Thunder!
Pikachu, 100,000 Volts!
Shigeru!
Fire’s getting away!
That’s fine.
What’s that?
A feather from Fire.
This was my objective.
It was, huh?
Go, did you get a video of Fire?
I was sure I pressed
the Record button...
That’s not like you, Go...
You can’t rush things.
Mind your own business!
All right...
Got it!
What’s that...?
An Armorgaw. I called for it.
Look after it.
Everyone was worried about you!
At any rate, I’m surprised
it went to challenge Fire to a battle.
I was shocked, too!
Battling Fire was so much fun!
And I’m glad you got
what you wanted, Shigeru...
Huh? Where’s Shigeru?
Did you receive the Fire feather?
Yes. I’m just verifying it now.
Who’s he talking to?
To tell you the truth,
Shigeru is taking part in Project Mew.
Huh?
Then, does that mean...?
Yes.
It looks like his Trial Mission
was to acquire a Fire feather.
I’ve verified the Fire feather.
Good work, as always.
I’ll send you the token, then.
And I’ve received it. See you.
Shigeru? What’s a token?
You get them for clearing
Trial Missions.
I see.
Go, I hear you declined
an invitation to Project Mew.
That’s a wise decision!
A trainer at your level
could never pass the missions.
Well then, I’ll be off again,
Grandfather.
I mean... Professor Okido.
See you next time.
Right.
Take care out there.
And come visit if you’re ever nearby.
I will. See you, Satoshi.
Shigeru...
Where are you going now?
I’m aiming to research
everything to do with Pokémon.
To do so means I need to research Mew,
who holds the genes of all Pokémon.
I’ve made up my mind.
Even if my goal seems impossible,
I’ll press on ahead without giving up.
I get it. I’ll cheer you on!
Thank you. And see you.
Everything about Pokémon, huh...?
He’s as cool as ever!
I’ll do it.
Project Mew!
Go! I’ll cheer you on
with everything I’ve got, too!
Thank you, Satoshi!
Yes. Shigeru will be pleased.
Huh? Why?
Provoking you was likely
his way of expressing...
...that he’d like you to take part.
Then he should’ve just said that!
He can never be honest
about how he feels...
I... kind of feel like he
completely beat me.
Either way,
there’s one thing I now know!
Right now, I can’t beat him!
So I’m going to try harder!
And then,
the future will be in my hands!
Go has decided to participate
in Project Mew.
What sort of trials
await him in the future?
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Well then, how about asking
Sarunori and Eevee to run the errand?
Sarunori... I know you can do it!
Eevee... It’s all up to you!
That’s a pretty big road!
Will they really be okay?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
I Want to Watch Their First Errand!