Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Eleboo, use Shock Wave!
Riolu!
Eleboo! Electric Ball!
Are you okay?!
You can still do this!
Stand up!
That’s it, Riolu!
You got this!
Yes! Time to finish it!
100,000 Volts!
Now! Vacuum Wave!
Eleboo is unable to battle!
Riolu wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
All right!
You did great, Riolu!
I can’t believe you beat Eleboo!
Amazing!
Based on the results of this battle,
the rankings will be updated!
Current standing in
the Pokémon World Championships rankings:
901st place.
It went up! Yeah!
All right, let’s keep up
the winning streak!
What’s up, Pikachu?
You wanna fight next?
I see you’re real pumped!
But Riolu’s on a roll right now.
Counting on you for
the next one, too, Riolu!
All right, let’s train some more
when we get home!
Who should I have you face?
Kairyu? That’s a tough one!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Pikachu's Reluctance,
and Barrierd's Exasperation
Satoshi is training with Riolu,
excited for his next official battle.
Kamonegi,
use Crossroad Kill!
Riolu, counter with
Force Palm!
All right! That’s enough!
You still wanna go on?
Wanna have Riolu
fight my Kamonegi, then?
Sounds great!
Well done.
Kamonegi!
Shadow Clones!
Riolu! Strike all the clones
with Vacuum Wave!
Impressive, Riolu!
Okay! I think it’s time we...
You still wanna go on?
Spear!
Turning Swallow Strike!
You gotta be tired
by now, yeah?
That’s it for today’s training!
Pikachu, sorry I kept you...
Pikachu... You’re asleep?
Oh, come on...
Riolu was working so hard.
I can’t send you out in official battles
if you act like this.
What are you doing?!
Same as ever, I see.
Mom?
What brings you here?
One of my friends
lives near the laboratory.
She said she was going home,
so I came along.
I thought I might drop by for a visit.
I haven’t had Mom’s cooking
in a while!
Go, Koharu, you eat up, too!
Sure!
Perfect timing!
Mom’s out with Sota today.
I feel bad for having you
make so much.
Oh, it was nothing. You’ve been taking
such good care of Satoshi for me!
We’re happy to have him here!
Would you like to stay the night with us?
What? May I?
Of course!
We have a guest room.
I suppose I’ll take you
up on that, then.
Dinner time!
Hey, Satoshi!
Ah, I’m stuffed...
Thanks for the food.
It was delicious!
You guys done, too?
Huh? You still wanna train?
Oh, you!
You hate losing
just as much as I do!
Okay! Let’s work off the meal, then!
Satoshi is really fired up for his
Pokémon World Championships matches.
Too fired up, if you ask me.
Oh, that’s just like him.
Right, Pika-chan?
I think Pikachu might be jealous.
Wanpachi went through the same
not too long ago.
Pika-chan.
You’re special to Satoshi.
You’ve been with him ever since
the day he left home, after all!
Oh, come to think of it,
how did Satoshi and Pikachu meet?
On his tenth birthday, the day he was
supposed to get his first Pokémon,
he went and overslept.
Pika-chan was the only one left.
I hear it took a while for Pika-chan
to warm up to him.
I see.
I guess everybody
has their issues...
Right?
Now, Ma’am...
You must be tired.
We’ll clean up here,
so you can take it easy.
Barrierd, can you show her
to the guest room?
If you’ll excuse me, then...
Oh, you too, Pika-chan?
It’s just about bedtime.
You’ve done great, Bari-chan.
Oh, and thank you for
always looking after everyone!
All right, Pika-chan.
You should go back to
Satoshi and Go’s room.
Pika-chan?
Pika-chan...
Satoshi will be lonely.
You’re like a baby.
Satoshi used to sleep in my bed all the time
when he was younger.
Sleep tight...
In Mommy’s arms...
Together with the new breeze...
Thank you for having me.
You’re welcome.
Come visit again whenever you like.
See you, Go.
Yes!
Satoshi, remember to do
as the Director says.
I know!
Oh, Pika-chan.
Hang in there!
See you, Rio-chan!
Bari-chan,
look after everyone for me!
Go, there’s some data
I’d like your help with.
Okay.
Riolu, let’s get back to training!
I’ll train with you later.
Wait for your turn!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Barrierd
Fairy
Psychic
Can you give me a ride
to Kuchiba City?
Sure can! Hop on!
Thank you so much!
What’s that? Y’all hitchhiking?
Ya want a ride?
Yeah, I gotcha.
Y’all wanna go this way, yeah?
Sure, hop right on!
I’m gon’ turn right now.
Y’all good with that?
Okay!
What’s that?
Y’all gettin’ off?
I gotcha.
Yer nearly there, huh?
Take care, now!
Pikachu!
I thought I’d find you here!
I’m sorry I made you
feel lonely, Pikachu.
Koharu really let me have it, too.
She said I didn’t understand
how you felt at all.
It was all my fault.
Sorry.
Why...?
Geez! Do you know how worried
we were, Pika-chan?!
Bad!
Now, let’s eat.
You must be hungry.
I really appreciate you all
keeping Satoshi company.
You can sleep here tonight.
Thank you!
And don’t worry,
I’ll look after Satoshi!
I’m glad to hear it!
Time to...
Hey, Satoshi!
Pika-chan, you too?!
I’d better thank Barrierd
again tomorrow.
You’re tired, right?
Guess we’d better go to sleep.
Oh!
Sleep tight...
In Mommy’s arms...
You know the lullaby
Mom used to sing for me, too?
Together with the new breeze...
We don’t know if Pokémon dream.
But let’s hope that tomorrow,
the day after, and even beyond that...
...when they wake up, they’ll be with
the one they love the most.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Koharu says one of Sota’s friends
is having some trouble.
Oh, it’s a Hinbass!
Yeah. She’s having trouble
with that Hinbass.
Battling trouble?
Is it gonna battle?!
No. She’s not sure how to show
how great Hinbass is...
That’s the perfect reason
to battle, though!
Oh, be quiet.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Hinbass's Pretty Scale
Hinbass’s Pretty Scale