The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament Finals.
Satoshi only had Pikachu left,
and Dande had Kyodaimaxed
his supreme partner, Lizardon.
When the Z-Move 10,000,000 Volts
and Kyodai Hellfire collided,
Galar particles
reacted in abundance.
Perhaps sensing
this growing power,
the Legendary Pokémon
Mugendaina appeared.
Mugendaina...
What happened?
Could it be... the one who brought
a vortex of chaos upon the Galar Region,
Mugendaina?!
Grandmother,
everything okay over there?
Mugendaina appeared over
Shoot Stadium!
Yes, we’re fine, Sonia.
What’s happening there?
Galar particle activity is abnormally high
in the sky above us.
That is most likely
what provoked Mugendaina’s reaction.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Finals IV - "Partner"
Pikachu!
Mugendaina... But why?
Stable Galar particles
make for a stable Galar.
Mugendaina protected us,
didn’t it?
Keeping our lands peaceful.
Thanks, Mugendaina.
So cool!
Please keep watching over us all.
To protect the world from devastation...
To preserve world peace...
Piercing through with the beam
of truth and love...
It’s the lovely, charming Mugendaina...
Just kidding, meow...
Now, let’s collect ourselves
as the match resumes.
Satoshi!
Mugendaina even gave us a little gift!
The Daimax Bands...
Watch this, Mugendaina.
Return, Lizardon!
Competitor Dande
recalls Lizardon.
Aceburn, I’m going with you.
Kyodai... max!
This is unprecedented!
Two Kyodaimaxes in a single match!
Incredible, Big Bro!
Why don’t we try it too, Pikachu?
I knew you’d say that!
Let’s get huge!
Kyodaimax!
Pikachu’s huge...
Yeah... Amazing...
Competitor Satoshi
also Kyodaimaxes!
What a tumultuous climax
to the Masters Tournament Finals!
Now, let’s do this, Aceburn!
Kyodai Fireball!
He’s not gonna outdo us,
Pikachu!
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Kyodai Fireball versus
Both are withstanding
the other’s attack!
And they hit!
Pikachu!
Aceburn!
The intense power forced them both
back to normal size!
Aceburn is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins
the Kyodaimax showdown!
All right! We did it, Pikachu!
He did it!
Pi-ka-chu! Pi-ka-chu! Pi-ka—!
Big Bro...
Return, Aceburn.
Your Kyodaimax was incredible.
Satoshi! Our final battle...
...really did come down to these two.
Yeah! A partner showdown!
Come out, Lizardon!
The Masters Tournament Finals!
Competitors Dande and Satoshi
are both down to their last Pokémon...
Lizardon and Pikachu!
You’ve done well,
pushing me this far.
You’ve made me grow
even stronger.
Let’s burn brighter and brighter,
until our very last blow!
We’ve kept growing stronger
because of you and your team.
This battle...
Everything since me and Pikachu met...
All our adventures
come together in this battle!
Which is why...
We’re gonna win!
Go! Lightning Speed!
Primal Power!
Pikachu strikes first!
Iron Tail!
Blow him away!
Pikachu!
Air Slash!
Great Blaze!
Electric Net!
Run for it, Pikachu!
Pikachu narrowly dodges
the Great Blaze!
100,000 Volts!
Great Blaze!
You okay?
You’re still good to go, yeah?
Iron Tail!
Lizardon, take the hit!
Dragon Pulse!
We’re not done.
We’re just getting started!
This is the best!
Satoshi! Pikachu!
Let’s raise our power higher,
Lizardon!
Win it! Big Bro! Lizardon!
Pikachu! Use Lightning Speed!
What?! I didn’t see a thing!
Primal Power!
Air Slash!
Iron Tail!
Wow...
Great Blaze!
100,000 Volts!
Whoa! The 100,000 Volts
didn’t make it!
It got engulfed by
the Great Blaze!
Pikachu!
So cute! This is the best one!
Pikachu, nice to meet you.
That’s right, Pikachu!
Everyone’s at our side!
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
Good job, Pikachu!
You stood back up!
Now there’s the Satoshi and Pikachu
I was waiting for!
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!)
Pikachu!
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
We’re gonna bet it all
on this attack!
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Lizardon!
It’s Champion time!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
100,000 Volts!
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
Great Blaze!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
Go!
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pikachu! You okay?
You were awesome
out there, Pikachu.
Your last attack
left me electrified!
Lizardon is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
It’s over!
A new Champion is born today!
Hailing from Masara Town in Kanto,
Competitor Satoshi!
Pikachu!
Thank you so much!
We beat Mr. Dande thanks to you!
Ooh, I see Pikachu’s all perked up.
Mr. Dande!
That was a great battle.
I had fun!
I had fun, too!
It reminded me of my first-ever
Pokémon Battle.
It was fun...
It was frustrating...
And it made me think,
“So this is a real Pokémon Battle.”
Yeah.
From today,
I’m just another challenger.
I’ll have lots of battles
and get even stronger!
I wanna battle lots more, too!
Let’s battle again sometime.
Yeah. For sure!
Satoshi! It’s almost time
for the award ceremony!
Um... That goes for
you too, Mr. Dande.
Gathering Champions from various regions,
giving us the greatest of spectacles...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
Now, Competitor Dande presents the trophy
to our new Champion, Competitor Satoshi!
Celebrating with
A display of fireworks
Lovely it is
All of the allies
Who waited dearly for this
Have a mother’s thanks
All of a sudden...
I’m in the mood for a battle now, too.
How about one, right now?
Satoshi! Congrats!
Congrats!
My... Now that’s our Pikachu...
I’m full of emotions
right now, meow...
But I feel like we’re
forgetting something...
Satoshi finally took down the undefeated Dande,
and was crowned as the supreme battler.
The Pokémon World Championships, weaver of many a grand battle...
...have concluded!
Incoming call from Go.
Pikachu!
It’s gotta be about Mew!
Hello? Go?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Roentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Roentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Roentorar
Electric!
Showers
Roentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
We Chasers will land on Faraway Island
and begin our search for Mew.
Our transmitters...
My Smartphone Rotom...
Not our Monster Balls, too?!
None of our devices
are working?!
We’ll take a different route
to the center!
We’ll keep heading up!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Project Mew