Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
This is the Sakuragi Institute.
Late at night,
while everyone is fast asleep...
...a certain Pokémon
is up and about.
Shishi, shishishi!
Let’s start with just one, shi...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Sakuragi Institute is Under Attack!
Breakfast... really is the best!
What about lunch and dinner, then?
Well, lunch is super-tasty...
...and dinner is hyper-tasty!
What’s that supposed to mean?
Ah... What a nice scent.
Good weather, and good moods.
Looks like we’re in for
a quiet, peaceful day.
Bad news, Director Sakuragi!
Ow, ow!
What’re we gonna do...?!
What’s wrong, you two?
What’s wrong... you say?
The data... The Pokémon data
you put so much effort into collecting is gone!
What?!
It’s true.
And it’s only data on Isshu
that’s missing.
Can we recover it?
I’ll try,
but it could be pretty hard.
No way...
That can’t be right!
Did... Did it fall out anywhere?
Hey, data! Hey! Data!
C’mon, data!
Wait...
Data doesn't just “fall out”!
Huh?
I wonder where our data went...
The Director said there were traces of
someone accessing the Institute’s main data.
Maybe someone
went and deleted it.
Here.
For Jimeleon.
Thanks.
How’s Jimeleon been?
He’s been eating plenty every day.
He’s cooped up, but doing fine!
You’re covered in mud!
This one spot is muddy...?
There. It’s all done.
We even changed
all of our passwords.
With all the extra security,
we can rest easy now!
Did I imagine that?
Wild!
I got all of their new passwords, shi!
Shishishishi!
A-n-d... delete, shi!
Hey...
You don’t have to sulk so much...
How could we not be
sulking right now?
We spent the whole day
improving security yesterday...
But it was breached like
it was nothing, and now...
The Galar data was deleted!
No...
You worked so hard
collecting so much valuable data...
I’m so sorry...
Director Sakuragi,
you shouldn’t be apologizing!
Whoever deleted it is to blame!
He’s right! Director!
We didn’t go far enough!
Let’s do it!
Impenetrable super-security!
Okay... Let’s go!
Go for it!
You ate plenty again today,
huh, Jimeleon?
Hey, um... We’ve been dealing with a problem
at the Institute the past few days...
Someone’s been deleting the data
we collected together.
Even our data from Galar.
That data...
It was our memories
with Pokémon.
Jimeleon...
Lots of the memories I made with you
were in there, too.
I...
I can’t let them get away with this.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kakuleon
Normal
Nobody around, huh...?
No way...
Jimeleon?! What are y—
Something’s there!
A Kakuleon?!
Kakuleon! Color Swap Pokémon!
Normal type!
It can freely change its body’s color!
The zigzag pattern on its belly
doesn’t change!
Wait... It was this Kakuleon
who deleted our data?!
That’s right, shi.
It can speak?!
We deleted your data, shi!
You should’ve noticed sooner, shi.
Shi, shishishi, shi!
Yabashi counters, shi!
Are you okay, Jimeleon?!
See ya, shi!
Man...
Yeah, got it!
What is it...?
Huh?
Stop, Kakuleon!
Go!
That thing’s been
deleting the data!
What?!
Stop!
Don’t let it get away,
Jimeleon!
Wild!
You don’t know
when to give up, shi!
What?
I’m Yabashi!
The man who’s gonna make a wild Institute
way better than Sakuragi Institute, shi!
Better than Sakuragi Institute?!
So... You deleted our data
because it was in your way?!
Exactly, shi.
Well then...
Surprise Attack, shi!
Jimeleon!
Wild! Your Jimeleon’s
so weak it’s wild, shi!
In comparison, my Kakuleon’s
had a special training regimen, shi,
and it’s much stronger and smarter
than the average one, shi!
Now then, Kakuleon! Bind!
Pound, Jimeleon!
Don’t give up, Jimeleon!
Shi, shishishi!
Jimeleon!
Are you okay, Jimeleon?!
Shi, shishishi!
All beat up and in a wild spot,
so let’s give it a good wallop, shi!
Look out! Run for it, Go!
Don’t worry! I’ll protect you!
Wanna come with me?
People may call you timid,
but I think it’s good to protect yourself!
I’ll be with you in spirit,
even when we’re apart!
Ahh... This is wild!
You evolved...? Jimeleo—
Inteleon’s data will be
added to the Index!
Inteleon!
Wild! Kakuleon,
use Iron Tail!
Wh-Whoa...
You’re super cool, Inteleon!
This is wild,
the ultimate in wild!
Now you’ve gone and made me...
...run for it, shi!
Snipe Shot!
Wh-Wh-Wha...?!
Wild! This is wild!
Shi?
All right!
What’s with that wild face?!
Stop that, you smug Inteleon!
My Kakuleon is a pure lady!
Don’t you dare try anything, shi!
Inteleon!
Hey, Yabashi!
How could you delete our data?
Don’t blame me, shi!
Blame your
shoddy security, shi!
What did you say...?!
Go, you say something, too!
I guess it’s too late
now that it’s already gone...
But that data
was really important to us.
I want you to realize that.
Was I correct in hearing that
you deleted our data?
Th-The one and only...
Mr. Professor Sakuragi, sir!
This is wild,
the ultimate in wild, again, shi!
I never imagined I’d be standing before
the one and only Mr. Professor Sakuragi Sir!
“The one and only
Mr. Professor Sir”...
What’s going on?
I’m a huge fan!
Please sign this!
A huge fan?!
And you are?
Yabayabashi.
But call me Yabashi!
Yabashi.
Let’s be honest here.
It isn’t really gone, is it?
Our data.
Y-Yes. It’s still there.
I thought so.
I... I really like and admire
your Institute.
I just wanted the one and only
Mr. Professor Sakuragi Sir to notice me.
And that’s why you deleted our data.
I-I’m sorry, shi!
So that was it.
Will this do?
Well, problem solved!
The data’s back!
What a relief... Really.
Inteleon?
I’m not gonna cry!
Bidding tears farewell,
Go and Inteleon look ready to start
a new kind of relationship.
I can’t wait to see what
tomorrow brings.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Eclipse Castle?
They’ve cherished Eefee and Blacky
as special creatures for eons.
Eefee and Blacky?
They’re both evolutions of Eevee.
I want to go!
Right, Eevee?
I’ll go, too!
Go and have fun,
all of you together.
All right!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Moon and Sun,
Koharu and Haruhi