Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
While running an errand
for Director Sakuragi,
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu visited
Kuchiba City’s Pokémon Center.
Thank you for waiting.
Here are the supplements
you requested.
Thank you!
That’s what we need
for the errand, then?
Yeah.
Huh? Where’s Sarunori?
Huh?
Sorry about that!
Stop, Eevee!
How is it your Sarunori always
ends up making mischief?
It’s always raring to play!
Your Eevee’s the same way.
Really?
Compared to Eevee,
Sarunori seems really childish...
Eevee tries to copy everything she sees.
That’s childish, too.
Eevee always behaves
when she’s alone with me.
Sarunori can behave, too!
Look out!
The cars, the cars,
the cars, the cars!
Well, you can’t call that behaving...
Ahh!
But she’s sweet, and she’s smart,
and cute!
Sarunori is sweet, smart,
and cute, too!
Well then, how about asking
Sarunori and Eevee to run the errand?
Th-The errand?
What now?
You could do that,
right, Pikachu?
So can Eevee!
So can Sarunori!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I Want to Watch Their First Errand!
Now, these are very important.
So make sure you take them back to Dad,
without losing them.
See this?
You start here, and when you make it
up the hill at the end,
you’ll be at the Sakuragi Institute!
Got it?
Don’t get sidetracked.
Sarunori... I know you can do it!
Eevee... It’s all up to you!
All right, Sarunori and
Eevee’s first errand...
...starts now!
Go, go!
Take care!
I’m really worried about them.
Yeah...
What are you two doing?
Quick, after them!
Huh?
After them?
Yeah!
You want them to succeed, right?
If it looks like something
might go wrong,
we can give them some
sneaky full power backup!
I get it now!
Plus, I can show you how sweet,
smart, and cute Sarunori is!
Then I’ll show off how sweet,
smart, and cute Eevee is, too.
Time for the first...
No Matter What Pokémon Pops Out,
We’ll Be Ready To Battle With It...
Training Session!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
What are we getting?!
The Apple Juice Pokémon,
Tarpple!
Something smells great, meow...
Why?
What? You’re asking me?
Yep.
All right...
Let’s see...
Tarpple is...
Grass/Dragon type.
Says its body is covered
in sweet nectar.
Looking at this thing
is making me crave some...
Same here!
What’re we gonna get?
The Fresh Snow Pokémon,
Vanipetit!
H-H-H-H-Hold on a sec!
Kojiro, where’s Morpeko?
Over there. Why?
It stuffed itself eating us out of snacks again,
then fell asleep, meow!
Nice timing!
Watch this, guys.
Wh-What the...?!
Vanipetit-on-Tarpple!
Yeah!
A perfect recreation of a hot and tasty apple pie
topped with vanilla ice cream.
You’re right...
I can’t help it...
I’m already savoring the hot and tasty apple pie
topped with vanilla ice cream...
Same here, meow!
Now I really want some hot and tasty apple pie
topped with vanilla ice cream, meow...
I know, right?
So, I thought this might happen...
And got us an apple pie!
Whoa!
Sooo... Why don’t we go buy
some vanilla ice cream while it’s asleep,
and have this for snack time?
Agreed!
Okay then, go buy us
some vanilla ice cream.
Right! Buy us some, now.
Bring it straight back, meow!
Hold it, hold it, hold it!
Pelipper, are you really
up to running errands?
Hey, wait... Uh, what...?
Hey, wait! Hey!
What did it say?
“Leave it to me,” meow!
Really?! I’m, like,
sooo worried, though!
Looks like they’re doing well.
They’re going the right way.
Yeah, you’re right.
Look!
It’s an Ishitsubute!
Not good...
That look on Sarunori’s face...
That’s its time-for-mischief grin!
Not that way! You’ll get lost!
Leave it to me.
Come on out, Gänger!
We’ll give them some
sneaky full power backup!
We’re counting on you.
This way! We’ll cut them off!
Gänger, go for it!
Psychokinesis!
Not that way!
H-Hold on...
Uh... Don’t scare them,
just get them back to the road.
What a relief!
So? Did they come back?
They went too far...
All right,
Pelipper hasn’t noticed us following it.
I got worried enough to
follow it all the way here,
but it’s actually doing fine?
If it just goes straight down this road,
then takes the first right,
the ice cream shop’s
right there, meow!
You can do it, Pelipper!
This errand’s like taking candy
from a Bayleaf, Pelipper!
Oh, no...
That’s its
“I forgot everything” face...
We’ll have to give it some
full power backup!
Ooooh!
You little whippersnapper!
I have something to give you.
Here, it’s a map to
the ice cream shop.
Go straight down this road!
Go straight, then turn right,
and the ice cream shop’s right there!
Straight, then right!
Right, meow!
Just look at the map
and you’ll get there, meow.
Right! Keep your eyes
glued to the map, that’ll do it!
The map!
Huh?
I have a bad feeling about this...
I knew it...
It really did keep its eyes glued
to the map, meow...
This errand’s doomed to fail,
isn’t it?
No! I’m not giving in yet!
We’ll just have to hit it hard
with our trump card!
Looks like they’re gonna make it back
to the institute before dark!
Ah! Look!
That’s a pretty big road!
Will they really be okay?
They’re looking right, looking left,
then looking right again!
That’s perfect!
Just keep going,
and make it across!
You’re nearly there...
Nearly there!
What?!
Look out!
Wh-What do we do?!
Sneaky full power backup!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Tarpple
Dragon
Grass
Come on out,
Negigaknight!
Stop that Pelipper!
All right!
That was close...
Yeah...
They’re crouched down!
D-D-Did they get hurt somehow?!
Or a stomachache or something?!
Just wait there! I’m coming!
They were just looking at
a Digda hole...
Ice cream! Ice cream!
Anyone looking for
some tasty vanilla ice cream?!
Vanilla ice cream!
Any Pelipper out on an errand
to buy vanilla ice cream, head this way!
Now, these are very important.
Eevee... It’s all up to you!
Eevee...
Hurry, hurry!
Never expected we’d end up
selling it the ice cream...
Or rather, we could’ve just eaten this ice cream
in the first place, meow.
Ice cream! Tasty ice cream!
Ice cream!
Oh, welcome!
Are you here for this vanilla ice cream
shaped like a Vanipetit?
Oh, you must be!
You want vanilla ice cream,
right?
Your vanilla ice cream!
Thanks for waiting!
Thank you for your patronage!
Any Pelipper out on errands
should remember to head straight home!
Sarunori...
Go!
Koharu, you head back
to the institute without us!
Uh, sure!
Eevee...
You’ve got this, Eevee!
A Kabigon!
Huh?
It’s gone...
Eevee... You are going to
be okay, right?
Somehow, we managed to
make it back before Pelipper...
The apple pie’s safe too, meow.
That’s enough...
You don’t have to stay posed like that.
Welcome back!
How’d your errand go?
Amazing, Pelipper!
See? You can do it if you try!
Now, to put this on here,
and it’s ready, meow!
A hot and tasty apple pie
topped with vanilla ice cream!
Sarunori... I know you can do it!
I hope Eevee didn’t go
the wrong way...
So you never found
Sarunori, then?
Right...
But...
Eevee!
Welcome back!
You really held on to them
any way you could!
Well done, Eevee!
Great to see it, Koharu.
Yeah!
But Sarunori still isn’t back...
Don’t worry.
Sarunori...
Hold on!
You’ve got this, Sarunori!
You’re nearly there.
You’re so close!
Just a few more steps
and you’re home!
That’s it!
You can do this!
You can do this, Sarunori!
Sarunori!
Wow...
You worked so hard!
That’s amazing, Sarunori!
You really did it!
All right!
That’s Eevee and Sarunori’s
first errand... Complete!
You did it!
Despite all their troubles...
Sarunori and Eevee have grown a little
through their first errand,
and perhaps Go and Koharu
have, too.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Ahh! My dinner’s gone again!
So is mine, meow!
Can’t we do something
about that thing, Kojiro?!
How am I supposed to know
what to do about it...?
Ack!
Oh, it’s fine,
you can keep eating...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Please! Catch Morpeko!!
Please!
Catch Morpeko!!
Let’s just get it out of our hair
and back to the wild!