Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Hodomoe City, Isshu Region
This is Hodomoe City,
a port city in Isshu.
Satoshi and Go have arrived to investigate a rumor
of a newly-discovered Pokémon. However...
I-It wasn’t true?!
Th-Then what about that newly-discovered
evolution of Gear, Gegegegegegegegegegear?
Just a funny joke I came up with
to advertise this shop.
But what about these
sketches from eyewitnesses?
Yeah, I drew those too.
Well then, how about some
life-sized Gear Cookies? An Isshu specialty!
Why not buy some as a souvenir?
Why didn’t you check
if it was real?
We came all the way
to Isshu for this.
Well, I just saw it
on the news, meow.
You’re the one who said
we should go, meow.
Come on, just drop it already...
I wanted to catch that
Gegegegegegegegegear...
That’s too many “Ge”s, meow.
It’s Gegegegegegegegegear, meow.
No! It’s
Gegegegegegegegegegegear!
It’s Gegegegegegegegegear, meow!
Is not!
Does it matter?
It was just a hoax anyway!
Wow, Hodomoe City Market
was amazing!
Huh? Your investigation’s
over already?
Yeah...
How was your shopping?
All done!
I bought all sorts of things.
She’s the only one
who had any luck...
Did something happen?
Come on...
Ooh! Hey, look over there!
It’s the brat boys!
You really think I’d believe...
They are!
No time for arguing.
Let’s catch Pikachu, meow!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Underground Maze Shuffle Panic?!
These Gear Cookies really are tasty!
That’s right!
I came all this way to buy these cookies.
One hundred percent came all this way
to buy these cookies.
He’s trying to convince himself...
I... came here...
to buy... these cookies.
What’s wrong, Sarunori?
What is that?
Building works?
No, it couldn’t be...
Looks pretty deep...
Eevee, no!
Sarunori!
Eevee!
We’ve gotta go after them.
Yeah.
Let’s hurry!
They went down there.
Think you can escape us?
After them!
Hold on!
Wouldn’t it be better
to ambush them here?
Huh?
I’ve got it!
Sonansu—
Sonansu, you stay here
and keep watch, meow.
If Pikachu pops out, then—
Catch it with that!
We’ll hunt them down!
Yeah!
Wait for me, meow!
Sarunori!
Eevee!
Down this way!
There!
What a relief!
What is this hole...?
It’s like a maze down here...
Looks like they don’t
suspect a thing.
Time to catch him!
Hyper Catching Machine, activate!
Huh?
You broke that machine
when you stepped on it, meow.
What?!
Didn’t I tell you to fix it?!
Now how are we
supposed to catch him?!
This is your fault, meow!
How’s it my fault?!
What?!
Come on, stop fighting...
Morpeko?!
Looks like it went straight
to hungry, meow!
Shush!
They’ll spot us if we’re too loud!
Who’ll spot you, now?
Why are you three here?
You’re plotting something again,
aren’t you?
See? We got spotted!
In that case...
We’ll have to take him by force!
Watch out, Pikachu!
Eevee, where are you?
There’s too much smoke!
Let’s just grab Pikachu
and get out of here!
Stay with me, Sarunori!
I bumped into something, meow...
What was that for...?
Pikachu... Are you okay?
Morpeko?!
We did it! Pikachu’s ours!
That went well.
Ack!
That’s not Pikachu!
What a mess...
Where did Sarunori go?
I lost track of everyone else, too...
Eevee!
Looks like it’s not here, meow.
Nyarth?
Hey! Go! Koharu! Pikachu!
This place really is a maze...
Where’d everyone go?
Morpeko, you have any idea?
You’re hungry again?!
I just gave you some
Gear Cookies!
Okay...
But just one.
I’ll be in trouble
if I run out of cookies...
Another fork...
Do I try going left this time?
Pikachu, make sure you stick...
Huh?
Pikachu?
Pikachu!
Stop, Pikachu!
Stop it. If you just pick at random,
you’re going to get lost.
Uhh... How did I get here?
I think I went left, left, then right...
I told you, stop!
Huh? Something stinks...
Eevee! If you can hear me,
say something!
Why are you following me?
This is the only path.
What else am I supposed to do, meow?
Hey... Team Rocket take Pokémon
from people, don’t they?
Why do you do that?
It’s our duty as the evil organization
known as Team Rocket, meow!
A-Are you okay?
Oh, you’re covered in dirt.
Hold still.
Th-Thank you, meow.
She’s kind, meow...
Worlds apart from Musashi, meow...
Can you smell something?
Yeah...
Look out!
Are you okay, meow?
Th-Thank you.
He saved me?
Maybe he’s not that bad after all...
No Pikachu, no brat boys,
and we can’t even find our way out.
Hey, you.
Any idea how to get out of here?
No idea what you just said!
If only Nyarth was here...
Who cares?
Not like having Nyarth here
would change anything.
Don’t say that.
He’s part of our team.
Hey, since we’re stuck with it anyway,
why don’t we just get Eevee to join Team Rocket?
Yeah... If we do that,
we could even have it spy on the brat boys.
Yeah, that’s a great idea!
That decided...
Time for a crash course on all it needs to know
to be part of Team Rocket!
I wonder if Sarunori is with anyone...
It was Team Rocket’s...
What if they’ve caught it again by now...?
Sewers?
So that’s what the smell was...
If there’s sewers,
they must connect to the surface.
So then...
Again?
Wait for me, Pikachu!
You need to stop and think
before you act!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gamageroge
Ground
Water
What’s that...?
Gamageroge! Vibration Pokémon!
Water/Ground type!
The vibrating of the bumps all over its body
causes earthquake-like tremors!
Okay...
Pikachu! Iron—
Pikachu!
No!
Electric moves don’t work
on Gamageroge!
Use Iron Tail!
All right, good work!
Now’s my chance to catch it!
O-Oh...
You can’t do that, Pikachu...
This feeling of having
someone else take the lead...
It reminds me of...
Now I get it,
you’re just like Satoshi!
Pokémon really do
take after their trainers...
I told you that you
can’t eat them all!
I’m starving, too!
Well, if that’s how you wanna do it...
I’ll just have to eat them first!
How come you know how to talk?
Well...
I learned how to for this girl I liked
a long time ago, meow...
Really?
What sort of girls do you like?
I... I like k-kind girls, meow.
You do?
But if you want people to be kind to you,
you should be kind to them first.
Y-You think so...?
Hey, Nyarth...
Why don’t you stop doing bad things?
Wha—?!
Oh, wait...
You’ve been caught by Team Rocket...
Not the case, meow.
Huh? Really?
But you’re friends, right?
Not anymore, meow!
Musashi’s selfish and she never treats Pokémon well.
She’s awful, meow!
You can’t say that.
You shouldn’t speak ill of others,
no matter how bad they are.
If you’ve had a fight,
you need to make peace with her!
She’s dazzling me, meow...
I’ve made up my mind, meow.
I’m leaving Team Rocket
and letting her catch me, meow.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Okay, pause!
So, you do the
“Just kidding, meow!” bit.
The introduction scene is the best time
for righteous evil to shine.
The timing is the key!
Okay then, time for a rehearsal!
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
That was great!
Are you sure about this?
Replacing Nyarth with an Eevee...
It’s fine!
Now, one more rehearsal,
li’l Eevee!
Someone’s there!
It could be Satoshi!
Let’s go!
Iront! Iron Ant Pokémon!
Bug/Steel type!
They have steel armor
and large mandibles!
They dig maze-like nests
and group together to protect themselves!
So this hole was an Iront’s nest...
Pikachu! Electroweb!
That’s not good!
Run for it!
You’re not getting these!
Iront...
Hey, take a look around!
We don’t have time for this...
This thing...
Oh, I know!
I’m not gonna feed ya!
Bleh-bleh-bleh!
Ouch...
That worked!
Run while we can!
That’s a pretty stone, meow...
I’ll give her this and tell her
how I feel, meow!
Ahem...!
What is it?
P-Please be—
What are those things?!
Let’s just run for it!
Satoshi!
Go! Pikachu!
Koharu! ...and Nyarth?!
The brat boy...!
Both of!
Eevee!
What a relief...
If that was me, meow...
So you were okay.
I mean,
not like it matters to me.
Come on...
Right back at ya, meow!
Huh? Where’s Sarunori?
We’ll just have to fight them off...
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Sarunori, where did you go...?
Sarunori!
And...
Sonansu?
What’s that?!
Kuitaran! Anteater Pokémon!
Fire type!
Using their flaming tongues,
they burn through Iront’s bodies and consume them!
Iront is their prey!
Hey!
Wouldn’t this be a good time
to get away?
Yeah!
We should run, too!
We’re finally safe...
Huh? Why is an Iront here?
Did you run away?
I get it...
Then why not come with me?
Monster Ball, go!
Iront’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught Iront!
Huh? Where’d you learn that?
This is gonna be my only chance
to tell her, meow!
I-I love you, meow!
Please be my friend, meow!
Wh-What is this all of a sudden?
Sheesh! We’ve always been a team!
Yeah. We have!
U-Uh... That wasn’t...
I’m glad you managed
to make up with her!
Wh-What?!
Oh, right!
That thing was super hungry!
Where’s the cookies...?
Huh?
I must’ve dropped ‘em.
Kojiro, do something!
R-Right...
Morpeko, retur—
What an awful feeling!
That was rough, but fun!
Yeah.
I even caught an Iront!
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu got tangled up in
unexpected trouble.
Perhaps reuniting with their partners
has brought them a little closer.
She was lovely, meow...
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Six Tairetsu work together as a perfect team
to form one Pokémon.
But doesn’t something about
that Tairetsu look weird to you?
Hey, let’s head back.
It’s the six of you together
that make a Tairetsu, right?
What Pokémon’s this?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Commander Pikachu!
Head Forth, Tairetsu!!