Project Mew seeks to
conduct a search for Mew.
Go was accepted as a member,
and finally became a Chaser.
Though troubled by urgent summons,
he exchanged words of encouragement with Satoshi,
and headed toward the meeting place.
At the port of Kaina City
in the Hoenn Region,
Go met up with Tokio and Shigeru...
...and reunited with Professor Hodaka
and his senior Chasers, Tsurugi and Asahi, at the lab.
Then...
As Satoshi and Dande’s heated
Masters Tournament finals battle was starting...
The extremely short dry season
arrived much earlier than expected,
so we had to bring forward
our departure.
I thank you for your prompt response
to our urgent summons.
I can’t help but imagine
Mew laughing at our being put in disarray.
We are currently headed
to a place called Faraway Island.
Hurricanes and storm clouds
constantly cover the island,
making landing impossible.
But the clouds clear once a year
for the dry season.
Last year, around the center
of Table Mountain...
...we picked up
extremely strong psycho-energy.
Presuming it to have come from Mew,
I set up Project Mew.
We Chasers will land on Faraway Island
and climb Table Mountain.
At its center,
we will search for Mew.
However!
Table Mountain is surrounded
by turbulent wind currents,
making it impossible to
approach by air.
We will land some distance away from it,
and head for Table Mountain on foot.
We’re about to fly
over the island.
Brace for turbulence!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Project Mew
Faraway Island
If anything happens,
report in immediately. Understood?
Chasers,
I pray you find success!
Thank you, sir!
All the Pokémon here
look so lively.
A true Pokémon paradise.
Let’s go.
Yes, sir!
Go, turn on your sensor.
Yes, ma’am.
So... that’s your invention,
which Professor Hodaka
then went and upgraded?
Yeah.
It picks up nearby psycho-energy,
and transmits it to the lab.
Then the lab compares it with the waveform
of Mewtwo, who I’ve met before.
Mew and Mewtwo should have matching
psycho-energy waveforms, after all.
How’s it going,
Professor Hodaka?
It’s functioning properly.
I’ll let you know if I find anything.
That’s amazing!
Something you made
is being used in Project Mew!
It just happened to be
my field of expertise.
Ms. Asahi, your specialties are
molecular biology and geology, right?
Yes.
I approach the many mysteries of Pokémon
from those two perspectives.
Mr. Tsurugi,
your field is mountain ranges,
and you research the ecosystems of
Pokémon living in harsh conditions, right?
Yeah.
Places no human has ever been
are his favorite.
Attempting the impossible
is what he lives for.
If we do meet Mew,
will you catch it?
What would you do, Go?
Huh?
I can’t say for sure what I’ll do
until the moment comes...
...but I guess
I’d want to catch it.
What if...
...just like we look for the Pokémon
we want to catch...
...Pokémon are also looking
for the right person to catch them?
Wouldn’t that be great?
You’re such a romanticist, Tokio.
Sorry...
But I can’t rule out the idea.
If Pokémon are like that,
then maybe Mew appeared before me...
...because it wanted me to catch it?
Don’t know if I’d say that.
Whoa, out of nowhere?!
A Laglarge!
Then I’ve got
just the right Pokémon!
Magical Leaf!
You’re incredible, Tokio!
That’s a Viridion, right?!
Yeah, I caught it
during my Last Mission.
Wow, you did?
Viridion! Grassland Pokémon!
Grass/Fighting type!
A legend tells of this Pokémon
working together...
...with Cobalion and Terrakion
to protect the Pokémon of the Isshu Region!
That’s so cool!
Viridion!
Thank you.
Let’s hurry on ahead.
Yes, sir!
It’s that huge...?
And such a mystifying place...
Apparently ancient fishermen
called it “Sharishari-ma.”
“Sharishari”?
It’s the sound of the mountain’s evil spirits
eating humans.
Meaning this is a fearsome mountain
to stay away from at all costs.
It’s also a geologically
important mountain.
Its topography hasn’t changed
for hundreds of millions of years.
It may have been the center—
the core— of the world since time immemorial.
This is...
The center of the world...
This is Hodaka.
Can you hear me?
We hear you.
The sensor has picked up
psycho-energy!
And the waveform?
Professor Hodaka,
what was the waveform?
—can... ear...
Professor!
Huh...?
It cut off...
Same here.
The sensor isn’t working, either...
My Smartphone Rotom...
No luck.
Even my flashlight...
Not our Monster Balls, too?!
This can’t be real...
None of our devices
are working?
Looks like it.
That means we can’t even recall these three
to their Monster Balls...
And behind this is...
...Mew?
We weren’t able to
confirm the waveform,
but it definitely picked up
psycho-energy.
So, it came from near here?
Should we head back for now
and get reorganized?
If Mew is behind this,
we can’t let this chance get away.
We no longer have the help of Pokémon
other than Manyula, Marilluri, and Sarunori.
We use everything we currently have
and begin the climb.
Understood?
Yes, sir!
Sarunori, let’s do our best!
Manyula and I will go first
and anchor the rope.
Use that rope to follow us.
Then I’ll be your backup.
My backup will be Manyula.
Shigeru, you climb behind us
and guide the followers.
Yes, sir.
I’ll be at the tail end
and ensure everyone stays safe.
Please do.
Following Shigeru
will be Tokio, then Go.
Yes, sir!
I’m pathetic for always
relying on my Pokémon...
Shigeru, watch out!
Huh?
An Airm'd?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Looks like this is their territory.
What do we do?
We’ll take a different route
to the center!
Got it.
We’ll keep heading up.
Manyula,
you back up Shigeru.
Let’s go.
Yes, ma’am.
Thank you.
What’s that...?
A waterfall?
If we so much as touch the stream,
it’ll send us falling headfirst...
Looks like we’ll have to turn back.
What is it?
A cave...
We might be able to
go through there.
Good work.
So this is...
...Table Mountain’s summit...
This is just our starting point.
Let’s get to the center.
Y-Yes, sir!
Pokémon?
They’re Melecie.
Are they sleeping?
We don’t know
what dangers there could be.
Everyone, stay vigilant.
Yes, ma’am.
The center would be about here.
What’s this?
An unnaturally perfect
round hole.
Like it was made by someone...
Mew?
Yes.
This will work.
I’ll check inside.
Right!
What happened?
Kurabo Berries.
And noticeably eaten.
So a Pokémon was here?
It hasn’t been long since...
What?
Is something there?
Some sort of hair is stuck to it.
A hair?
A very short, fine hair...
It might belong to Mew!
Huh?!
When we get back to the lab,
we’ll run a DNA analysis.
This is quite a strange space.
I wouldn’t have thought
it’d be this open...
There are the usual
cave Pokémon here,
but also so many fossil Pokémon
living wild...
This is likely a closed space
completely untouched by humans,
cut off from outside contact
for hundreds of millions of years.
There could be Pokémon
with unique biology here!
Mew comes first. Let’s go.
Y-Yes, sir!
If Mew was the one eating
those Kurabo Berries from earlier...
...it could be down this cave!
Do you think it’ll appear to us?
Of course!
But Mew doesn’t appear when it senses
the evil feelings of humans, right?
Don’t worry!
We don’t have
any evil feelings at all, yeah!
Even if we get to see Mew,
don’t let your guard down.
When Professor Hodaka
did research in various regions,
he found many reports
of Mew sightings.
While some say
it was as merciful as an angel,
others call it as cruel as a demon.
A demon?
Apparently a trainer chasing Mew
was slammed to the ground,
and had fire and cold
launched at them.
I don’t believe that!
That trainer must’ve done
something pretty bad, don’t you think?
It’s not here.
If we could at least find
some sort of trace of it...
Down there...
Looks like we can get through.
I’ll check it out.
Kabutops and Ptera!
Stand back, Shigeru!
Meet them with Crossroad Kill!
Evil Pulse!
Now’s our chance!
Right!
Solrock and Lunatone!
The Meteorite Pokémon,
said to have fallen from space?
Both of you, get behind me!
Yes, ma’am!
Marilluri! Light Screen!
Sarunori!
Hydro Pump!
Go, Tokio, follow me!
Yes, ma’am!
Sarunori, you okay?
Good to hear it.
Mr. Tsu—
Something’s here!
Groudon?!
An underground lake...
Look! We might just be able
to pass through there!
We have no choice but to try.
Yes, ma’am!
Kaiogre!
Suddenly, the Legendary Pokémon
Groudon appears...
...along with Kaiogre.
Will Go and the others
be able to encounter Mew...
...somewhere on this
enigmatic island?!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The sensor is responding!
There’s no way to calm Mew down
but to battle it!
You’re still going?
Mew can be an angel or a demon!
If we let it keep rampaging,
the other Pokémon will be in danger!
I’ve longed to see you again,
but not like this!
Taking the Future in Hand!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Here we go!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Championing the evils of truth and love!
Team Rocket Explorers!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Following an order
to catch new Pokémon...
...we made our first visit
to the Paldea Region.
Oh, meow?
There’s one, meow!
I think that one’s...
The Grass Cat Pokémon,
Nyahoja.
It says it sulks if it sees its trainer giving attention
to a Pokémon other than itself.
You like to sulk too, Nyarth!
When Sakaki’s with his Persian—
How rude, meow!
That doesn’t bother me at all,
you hear, meow?!
Well, let’s catch it quick!
Yeah!
Huh? What’s that?
What a great aroma...
Don’t fall asleep, meow!
What an awful feeling...
Today’s roundup!
Nyahoja has...
...such a great scent!
Such a
great
scent