Would you become research fellows
at my institute?
“Research fellows”?
It means special lab assistants.
Satoshi and Go have become
research fellows at the Sakuragi Institute.
They were intrigued by
Pokémon growing gigantic,
which led them
to visit the Galar Region.
Now, Pikachu! Electric Net!
At their first stop in Shoot City,
Satoshi had his backpack
stolen by Hibunny,
but he managed to get it back...
...before boarding the train
to the Wild Area.
The next day...
Looks delicious!
Thanks for the food!
You know,
this bread is really hard...
Well then, why don’t you break it
with your hands before eating it?
Great idea!
I thought I saw something.
Must have imagined it.
Delicious!
What was that?
You try it too!
It tastes better this way!
There’s no way.
This is great!
I know, right?
I am so sorry!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Kabigon Grows Giant?!
The Mystery of Daimax!!
What?
All right, let’s go find
a giant Pokémon!
Better get some pointers first.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
I’ve heard there are Pokémon
that grow giant around here.
Do you know anything about it?
Grow giant?
Oh, you must mean Daimax.
Daimax?
That’s right. You can find it by
following the red lights.
Wild Area, Galar Region
What are you looking at?
Are these the red lights
the station worker was talking about?
No, they couldn’t be...
Is that...?
I see! Is this Daimax?
Awesome!
Kabigon! Sleeping Pokémon!
Normal type!
It eats 400 kilos of food every day!
It starts nodding off while eating—
and continues to eat even while it’s asleep!
Its average height is 2.1 meters!
All right! Let’s get recording!
Okay!
This Kabigon’s height...
...is 3.2 meters!
Hey, Satoshi...
I...
...expected something grander.
Actually... I did too.
You think so, too?
Maybe Director Sakuragi...
...wanted to teach us that things aren’t always
as impressive in real life as stories make them out to be.
It really isn’t moving at all...
We should observe it
for a bit longer, I guess.
Yeah.
Go.
Maybe Kabigon’s
waiting for that to fall?
There’s no way.
It’d just grab that
if it wanted to eat it, yeah?
You think so?
You were right!
Ouch...
Who threw that rock?
Huh?
Hibunny?!
The one from yesterday?
But... it’s not brown!
Oh! It washed off the mud!
You look better this way!
Were you following us?
I think it wants to come with you!
You really...?
I’m sorry.
I decided that
the first Pokémon I catch...
...will be Mew.
I made up my mind way back then.
If you really did follow me,
then I’m honored.
But... I’m sorry.
Huh? What’s this?
Red lights!
Don’t tell me...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kabigon
Normal
Satoshi, what is this?!
How should I know?!
Run!
Hibunny! Follow me!
Hibunny!
Is this...
...what the station worker mentioned?
Daimax?
This is a mountain!
I mean, it’s massive,
and there’s even a tree up there!
This is bad, Satoshi!
What?! It’s on the tracks!
A train will pass by here
in eight minutes!
What?!
Hey! Wake up, Kabigon!
Stand back, Go!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
No use...
Satoshi!
That was close!
Is it moving in its sleep?
Whatever the case,
we have to move it, and fast!
Wake up, Kabigon!
Please, just wake up!
Wake! Up!
Satoshi, look!
If we drop that berry...
It might move in order to eat it!
Got it! I’ll give it a try!
Counting on you!
Pikachu!
Let’s do this!
All right...
It’s huge!
This is insane...
Where do we drop that?
Satoshi!
Drop the berry right here!
Got it!
Pikachu, hit it with an Iron Tail!
No good, huh?
Go! How much time left?!
Four more minutes!
Then it’s all or nothing!
Pikachu!
Use a flurry of Iron Tails!
Come on!
Good job, Pikachu!
One more!
You did it!
I knew you could!
Go, it’s headed your way!
Good, keep it up!
Go!
Not good!
Move!
Please, move!
Is it hopeless?
That’s...!
All right! We’re gonna
move it for sure!
Pikachu!
Move...!
Hibunny, Double Kick!
Hit it with a Double Kick!
Do it!
All right!
Hibunny...
Hey! You can’t eat Hibunny!
Thank goodness!
You did it, Hibunny!
Look! Your Double Kick
saved everyone!
Thanks!
Wait!
You were really cool!
I’ve decided!
The first Pokémon I catch
will be you!
That okay with you?
Better catch you
with a curve ball, yeah?
Monster Ball, go!
Did it work?
Don’t worry! You got it!
Really?
Hibunny’s data will be
added to the Index!
You did it, Go!
I caught my first Pokémon!
Hibunny, go!
I look forward to working with you!
Looks like they’ll make
a great team.
We’re back!
Really? Kabigon’s Daimax?
It was as big as a mountain!
And it still managed to jump
at that size!
Sounds like quite the experience!
What’s wrong, Wanpachi?
Hibunny?
Go, is that...?
Let me introduce you!
This is my first-ever Pokémon:
Hibunny!
Satoshi and Go met a Daimax Pokémon
in the Galar Region...
...and Go caught
his first-ever Pokémon: Hibunny!
Next time, more dreams and adventures
await in the world of Pocket Monsters!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’m getting the urge to go on a huge catching spree
and fill out the Index!
All right, wanna go
catch some right now?
There! It’s a Poppo!
All right! Monster Ball, go!
Huh? Right away?
It’s Raising Wind!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
I Got Loads of Pokemon!
´
The Road to Mew!!
I Got Loads of Pokemon!
´
The Road to Mew!!
I Got Loads of Pokémon!