The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The eight mighty trainers
aiming for the summit...
...have begun battling.
The first round,
composed of 3v3 battles...
The second match was
Wataru versus Carne.
Against Wataru’s advancing
dragon brigade,
Carne skillfully used super effective attacks
and defensive moves to claim victory,
landing a seat in the semifinals.
And now, the third match is the Champion of Sinnoh,
Shirona, versus the Champion of Isshu, Iris.
This battle is a 3v3! Both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Come out, Doryuzu!
Emerge from the waves, Tritodon!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
VS Shirona!
Iris, the Path to be Dragon Master!!
Tritodon! Sea Slug Pokémon!
Water/Ground type!
Although its body is squishy,
it’s remarkably resilient!
The softness of its body
helps absorb the force of impacts!
Doryuzu! Subterrene Pokémon!
Ground/Steel type!
Also known as the Drill King!
It can tunnel through the terrain
at speeds reaching 150 km/h!
Iris has been raising that Doryuzu
since he was a Moguryu!
I haven’t seen him in so long...
What?! You know her too?!
You see, Iris adventured
around Isshu with Satoshi.
He’s well acquainted
with Ms. Shirona, too.
Wh-What’s up with you, Satoshi...?
We’re bursting with excitement!
It’s gonna be
squishy against steely!
I can’t wait, meow!
Snore, snore...
It went back to sleep!
Huh?
What is it?
Getting a good look at her,
I recognize that frilly girl, meow!
You’re right!
It’s the Isshu brat girl!
My, oh my,
she sure is all dressed up.
But Iris is a Dragon user...
Doryuzu was quite the surprise.
Apparently, she’s even had lessons
from Ms. Shirona.
So both of them
know each other’s cards...
Will we get to see
a changing of the guard?
This is one to watch!
Tritodon versus Doryuzu!
What sort of battle
is about to unfold?
Let the battle begin!
Tritodon!
Rain Prayer!
It started to rain!
The power of Water-type moves
will increase!
Doryuzu! Metal Claw!
Metal Claws
cleaving through the rain!
Tritodon!
Take the blow!
It connec—
Whoa! It repelled him!
I can tell you’ve
sharpened up your attacks!
You taught me a lot,
Ms. Shirona!
Your advice from back then...
...is still helping us,
even now!
Thanks to you,
I even became Champion!
And today,
as the Champion of Isshu, Iris...
Ms. Shirona,
I’m going to defeat you!
Tritodon,
use Muddy Water!
Focus Blast!
Doryuzu!
As we stand upon this stage...
We are both nothing more than
Pokémon Trainers!
Yet at the same time,
challengers aiming for the top!
I won’t go easy on you.
To test my own potential...
I shall defeat you
and move onward!
Tritodon! Dissolve!
Drill Liner!
Oh? Tritodon is completely unfazed
by the Drill Liner!
Of course, Dissolve is a move
that raises your defense.
Her Water-type moves
have been powered up with Rain Prayer, too.
Ms. Shirona is ruthless!
What’s your attack plan, Iris?
Don’t worry, Doryuzu!
It’s our turn, Tritodon!
Muddy Water!
Doryuzu! Dodge it!
And Doryuzu is swallowed
by Tritodon’s Muddy Water once again!
I’ll put my faith in Doryuzu...
...and bet on this attack!
Horn Drill!
One-hit... knockout!
Tritodon is unable to battle!
A one-hit knockout victory
from Doryuzu!
Competitor Shirona is the first one
to take a black mark.
The Rain Prayer’s effect
has also ended.
All right!
Good going, Iris, Doryuzu!
But she can’t let her guard down.
She’s up against Ms. Shirona.
You’re not half bad,
frilly Isshu girl.
It’s thanks to all our training
that you made it this far, meow.
You should come
thank us sometime.
You did well, Tritodon.
Spirit of water, show your elegance...
Milokaross!
Competitor Shirona
sends in Milokaross!
Right now, Competitor Iris
is keeping up the pressure.
What will she do next?
Rush in, Doryuzu!
Drill Liner!
Hydro Pump!
Hydro Pump hits its target!
Doryuzu is unable to battle!
Doryuzu...
You did good hanging in there.
That incredible speed...
I couldn’t predict
how Milokaross would move!
This time, Competitor Iris
takes the black mark!
Kairyu, I’m counting on you!
Ooh, I haven’t seen him in a while.
Ms. Shirona, just watch and see
what Kairyu can do!
Thunder Punch!
An Electric move,
super effective against Water types!
That’s gotta sting!
Charm Voice!
A Fairy move!
They’re devastatingly effective
on Dragon types!
Kairyu, hold on!
Milokaross!
Oh, no!
Iron Head!
Kairyu!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
Kairyu couldn’t stand up
to Milokaross’s rapid onslaught!
Competitor Iris
takes a second black mark!
She’s strong...
That Milokaross is terrifying...
Kairyu...
You must feel frustrated.
The pain of my Pokémon...
I feel it, too!
Just wait and see.
I’ll win the next bout!
Ononox...
It’s all up to you!
There he is! Ononox!
He’s really strong!
I knew she’d pick him!
But he’s a Dragon type...
How’s he supposed to handle
Milokaross’s Fairy moves?
Ms. Shirona!
When I became the Champion,
he’s the one who finished the battle!
He’s always giving me strength!
Milokaross! Charm Voice!
Psycho Cutter!
Pretty good.
All right!
So her approach is
“offense is the best defense”?
Looking good, Iris!
Wide Breaker!
Hydro Pump!
Cutting through the Hydro Pump,
the Wide Breaker bursts forth!
Milokaross is unable to battle!
That was so cool, Ononox!
You fought well,
Milokaross.
Competitor Shirona is also left
with only one Pokémon.
She’s got Ms. Shirona cornered!
Amazing...
Is it finally time for her ace?
Take to the skies...
Gaburias!
So you’re finally here,
Gaburias.
You gotta keep your calm, Iris!
Dragon versus dragon...
This is going to settle it.
Competitor Shirona’s third Pokémon is her greatest partner,
whose countless battles have become legends... Gaburias!
Now, how will Competitor Iris
and Ononox combat this?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Shower upon us, stars of the heavens!
Draco Meteor!
Reversed Scale!
Ononox charges in without any care
for the Draco Meteor!
Wow...
What a battle style!
Does nothing scare him?!
A fierce trade of blows!
But neither goes down!
Oh! Ononox has become confused
from Reversed Scale’s effect!
What’s this? Ononox hit his own head
to snap out of the confusion!
Now that’s amazing!
I’ve never seen anything
like this before...
That’s Iris’s brand of
crazy tactics!
Yeah! You can do this, Iris!
This isn’t over.
Nowhere close.
We can still keep fighting!
You are marvelous, Iris.
Now, let’s do it! Ononox!
Right.
In that case...
I shall defeat you
with all my might!
That’s...!
...a Key Stone!
Gaburias...
Mega Evolve!
Mega Gaburias!
She’s so cool!
Ms. Shirona
used Mega Evolution?!
I suppose this is
her showing she’s serious.
However, Ononox has
a lot of potential, too.
I can’t tell how the battle
will play out.
That’s an incredible
hidden trick, meow.
Now I’m getting fired up!
How strong!
I want it! I really want it!
Dragon Claw!
Ononox! Lure her in,
then use Psycho Cutter!
Tremendous power
collides with tremendous power!
Attack!
That Ononox is
putting up a real fight!
Dragon Pulse!
We’re almost there!
I’ll hone my mind...
...and become one
with my Pokémon!
Ononox.
This is our final attack.
Let’s give it
everything we’ve got!
Gaburias,
finish her with the next move.
Draco Meteor!
Ononox!
Use Dragon Pulse!
Ononox is unable to battle!
Gaburias wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Shirona!
It finally comes to an end!
In the third match of the first round,
the referee’s fan rises for Competitor Shirona!
Gaburias...
You battled well.
Thank you.
You did your best, Ononox.
Ononox... Kairyu... Doryuzu...
I love all of you.
Iris?
Ms. Shirona...
Thank you very much.
I’m going to get
a whole lot stronger.
That was an unforgettable battle.
You have my thanks, too.
The frilly Isshu girl
was so close, meow!
No, this loss will
only make her stronger!
I know it will!
That’s right...
You can follow our example.
That was a really amazing
Dragon showdown!
Yeah...
Iris...
Hey, Satoshi?
And so, Competitor Shirona
secures her advancement to the semifinals!
The upcoming fourth match
will decide her opponent.
Iris... Tough luck, huh?
Satoshi...
I lost.
You did, huh?
Ms. Shirona is so amazing!
She’s amazing...
Amazing, but...
Ah, now I feel better!
Thank you.
I know! For Satoshi’s next match,
let’s cheer him on together!
Yeah! Let’s!
I’m counting on you two, then!
The third match of the first round
in the Pokémon World Championships...
...has ended in Shirona’s victory.
And now, Satoshi’s battle
is finally beginning.
His opponent is
the Champion of Hoenn, Daigo.
How will Satoshi fight this mighty
opponent?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
Next is the fourth match
of the first round!
The Champion of Hoenn, Competitor Daigo,
versus the Champion of Alola, Competitor Brat Boy, meow!
So, what should we
keep our eyes on?
Let’s see, it’d have to be...
My good looks, hmm?
Mr. Head Deluxe, go ahead!
The regional delicacies
that Morpeko’s always snacking on, meow!
You’re picking that?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi Heads Into Battle! VS Daigo!!
Let’s all tune in, meow!