Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Oh, just the wind?
What was that?!
Renji?!
What happened?
Satoshi, Go...
G-Gänger...
It’s back?!
And that means...
Another chance!
This time I’ll catch it, for sure!
I’ll find it first!
No, I will!
D-Don’t leave me!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi is Cursed...!
Where are you, Gänger?
Not here...
The temperature should drop
wherever Gänger is.
Satoshi?
It’s nothing.
Over there!
Yeah!
Oh, here!
Kikuna, was that Gänger again?
Y-Yes...
Barrierd?
A book?
“Gän-Gera-Geh?”
Tea...
Crash!
Got soaked...
Your broom...
“Gän-Gera-Geh?”
And there you have it.
There you have what?
Well anyway, let’s find Gänger!
Right, Pikachu?
Pikachu!
Are you okay?
That’s good.
Ow!
What?
Ow! Ow!
Gänger!
Pikachu, use Electroweb!
Cut it out!
Huh?
It ran away?
Looks like it made
another huge mess...
Let’s all clean it up.
Sure.
Sheesh...
What does that Gänger want to do?
Does it show up for
some specific reason?
Actually, the person who
showed me this building told me...
...that it was a nasty workplace.
It was a nest of Iwark?!
A nasty work place.
He said that, whenever people came by,
poltergeist activity would occur.
I’m sure Gänger was
living here even back then.
What?! Why would you make
a place like that into your institute?!
Well...
I figured having things fall over, the electricity cut out
and doors opening on their own would be fun.
Oh, dear...
Right...
A blackout?
Good grief...
It always settled down quick,
so I figured it would be all right!
That’s our director...
Maybe Gänger gave up because
its tricks didn’t work on Director Sakuragi.
Then why did it start
causing trouble again?
That’s the rub!
First, Renji and Coil were
attacked in the basement.
Which means...
What? It’s my fault?!
That could be part of it, but...
There’s us, Satoshi, Go,
and all the new Pokémon...
It might not like that
things have gotten so lively.
Yeah! That’s gotta be it!
Satoshi?
I feel a chill...
What if you’ve been
cursed by Gänger?
Cursed?
It’s still not entirely clear
what Gänger is,
but it might even curse its own trainer,
gradually weaken them,
until finally...!
W-W-What?!
That’s just a hypothesis.
Y-Yeah!
There’s no cur—
Satoshi, are you okay?
Just fine...
Huh?
You look pale.
No, I’m fine!
That’s a flower vase!
Come on...
What are you doing?
He really is cursed! I knew it!
Oh, Renji, you exaggerate!
Whoa!
H-H-H-Hey?!
I really do think
something is going on here.
Oh, come on, there’s no curse!
But Satoshi...
I’m totally fine!
No big deal!
This’ll all go away with
some exercise!
Satoshi?!
Come on, Hibunny!
Running sure helped,
right, Pikachu?
It’s the brat boy and
Pikachu, meow!
What? What was that?!
Ow...
I’m sorry!
Watch yourself!
What’s this? You still cursed?
That was three years ago.
I’m as lucky as it gets!
There’s no stupid curse.
Satoshi!
But it sure was awful
back when it was around.
I couldn’t win any battles,
and all my attempts at catching Pokémon failed...
I’d fall down the stairs
or lose things...
I had bad luck
with everything I did.
That’s hilarious!
That’s what we call a curse!
That plague has left me!
My luck’s perfect now!
You wait here, okay?
Don’t go anywhere, you hear?!
Here you go.
I’ll be cursed!
I swear... I never should have
caught that miserable Gänger.
Gänger?!
This is where you were?!
W-Why are you...?!
Gänger!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gänger
Poison
Ghost
W-What? No way!
Stop it, Gänger!
That’s your trainer, right?
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Calm down, already!
That Gänger is yours, right?!
You should listen to...
Satoshi, look out!
Stay away! Stay away!
Stay away!
I told you to wait there,
didn’t I?
Nothing but trouble comes my way
when you’re around!
I’ve had enough of you!
That’s just cruel!
Shut up, shut up... shut up!
Hey, wait!
Hey!
Gänger...
Being abandoned by its trainer
must’ve been shocking.
Satoshi!
I’ll find Gänger!
I can’t leave it like this!
Yeah, I should have figured...
That’s so you, Satoshi.
I-I was just thinking
I might try to catch Gänger!
It’s not like I want to
help Satoshi out or anything!
Hibunny, let’s find Gänger!
I want that Gänger.
It looks pretty tough.
It’ll be ours, meow.
Hey, excuse me?
You, Gänger over there.
Would you like to
follow the path of evil with us?
I heard what happened to you, meow.
I really feel ya, meow.
You should forget that nasty trainer
and team up with us, meow!
Just use your power
without restraint,
and blow up
anyone that bothers you!
It’s saying “You’re not fooling me.
I won’t trust filthy humans!”, meow.
It really doesn’t
trust humans, huh?
Quit whining and come with us!
Yeah!
You’re wasting your time!
We came prepared for you!
Its distrust of humans
is growing stronger, meow.
Who cares?
As long as we catch it, we win.
Iron Tail!
You okay, Gänger?
The brat boy!
Team Rocket!
What are you up to?!
We were so close!
Gänger, will you
help me battle them?
Hey, Satoshi?
Forget what your old trainer said.
I need you... right now!
C’mon, Gänger!
Hey! Don’t just carry on
like we’re not here!
That Gänger belongs to us!
Yeah, meow! Besides, that Gänger
doesn’t trust humans anymore, meow!
You don’t have to
trust me right away.
But just know I trust you!
You’ll help me, Gänger?
Why’d you go to him?!
Well in that case...
Yeah!
Vending, come on!
Here we go, Nyarth!
Bring it, meow!
Rocket...
Vending...
Secret!
Here it comes!
We got two!
Throw ’em, already, meow!
You’re up!
Come forth!
The Beckon Pokémon,
Samayouru!
Huh? They’re both Samayouru?
Ya got a problem with Sakaki?
Not at all, meow!
Samayouru. Beckon Pokémon.
Ghost type.
It sucks drifting will-o’-the-wisps into its body.
What happens inside is a mystery.
All Ghost types...
You got this, right, Gänger?
We’ll take both
Gänger and Pikachu!
Samayouru!
Shadow Strike!
Dodge it with Lightning Speed!
Ice Punch!
It attacked Pikachu?!
Thanks, Gänger!
Oh, that’s what it was...
Fire Punch!
Gänger!
Night Head!
It countered with
another Night Head?
Fire Punch!
Pikachu!
Now, Night Head!
Oh no! They’re taking a beating!
Go, go!
Nice work!
Gänger!
Samayouru!
Oh, they got pushed back, meow!
Wha—?! It vanished?!
Gänger, use Shadow Ball!
It was going so well at first!
I thought it didn’t trust humans!
We’ve been tricked, meow!
What an awful feeling!
Amazing! You teamed up
with Gänger and actually won?!
Gänger did all the work.
Thanks, Gänger!
Now, let’s go back
to the institute.
Satoshi?!
I... I...
Satoshi... Satoshi...
Satoshi!
You okay, Satoshi?
Yeah...
You didn’t realize you had a fever?
Sorry.
Well, I should apologize for
chalking it up to Gänger’s curse, too.
That’s right!
Where’s Gänger?!
Ow!
An apple?
Is it... worried about you?
Gänger?
A Monster Ball?
This must mean...
Gänger!
Gänger, be my partner!
I got Gänger!
I wanted that Gänger, too...
Come out!
I’ll be counting on you.
Gänger?
Hey?!
Hey, Gänger?
It’s probably telling you to
eat those and get better fast!
I guess.
Delicious!
You want some, Pikachu?
The curse situation has been
safely resolved.
Gänger still might cause
some trouble, but...
It’s slowly warming up
to our heroes... right?
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Hibunny wants to use a Fire move?
Try more like...
Graaaah! Open up wide, then launch the heat
from your belly, like, a-ta-ta-ta!
You really don’t need to
push yourself so hard, though...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Hibunny's Fiery Kick!
Working For Tomorrow!!
Hibunny’s Fiery Kick!