Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
The strange, strange creatures
who live on this planet.
In the forests,
in the skies,
in the seas,
and in space...
You can find them
all over the world.
And... One Pokémon is said to hold
the genes of all Pokémon...
Mew!
As a matter of fact, psycho-energy thought to
belong to Mew has been detected.
What?!
This is the Sakuragi Institute,
which researches Pokémon.
Sakuragi Institute
Mew is...
Does that mean Mew’s there?
It’s not impossible.
Sakuragi Institute Director
Professor Sakuragi
Hear that? What now, Go?
I... might get to catch Mew!
These boys are Satoshi and Go.
Satoshi                              Go
As research fellows,
or special lab assistants,
they have met and
interacted with Pokémon,
sharing many
different experiences.
Director Sakuragi!
I wanna go see Mew!
I’ll go, I’ll go!
I’ll go for sure!
I thought you’d say that,
so I arranged for a boat.
Yay!
That’s great!
Ever since they first met
at the Pokémon Camp,
Director Sakuragi's daughter
Koharu..........
Mew has been Go’s inspiration.
More than my inspiration,
it’s my target, yeah?
Huh?
Koharu, what about school?
See you later!
So, where is it?
Where’s Mew?
Right. As for that... Kikuna?
There was only one landmass in the area
where the psycho-energy was detected.
Assistant
..........Kikuna
Here, the isolated isle of Cero Island!
Assistant
..........Renji
An isle surrounded by steep cliffs
that keep people away. It’s very mysterious!
That gets me fired up!
Yeah!
To understand Pokémon is
to understand the world.
As a researcher myself,
I pray that you do get to see Mew.
Yeah!
Cero Island
This is Cero Island...?
Mew is somewhere
on this island!
Satoshi!
Yeah!
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Battling & Catching!
Mewtwo Rises Again
All right!
Where should we start?
Ta-daah!
We’re close enough that my special sensor
can pick up Mew’s psycho-energy...
Huh? Nothing detected...
Then let’s just look wherever.
In this huge jungle?!
I’m going first!
Wait for me!
Poppo! Onisuzume!
Butterfree, too!
A Mankey!
Monster Ball, go!
Mankey’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
My first catch of the day!
Great!
Huh? Why’d the Mankey stop?
Go!
A sinking bog!
Hold on, Satoshi! Go!
Heracross,
I’m counting on you!
Heracross, catch!
You saved me, Heracross...
Water Gun!
Oh! All cleaned up.
Thanks, Messon.
Now, then...
How do we get across...?
Don’t worry, it’ll work out!
You’re always
so easygoing, Satoshi.
Caterpie, I’m counting on you!
Caterpie, String Shot!
Okay! Good work!
I’ll wrap the string here
on a branch...
And the Caterpie Tightrope
is complete!
Ooh!
I’ll go first, then!
Sure!
Pikachu, you hold on tight!
One, two...
Okay then, me too...
Kingler?!
Go!
Go, Monster Ball!
Great!
All right!
Go, watch out!
Well done!
Crab’s data will be
added to the Index!
Successful landing!
Excellent!
Even when you stumble,
you land feet first, Go.
I didn’t stumble. That near-fall was
well within my expectations, yeah!
Let’s cross here.
Okay!
Come on, Go!
I know!
Gyarados?!
Satoshi!
I’m fine!
Monster Ball, go!
Pikachu, Electric Net!
Thanks, Satoshi!
Go! Cross over while you can!
Right!
Pikachu!
Lend us a hand, Dugong!
Satoshi!
You’re kidding...
Dugong, do your best!
Pikachu!
Dugong, return!
Where are we?
We went over the waterfall,
then blacked out...
So cute!
What happened?
Hey, you guys!
Do you live...
They ran off.
Did we frighten them?
Why have you come here?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gyarados
Flying
Water
Why have you come here?
It talks?!
No, is this what’s
called telepathy...?
Mewtwo.
Mew... two?
Did you save us?
Thank you!
Not Mew, but Mewtwo...
It is bigger than Mew, I guess.
But it gives off kind of
a similar vibe.
I’m getting a reaction!
What’s going on?!
Or... is Mew
somewhere nearby?!
You seek Mew?
Yeah!
To what end?
I’ll catch it!
Catching every Pokémon
to reach Mew is my dream!
Hmm...
How will catching every Pokémon
mean reaching Mew?
To catch a Pokémon is to understand it,
that’s what I believe.
I want to catch all sorts of Pokémon,
and learn more about Pokémon!
If I understand every Pokémon,
I can reach Mew,
who holds the genes of every Pokémon!
Go...
Mewtwo...
You’re a Pokémon, right?
Which means...
I can catch you in a Monster Ball, right?
Catch Mewtwo?!
I want to learn more about you!
So... I’ll catch you!
I am strong.
I was created to be
the world’s strongest Pokémon.
Mewtwo!
I want to battle you!
I wanna beat the strongest
Pokémon in a battle,
to get closer to my dream of
being a Pokémon Master!
So, you’re fine with that, right?
C’mon, Mewtwo!
As you wish.
Then... Put those “dreams” of yours
on the line, and face me!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Come on out, Aceburn!
Iron Tail!
Blaze Kick!
Are you okay, Pikachu?
Aceburn!
Satoshi!
Yeah. Combination!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Blaze Kick!
100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
Rest up here.
Lucario, I choose you!
Aceburn, use Pyro Ball!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Aceburn!
Lucario!
All right!
Good going!
Shadow Clones!
Lightning Speed!
Force Palm!
Don’t give up! Blaze Kick!
Reversal!
Aceburn!
Lucario!
Gah...!
Are you finished?
Not yet!
Lucario, can you keep going?
Do all you can, Aceburn!
Okay! Shadow Clones!
Pyro Ball!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Go!
You spoke of your dreams before.
The world is vast.
There exist many Pokémon
you cannot even imagine.
Knowing that, will you still
chase your dreams?
Of course!
Always!
Because I have my friends!
It seems you have
formed bonds properly.
Here, here...
However,
not everyone does the same.
Do you mean that when
they were scared of us,
it’s because they’d
been hurt by humans?
I get it. Mewtwo rescues
Pokémon like that from people...
This is not a place
for humans to tread.
However, I have enjoyed today
more than anything in a long time.
Mewtwo!
Hold on!
You are frail, fleeting, immature...
But that is exactly why
you possess infinite potential...
Mewtwo!
Your journey...
has only just begun.
Mewtwo...
was really strong.
Yeah. We’ve still got
a long way to go.
Huh?
This is the Sakuragi Institute.
Did Mewtwo bring us here?
I hope we’ll see it again.
‘Course we will!
After all,
the future lies in my hands!
Our hands, right?
Go? Satoshi?
Koharu!
We’re back!
Welcome back!
How was it?
Did you get to see Mew?
Satoshi and Go will keep running
towards their dreams.
Now then, everyone... A world of dreams and
adventures with Pocket Monsters awaits!
Let’s go!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Pokémon Eating Contest?
That sounds fun!
Let’s enter, Go!
How naïve.
Kuchiba City’s Eating Contest
is famous for attracting veteran eaters.
If the two favorites face off...
...then even the winner’s
not getting off lightly.
Team Rocket’s gonna be headed...
...straight for the victory road!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Pokémon Champion!
The Battle of Big Eaters!!
The Battle of Big Eaters!