The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
Satoshi has defeated the formidable Saito,
and risen up to 36th place.
Now,
who will he be facing today?
Everyone’s yellin’ for me.
I’ve gotta win this!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mary From Spike Town!
Spike Town, Galar Region
Is this really
where I’m gonna battle?
Hmm...
Well, this is where
those Team Yell guys said we should go...
We’re the thoughtful Team Yell!
The thoughtful and kind Team Yell,
with a message to tell!
Today’s battle won’t be here
in Shoot City after all!
Spike Town’s the place,
for real!
They said that, but...
Oh, there’s a Gym here.
That must be the place.
Let’s go!
Here’s a number I’ve been saving!
Excuse me!
Strinder! Discharge!
Hey, that’s dangerous!
I’m rehearsing right now.
Nobody’s allowed in here.
Isn’t this supposed to be a Gym?
It is.
This is our stage, Spike Gym.
I’m the Gym Leader,
the Evil-type Pokémon prodigy.
They call me the Sorrowful Nezu!
Let me introduce my band!
Backup vocals:
Tachifusaguma!
Drums:
Gorillander!
Guitar:
Strinder High!
Bass:
Strinder Low!
Strinder! Punk Pokémon!
Electric/Poison type!
When clawing at
its chest protrusions,
its High Form sounds like it’s strumming a guitar;
and its Low Form, a bass guitar!
Concert’s in an hour.
Come back then.
My name is Satoshi!
I’m here for
a Championships battle!
Satoshi...
The one from Kanto,
in the Hyper Class?
Yeah! You’ve heard of me?
Ooh, Satoshi, you’re famous!
This is odd.
Mary should be waiting for you
at Shoot Stadium already.
Huh? Shoot Stadium?
Some “thoughtful Team Yell” guys
told us the battle was here...
Don’t tell me they...
Yell!
Those guys of ours...
I’m sorry for the trouble.
And wait, who’s Mary?
My sister.
Your sister?
This isn’t good, Satoshi!
We don’t have time!
What do I do?! What do I do?!
What do I do, what do I do,
what do I do...?!
I take full responsibility.
I’ll take you to Shoot City.
Whoa, this is cool!
Satoshi, you go on ahead.
We’ll catch up to you later.
Okay!
Make sure to hold on tight.
Here we go!
Um...
Can’t we go any faster?
My motto is “safety first.”
Oh...
Mr. Nezu,
what is Team Yell?
Mary’s fans.
Her fans?
They used to be
Spike Gym’s trainers, too.
They’ll use any trick they can think of
if it’s for Mary.
That’s why they lied to me?
Oh, but I wouldn’t mind
battling at Spike Gym!
Mary can’t show
her full potential there.
Spike Town doesn’t have
a Power Spot for Daimax.
So you don’t use Daimax, Mr. Nezu?
Right. I like ordinary battles.
But because of that,
the Gym doesn’t see many challengers,
and the town’s wound up
almost deserted.
The reason Mary
entered the Championships...
...is that she hopes that becoming Champion would
make Spike Town famous, and help revitalize it.
Revitalize it, huh...?
She wants people to think,
“Wow, even Spike Town has trainers this tough?”
Team Yell has the same goal.
But... That should be my duty,
shouldn’t it?
I’m hopeless.
All you folks watching...
The scheduled start time has come and gone,
but Competitor Satoshi
has yet to show himself.
If he doesn’t turn up,
Competitor Mary will win by default!
Win by default!
I don’t want that!
I wanna ‘ave a
right and proper battle!
I’ll wait for ‘im!
Shoot Stadium,
Galar Region
Thank you, Mr. Nezu!
Sorry I’m late!
Took your time.
I’m so sorry about that.
Hey! How dare you
make our girl wait so long?!
You’re gonna fail!
What?! You wanna go there
after you went and tricked me?!
You don’t got any right to battle!
Our girl’s winning by default!
Shut your gob!
Was that true?
They tricked you?
Yeah.
They said the battle was moved.
But Mr. Nezu drove me here.
My bro did?
We just wanted our girl to win!
See, a victory for you’s
a victory for Spike Town, too!
Not like this, it ain’t!
Mr. Nezu...
Big bro...
Mary! Give it all you’ve got
in your battle!
Competitor Mary’s brother Nezu, who is also
Spike Town’s Gym Leader, has arrived to cheer her on!
Satoshi.
I got skin in this game
too, y’know!
I can’t afford to lose this!
Mr. Nezu told me.
You wanna revitalize
the town, right?
Pretty much.
But I’ve come a long way
to get here myself!
I can’t lose here!
Let’s hurry.
Everyone’s waitin’ for us.
Yeah.
I’m looking forward to today!
Thank you for waiting.
Now, the match begins!
I made it...
Good job making it here.
Mr. Nezu...
It’s all thanks to
the Armorgaw Taxi.
You gotta win this, Satoshi!
The Pokémon World Championships
Hyper Class.
And here are the two trainers
for today’s match!
Currently ranked 29th, a new star hailing from
Galar’s Spike Town: Competitor Mary!
Our girl!
You’re gonna prevail!
Her fan club?!
Well, something like that.
Currently ranked 36th,
hailing from Kanto’s Masara Town,
and on a winning streak after recently defeating
Competitor Saito: Competitor Satoshi!
Satoshi! Go for it!
We can see it!
He’s gonna fall!
We can hear it!
He’s gonna bawl!
Now, today’s battle will be a 1v1.
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3...
2...
1...
Go!
Gänger! I choose you!
Go, Olonge!
Olonge! Buildup Pokémon!
Evil/Fairy type!
Its hairs work like muscle fibers!
When its hairs unfurl, they latch on to opponents,
ensnaring them as tentacles would!
Olonge is Mary’s ace.
Gänger just got
a huge power-up, too!
I’m counting on you, Gänger!
I’ve gotta win this if I’m gonna be the Champion!
I’m comin’ at ya with everythin’ I’ve got!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Battle, start!
Soul Crush!
Magical Shine!
Olonge swings and misses!
Okay! Ice Punch!
Let’s make this quick!
Shadow Ball!
Olonge! Do it!
Groveling Jab!
There’s the Groveling Jab!
That’s Olonge for you!
His hair is a shape-shifting weapon!
It’s super effective!
Right on the mark.
All right!
Wow...
That’s Mary and Olonge’s
special move.
But that’s not all Mary can do.
I see Satoshi’s wearing
a Daimax Band, too.
Who’s going first?
Olonge, here goes!
Mary used hers first!
My bro might not use it...
But if it helps me win...
Kyodaimax!
So they did it.
Kyodaimax is the best!
Mary specializes in Daimax battles.
The one thing you can’t do
at Spike Gym.
She has her own way of battling.
Me and Mary, we should just both do what we can
to revive Spike Town, each in our own way.
Now, faced with
Kyodaimax Olonge,
what will Gänger and
Competitor Satoshi do?
Kyodai Snooze!
Magical Shine!
Amazing! He stopped her ultimate attack,
Kyodai Snooze, with Magical Shine!
Interesting.
Satoshi’s battles
are always crazy.
Keep holding on!
Gänger!
Gänger’s overcome
with drowsiness!
But it resisted, resisted!
It is resisting!
Gänger!
You’re so cute! So cute!
Morpeko...
Is that even possible?
Resisting a Kyodai Snooze...
They might prove t’ be
at least a li’l interesting.
Let’s go, Gänger!
Sludge Bomb!
Gänger’s playing with Olonge,
using the tricky moves only Ghost types can pull off!
Then how about this?!
Dai Earth!
Gänger got caught in
the Dai Earth!
Gänger put its all
into a Sludge Bomb!
But Olonge didn’t even flinch!
Gänger, you okay?!
Now, it’s our turn!
He’s doing it!
Let’s get huge!
Kyodaimax!
Gänger also used Kyodaimax!
Shoot Stadium is quaking
from this Kyodaimax showdown!
Perfect!
Dai Acid!
Dai Fairy!
Olonge turned back!
All right, Gänger! Dai Ice!
Soul Crush!
He’s strong...
Sorry, but the winner here’s
gonna be me!
Olonge! DD Lariat!
Let’s go! Kyodai Phantom!
Even the Kyodai Phantom
can’t stop the DD Lariat!
Our girl!
That’s the end of
Gänger’s Kyodaimax.
Olonge! Charge in!
In that case...
Gänger! Swallow Olonge!
It swallowed him!
Is that even possible?!
Great work, Gänger!
There goes the Kyodaimax!
And with it, Olonge is released!
The way he avoided leaving himself defenseless
as the Kyodaimax wore off... Incredible!
That Satoshi’s quite good.
Stomping Tantrum!
Stomping Tantrum becomes more powerful
if your last move missed.
Shadow Ball!
Go!
Olonge is unable to battle!
Gänger wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
And the victor of this Kyodaimax battle
is Competitor Satoshi!
All right!
He did it!
Our girl!
We did it, Gänger!
Olonge.
You did great.
Amazing!
Olonge! You were really cool!
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
With this victory, Competitor Satoshi
rises to 15th in the Hyper Class!
Your Gänger was pretty strong.
Your Olonge was strong, too!
You kept making me sweat!
You’ve gotten stronger, Mary.
You should let out your regrets
at our next concert.
Yeah.
Our girl,
that was incredible!
All the people enthralled by our girl battling
wanna go to Spike Town now!
Mr. Nezu!
This is gonna revive the town!
Looks like you succeeded, Mary.
Come on,
give them a bigger smile.
Yeah.
Satoshi, thanks for today.
But don’t think
I’m givin’ up yet.
Let’s both do our best!
Winning another battle, this time against Mary,
Satoshi’s rank continues to rise.
The Master Class is just up ahead!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’m going training
with Mr. Dande right now!
Mr. Dande?!
How?
Dande’s actually nothing
like you’d think from his public image.
Is this how you train
every day, Mr. Dande?!
Yeah! Isn’t it fun?
It’s super fun!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Up Close! Dande’s Special Training!!
Up Close! Dande's Special Training!!