Sinnoh Region
In the midst of investigating
nightmares occurring in Sinnoh,
Satoshi and Go
are in pursuit of Darkrai.
Meanwhile, Koharu and Eevee
were traveling in Sinnoh...
...and met Hikari,
a girl headed for a Contest.
At a forest they wandered into,
the two of them found...
Cresselia...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Cresselia: A Midsummer Night's Light
Cresselia. Crescent Moon Pokémon.
Psychic type.
It is referred to as
the crescent moon incarnate.
Its feathers are said to have
the power to drive away nightmares.
Cresselia...
She should be
on Full Moon Island...
Full Moon Island?
Yeah.
I’ve met her there before.
She’s badly hurt...
We need to treat her!
It’s fine, it’s fine!
We’re not enemies.
Eevee!
If we face each other earnestly,
people and Pokémon can truly understand one another.
It’s fine...
Koharu! Be careful!
We want to help you.
Let us treat you.
Oh, right, healing herbs.
That looks good.
This will sting a bit,
but just try to tough it out.
Did someone attack her?
Darkrai... perhaps?
Darkrai?
Yeah.
A Pokémon with the power to
give people and Pokémon nightmares.
Cresselia can dispel
Darkrai’s nightmares.
In other words...
I guess they’re enemies?
I see...
All right, this’ll do the trick!
You’re amazing, Hikari.
You even know how to make
herbal medicine.
Back when I was traveling
with two friends,
one of them was a
Pokémon Doctor in the making.
He taught me a few things.
Ah, that brings back memories.
Now, my other friend... it was like
he never thought about anything but Pokémon.
I guess you could
call him a Pokémon freak?
Oh, I have a friend
who’s just like that, too.
So you came to Sinnoh
to watch Contests?
Not exactly.
When I got here, I saw an interview
with a woman named Ayako.
Oh, you saw Mom’s interview!
Mom?
What?! The Ayako I saw on TV
is your mother?
Yeah.
Wow!
A legendary
Pokémon Coordinator?!
Y-Yeah...
I decided I’d chase after
the same goal she did.
You did, huh...?
Koharu, what do
your mom and dad do?
My mother’s an illustrator,
and my father researches Pokémon.
Ooh! He’s a Pokémon Professor?
Yeah.
But I don’t like when people assume
I’m going to be a professor just because he is.
At one point, I was panicking.
I was trying to think of something I wanted to do.
Then I met Eevee,
and realized I don’t need to rush it.
Eevee?
She’s a bit unique.
It’s like she still doesn’t want to decide
what to evolve into.
So she copies the moves of other Pokémon,
and tries out all kinds of things.
Oh!
So earlier she was copying
Pochama’s move!
Yeah.
She seems to really enjoy that.
So I thought that it would be fine for me to hesitate
and just enjoy trying new things, too.
Ah, I see.
My Pochama decided on his own
not to evolve.
Huh?
He seems to want to stay by my side
as a Pochama forever.
At the time, I wasn’t sure
that was really a good idea.
But since then,
I’ve gotten a lot closer to Pochama.
So you’ll be fine, just fine!
Thinking really hard about it
for a long time, then going “Eureka!”...
That’s how the greatest
dreams are born, I bet.
Yeah!
Hey, Koharu...
You should enter
the Contest after all!
Huh?
Where’d that come from?
Trying things out
is more fun, right?
Come on!
Let’s practice, let’s practice!
Pochama!
Here we go, Koharu!
Right!
Pochama!
Charm up!
Pochama! Whirlpool!
Wow...
That’s a taste of what it’s like.
Wow! That was so beautiful!
H-Huh? You want to try?
It’ll be fine, it’ll be fine!
You can do it!
Um... Now, then...
Ch-Charm up!
Eevee! Whirlpool!
Wow!
You did it!
Wh-What went wrong...?
It’s fine, Koharu...
It’s not fine...
Does this look good?
Yeah, you’ve got it!
Get well soon, Cresselia.
You hear me?
She’s so pretty.
Cresselia can use a move called Crescent Moon Dance,
which heals up her allies’ wounds.
Crescent Moon Dance, huh?
That must be beautiful.
Huh?
Where... am I?
Hikari?
Eevee?
Pochama!
Where are you?!
Hikari!
Koharu!
Where are we?
Huh?
A town?
What’s going on?
What happened?
They all look like
they’re having bad dreams...
Darkrai!
Then...
Darkrai must be giving
everyone nightmares!
It looks kinda lonely...
Cresselia?!
Everyone’s waking up!
That’s what Cresselia can do?
Darkrai...
W-Was that a dream?
Huh? Where’s Darkrai?
Huh? You also saw it?
“You also saw it?”...
You saw it?
A town covered in fog...
Darkrai and Cresselia...
Cresselia!
That’s the same gaze
as in the dream!
What we just saw,
could that have been...
Cresselia’s dream?!
Darkrai’s not around here...
If we had some sort of clue...
It’s an Usohachi!
Doesn’t it look like
it’s having trouble sleeping?
It could be having
a nightmare...
That means...
Darkrai has to be close!
Darkrai!
No one can sleep
because of your nightmares!
Go back to
New Moon Island!
What?
Gotta be something that way.
Let’s go!
Y-Yeah!
She’s flying!
Are you okay, Cresselia?
Darkrai!
So it really was Darkrai who...
No!
You stay away from her!
So? Any luck?
Nope, nothing.
Meow?!
Spot it?
It’s Darkrai, meow!
Darkrai?
That’s right, the bowl-headed four-eyes
said Sakaki was after Darkrai, too...
Then we should...
...catch it first!
Vending, come on!
Cresselia?
That gaze again...
Are... Are you telling us
not to fight it?
What?
There’s the Darkrai!
Time to catch it, meow!
Team Rocket!
Wait, you know them, too?
Y-Yeah...
Rocket...
Vending...
Secret!
What’re we gonna get?!
The Gripper Pokémon,
Yonoir!
The Meteorite Pokémon,
Lunatone!
Yonoir, deal with them!
Lunatone! Moon Force!
Let’s run while we can!
Yeah. Let’s go, Cresselia.
No way...
What do we do now?
Someone’s coming!
Everyone, get ready!
Huh?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Darkrai
Evil
Huh?
How come...?
Hikari!
Satoshi!
I can’t believe it!
It’s been so long!
Wh-Why are you with Koharu?
What? You know each other?
Huh? You know Satoshi, too?
What a coincidence!
What’re you two doing
all the way out here?
Hold on a second.
Let’s settle down
and go over things.
Oh, so you’re friends
that traveled around Sinnoh together.
Yeah, together with a guy
called Takeshi.
I was surprised to find out
you knew Koharu.
Same to you...
And you had
Cresselia with you!
Hey, when you mentioned
a Pokémon freak...
Yeah, I meant Satoshi!
I knew it!
Why are you here
all by yourself, Koharu?
Uhh... Well,
lots of things happened...
And you two are here
investigating the nightmares, right?
Yeah.
We were pursuing Darkrai.
Darkrai?!
What an awful feeling!
I thought we’d fly further...
Yeah, meow...
I’m not giving up yet!
Huh?!
Darkrai went to Cresselia?
That means...
It was wandering around
because it was looking for her?
But why?
Cresselia was really hurt, right?
In that case...
Basically, Cresselia battled with Darkrai,
took damage, and ran away!
Then Darkrai came after her...
I get it!
Hold on!
I... don’t think that’s right.
I don’t really get it,
but I don’t think
Cresselia and Darkrai are enemies.
I agree.
But you said they nearly
ended up battling, right?
I wonder... if that was just Darkrai
being mad at us, thinking we’d hurt Cresselia.
But then...
Who did this?
What?
Cresselia located!
Capture it.
Don’t let it get away again!
Ma’am!
Team Rocket!
Obstacles inbound.
So you hurt Cresselia!
You’ll pay!
Eliminate them.
Roger!
Go!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Skutank! Flamethrower!
Aceburn! Blaze Kick!
Dokurog! Venom Shock!
Pochama! Bubble Beam!
Dosaidon! Stone Edge!
Bunyat! Chaotic Scratches!
Eevee! Tackle!
That’s...
Darkrai!
How lucky
to find Darkrai here, as well.
Capture it along with Cresselia!
Skutank! Flamethrower!
Dokurog! Venom Shock!
Darkrai helped Cresselia!
So they weren’t enemies
after all!
Agh... Attack, Skutank!
Good job, Darkrai!
All right!
Everyone, go for it!
Ugh...
Fire the electroshocker!
Full power!
We gotta help Darkrai!
Stop making yourselves a nuisance
and stay out of our way.
Now, grab Darkrai!
What...?
Darkrai...
Its wounds are fading away...
Crescent Moon... Dance...
It’s beautiful...
Cresselia!
Im... possible...
Use Iron Tail!
Thanks, Pikachu!
Hold it!
The ones
who’ll get all the glory...
...by catching Darkrai...
...are us, meow!
Promoted... to... admins...
Rising up... the ranks...
Meow...
Huh, those guys were here.
Yeah, they were.
Forget them,
how’s Cresselia?!
Right!
Cresselia...
She used up all her power...
Her strength is coming back!
That’s... Moonlight!
Oh, because the clouds
went away...
Darkrai did it
to help Cresselia!
I think they’re going home.
Back to Full Moon Island
and New Moon Island.
So Darkrai was searching
for the wounded Cresselia.
I thought they were enemies...
But maybe they’ve actually
been looking after one another.
Darkrai gives everyone
nightmares.
But it can’t control that power,
so it always ends up hated and alone...
Maybe Cresselia lives on Full Moon Island
because it doesn’t want Darkrai to be lonely...
That’s amazing, Koharu!
You really understand how Pokémon feel!
If we face each other earnestly,
people and Pokémon...
...can truly understand
one another...
Eevee.
Dad?
Koharu!
You never called me!
Are you doing okay?!
Are you lonely?!
Having any trouble?!
I’m fine, I’m fine.
But never mind me.
How was that egg?
Oh, they all hatched fine.
See? They’re all so cute!
“All”?
Hey! Don’t fight!
Okay then, Koharu.
Let me know if you need anything!
Hey, wa— Dad?
Sheesh...
Now you’ve done it, Satoshi!
That feels nice and refreshing!
Hey, if you want to make it to the Contest,
we should leave soon...
Oh, that’s right.
Pochama, let’s go!
Eevee, we’re leaving!
She’s more interested in the sea
than the Contest right now, I guess.
Wha...
Oh, well.
It is summer vacation.
That’s right.
So you should be out here with us!
Huh? Oh, hold on!
Satoshi, Go, Koharu, and Hikari have experienced
the mysteries and bonds of Pokémon in the Sinnoh Region.
Their fun summer vacation is only just
getting started!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Pokémon Catching
Adventure Race?
We’re headed
for the top of that cliff!
We have a secret plan!
Let’s go!
Z-Move!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Full Power!
The Alola Deserted Island Race!!