Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Hey!
Māmane!
Satoshi! Go!
It’s been a while!
Māmane! Togedemaru!
You been doing good?
Denryu!
Denryu! Light Pokémon!
Electric type!
The tail’s tip shines brightly,
and acts as a beacon for lost people!
It’s also famous for being used as
a lighthouse beacon to keep ships safe!
So it’s here for the project?
Yeah!
Come on, I’ll introduce you.
A-Ahh! Sorry!
It’s a little scatterbrained...
Y-You don’t say...
I’ll be fine...
Nice to meet you, Denryu.
This is Sarunori.
Nice to meet you,
Sarunori.
Everyone in Alola
doing good, too?
Of course!
They’re all dying to see you!
Kaki even said he wants
another match with you, Go!
Oh, where’s Rabbifoot?
Come on out!
Aceburn!
Rabbifoot’s evolved form!
Wow! That’s so cool!
So, ready to go?
Into the Tokusane Space Center!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Reach Into Space!
Denryu's Light!!
Tokusane Space Center, Hoenn Region
Satoshi and Go have arrived at
the Tokusane Space Center in Hoenn.
What could they have
planned for today with Māmane...?
Whoa... Cool...
Thank you so much for inviting us,
Māmane! This is the best!
W-Well... Yeah...
Ooh, what’s that?
Hey, Satoshi!
You’ll get lost
if we don’t stick together!
But yeah, I never imagined you’d be working
on that Fiarrow2 Retrieval Project...
I know!
I still feel like I’m dreaming!
Oh! So these are your guests,
Māmane?
Yes!
I’m Satoshi!
My name’s Go!
Thank you for having us.
Welcome.
My name’s Hirota,
I’m a researcher here.
Thank you very much for letting us
come and watch today!
I can’t believe we get to see one of
the century’s biggest projects up close!
It’s amazing to think there’s Fiarrow
out in space of all places!
No, there aren’t.
It’s the name of
an asteroid explorer.
Huh? Really?!
Fiarrow2 was launched from right here
at Tokusane Space Center,
with the mission to
probe an asteroid!
Here’s some footage
from the launch.
It’s so cool...
Fiarrow2 detached from the rocket,
and set off toward its target.
After a very long time,
it landed on the asteroid.
It successfully completed
its mission.
And right now,
it’s in the midst of heading back home.
Which is where
Denryu comes in!
The light from Denryu’s tail
has a special wavelength.
We’re going to amplify it
and beam it out!
And Fiarrow2 has
a light receptor fitted to it.
That light will guide it straight back home,
and prevent it from getting lost in the depths of space.
In other words, the light from Denryu’s tail
is working like a lighthouse beacon, right?
So it’s not just a sea lighthouse,
but a space lighthouse, too!
Since we want to drum up
interest in the study of outer space,
we let children from all over the world
help with this project.
Ooh, there’s lots of them!
Aw! If only I had a Denryu!
Now, it’s almost time to begin.
Māmane, Denryu,
can you get yourselves ready?
Yes!
Come on, Denryu!
A-A-Are you all okay?!
A-Anyway,
just get into position for now.
Is this really going to work...?
You got this, Denryu!
Line connection complete!
Begin countdown to switchover
from Kleiber Observatory.
17, 16, 15, 14, 13, 12, 11...
Here we go, Denryu!
Light, on!
10, 9, 8, 7, 6...
Illumination angle at -0.2.
Output power at 80%.
Illumination from
Kleiber Observatory ending now.
3, 2, 1...
Tokusane Space Center
will take over.
Illuminate!
Contact with Fiarrow2 confirmed.
All systems normal.
I don’t know what’s going on,
but wow!
I can’t believe
I’m watching this up close!
That’s it, Denryu!
What?!
Emergency shutdown!
Ask Aeneas Observatory
to take over ASAP!
On it!
Status?
All systems normal with illumination
from Aeneas Observatory!
Fiarrow2 navigation is on course!
They did it in time...
Did we do something wrong...?
Sorry about that.
We’ll have it fixed for the next illumination,
so why don’t you let Denryu have a little rest?
Sure...
Denryu, you were amazing!
They had some malfunctions,
but your light reached Fiarrow2!
Yeah! It shined out really bright,
like “whoosh!”
Mr. Hirota and crew
will fix the machine.
Then you can just give it
another try!
Yeah. Thanks.
Denryu. Light, on.
Huh?
Does that mean...?
It can’t turn its light on
anymore?
What happened?
It was shining so bright earlier...
Hmm...
Maybe it fell into a slump
from the shock of failing?
Denryu. If you just relax,
I’m sure you can do it again.
D-D-Denryu?
Denryu!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Denryu
Electric
Denryu!
It’s not here...
I knew I wasn’t
the right person for this...
Māmane?
Since I’m not Denryu’s trainer...
Huh? You didn’t catch it, Māmane?
Right.
I borrowed it from Big Mu
to take part in the project.
Big Mu?
Oh, Mr. Mullein
from Hokulani Observatory.
Māmane’s cousin.
I wanted to take part really bad,
so I asked Big Mu and borrowed his Denryu.
They invited me here to
the Tokusane Space Center because of Denryu...
So I really wanted
to make this a success.
Māmane...
I can’t do anything to cheer up Denryu,
so I’m just a nuisance to everyone else...
I should never
have accepted the invitation...
Don’t think like that!
Satoshi?
You’re always trying your hardest,
going at full power!
You even came here today
‘cause your dream’s to be an astronaut, right?
Yeah.
So give it your full power
‘til the very end!
He’s right!
It’s not over yet!
And that’s why
we need to find Denryu!
Huh?
Where’s Sarunori?
Sarunori’s disappeared, too!
Well, knowing Sarunori...
...it might’ve gone chasing after something
thinking it was Denryu’s light.
Sarunori!
Denryu!
Hey! Where are you?!
What a relief...
That just leaves Sarunori.
The weather’s not looking good.
That’s it!
Togedemaru, light!
No good...
It’s not enough light!
Then you use
100,000 Volts, Pikachu!
Even 100,000 Volts
isn’t enough?
We need some stronger light
that can shine for longer...
Yeah.
Denryu!
Help us out!
We need your light
to find Sarunori!
Denryu...
I mess things up
and get depressed a lot, too...
But I trust that if I don’t give up,
my dreams will come true!
Maybe I’m not the most reliable person,
but I’ll do my best.
So would you be up for
giving this another try with me?
Almost got it!
Looking good, Denryu!
All right! Go for it!
Go! Over there!
Sarunori!
Sheesh...
You had me so worried, Sarunori...
You really are like a lighthouse!
Thank you!
Denryu,
your light is a beacon for everyone!
Denryu!
Let’s go back to the Center!
Mr. Hirota.
Would you consider
letting us try again?
Māmane... Denryu...
Of course.
The equipment’s completely fixed, too.
Come on, Denryu!
Go for it!
We have an emergency!
Fiarrow2 deviated
from its trajectory!
What happened?
An evasive maneuver
to avoid a meteorite.
The sudden movement
didn’t give us time for attitude control.
What does that mean?
It’s left its intended course.
If it stays like this,
Fiarrow2 will never come home.
Huh?
Māmane?
Yeah, this can work!
Mr. Hirota!
I have an idea!
An idea?
Right now, light from Kleiber Observatory
can still reach it.
And by switching to Aeneas and Karna in turn,
we can pull it closer, bit by bit.
Then if we send the re-entry signal
the moment it’s above Tokusane Space Center,
it should still be able to return!
The math seems correct...
We’ll give it a try!
Right!
Contact the observatories!
Get ready!
Right!
Kleiber, ready to illuminate!
Aeneas and Karna
will be ready at any second!
Commence operation!
Let’s make this work!
Right!
It entered return trajectory!
One minute until it’s above
Tokusane Space Center!
Māmane, Denryu,
we’re counting on you!
Right!
Come on, Denryu!
Send the light of hope
out into space!
Light, on!
3, 2, 1...
Illuminate!
Illuminating!
The signal isn’t reaching!
Why?!
Is... the cloud cover too thick?
Denryu! We need more!
Pikachu!
We can help out, too!
100,000 Volts!
Togedemaru,
use Shocking Prickles!
You can help, too!
Raichu, use Cheek Rub!
Go!
Contact with Fiarrow2 confirmed!
It’s entering the atmosphere!
You did it, Māmane!
This is a feat
for the history books, no question!
W-Well... Yeah...
You did it too, Denryu!
Māmane! I’ll be rooting for you
to become an astronaut!
Yeah!
Satoshi, Go...
You keep working toward your dreams, too!
Of course!
We’ll make them come true!
Until next time!
Seeing Māmane work
to reach his dream,
Satoshi and Go reaffirmed
their commitment to their dreams.
There’s bound to be a bright light
illuminating their paths forward.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Those Yadon have yellow heads!
You’re right.
Too spicy!
What’s that?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Yadoking!
A Curry-ously Great Encounter!!