The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon Battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
Satoshi’s next opponent is...
...Dracaena of the Kalos Elite Four,
a Hyper Class competitor ranked 12th.
With the help of
his former companion, Citron,
Satoshi trained
Negigaknight and Uonoragon...
...and succeeded
in teaching them new moves.
And now...
It has been many moons,
Sir Satoshi.
Mr. Gampi!
Oh! Negigaknight!
Thy Kamonegi hath evolved?
Yup!
Good! He is lucky to have thee, Negigaknight!
Do not forget thy knightly spirit!
And who is this Pokémon?
That’s...
Huh?
Ms. Dracaena!
Oh my, what a simply
precious little Pikachu!
And you...
You must be Uonoragon.
It’s such a pleasure to meet you!
I have heard so much about you.
Madame Dracaena said she would be
most delighted to meet you before the battle.
How do you do?
Come, now.
You greet him, as well.
Quite lovely, don’t you think?
This is my most precious partner.
We are ever so pleased
to make your acquaintance.
Yeah!
Th-The pleasure’s all mine!
I had a look at your battle record.
However...
Your forward march ends today.
And with that,
I wish you a wonderful day!
That really got me nervous...
What tremendous tenacity...
What did you think of them?
I do believe
I will enjoy today’s battle.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Hyper Class!
VS Elite Four Dracaena!!
Miare City, Kalos Region
The Pokémon World Championships
Hyper Class!
Today’s match-up is between
these two,
both aiming to become
the world’s greatest Pokémon Trainer!
Hyper Class, ranked 12th:
Competitor Dracaena of the Kalos Elite Four!
She seems pretty kind.
Absolutely not!
She deceives everyone with that smile.
You can trust my bro on that!
He didn’t stand a chance against her!
You didn’t have to mention that...
Her opponent, ranked 15th
and also in the Hyper Class...
...is Competitor Satoshi
from the Kanto Region!
Hello!
Satoshi!
You got this!
This battle will be a 2v2.
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3!
2!
1!
Go!
Negigaknight, I choose you!
I’m counting on you, Onvern!
Onvern, huh?
Onvern! Sound Wave Pokémon!
Flying/Dragon type!
Flying through the darkness, it weakens enemies
with ultrasonic waves that could crush stone!
Its fangs finish the fight!
Will they be all right?
The Fighting-type Negigaknight is weak to
the Flying-type Onvern.
Negigaknight,
keep your eyes on Onvern!
Battle, start!
Fangs of Rage!
Brutal Swing!
Oh, dear.
It unleashes a Brutal Swing,
expertly using its shield!
Competitor Dracaena is astonished, too!
Very impressive.
Amazing!
Well done, Negigaknight!
He’s paying close attention to his foe.
Okay! Great work, Negigaknight!
Oh, my...
I think you may be underestimating us.
Onvern! Blast Waves!
What is this...?!
You see?
No more guarding.
Negigaknight!
Pick up your shield!
Dragon Pulse!
Negigaknight!
Blast Waves!
It’s now or never,
Negigaknight!
Grab your sword and shield!
Good, Negigaknight!
Truly indomitable!
Negigaknight reclaims its sword and shield!
Dragon Pulse!
Here we go, Negigaknight!
Star Assault!
Onvern!
What?!
Onvern’s massive wings
block the Star Assault!
Well done!
Oh, dear...
You are robust.
Don’t push yourself!
Come back, Negigaknight!
You’ll have your chance later.
Rest for now.
Calling him back here
was a wise move.
Using Star Assault
renders you immobile for a bit.
Satoshi’s smart.
So who’s his next...?
My heart’s pounding really fast.
Negigaknight was able to damage it...
Now it’s up to you
to bring it home!
Uonoragon!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Competitor Satoshi’s second Pokémon
is Uonoragon!
A rare Pokémon
discovered in the Galar Region!
Oh, there you are, Uonoragon.
I have been quite eager to battle you.
Fangs of Rage!
Here it comes!
Ice Fang!
You okay, Uonoragon?
He’s in trouble already?!
Fangs of Rage is a powerful move.
It cuts the opponent’s stamina in half!
But look at Onvern!
Both sides took heavy damage!
Onvern in particular took a super effective hit!
Come back, Onvern!
Now, it’s your turn, Tyltalis!
There it is... Tyltalis!
Competitor Dracaena’s second
is Tyltalis!
Tyltalis! Humming Pokémon!
Dragon/Flying type!
This Pokémon has a kind disposition, but if it’s provoked,
it will threaten opponents with shrill cries...
...before attacking them
without mercy!
Hey! Uonoragon!
Oh, dear... My, my...
Sheesh... What is it thinking?!
It’s ‘cause of how it was fluttering.
Just like when it bit
Negigaknight’s sword.
I guess it’s just drawn
to things that sway.
An astonishing leap into action
by Uonoragon!
Let’s make use of that, then!
Ice Fang!
Cotton Guard!
It blocked the Ice Fang!
Tyltalis’s defense rose drastically!
Aren’t its plumes just lovely?
They can be used to
avoid heavy damage, too.
Both Onvern and Tyltalis are way too good
at using their wings for defense!
Yeah, that’s it!
That’s exactly what got you, right?
I told you,
you didn’t have to mention that...
How do you like this, then?
A Key Stone?!
Power of dragons, awaken!
Mega Evolve!
It has Mega Evolved!
Mega Tyltalis!
So pretty!
She’s finally Mega Evolved it!
Madame Dracaena
appears to be enjoying herself.
Now, let’s do it!
God Bird!
Bring it on!
Jaw Bite!
Ice Fang!
The God Bird attack lands!
Figures... Its speed and power are on
a whole other level now that it’s Mega Evolved.
Play Rough!
You okay, Uonoragon?!
It’s so soft and fluffy,
but it’s got perfect offense and defense!
Its plumes...
That’s it!
You figured it out too, Eureka?
This brings me back...
Satoshi always surpasses
anything we can imagine!
Uonoragon! Water Gun!
Use God Bird again!
Mega Tyltalis blocks with its wings!
Yes!
What?!
The ferocious Water Gun
has drenched Mega Tyltalis’s prided wings!
You have quite the nerve!
Let’s finish this!
Dragon Dive!
No, Satoshi! Don’t!
It didn’t work?!
It doesn’t affect Mega Tyltalis!
What’s going on?
Tyltalis is a Dragon/Flying type,
but when it Mega Evolves...
It becomes Dragon/Fairy.
You acted exactly
as I anticipated you would, little Satoshi.
Dragon-type moves
don’t work on Fairy types!
Wide Breaker!
Ice Fang!
Come back, Uonoragon!
It’s all up to you,
Negigaknight!
Oh, dear.
What’s this?
Uonoragon came back out?!
What’s up?
You wanna cheer for Negigaknight?
It seems Competitor Satoshi
is letting Uonoragon watch the battle.
I love your spirit.
Allow me to answer in turn.
Wide Breaker!
Star Assault!
Tyltalis is unable to battle!
How is this possible?!
Yay!
Yeah! Amazing, Negigaknight!
Uonoragon had chipped away
at Mega Tyltalis’s stamina.
But he can’t relax just yet!
Thank you, Tyltalis.
You fought very well.
Negigaknight is unable to battle!
Negigaknight!
What an upheaval!
Negigaknight has run out of strength!
Such vigor! Thou kept standing back up
for the sake of thy lord!
Thou art a true knight!
Come back, Negigaknight!
Thank you.
Now Negigaknight, too?
It wants to cheer on Uonoragon?
Yes! It’s the passionate friendship
between Pokémon!
I see!
You wanna support Uonoragon, too!
Okay!
I’m counting on you,
Uonoragon!
I see. Well, if so...
Go, Onvern!
You are quite remarkable,
to push me this far...
But that ends now!
We’re gonna win!
Come on, Uonoragon!
Dragon Pulse!
Dragon Dive!
Uonoragon!
Blast Waves!
Competitor Dracaena
keeps up the pressure!
Yes! Stand up!
Uonoragon!
It’s time to finish this!
Here it comes, Onvern!
Dragon Dive!
Dragon Pulse!
Onvern is unable to battle!
Uonoragon wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
Competitor Satoshi wins!
He has overcome
Competitor Dracaena of the Elite Four!
Ow, ow, ow...
We did it, Negigaknight!
Oh, dear...
It seems we lost.
What a shame.
You gave it your all, Onvern.
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
Competitor Satoshi climbs to
9th place, in the Hyper Class!
9th?!
You did it!
He’s made it all the way to 9th!
Amazing, Satoshi!
Congratulations!
Satoshi. Congratulations on climbing
to 9th place, the top of the Hyper Class.
Thank you very much!
The battles to come
will not be quite so easy.
I know! I’ll give it my all!
Your Negigaknight and Uonoragon
are entirely too charming.
I’ll be cheering you on.
Continue striving for thy goal.
I will, Mr. Gampi!
What is it, Eureka?
I’ve decided!
Ms. Dracaena!
Marry my brother, s’il-vous-plaît!
You’re just so strong
and responsible...
I can’t think of any other person
fit to marry him!
Oh, dear...
What ever am I to do?
Wha—? How come?!
Don’t “How come?!” me!
Satoshi has defeated Dracaena of
the Kalos Elite Four and risen even further in the ranks.
Soon, he will be able to challenge
those eight world-class trainers, the Masters Eight!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Roentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Roentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Roentorar
Electric!
Showers
Roentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Miracle Ruthia’s Contest Scouting!
This is the trainer
I’m gonna scout today!
Huh?! Scout?!
Koharu, you’re gonna
participate in a Contest?!
Um... I’m still not entirely sure.
Well, we’ll head to the Contest Hall
to come join you, then!
See ya!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Eevee and Nymphia!
A Meeting and a Reunion!!