Satoshi and Go went to the Galar Region
to investigate the mystery of Daimax.
The two got separated in the forest,
and both ran into mysterious Pokémon.
After that, Satoshi went with Dande
to stop the rampaging Daimax Pokémon,
while Go went with Sonia
to search for clues to the legend.
What awaits each of them
at their respective destinations?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Sword & Shield II
"The Black Night"
Underground Energy Plant, Knuckle City
I’m so sick of this!
It’s heavy, it’s hot,
and I’m all sweaty!
Why do we have to do this?
We’ve got no choice.
Sakaki’s orders, meow.
True. It’s for our righteous evil.
Yeah!
Right, meow!
Hey, you! Quit slacking!
Are you okay?
Well... I guess...
Ms. Sonia’s driving sure was something.
Look at this, Go.
Turf Town Geoglyph
That’s Turf Town’s geoglyph?
They say it depicts the legend of Galar.
Let’s see...
When the Galar Region
was engulfed by a black vortex,
gigantic Pokémon rampaged.
Then a lone hero wielding
a sword and shield appeared,
and quelled the raging beasts.
And you’re investigating the connection
between that legend and Daimax, yeah?
Yeah. It’s my grandmother’s
homework for me.
What does this geoglyph look like to you?
Gigantic Pokémon rampaging, I guess?
Is that the vortex?
Could be.
Say, Go... Don’t you think
that seems a lot like the current situation?
Now that you mention it...
Perhaps the black vortex that brought about
the disaster, the Black Night...
...is about to appear in Galar again?
A black vortex...
The Black Night...
I thought I could figure something out
by coming here...
It looks like what happened back then.
I once met Lugia.
Lugia?! Whoa, that’s incredible!
The clouds formed a vortex back then, too.
Maybe vortexes form whenever
legend-tier Pokémon show up?
So the Black Night might be connected
with some crazy powerful Pokémon or something.
Good point...
Go, this could be a real breakthrough!
Come to think of it,
the first time we came to see Mr. Dande fight,
I saw a massive Pokémon in the clouds.
Maybe that one
has something to do with this!
Intel was that this plant
hid the strongest, evilest Pokémon...
But where is it?
Chairman Rose, should I halt the injection of
Galar particles until the hangar has been strengthened?
Is this not incredible, Olive?
So much energy is flowing
that we can’t control it all.
The Black Night... The disaster that once
pushed the region to the brink of destruction...
It will be revived as Mugendaina,
the savior of Galar’s future.
That’s it.
The strongest, evilest Pokémon!
We’ll catch it for sure, meow!
Ah... I see.
Don’t let them out of your sight.
Very well, ma’am.
Continuing purs—
M-Ms. Sonia...
Sorry... I did it again.
By the way, Go,
where were you headed?
Brassie Town. To go see someone
named Professor Magnolia.
Huh... So we’re going
to the same place, then.
Professor Magnolia
is my grandmother.
Do you see it, Satoshi?
What is that?
Sekitanzan. Kyodaimax form.
Coal Pokémon. Rock/Fire type.
Flames hotter than 2,000 degrees
burn in the massive furnace within its body.
Here we go. Stay alert!
Got it!
Ms. Sonia, what are these photos?
They’re four tapestries
we found in the Knuckle City vault.
“Two youths gazing at the sky.”
“A disaster occurs...
The two bewildered youths.”
“The youths looking on at
the sword and shield that stopped the disaster.”
“The youths being crowned.”
It’s said that they tell the story
of the birth of Galar.
Mind telling me what you think?
The same two people
are in all the tapestries.
Did these two stop the Black Night
and were then crowned kings?
In which case,
there wouldn’t be one hero but two?
You think so?
I was thinking the same thing, too.
But there was only one
hero statue in the stadium.
Yeah. Over the years, people may have
made mistakes retelling the legend.
Then...
Could there be other mistakes, too?
It’s certainly possible.
All right...
I’m really getting excited!
I’ll report to Grandmother,
pass her test,
and become a Pokémon Professor!
...Yeah, right.
No way it’ll go that well.
Grandmother is crazy strict.
Why do you want to be
a Pokémon Professor?
Part of it is wanting to be
with Grandmother, but...
Mostly because of Dande, I guess?
Mr. Dande?
Dande and I are childhood friends.
We both loved Pokémon
and dreamed of becoming strong trainers.
When we were younger,
I taught him about battling...
But after he made his trainer debut,
it became clear real fast that he was a natural,
and before I knew it, he was the Champion.
Try as I might, there’s
no way I can beat Dande in battle.
So I thought I’d try working with Pokémon
in an entirely different way.
Drapult! Dragon Arrow!
Gänger! Shadow Ball!
Gänger! Psychokinesis!
The longer this takes,
the more damage it’ll cause.
Satoshi, let’s finish it quickly!
Yes!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Drapult! Dragon Dive!
Gänger! Shadow Ball!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Gänger, return!
Come back, Drapult!
You messed up the mine!
You maniac!
Never come back!
Get out of here!
Cut it out!
It’s not Sekitanzan’s fault!
Remarkable! I knew I could depend
on the strongest Champion...
...and the young trainer
who has his respect.
Chairman Rose?
Why are you here?
I just happened to be here
for an inspection.
Then I heard about the incident
and came as fast as I could.
Allow me to introduce you.
This is Chairman Rose of Macro Cosmos,
the company behind development
and supply of energy for all of Galar.
He took notice of me
when I started out as a trainer,
and raised me.
I owe him a lot for that.
Oh, I’m...
Satoshi, yes?
Dande told me about you.
He said you showed
great promise as a battler.
I have wanted to meet you.
I-It’s a pleasure...
Chairman Rose.
Do you still not know why
the Daimaxed Pokémon are running rampant?
I did look into it extensively,
but I couldn’t find a clear answer.
Is this a threat to Galar...
...or is it...
...simply a trial
necessary for our future?
We need to do something fast.
At this rate, the lives of
Galar’s people and Pokémon will crumble.
I agree!
Satoshi.
The Pokémon aren’t rampaging
because they want to, either!
How about a dinner
to commemorate our meeting?
I’ll treat you to plenty of
Galar’s most famous dishes.
Famous dishes?!
It’s a good opportunity.
Go ahead and join him.
I’ll help fix the mine.
I’ll help, too!
Brassie Town
Professor Magnolia’s lab!
Researching legends
is pretty exciting, huh?
You think so?
Yeah! Seeing or hearing
about new Pokémon...
...makes me want to find
and catch even more!
It’s kinda like my world expands
every time I learn something new...
Or like I’ve taken the future in hand!
I know, right? You might make
a good Pokémon Professor!
Professor, huh?
But first I gotta fulfill my dream
of catching every Pokémon!
Wow... What a dream!
All right... I won’t give up!
I will become a Pokémon Professor!
Yeah!
What’s that?!
A meteor?
Amazing! It’s...
A Wishing Star.
They are said to fall into the hands
of those who bear earnest wishes.
Grandmother!
Professor Magnolia!
You came from Professor Sakuragi’s institute?
Is he doing well?
Yes.
I came because I wanted
to learn more about Daimax.
I see. There are still
many things we do not know...
But what we do know is that
a special power which only exists here in Galar...
...is linked to
the Pokémon Daimax phenomenon.
We call this power Galar particles.
Galar particles...
Have you ever seen Pokémon
Daimax in the Wild Area?
Yes, I have.
Galar particles are found within
the red lights that are released...
...from special Power Spots.
They bring out the power
from within Pokémon and trigger Daimax.
Power from within Pokémon...
And further research has revealed...
...that the Wishing Stars
falling from the sky...
...likewise contain Galar particles.
That meteor from earlier?
Wishing Stars are capable of
attracting and drawing in Galar particles.
I thought that making use of that capability
should enable us to control the gigantification of Pokémon,
and so I...
...cooperated with Chairman Rose
from Macro Cosmos,
and together, we succeeded
in developing Daimax Bands.
That’s awesome!
And on that note...
Ta-daah! A present!
I did some work on
the Wishing Star we just found!
A Daimax Band?!
It’s better to have one
if you’re gonna travel through Galar, right?
Thank you!
But why can Pokémon only
grow giant in the Wild Area or in stadiums?
The Power Spots.
Daimax can only be used
at Power Spots.
I see.
Galar particles conceal much potential.
Together, Chairman Rose and I researched
how to turn that power into energy.
However...
Did something happen, Grandmother?
No.
In any case, Sonia, I hope you
haven’t forgotten your homework.
Please show me the results
of your research into the legend.
Of course!
I see...
There were two heroes,
and the Black Night was caused by a Pokémon...
A truly fascinating discussion.
You did well, Sonia.
I got some help
from you, too, though.
Way to go, Ms. Sonia!
But I cannot yet say
that you have passed.
Where are the sword and shield
from the legend?
How was the disaster prevented?
You need to solve all the mysteries.
Figured as much...
See? She’s really strict, right?
But I wanna know
all about the legend, too!
We just gotta research it
thoroughly, yeah?
I suppose! Let’s give it our all!
Rose Tower, Shoot City
This is great!
I love the view from here.
Each and every one of these lights...
...houses countless lives and dreams.
Galar itself is what lifted me out of poverty
and let me reach my current life.
And I intend to do everything
within my power,
in order for this marvelous view
to last a thousand years.
Oh, yes, Satoshi!
I strive to guide
talented trainers like Dande...
What do you think?
Huh? Me?
I would support a strong trainer like you
with everything I have.
Please stay by my side, as well,
and help me protect Galar’s future.
Oh, you’re so lucky, getting an offer like this
from Chairman Rose!
I’ll pass.
I wanna travel the world
with my own two legs,
meet loads of Pokémon,
and become stronger with them!
Is that so?
Very well. I understand.
So nice and soft!
I wish Go could be here, too.
Come to think of it,
didn’t he say we’d meet up later?
Incoming call from Go.
Go?
Huh? You’re at
Professor Magnolia’s lab?
Yeah.
I’m staying here for the night, and tomorrow
I’m going with Ms. Sonia to see the ruins in Lateral Town!
I see. I’ll come to
those ruins, too, then!
Yeah! We’ll meet up there!
Sure!
Knuckle City
Is it simply a trial
necessary for our future?
Does Chairman Rose
know something about the incident?
What is he doing
in the underground plant here?
We’re off, Grandmother.
Leave it to us, Professor!
Sonia.
I need to tell you...
...why I broke off
my partnership with Chairman Rose.
It was because I could sense
madness in his gaze.
Chairman Rose will stop at nothing
to achieve his goals.
These recent incidents of
Daimax Pokémon rampaging...
I have no proof,
but I have a bad feeling about this.
And that is why, Sonia...
...you need to make haste in
uncovering the truth behind the legend.
Don’t worry!
I’ll get to the truth, for sure!
Me, too!
Weeds should be plucked
as soon as possible.
Lateral Town
The Lateral Town mural...
It’s not really what I expected.
It looks like it was painted
long after the time of the legend.
It looks more like a doodle.
Guess that’s a miss.
Don’t worry about it!
Let’s go investigate the next ruin!
Can’t let you do that.
You will come with us.
Who are you?
Do as I say, and you won’t get hurt.
You have to be kidding!
Rabbifoot!
If you won’t do as I say,
then I have no choice.
Come forth,
Kyodaimax Dustdas!
Kyodaimax?! Wait,
is this a Power Spot, too?!
Ah! There’s Galar particles
coming from the mural!
Which means...
Come back, Rabbifoot!
Daimax!
We just gotta give it a go, yeah?!
All right! Now, do it, Rabbifoot!
Dai Burn!
Kyodai Stench!
Rabbifoot!
Impossible!
There were statues behind the mural?!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Rabbifoot! Dai Burn!
If Pokémon are exposed to that light,
they’ll start rampaging again!
I have to do something, Go!
Got it! I’ll go search for
Zacian and Zamazenta!
I won’t let you make any more
innocent Pokémon rampage!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Sword & Shield III
"Mugendaina"
Sword & Shield
“Mugendaina”