The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The eight mighty trainers
aiming for the summit...
...have begun battling.
The first match of the semifinals
was Dande versus Carne.
One more Kyodai Hellfire!
Blow them away!
Dande emerged victorious.
And the second match will be
the Champion of Sinnoh, Shirona, against...
...the first Champion of Alola,
Satoshi.
All right!
It’s finally time.
I’m counting on you all!
Satoshi...
You better win!
Course!
Now, let’s move!
I’m cheering for you.
Thank you.
I’ll show you
that I’m worthy of your hope.
You’re the one
who’ll end Dande’s win streak.
That’s a lot of pressure.
I’ve decided something.
What is it?
Once this tournament’s over...
I’m retiring from battles.
Huh?!
Ms. Shirona...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Semifinals II - "Bedazzle"
Very well! Everyone is here!
Well then,
let’s cheer for Satoshi!
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament!
This tournament has truly been a special one,
with Champions gathered from various regions!
It’s the second match
of the semifinals!
Ranked 8th in the Masters Eight,
Competitor Satoshi steps onto the field.
Bearing the monumental title of
first-ever Champion of Alola,
he has boldly climbed
all the way to the semifinals.
What sort of battle
will he show us today?
Next, ranked 2nd in the Masters Eight,
Competitor Shirona steps onto the field.
As everyone knows,
she is the Champion of Sinnoh!
She has the strength and
imposing presence of a queen!
Now, who will be the one
to battle Competitor Dande?
Competitor Shirona?
Or Competitor Satoshi?
That’s right!
All eyes are on this battle, meow!
And we’ll be passionately commentating
their white-hot battle all the way!
Above all, Competitor Shirona’s Pokémon
are sure to be strong!
You’ve gotta see ‘em!
The semifinals are 6v6 full battles!
There is no limit on match length
or switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all six of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, per match, you are allowed a single use of only
one of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolution.
In the first round, Competitor Shirona
used Mega Evolution,
and Competitor Satoshi
used a Z-Move.
Will they play the same cards
in the semifinals?
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Kairyu, I choose you!
Tremble, souls! Mikaruge!
Mikaruge!
What a surprise! Competitor Shirona’s first Pokémon
is the Sealed Pokémon, Mikaruge!
That Pokémon’s
supposed to be strong?
I’d call it more creepy
than strong, meow.
No, no! The Champion of Sinnoh
sent out that Pokémon! It has to be strong!
You can’t let your guard down
against her, Satoshi!
What a play. She took control of the field
by using a Pokémon nobody had predicted.
Yeah.
My Kairyu’s not gonna lose,
no matter who she’s up against!
Let the battle begin!
Dragon Meteor Shower!
Surprise Attack!
A Surprise Attack
steals Kairyu’s thunder!
It’s laughing!
What a display of toughness from Mikaruge!
Dragon Claw!
Hypnosis!
Kairyu!
And she falls asleep!
This isn’t good!
This isn’t good for Kairyu!
She won’t be waking up
easily from that...
Dream Eater!
Dream Eater, a move that
drains a sleeping Pokémon’s stamina, hits its mark!
What a combo...
That’s scary...
Keep using Dream Eater!
Now that’s evil...
See? Told you it’s strong!
Kairyu’s power is being sucked up
little by little, meow...
Kairyu! Wake up!
C’mon, wake up!
She shows no sign of responding.
This...
Kairyu!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
No way...
Competitor Satoshi
has already lost his first Pokémon!
His Kairyu barely did anything...
Return, Kairyu!
Sorry.
I won’t make the same mistake again.
Return, Mikaruge!
Oh? Competitor Shirona
recalls her Mikaruge!
Come out, Gänger!
Bloom, Roserade!
Now, next up is
Roserade versus Gänger!
Is Satoshi gonna Daimax it
to turn the tide?!
I don’t know...
This is how the Champion of Sinnoh,
Ms. Shirona, battles...
Roserade...
Seed Machine Gun!
Shadow Ball!
Seed Machine Gun
isn’t very effective on Gänger!
Yet, Roserade remains confident!
Will-O-Wisp!
Leaf Storm!
All right!
Neither managed
to block the attack.
But Roserade was burned
by the effect of Will-O-Wisp!
That’ll eat away at its stamina!
Return, Roserade.
Competitor Shirona
recalls her Pokémon again!
And here I thought the Will-O-Wisp
would give him the upper hand...
She’s not giving up control,
no matter what...
Gänger! Let’s keep going!
One more time, Mikaruge!
Mikaruge returns?!
Again?!
We’re not falling for
Hypnosis or Dream Eater again!
So it’s a Ghost type showdown!
Magical Shine!
Surprise Attack!
Magical Shine and Surprise Attack
are both super effective!
Gänger!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
One more time, Mikaruge!
Mikaruge returns?!
Again?!
We’re not falling for
Hypnosis or Dream Eater again!
Magical Shine!
Surprise Attack!
Gänger!
And they’ve now both
taken heavy damage...
Will they be able to
recover from this?!
Good job, Gänger!
Gänger is unable to battle!
Mikaruge gives Competitor Satoshi
another black mark!
The switch-up
from Roserade paid off!
This is looking pretty tough
for Satoshi...
Don’t worry.
The battle’s barely started.
Things really aren’t
going his way today...
That Champion of Sinnoh’s
just too strong, meow...
We can’t get fired up
when the battle’s this one-sided!
Return, Gänger!
I’m gonna make the most
of all your effort.
Return, Mikaruge!
Oh! Competitor Shirona
recalls Mikaruge yet again!
Is she concerned about the damage
from Magical Shine?!
Unfurl your blessed wings,
Togekiss!
Togekiss?
Togekiss! Jubilee Pokémon!
Fairy/Flying type!
Known as a bringer of blessings,
it’s been depicted on good-luck charms
since ancient times!
Switching again...
She might be doing this
to throw him off his game.
Don’t panic.
Don’t let Ms. Shirona
set the pace!
Pikachu...!
Counting on you!
Competitor Satoshi’s
third Pokémon is Pikachu!
We can look forward to the 10,000,000 Volts Z-Move
that decided his first round match.
Turning the tide
with his greatest partner...
That’ll be Satoshi’s plan.
Sending Pikachu out now, huh?
It’s up to you, Pikachu!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Air Slash!
It hits!
Togekiss is tossing
Pikachu around!
Pikachu!
Mind Headbutt!
Electroweb!
What’s wrong, Pikachu?!
Pikachu!
Togekiss’s ability
is Heaven’s Blessings.
Yeah.
So its ability helped flinch him...
You’re really using all sorts of tricks,
Champion of Sinnoh!
Return, Togekiss!
What?!
Another recall!
Pikachu! Are you okay?
Emerge from the waves!
Tritodon!
Electric moves won’t work on Tritodon!
Ms. Shirona knows Satoshi well.
She’s expecting he’ll keep Pikachu in,
and plans to take him out!
Earth Power!
Pikachu, jump!
I thought so.
Iron Tail!
Stone Edge!
All right! Hit ‘em!
That’s it! Send ‘em flying!
But Tritodon just
absorbs the impact!
Now!
Lightning Speed!
Tritodon is unable to battle!
The first black mark
for Competitor Shirona!
We did it!
Good work, Satoshi, Pikachu!
This’s a comeback!
A comeback!
Marvelous!
That’s our Pikachu!
Our training wasn’t
all for naught, meow!
He’s still got that glittery strength!
Huh?
Is it over?
Type match-ups truly are
nothing to Satoshi.
His rhythm of attacks
is wonderful, too.
This is my kind of battle!
Now we’re getting to
see Satoshi’s strengths.
His will to find opportunity in a crisis,
and Pikachu’s skill in seizing it... They’re both incredible.
Pikachu!
Let’s keep this going!
Return, Tritodon!
You fought well.
Leave the rest to me.
Come out, Mikaruge!
Mikaruge makes
its third appearance!
There it is...
Don’t worry, Pikachu.
I have a plan.
Spin around using 100,000 Volts!
What is that?!
It’s like he’s breakdancing!
It’s too early for a victory dance.
Hypnosis!
Wow! Blocked by Pikachu’s 100,000 Volts,
Mikaruge’s Hypnosis can’t reach him!
That can’t...
Finish it!
It’s like they say...
Offense is the best defense!
Ms. Shirona!
That was Counter Shield, a move we came up with
when we traveled through Sinnoh!
I remember it!
You showed it off at the Sinnoh League.
We’re stronger
than we were back then!
Pikachu, Electroweb!
Surprise Attack!
Now! Iron Tail!
Mikaruge, go ahead!
All right!
He beat Mikaruge!
Wh-What is this?
What?!
Pikachu!
It’s Drag Along!
Mikaruge and Pikachu are both
unable to battle!
An unbelievable double knockout!
Drag Along is a fearsome move with which
the defeated Pokémon also takes down its opponent.
Now Competitor Shirona has four Pokémon left.
Competitor Satoshi is left with three Pokémon.
Having lost Pikachu,
he can’t use his Z-Move, 10,000,000 Volts!
Pikachu was Satoshi’s ace.
He’s just suffered
immeasurable damage.
Well, now...
This is getting interesting, eh, Satoshi?
Mikaruge...
You truly fought well.
Rest yourself.
Ms. Shirona’s strong...
Pikachu is already down.
Shirona stands tall before Satoshi
and his hopes of reaching the finals.
Their fierce fight is only just
beginning!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
What a shock!
Competitor Brat Boy’s Pikachu is down!
And Competitor Shirona
hasn’t even sent out Gaburias yet!
What’re you gonna do, brat boy?!
You’ve gotta do something! Hey!
Morpeko, gimme that!
Calm down, Morpeko!
We’re live, you know?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Semifinals III - "Valor"
The Semifinals III - “Valor”
Let’s all tune in, meow!