Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Here goes! Go!
Come at me, Satoshi!
It’s over!
That was nothing...!
Okay! No, it’s not...
I’ve gotta get way, way stronger...
...if I wanna keep up with
Kamonegi’s training.
Owww...
Still, is there any point in
practicing fencing with leeks?
Sure there is!
Aim to be a Leek Master!
That’s a huge rock you smashed...!
You’re amazing, Kamonegi!
It’s getting better and better
at handling its leek!
Yeah.
Ever since it lost to Earlade,
it’s been training everyday.
So I want to help it train...
as much as I can!
Hey! Satoshi!
Oh, Director!
You were looking for a place
where Kamonegi can train, weren’t you?
Renji found something interesting.
Did you find somewhere good?
This is over in the Kalos Region, but...
“The Castle of Chivalry.
“Pokémon and trainers
seeking true strength are welcome!
“Hot-blooded coaching by Gampi
of the Kalos Elite Four”... Wow!
The Elite Four are the strongest trainers
of a given region, right?
Yeah!
Kamonegi, should we try it?
Oh, Strike!
Do you want to go too, Strike?
I get it. I haven’t taken you out
to battle much lately...
Okay! Come with us!
All right! Let’s go to Kalos!
Trying to become stronger,
Satoshi and Go departed for Kalos.
What awaits them in
the Castle of Chivalry?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gampi of the Elite Four!
The Castle of Chivalry!!
The Castle of Chivalry, Kalos Region
So this is the Castle of Chivalry...
It certainly looks the part!
How are we supposed to get in?
Thou who seekest strength,
I welcome thee here!
I am the Man of Steel
of the Kalos Elite Four, Gampi!
He’s really intense...
I believe chivalry to be
the path of the truly strong.
And in order to convey such to
trainers and Pokémon around the world,
I established this Castle of Chivalry!
Gilgard! Royal Sword Pokémon!
Steel/Ghost type!
It fights by switching between
two Formes: attack and defense!
It can use spectral power
to control people and Pokémon!
Now! Let us seek
new heights together!
Yeah.
Thank you!
Good answers!
Oh, how refreshing thy bright eyes are!
Glory be to thy futures!
H-He’s crying?
He seems really passionate...
Challengers,
I ask for your names!
I’m Satoshi!
This is my partner, Pikachu.
We came here to train Kamonegi.
I’m Go! And this is Strike!
My, what wonderful expressions.
This one shall be a worthy student!
Oh, this is so cool!
Yeah. But why do we
have to wear armor, too?
There is but one reason!
Since ye dost pursue true strength!
Ye shall discover why
as soon as your training begins!
We will?
I’m getting excited!
This Castle of Chivalry is composed of
three different training grounds.
When Pokémon and trainer overcome
the three tasks together, and reach the roof...
As proof of their true strength, they shall be bestowed
Knight Medals to honor their title as knights!
Knight Medals...
We’ll get ‘em for sure,
Kamonegi!
We begin with the first task!
A knight must show
peerless strength!
One must polish and hone oneself!
Showing peerless strength...
Then we’re starting
with battle training?!
Run ten laps around the castle!
What?!
Yeah! Thanks for
cheering me on, Pikachu!
So we’re building stamina!
Well, that’s the place to start!
Ten laps isn’t exactly easy, though.
This armor’s pretty heavy, too.
It’s no big deal!
We’ve gotta be able to do this, no sweat!
Right, Kamonegi?
Kamonegi and Strike are both
super determined, huh?
Wh-What’s that?
Dainose! Compass Pokémon!
Rock/Steel type!
It exudes strong magnetism
from all over!
It freely controls three units
called Mini-Noses!
Dainose, huh?
I wonder what it’s doing here.
It must’ve come here
to train too, right?
Wh-What?!
My body’s suddenly so heavy...
Dainose is my companion,
aiding in the first task!
Withstanding and outrunning its strong magnetic field
builds a strong mind and a strong body!
So that was it!
But... This is pretty tough,
you know?!
Kamonegi!
And Strike!
All right! We aren’t gonna...
...give up either, yeah?!
Yes! Your steadfast hearts pushing onward
are marvelous!
It stopped!
Good work running!
Ye have all passed the first task!
We did it...
My joints are creaking,
but that felt good!
What extraordinary resolve
I have witnessed from you!
Keep that fighting spirit
and proceed!
Now, to the second task!
This is the site of the second task,
the Maze of Doubts!
The Maze of Doubts?
It looks like a creepy place.
A knight must show
peerless bravery!
Fears and doubts constantly
assail one on the battlefield.
Pokémon and trainer must work hand in hand
to escape this maze filled with traps!
I see... Let’s do our best
to get through, Strike!
We aren’t giving up either!
Right, Kamonegi?
Huh? Hey, wait for me!
Let’s go together!
No change with Kamonegi, I see.
Hold on!
This task tests the bond between
the pair of Pokémon and trainer.
Thou mayest wait for everyone
at the exit, alongside me.
Pikachu, I’ll see you later!
The path splits in two...
We’ve reached the crossroads of destiny...
Which way should we go?
What’s that?
The die has been cast!
Looks like it.
Let’s meet up at the goal, Go!
Yeah!
What?
That was great, Strike!
Okay, let’s keep going!
The path splits again...
Hey, Kamonegi!
Ah, Dedenne!
Why’s a Dedenne here?
That tickles!
Hey! Wait for me!
Kamonegi! Look out!
Huh? A dead end?
Oh, well... Let’s go back
and take the other path.
Kamonegi?
What? Really?
Wow...
What? What’s going on now?
That Kamonegi has rare gifts
in fighting spirit and power.
A lone warrior who follows its own path
and never backs down.
What wonderful talent.
However...
As it is, it cannot hope to
achieve true strength!
I wonder how much longer
until we reach the goal...
Kamonegi!
Kamonegi! I’ll save you!
Nearly there...!
Your leek!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gilgard
Ghost
Steel
That was close.
Here. I’m glad it’s safe.
That leek is what’s most
important to you, after all!
Now, let’s hurry on ahead!
Hmm? A sign of change, perhaps?
Satoshi.
Go? That means...
The goal?
Yes! Ye have passed
the second task!
We did it!
We passed!
Marvelous, truly marvelous!
Let me express my sincere respect
for making it this far.
Now, this is the last: the third task.
Take care as ye proceed.
This looks pretty barren...
I wonder what the task is?
Now, ye shall undergo
the third task.
As I stated beforehand, those who pass this
will be awarded Knight Medals.
Your task is simple and clear.
Open the locked door behind me,
and ye wilt have passed.
And as for the key to the door...
Cleffy!
Cleffy! Key Ring Pokémon!
Steel/Fairy type!
It absorbs metal ions
through its horn!
It has a habit of collecting keys!
If trainer and Pokémon work together
to take the key from this Cleffy, and open the door,
ye shall all pass.
However...
Taking it will not be easy!
So that’s it.
Are ye prepared?
Now! Now!
To battle! To battle! To battle!
We just need to take that key, right?
He who strikes first wins!
Kamonegi! Crossroad Kill!
Strike, use Slash!
Guard, Gilgard!
Consecutive Cut!
Air Slash!
That Gilgard’s really tough...
Hold on...
He never said we couldn’t
take the key, did he?
Oh, right!
Then while we have the chance...!
The key’s ours!
I believe I said taking it
would not be easy!
You’re fighting too,
Mr. Gampi?
These are replica swords
for the training here,
but they are still
not to be taken lightly.
Now, to battle!
So this is why you had us
wear the armor?
See, Go? Fencing with leeks
really did help!
What’s the matter?
Is that all ye have?
We’re not getting anywhere like this.
Okay, I’ll stall Mr. Gampi.
Huh?!
Kamonegi, can you
take care of Gilgard?
Go and Strike, you take the key from Cleffy
while they’re busy!
Got it.
Let’s go!
Hold on!
A brave decision.
But also reckless,
wouldn’t thou agree?
I’m not giving up!
Hmm? Then thou shalt
have to do better!
Gilgard! King’s Shield!
It’s just like with Earlade.
That approach won’t work!
Dost thou have the liberty
to be looking away?!
Stop!
Strike!
You don’t have to thank me.
We’re both helping each other!
Let’s give it one more go!
Corner it from either side!
Go!
This is the end!
I’m glad it’s safe.
That leek is what’s most
important to you, after all!
Gilgard! Sacred Sword!
Thy Kamonegi cannot
defeat Gilgard!
No way it can’t!
I believe in Kamonegi!
Then you shall believe...
...as you are struck down together!
Kamonegi, you...
It rushed to its trainer,
despite having to take damage...
But it cannot withstand
another attack!
Gilgard! Sacred Sword!
That’s... Detect!
Okay! Keep going
and use Crossroad Kill!
Hold on, Kamonegi!
We got the key!
Marvelous!
A knight is one who fights to protect their precious lord,
and the weak and powerless.
When one truly treasures another, and fights to protect them,
their strength is magnified manyfold.
Sir Satoshi, Sir Kamonegi,
Sir Go, Sir Strike...
I hereby acknowledge your success in training,
and award you these Knight Medals!
The Knight Medals...
...are ours!
By the way, Sir Go, hast thou ever considered
evolving thy partner, Sir Strike?
If thou transferrest Strike as it holds
this item, a Metal Coat...
Whoa! It evolved into Hassam!
I’m happy for you, Hassam!
Hassam’s data will be
added to the Index!
Hassam! Pincer Pokémon!
Bug/Steel type!
It smashes enemies
with pincers hard as steel!
Mr. Gampi,
thank you so much for today!
Indeed!
Be sure to keep training diligently!
Right!
Kamonegi! Let’s beat Earlade
next time, you hear?
Satoshi and Kamonegi, and Go and Hassam have learned
the way of the knight; strong, brave, and kind.
Their days of dreams, adventures and
training are sure to continue!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
It’s snowing!
Let’s have a snowball fight!
Never mind that!
I want to catch Ice-type Pokémon!
I can’t let this chance get away!
Why not come home with me?
Huh?
I’d be all alone at home too,
so you can stay with me.
You could just become
a Koduck’s trainer...
Just looking at them
is enough for me.
And...
Love is a Koduck
Next time, on Pocket Monsters: