Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Pikachu! It’s going your way!
Are you okay, Messon?
H-Hey...
Messon... C’mon, cheer up.
Hihidaruma takes any chance it gets
to play a prank...
You might want to hit back
every now and then!
Well, Messon will be Messon...
Oh, it was incredible!
When I went out for lunch, they were shooting a movie
in the warehouse district!
And get this, it was the sequel
to “Spy & Sniper”!
Really?! That’s a big title!
What’s that?
You don’t know it?!
It’s a movie starring
a female spy Pokémon Trainer,
and she has this really cool
Inteleon partner!
Inteleon! Agent Pokémon!
Water type!
Its body has many
hidden capabilities,
such as fingertips
that can shoot water,
and a membrane on its back
that it can use to glide through the air!
It’s a huge hit that keeps people
coming back for more.
Yeah! It does look cool!
Right?
Looks like even Messon’s interested.
Well, Inteleon is
Messon’s final evolution.
I wanna see it!
Do you think they’re still filming?
Let’s go see!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Messon: Impossible!
And so, Satoshi and Go
have arrived at the film shoot.
According to Renji,
this should be it—
This is not it!
That voice...!
This man is Director Koreda,
a master of the movie world.
This isn’t it!
Thanks to Director Sakuragi, Satoshi and Go
were able to watch him film a movie once before.
If this does that, no,
if that does that...
It just needs a bit more flair...
Um... What should we do?
Everyone’s already standing by...
Agh, let’s go for it!
They’re starting, Messon!
Ready, start!
Hand over the case.
Go, Yamikarasu!
Good timing, partner.
Stop them both!
What?!
Hold...
...your...
...battle!
We are your aides, meow!
Get in, Inteleon!
We’ll make a getaway.
Um...
Was this in the script?
Who are those cartoonish intruders?!
Stop the came—
Don’t stop the cameras!
Sir?
This may just create that!
Keep filming!
So you’re not gonna fall for
this cliché plot...
If you say “Leo, leo”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket is on the scene!
Those guys were Team Rocket?!
A third side shows up!
This is it, this is it, this is it!
Inteleon! We’ve seen what you can do
in your movie.
Your sharp mind and spy skills...
We’d love to have you aid Team Rocket!
So there you have it.
Shut up and come with us, meow!
Don’t be so selfish!
We won’t let you
get in the way of the filming!
The brat boys?
We won’t let you get in our way,
either, meow!
Director!
Now there’s more weird intruders...
Don’t stop the cameras!
Capsules, c’mon!
All right...
Here goes, meow!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
I wonder, what’ll I get?
The Bite Pokémon,
Poochyena!
Yay!
The Dark Pokémon,
Delvil!
All right!
Go, Pikachu!
Aceburn, go!
Poochyena! Um, um, Yawn!
Dodge it!
Now this is a... movie...
Director!
How could you!
Your fault for dodging.
Hey. It’s that crybaby
Pokémon again.
Oh, so it is.
Then there’s just one thing to do.
Poochyena!
Scary Face the blue thing!
Oh, no!
Yay, yay!
That’s really cruel!
It’s your fault for bringing
that dead weight!
Yeah, that’s right!
Nyahahaha-ha!
Now! Delvil,
use Ember on them!
Poochyena! Shadow Ball!
Inteleon! Snipe Shot.
What?!
When did it...?
Concealing yourself without a sound,
without a trace...
That’s the first rule
of being a spy.
Right, Inteleon?
It disappeared again?!
Where’d it go, meow?
Now. Snipe Shot!
We may have failed...
But that Inteleon gives us
such a great feeling!
Amazing...
We’re wrapping up
the shoot early today!
Please clear the way!
That Inteleon was awesome!
Yeah! Even Messon
was totally entranced...
Huh? Where’d it go?
Hey! This area is for staff only!
Sorry! That’s my Messon!
You have to keep a close eye
on your Pokémon!
Messon...?
Um... Messon and I
had never seen an Inteleon before,
so please, is there any chance
we could spend some time with it?
What...?
That’s fine.
Our schedule cleared up anyway.
You must be happy, Messon!
That brings back memories.
It looks a lot like Inteleon used to.
Really?!
Yes. He was my partner,
even off camera.
Even he wasn’t always this strong.
Great going!
Messon’s really
looking up to Inteleon.
It did it again?!
Getting stronger will take time.
So what do you think?
Would you like to train with me?
Hah... Inteleon was
every bit as strong as I thought!
All the more reason
we should make it ours, meow.
But with that strength...
Brute force isn’t going to—
All done!
What’s that, meow?
A thorough plan.
Think about the Pokémon we’re taking on.
We’ll need to make
lots of preparations to catch it.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Inteleon
Water
All right!
Let’s train with all we’ve got!
Or well... What sort of training
should we even do?
Battling, naturally!
That Inteleon was super strong!
Well, let’s give it a try.
Hit us with all you’ve got, okay?
Okay then,
let’s get started, Messon!
Use Pound on Pikachu!
Counter it, Pikachu!
You’re scared of getting up close?
Then attack from a distance!
Messon! Water Gun!
If you’re not moving,
you’re gonna get targeted!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Messon! Fire while dodging!
Where’s the Water Gun?
I think... It prioritizes protecting itself
rather than fighting back.
It’s a hundred percent focused on
fleeing right now...
Well, staying safe is staying safe...
But that’s not much of a battle.
Let’s take a break!
Maybe Messon just
isn’t cut out for this.
Oh, that’s not it!
I meant your battle style.
Messon, you always watch your surroundings carefully,
and run away at the slightest danger, right?
People may call you timid,
but I think it’s good to protect yourself!
But that trait isn’t something
normal methods take advantage of...
We need another way.
Something that puts your timidness to good use.
Puts timidness to good use?
You mean, something like
running and hiding?
No, that won’t help battle...
Maybe it will!
Huh?
Concealing yourself without a sound,
without a trace...
That’s the first rule
of being a spy.
We’ll hone your skills of
running and hiding!
Let’s play tag, like a spy!
We’ll all chase you, while you run around
and try to avoid capture!
That’s great! It sounds fun!
Aceburn, you help out too!
Ready... Start!
Hold it!
Pikachu, go for it!
Messon spotted!
I feel like it should be around here...
Gotta do better! One more time!
Where’d it go?
Maybe over there?
Here!
It went that way!
Messon looked like it had fun!
It was getting better and better.
Somebody, help!
Are you okay?
You’re from that film crew!
I went with Gothim
to get lunch for everyone...
One hostage kidnapped!
Or rather, Pokénapped!
If you want it back...
They said I’d have to
bring Inteleon to this spot...
Those creeps...
So they hadn’t given up on him yet?!
We’ll go on ahead!
You go let everyone know
what happened!
Got it!
It’s probably around here...
Let’s go.
I was surprised to see a cave
with so much built in it...
But what are those things?
I thought they could be lookouts,
but they’re not
attacking us or anything...
And they seem to be placed all over...
Well, if they’re not getting in the way,
let’s go find Gothim.
Right.
That voice...!
That way!
Gothim?! Are you okay?
We’ll save you!
Why did it have to be
you people?!
Yeah! I even bought RC cameras
to record some cool Inteleon footage!
So those weird things were cameras!
But all we got shots of was you!
Don’t you know when to stop, meow?!
Huh? You’re the ones
who should stop!
Don’t copy me, meow!
Aceburn, break this cage!
Too bad.
It won’t break that easily!
Well, we’ve made it this far,
may as well pick up the loose charms.
Pikachu and Aceburn...
And that little crybaby Pokémon while we’re at it.
We’ll present them all to Sakaki,
along with Inteleon, meow!
Messon!
Let ‘em see what you’ve learned!
You’ve been thrown straight in the deep end,
but this is the start of your battle!
Hurry up and catch it!
Get ready, meow!
Messon! Aim straight up
and use Water Gun!
It vanished!
It soaked up its own Water Gun!
Now your enemies can’t see you!
Relax and use Water Gun on Nyarth!
Even if you can’t see it,
you can guess where it is!
Sonansu, around there!
Quickly get out of there,
without a sound and without a trace!
Now, Water Gun!
Then run for it, Messon!
Great job!
Attacking from a distance,
then running before it can be hit back!
That’s Messon’s
hit-and-run battle style!
That’s not fair!
Since it’s come to this...
You’ve forced our hand!
What’s that?
The device for when Inteleon vanishes
actually helped...!
If we can see you,
the battle’s ours, meow!
Forget about the battle!
Run, Messon!
Messon!
We’ll catch you, meow!
It went back into its ball...
What was that?
A move called
“Dragonfly Turnaround”!
That’s great!
You did it, Messon!
Hitting your opponent then returning,
you’ve learned the ultimate hit-and-run tactic!
All right, Pikachu, Messon, Aceburn!
Let’s break down this cage together!
Nyarth, are you okay?
Sonansu, snap out of it!
Now the tables have turned!
No way...
You can finish the job, Aceburn!
Pyro Ball!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
Gothim! I was worried about you!
We gave them a good beating!
Oh, this is it, this is it,
this is it, this is it, this is it!
Messon, you were the star.
We rushed over,
but didn’t have to do a thing.
Hey, Messon!
Where are you?
Hihidaruma?
It was up there?
Good job, Messon!
Meeting someone to aspire towards
has given Messon a change of heart.
Work hard with Go to hopefully reach that
lofty summit someday, Messon!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
“The Tale of the Luminous Maze Forest and You”?
Huh?! They’re nothing like
the Ponyta I’ve seen!
I’d like to see them!
Me too!
I want to catch it!
Then you should all
go see them together.
Are you trying to ask me
to help Gallop?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Tale of the Luminous Maze Forest and You