Satoshi and Go went to Galar in order to watch
the Pokémon World Championships.
Kyodaimax!
Before the excitement had a chance to die down,
Team Rocket attempted to catch a Pokémon...
...which ended up Kyodaimaxing!
Nyah, nyah!
Come over here, why don’tcha?!
Oh, what is this?!
A Kyodaimax Kajirigame
is going on a rampage!
Come on!
Yeah!
This way, Pikachu!
You too, Hibunny!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi Versus Dande!
The Path to Power!!
Hey! Calm down!
If you don’t stop,
you might wreck the entire stadium!
Looks like we’ll just
have to battle it!
Huh?!
We’ll draw its attention with a battle
and get it away from the stadium!
But how are you planning
to fight a Daimax Pokémon?
Don’t know!
Don’t know”?!
All the more reason to try!
You stand back, Go!
I refuse!
If you’re fighting, then so am I!
All right! Time for a tag battle!
Yeah!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Us too, Hibunny!
100,000 Volts!
Use Double Kick!
No good!
Here it comes!
Yeah!
Electroweb!
What’s up, Pikachu?
Hey, Satoshi, isn’t that...?
What?!
Pikachu Daimaxed?!
Satoshi!
Pikachu!
Just use Lightning Speed!
Satoshi!
The stadium’s still full of people!
I know!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
A Kyodaimax Pikachu?
Great job, Pikachu!
No way...
That young man’s battling
without a Daimax Band?
That’s...
The Rock-type Daimax move!
Tell him to use
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Mr. Dande?!
Your Pikachu should be able to use it!
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Okay! I’ll give it a try!
Pikachu!
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Did we do it?
I see! Kyodai Heavy Thunder, huh?
That was amazing, Pikachu!
Now’s our chance!
Let’s get that Daimax Pokémon!
Hurry, meow!
You two!
Are you all right?
Yeah, we’re fine!
Thanks for the help, Mr. Dande!
I’m the one who
should be thanking you.
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
I’m Go from Kuchiba City!
I’m Dande.
We know!
You’re the Supreme Monarch, yeah?
I’d like to ask you something.
Wait... Ask him?
Please battle me!
Satoshi! How crazy can you get?!
Hey! You can’t Kyodaimax
your Pokémon here!
No, you got it all wrong!
We were acting as bait
to lure that big one away!
They’re the heroes
who saved the stadium!
Show them some respect.
Oh, pardon me!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kajirigame
Rock
Water
The Galar Region’s scones
really are great, huh, Satoshi?
Satoshi?
Hey...
You’re so out of it that
you won’t even eat?
A Pokémon I’ve never seen before!
Hoshigarisu! Cheek-Stuffing Pokémon!
Normal type!
It eats berries nonstop!
When its cheeks are full,
it tends to stash more in the flaps in its tail!
Monster Ball, go!
Hoshigarisu’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
That’s my second Galar Pokémon!
Satoshi, something troubling you?
Then you should tell me!
Oh, I was just remembering
Mr. Dande’s battle yesterday!
Oh, I see...
Huh? Can’t I?
You think about Pokémon
or battling 24/7, huh?
No, I totally space out
if I don’t get 10 hours of sleep.
So that’s 24 hours minus 10,
which is...
Never mind that.
The point is, you want to
battle Mr. Dande, right?
Yeah, that’s right.
All right, I get it.
But getting to battle him
will be tough.
Huh?
If you want to participate in
the Pokémon World Championships,
you’ll have to sign up online,
and then win your way up through the ranks.
Ranks?
Your position, based on
your record and performance.
The top eight in the rankings
are called the Master Class.
At the end of the season,
those eight fight in a tournament,
where the winner
becomes the Champion.
So I can battle Mr. Dande
if I enter that?!
Think it’ll be that easy?!
Why not?
Trainers who enter get divided into four classes based off
their win/lose ratio and the contents of their battles.
All trainers entering for the first time
go into the Normal Class.
Then the trainers in that rank
battle it out between each other,
and the ones ranked 999 to 100
enter the Super Class.
Above that, 99 through 9
make up the Hyper Class.
What about Mr. Dande?!
He’s in the highest Master Class,
of course.
And he’s ranked number one, at that!
So if you want to battle him,
you’ll have to climb your way up to the Master Class!
Was that too complicated for you?
Well, I just gotta win battles, right?
Right! Let’s do this!
Here.
You really saved me!
What?! M-M-Mr. Dande?!
Wh-Wh-What are you doing here?!
You said you wanted
to battle me, right?
Um, but I just finished explaining
how that wouldn’t be so easy...
As the Supreme Monarch,
I thought I’d grant this young man’s dream.
Please!
What?!
We’ve been running
all over the place since yesterday...
...without catching a single thing...
Where’d that Daimax Pokémon go, meow?
Hey, Musashi! What’s that?!
What?
Who’s that Pokémon?!
Kamukame. Snapping Pokémon.
Water type.
Evolves into Kajirigame.
Well, ain’t that a shocker?
Oh, my! This thing can evolve into
that giant from yesterday, meow!
That’s great!
Get it for me, Kojiro.
A-Are you sure?
It’ll turn into
that ferocious thing, right?
Huh? It doesn’t hurt.
This is perfect, meow!
We’ll take it back and
offer it up to Sakaki, meow!
All right!
Mission complete!
What a great feeling!
Mr. Dande requested
that I be the referee!
Counting on you!
Have this, young Satoshi.
It’s a Daimax Band.
You battled without
a band yesterday,
but normally,
we use it to control Daimax.
This?
Yeah.
And when your Pokémon goes Daimax,
their move names change as well.
I’ll handle the rest!
Normal-type moves
become Dai Attack.
Steel-type moves
become Dai Steel.
And Electric-type moves
become Dai Thunder!
Dai Attack, Dai Steel,
and Dai Thunder!
Although, your Pikachu
uses Kyodaimax.
Kyodaimax?
In his case, Electric-type moves
become Kyodai Heavy Thunder.
Kyodai Heavy Thunder...
The move from yesterday, right?
In order to use Daimax,
you have to return your Pokémon to its Monster Ball,
and then fill the Ball with the power emerging
from the band before throwing it.
Pikachu won’t go inside
his Monster Ball...
But I’m sure we’ll manage!
All right, Mr. Dande,
I’ll be borrowing this!
So cool!
Now, both sides
send forth your Pokémon!
Pikachu, I choose you!
The one I choose... is you!
All right! Pikachu and I
both wanted to battle Lizardon!
It seems you understand
your partner Pokémon’s feelings!
I’m glad!
Pikachu has the type advantage here!
But Champion Dande and Lizardon
will never lose any battle!
Fine by me!
Let the battle begin!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Lizardon!
Counter with Thunder Punch!
I knew they’d be strong!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Another Thunder Punch!
Keep going!
Electroweb!
Don’t worry about it!
Keep going!
Air Slash!
Pikachu!
All right!
Use 100,000 Volts!
Flamethrower!
Even Pikachu’s signature 100,000 Volts
can’t beat that Flamethrower?!
Don’t give up!
Lizardon?!
The Kyodaimax was a success!
Interesting...
This was well worth it!
Return, Lizardon!
Let me show you
a true Champion time!
Kyodaimax!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Dai Attack!
Use Dai Jet!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Pikachu! Dai Steel!
Lizardon! Dai Thunder!
In that case...
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Now, enjoy the climax!
Kyodai Hellfire!
They’re evenly matched...
It’s not over yet!
Pikachu!
Pikachu is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Dande!
Looks like it’s over...
What a shame, huh, Lizardon?
Pikachu, you gave it your all.
Young Satoshi,
give Pikachu this.
Thank you.
Mr. Dande, I’m glad I got to have
a serious battle with you!
Battles are no fun if
they aren’t serious.
That’s all there is to it.
Oh, and have this...
Keep it.
Are you sure?
I like young,
unrefined trainers like you.
But if you want to satisfy me,
you’ll have to pop more!
“Pop”?
Put on more of a show!
Later, then.
Mr. Dande!
Please, battle me again someday!
Our next match will be
an official one, with a crowd!
Yeah!
I’ve made up my mind!
I’ll enter the tournament
and battle Mr. Dande again!
And next time, I’ll win!
That’s the first step towards
becoming a Pokémon Master!
That’s great!
There’s the Satoshi I know!
Pikachu,
let’s get stronger together!
Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who aims to
catch every Pokémon.
Next time, more dreams and adventures
await in the world of Pocket Monsters!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Here we are in the Isshu Region!
The newly uncovered ruins!
Try your hand at solving
their ancient riddles!
This desert is way too hot!
Don’t underestimate
the Resort Desert, you two!
Satoshi! Let’s fight a Raid Battle!
All right, I’m in!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
My First Time in the Isshu Region!
A Raid Battle in the Ruins!!