The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The eight mighty trainers
aiming for the summit...
...have begun battling.
And the semifinals are today.
The first match will be
Dande versus Carne.
The second match will be
Shirona versus Satoshi.
Fierce battles are in store
as they vie for a spot in the finals.
Shoot City, Galar Region
Near Shoot Stadium
stands Hotel Lond Rose.
This is where staff and participants
of the Masters Tournament are staying.
Hey...
Go!
Have you been up all night?
Yeah!
Project Mew sent me
all this material!
So I’ve been organizing the info
in my own way.
Whoa... That’s amazing!
Now I’ll be ready,
no matter when they call me!
Do your best,
and go find Mew!
Right!
I’m counting on you
to get through the semifinals, too!
Yeah!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Semifinals I - "Sweep"
All right, that’s enough!
You’re all looking nice and sharp!
That’s the spirit!
Naturally, they’re all fired up.
Satoshi! Kairyu!
Ms. Shirona!
Sorry for disturbing you...
It’s okay! Don’t worry about it.
By the looks of it, I assume you were
doing final preparations before our match?
Yeah.
You too, Ms. Shirona?
Yes.
All right, try flying now.
Okay, Gaburias!
Are you... massaging her?
Yes. It’s our pre-match routine.
It helps balance out her muscles,
aiding her maneuverability.
That’s gotta feel great!
You’re incredible, Ms. Shirona!
Okay, one more try!
No kidding!
She’s faster now!
It helps that much?
So sharp!
Yep, you’re looking good.
Cool! So many Pokémon!
Toria! Stop!
It’s all good.
Come on over.
Do you like Pokémon?
Sure do!
Ah! A Pikachu!
It’s okay, you can touch him.
So cute!
This Pokémon’s a Kairyu, right?!
Look at how big it is!
You can touch them, too!
Th-Thank you...
I’m Vic.
That’s my little sister, Toria.
I’m Satoshi!
And I’m Go!
Shirona.
Nice to meet you.
You’re in the Masters Eight!
I’ve seen all your battles!
Oh! Thank you!
Who are you cheering for?
Well, I... I’m a fan of Mr. Dande,
but your Pikachu was cool, too!
Huh? Pikachu?
10,000,000 Volts!
Think I can do that, too?
Hmm...
I wonder about that...
That’s a special move
only Satoshi’s Pikachu can pull off.
Pikachu is Satoshi’s partner.
They’ve been adventuring together for a very long time.
His partner...
I’ve decided my first Pokémon’s
gonna be a Sarunori!
Sarunori? Sounds good!
Yeah!
Then I’ll evolve it into a Gorillander,
just like Mr. Dande did!
And get it to Kyodaimax!
You’ll have to evolve it
from a Sarunori to a Bachinkey first.
I will! I wanna pull off an awesome move
like your 10,000,000 Volts!
I’m sure you have it in you.
Ms. Shirona,
who was your first Pokémon?
Oh yeah,
I’ve never heard who it was.
She was.
We’ve traveled together
ever since she was a Fukamaru.
Huh...
I thought it’d be more like
a Pochama, Hikozaru, or Naetle...
Indeed...
I hatched her from an egg.
An egg?!
Tell us, tell us!
Tell us what that was like!
You never know what will hatch
from a Pokémon egg, right?
I wondered and wondered
what it would hatch into...
It had my heart racing.
Then, when I warmed it up
with all my might...
She hatched from it.
I was so happy.
Wait, wait!
I hatched my Lucario
from an egg, too!
That’s right!
It was a mysterious egg.
Oh.
Mysterious?
It wouldn’t hatch,
no matter who warmed it up.
Various regions had examined it,
with no answers...
But the egg called out to Satoshi!
Wha...?!
Yeah!
I could feel his Guiding Waves,
like “Whoosh!”
Lucario is called
the Guiding Wave Pokémon, isn’t it?
So cool!
Maybe he was waiting for you.
For me?
Even I had heard
about that mysterious egg.
So you were inside.
Even now,
when I’m battling with Lucario,
it’s like “Bam!”...
I can feel my Guiding Waves growing.
The same thing happened
when I battled Mr. Kibana before.
Look after him.
I’m certain fate brought you together.
Will I get to meet
a Pokémon by fate, too?
You bet!
I just know you’ll think
all the friends you meet were fate!
Thank you for telling me
all of this!
Toria!
We need to get going!
Right!
Thanks, Gänger!
A Himenka!
Wait!
Oh... Hey! Toria!
Keep it up
with your battles! Bye!
We should be
heading out soon ourselves.
Yeah!
Now, Competitor Dande
has entered the battlefield!
Ooh, it’s Mr. Dande!
Toria!
Huh? That’s Vic...
Pikachu, Sarunori...
Vic!
What’s wrong?
Have you seen Toria?
Huh?
Did you get split up?
Yeah...
We’ll all look for her!
Don’t worry!
We’ll find her in no time!
Thank you!
The Masters Tournament semifinals!
The first match is about to begin!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey! Toria!
Toria!
Say something! Toria!
Toria! Where are you?!
What?
Come to think of it,
I heard this earlier...
Doesn’t that sound like
Himenka’s singing?
Himenka. Flowering Pokémon.
Grass type.
It whirls around in the wind singing a joyous song.
This delightful display has charmed many into raising it.
If we follow the singing,
we might find Toria!
Yeah!
Pikachu, we’re counting on you!
Toria!
Shh!
It really was a Himenka.
Did you come here
to watch that Pokémon?
Yeah.
You have to tell me
about things like that...
Sorry...
Is it evolving?!
Wow!
That’s Watashiraga, right?
Yes.
It’s leaving!
The seeds from its cotton fluff
carry nutrients for plants and Pokémon.
It’s departing upon the wind
to help enrich the nature of Galar.
Hey!
Bye-bye!
Look after yourself!
Oh! I forgot, Mr. Dande!
The battle!
It’s gonna start!
Hey, Satoshi! Look!
Huh? What?!
What a fierce first match!
Competitor Carne has already lost four Pokémon,
only having two left.
On the other hand,
Competitor Dande has only lost one,
leaving him
with five Pokémon to use.
Numelgon! Great Blaze!
It’s super effective!
Gorillander’s eliminated
Competitor Carne’s Pokémon one after another!
Will this powerful Fire move
finally take it down?!
And Gorillander holds on!
Impossible!
Acrobatics!
Numelgon is unable to battle!
All right! Good work!
One more and you’re in the finals!
He’s so cool!
Gorillander’s so strong!
I’ve never seen Ms. Carne
so overpowered...
It looks like in the end
you’re all I have left.
You’re on, Sirknight!
Everyone!
Have you been watching?
This is match one of the
Pokémon World Championships semifinals!
In the battle between Competitor Dande, Galar’s Champion;
and Competitor Carne, Kalos’s Champion...
Competitor Dande’s frenzied attacks have taken down
Competitor Carne’s Pokémon one after another, meow!
After this and that, her last Pokémon
is everyone’s favorite, Sirknight!
Princess Number 28,
what are your impressions on the battle so far?
Pumpjin lost,
so who cares anymore?
It’s not over ‘til the dust settles!
After all, she’s a star actress!
We’re cheering for
Competitor Carne, meow!
Shadow Ball!
Knock Off!
Psychokinesis!
Gorillander is unable to battle!
Gorillander finally goes down!
Competitor Carne’s counterattack has begun!
You fought well.
Come out, Lizardon!
Lizardon...
Competitor Dande’s ace,
Lizardon, has arrived!
Let’s finish this, Lizardon!
En garde, Dande!
Sirknight! Mega Evolve!
So you’re using Mega Evolution...
That means...
it’s Champion time!
All right! This is it!
Kyodai... max!
It’s Kyodaimax Lizardon!
100,000 Volts!
Now that’s powerful!
Whoa! Kyodaimax Lizardon
was greatly shaken!
Kyodai Hellfire!
Whoa! Incredible flames
wrap around Mega Sirknight!
Psychokinesis!
What?!
Is this real?!
Incredible! It’s controlling the flames
with Psychokinesis!
That’s pretty good!
Lizardon! Dai Jet!
What’s going on?!
The Psychokinesis,
the Kyodai Hellfire, and the Dai Jet...
They’ve all combined into one!
Ms. Carne and Sirknight’s desire to never give up
is giving them strength.
Sirknight!
Lizardon!
One more Kyodai Hellfire!
Blow them away!
An incredible blast
swallows Mega Sirknight!
Sirknight is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is...
Competitor Dande!
It’s over!
Competitor Dande heads into the finals!
Woo!
Big bro, you’re the best!
Wow... Amazing!
Lizardon’s so strong!
Yeah! It’s unbelievable!
I wanna have cool battles
just like Mr. Dande!
You’ll need to adventure lots,
catch lots, and battle lots to do that.
Yeah! When I get my partner,
can I battle you two?!
I wanna, too!
Yeah, let’s do it!
You’ve got yourself
some new little rivals.
Thank you.
Congratulations on
reaching the finals.
You made me sweat
time and time again.
I was just lucky today, that’s all.
So Mr. Dande will be waiting
in the finals...
Satoshi and Shirona are finally about to clash
over a spot in the finals match against Dande.
Who will win?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The second semifinals
match will be...
...Competitor Shirona versus
Competitor Brat Boy, meow!
Wait... She sent out
a pretty creepy Pokémon, meow...
It looks pretty strong!
That pansy’s nothing special!
Bleh, I say! Bleh!
Uh, it’s looking this way, meow.
It’s coming!
H-H-Hey, wait!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Semifinals II - “Bedazzle”
The Semifinals II - "Bedazzle"
Let’s all tune in, meow!