Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Coming!
Who could it be,
this early?
Huh? Ms. Junsa?
Is Director Sakuragi here?
Good morning.
Is there a problem?
Actually, we’re here to ask about a case that’s been
taking place here in Kuchiba City over the last few days.
A case?!
The detective in charge
will tell you more.
With me is the chief investigator
assigned to the case, Detective Decker.
Howdy there.
Call me Decker.
Sorry there ‘bout callin’ so early.
I’m Sakuragi, the Director.
Oh, don’tcha worry,
I ain’t gonna take your time.
If y’all gonna be cooperatin’,
we’ll be gone lickety-split.
Of course. Ask away.
Coppa relief!
Now ‘at’s good news.
Well ‘en,
let’s get right down to it.
Can ya gather up all the Electric-type Pokémon
ya got at Sakuragi Park?
Gather all the...
...Electric types?
‘Bout what I’d expect from
the Sakuragi Institute.
Quite the lineup ya got there.
What exactly is this?
Just a formality, is all.
Something kinda
feels awful about this.
Yeah.
I knew it.
No doubtin’ it, the culprit...
...was you!
Pikachu?!
The culprit?!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pikachu the Suspect?!
9:23 am,
suspect apprehended.
Ya have the right to remain silent,
and the right to consult an attorney—
H-Hold on a minute!
Why’re you arresting Pikachu?!
Pikachu hasn’t done anything wrong!
You’re Pikachu’s trainer, ‘en?
We’ve got a witness!
A witness?
Ms. Junsa, what’s going on here?
Actually...
There’s been a string of cases of
electricity being stolen from houses in Kuchiba City.
Electricity being stolen?
The power suddenly cuts out during the night,
and whenever we check, we keep finding
abnormal amounts of power consumption.
A task force was formed to solve the mystery of the case,
led by Detective Decker.
We haven’t been able to find any clues,
but we have had valuable witness testimony...
I followed the footsteps I heard.
Then for a moment, I saw a fleeing Pokémon,
illuminated by a car’s headlights.
And here’s the sketch we drew up
from his testimony.
That’s... Pikachu?
It does kinda look like one...
But still, it could be
another Pikachu.
We’ve been lookin’ at this city’s Electric types,
‘specially the Pikachu.
And we gathered that
each a’ the Pikachu’s got an alibi.
‘Cept for this Institute’s one here.
Alibis?
Then my Pikachu has one, too!
We’ve always been together!
Let me tell ya, the last theft
was at 11 pm, last night.
What were ya doin’ at that time?
...I was fast asleep.
Asleep?!
So ya sayin’ ya’d never’ve known
if Pikachu snuck out and stole electricity.
But...
Detective Decker,
isn’t arresting him a bit extreme?
We should rule out
any other possibilities firs—
My dear Junsa, I’m tellin’ ya!
My cop’s instinct is never wrong!
He’s bein’ arrested!
Ya got any more objections,
save ‘em for the station.
Cop yaself a break...
‘Fess up already!
Don’tcha give me that “Pikaaa...”!
Well, how’s about this?
Ya must be starving.
Have a bowl a’ Pokémon food.
The sun’s shinin’...
Beautiful day out there...
Hey, ya got a mom waitin’ for ya
atcha hometown, don’tcha?
Confessin’ to yer crimes and makin’ up for ‘em’d
make her happy, ya know?
Hey, ya even listenin’ there?!
Yer supposed ta spit it out!
Spit it out, not fill yer belly!
He’s acting like Pikachu’s a criminal!
Something’s really wrong here!
Ms. Junsa, do you think
Pikachu’s the thief, too?
No... I know Satoshi and his Pikachu.
I can’t imagine he’d do this.
Then let him go!
But... Fact is that the sketch
is our only clue.
Detective Decker’s been put in charge
of the investigation,
and he can jump
to conclusions at times.
You’d need to show him some evidence
that Pikachu wasn’t behind it to clear his name...
Evidence...
Wh-What?
What’cha tryin’ ta say?
What is it, Pikachu?!
He’s acting weird.
Let’s go check on him.
Pikachu!
Hey! Where are you going?!
Ya ain’t gonna cop outta this!
Guardie! After him!
Suspect has fled police custody!
Follow him!
Where is he going?
Is there something in this house?
Ya got nowhere ta run.
Thief! Electricity thief!
What’s wrong?
Oh, Ms. Junsa!
About ten minutes ago, the TV suddenly went off,
and my PC and fridge stopped running.
When I checked the meter,
there was a huge amount of power being used!
Someone’s stealing my electricity!
What?!
Ms. Junsa, isn’t this...
Yes. There’s no mistaking it.
That’s the MO of the serial electricity thief!
Ten minutes ago,
Pikachu was at the police station.
In other words...!
Pikachu has an alibi!
All right!
That’s great news, Pikachu!
I knew it.
Ya find true culprits
in the darndest places.
My instinct’s never wrong!
But all this time
you were saying Pikachu did it, yeah?
The thief must still be nearby.
Let’s look for them!
They gave us the slip!
They’ve always been
stealin’ at night before.
Now they’re doin’ it in broad daylight,
and still leavin’ no clues!
No, Detective Decker.
We did find a clue.
Huh?
When the theft occurred, Pikachu reacted to something
and ran to the crime scene.
Isn’t it possible he was sensing
the electricity being stolen?
What?!
Did you, Pikachu?
If we add Pikachu to the investigation team,
he may help us arrest the real thief!
Pikachu on the
investigation team?!
Okay, got it.
Pikachu’s joinin’ the case
as a special agent!
My dear Junsa, start up a thorough search
with Pikachu helpin’!
Yes, sir!
Wow, Ms. Junsa! Can I help, too?!
Oh, me too!
Sarunori, too!
Let’s start by patrolling this area.
We’re counting on you!
Right!
Hehe, they even let us
borrow the uniforms!
It feels like we’re
real police officers!
I’ve always wanted to try this.
Yeah, me too!
You’ve nowhere to run!
Pokémon Kidnapper,
you’re under arrest!
I’ve worked out all the tricks.
The truth is in my hands!
The culprit...
...was you!
Ms. Junsa!
What is it?
My Rokon disappeared!
A kidnapping?!
All right,
I’ll catch the kidnapper!
Leave it to me!
The truth is in my hands!
Or wait, right now we’re busy
looking for the electricity thief...
Oh, that’s right...
No...
Helping citizens in need is also
an important duty for police officers!
Right!
There’s tons of Rokon...
I couldn’t find it
out of all the others...
Can you tell us any way to
identify your Rokon?
Its tail looks like a heart.
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
You hear that?
Let’s check each and every Rokon.
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
Right!
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
I give up... I can’t find it...
Huh?
Where are Pikachu and Sarunori?
Each and every one of my memories
That’s it!
Can always be found inside a Ball
I’m so happy!
This is my Rokon!
Thank you!
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
Take care!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
That was hard work...
...but I’m glad we found it.
Ms. Junsa!
What’s wrong?
Greeting someone new is always fresh
You’re nearly there!
Thank you!
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
You there riding the Dodrio, stop!
On 3, let’s be friends!
Satoshi, Go, follow them!
R-Right!
Don’t ride Pokémon in cities!
It’s dangerous.
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
Let alone riding double.
Sorry...
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
I never knew Ms. Junsa
was so busy...
I choose you!
And with so many
mundane tasks...
Making sure everyone can live their lives happily
is a police officer’s job.
Having you two with me today
has been a great help, though!
But we haven’t had any luck
finding the all-important electricity thief...
What is it, Pikachu?
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Guardie
Fire
So you looked at the meter
and realized electricity was being stolen, correct?
Did you see anyone suspicious,
human or Pokémon?
No...
I think they’d already run off...
They’re fast at getting away...
Pikachu had even sensed them...
Even if Pikachu detects a theft,
there’ll always be time lost getting to the scene.
If only we could get there first
and lie in wait...
Lie in wait...
Oh, that’s it!
The thief targets houses
that use lots of power.
So let’s have Pikachu discharge lots of electricity
at some house, and lure the thief in!
I get it!
That certainly seems worth a try.
Okay! Let’s do it, Pikachu.
But whose house
do we lure them to?
Uhh... Well...
Why our house?
Oh, we just happened to be
in the neighborhood...
We would appreciate
your cooperation!
Well, if we can be of help...
Sorry, but just go along
with it, okay?
Sure, but...
What are we supposed to do?
You don’t need to do anything.
Huh?
Okay! Let’s begin, Pikachu!
Ooh! Awesome!
What is this?!
Go, is something wrong?
Is this sketch really a Pikachu?
Pikachu don’t have any habit
of sucking up electricity...
What Pokémon wants electricity...?
Dedenne!
Yeah! It does kinda
look like a Dedenne!
We thought the same thing,
but every Dedenne nearby turned out to have an alibi.
Huh... Then it really is a Pikachu?
Or is it some other Pokémon?
Ooh, that house looks like
it’s overflowing with electricity.
We’ll be able to get
lots of power here.
Today is looking up, meow...
Finally we can get some proper food...
That thing’s the reason
we’ve ended up like this...
No way!
Our month’s supply of food...
We’ll end up all shriveled
if this keeps happening...
Anything but that...
I know.
Morpeko’s an Electric type, right?
So if we let it feast on electricity,
then it wouldn’t have room for our food, right?
Right.
Let’s get lots of electricity, meow!
And that’s how this
electricity vacuum car was born, meow!
It’s all thanks to me that we’ve been able
to steal so much electricity, meow!
But how come every time we get back
to the hideout, the car’s empty?
It’s an electric car,
so there’s no getting around it, meow.
How come we’re always using up
the electricity we steal on the road home?!
Well, today we just have to feed it
the electricity straight away...
Hey, it looks like it’s really hungry...
Better get the power quick, meow.
Static?!
Whoa, electricity’s amazing!
No!!!
The power... went out?
Is this...?
It filled up in an instant, meow.
What a great feeling!
Now to feed it to Morpeko right a...
Huh? Where’s Morpeko?
Ah! Morpeko!
What’s it doing here?
It ran off!
There you are.
Were you stealing food again?
What’d you do that for?!
We’re out here stealing electricity
to feed you...!
So that’s it!
Team Rocket!
Brat cop boys?!
I understand.
The Pokémon the witness saw
wasn’t a Pikachu, but a Morpeko!
You’re under arrest
for the crime of electricity-theft!
You think we’re gonna go peacefully?!
See ya!
Hey, stop!
We’re off!
This is Junsa. I’m in pursuit of
the electricity thieves’ car.
What?!
Aight, I’ll be right there!
Come on, driving is gonna
waste the electricity!
Can’t you do something about
that patrol car?!
I’ll hit them with lightning, meow!
Just keep some for Morpeko!
And meow! And meow!
Guardie!
Speed Star!
We shook ‘em off, meow.
Serves them right!
Here you are, Morpeko.
Suckle on this to your heart’s content.
We’ll keep it coming.
Leave the food for us, meow.
It’s not interested?
But it’s an Electric type!
Wh-Why? How come?
Well, duh.
Morpeko creates electricity, which makes it hungry,
so it fills back up by eating.
Really?
Anyway, how come you didn’t
tell us that earlier?!
Huh? You never asked...
You’re such a...
We’ve found you!
You made people think
Pikachu was a criminal!
Whatever. We give up.
We don’t need no electricity.
You can have it all back!
Take this, meow.
Pikachu!
Did he just soak up the electricity
and power up?!
All right, Pikachu!
200,000 Volts payback time!
Step on it!
What an awful feeling...
Wh-What the cop...?
A certificate of appreciation,
for Pikachu.
We would like to express
our deepest appreciation...
...in recognition of your
exceptional contributions...
...in the solving of this case.
Thank ya, honest.
Congrats, Pikachu!
Thank you.
Satoshi and Go,
we appreciate your cooperation, too!
Oh, it was a lot of fun!
We really got a taste of
how hard Ms. Junsa’s job is...
Here’s my cop’s intuition!
This Pikachu’s gonna become
an official agent, and my partner!
So? Wanna try yer hand
at the hardest of cases?
I could call you...
Coppa lotta damage!
Pikachu, Satoshi, and Go successfully
managed to solve a case with Junsa.
The peace of Kuchiba City rests on their shoulders...
Well, perhaps.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Lizardon!
Fushigidane!
Of course,
who else could it be but Satoshi.
Shigeru!
By the way, Shigeru,
what was that goal you mentioned?
The Legendary Pokémon, Fire.
Fire?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Rival for Go?!
The Path to Mew!!