Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Kuchiba City
Pokémon Eating Contest!
Once again, proud eaters
have gathered here from all over!
Standing in the way of the new faces
that are brimming with confidence...
...are last year’s champ, Kabigon,
and our regular eating fighters!
And this time we have a special guest,
the globe-trotting legend
of the eating world!
Kaiser Burshamo has
come back to this contest!
Burshamo!
Whoever comes out victorious
will receive a free trip to Isshu, plus...
All-you-can-eat
gourmet Isshu food!
Everyone! Are you ready?!
It seems Satoshi and Go are taking part
in the Pokémon Eating Contest.
The reason behind this can be traced back
to several days earlier.
Everyone!
Here’s your food!
They’re asleep...
Let’s just let them sleep.
Wait, you already finished?!
Hoshii, Hoshii!
Want, want!
You want more?
Does your appetite ever end?
Would you like to
put it to the test?
The Pokémon Eating Contest?
That sounds fun!
All right! I’ll win it for sure!
How naïve.
Kuchiba City’s Eating Contest
is famous for attracting veteran eaters.
And that’s not all.
This time, the eating world’s top monarch,
Kaiser Burshamo will be attending!
That sounds fun.
Huh?
I’ll see just how far I can get
with Hoshigarisu!
Me, too!
Do your best, okay, Kairyu?
I’m counting on you,
Hoshigarisu!
No way.
They’re entering too?!
It doesn’t matter.
Focus on the contest for now.
We’ve been enduring
days and days of fasting with Morpeko,
all to build up to this day, meow!
And because of it, right now,
Morpeko’s appetite and determination
are bigger than ever before!
We just have to let it eat,
and victory will be ours, for sure!
Then we can enjoy
Isshu’s gourmet food, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Pokémon Champion!
The Battle of Big Eaters!!
The first round is
the Everyone’s Favorite Berries Battle!
The top ten contestants who eat the most
berry platters will make it through!
I really get to see
Kaiser Burshamo eat live!
I’m so emotional!
I never knew you were
a competitive eating maniac, Kikuna.
Is it really that interesting?
The best teacher is experience!
You’ll love it too
once you see it, Koharu!
Now then, the first round...
starts now!
Whoa! They all leapt on those berries
in perfect unison!
New Contestant Sazandra
digs in beautifully with its three heads!
Another new contestant, Kirikizan,
is strategically slicing the berries to eat them all at once?!
Whoa!
You can really see
each Pokémon’s unique skills.
Now, as for the regulars
facing them!
Of course, a show of eating
like you’ve come to expect!
Amazing!
And of course,
this Pokémon is on a whole other level!
A marvelous combination of
elegance and gluttony!
That gallant stature...
It truly is the Kaiser!
What will we get to see from its long-awaited
return to the Kuchiba City contest?
Burshamo! Go for it!
What’s this?! Sazandra’s momentum
has come to a halt?!
You can eat more!
Even if it has three heads,
it only has one stomach, meow!
It just filled itself up three times as fast!
Oh my! Kirikizan’s hand slipped and
it sliced straight through the plate and the table!
Unfortunately, it’s disqualified!
They got too excited
and messed up!
Things like this happen every year!
I see...
Now then, how are
the little rookies doing?!
What is it, Koharu?
They look so slow
compared to the larger Pokémon.
It’s like they’re eating
more delicately, or something...
Good job spotting that!
That’s because they’re
avoiding the seeds!
Smaller Pokémon will fill up quickly
if they eat the berries whole.
So even if it’s a hassle,
they have to leave the seeds.
By the rules,
leaving the seeds is allowed!
But you lose precious time
by doing so!
Will the little Pokémon be
dropping out here, as always?!
No, they can’t be fully ruled out...
Morpeko!
That expression...
How deep is its anger?!
It’s relentlessly
gobbling the berries whole!
Here’s your dish!
Is this the birth of a new star?!
Go, go, Morpeko!
Oh, and here’s another little one
with a fierce appetite!
It’s Hoshigarisu!
Go ahead and eat all you want!
Wow!
That’s our Hoshigarisu, all right!
But...
Is it gonna be okay, with that belly?
It’s about time, Hoshigarisu.
Seed Machine Gun into the air!
How well-researched!
It’s splitting the seeds and the fruit
with the lowest possible time loss!
Ah! Good work, Go!
You can do that?!
We’ll use Seed Machine Gun, too!
I never taught it that!
And stop!
Hold it for now!
There’s still more to come, meow!
Hoshigarisu was really strong!
Just according to plan, yeah?
How’d you do?
About that...
Kairyu...
...is a surprisingly light eater.
The results are in!
Proceeding to the next round...
...will be these Pokémon!
All right!
You two really worked hard!
Time to cheer on Go with all of you.
Let’s keep going just like that!
You’re excited just about getting here?
I can tell that you’re an amateur.
Were you talking to me?
Everyone here save
Hoshigarisu and that Morpeko...
...is a title holder from
a large regional contest.
In other words, we’re the pros!
To put it bluntly,
you’ll fade away next round.
What did you say?!
You’ll fade away!
Oh my,
fight you must not!
Eat a nice sweet snack, and relax, yes?
Here you go!
Cookies on the house, meow!
When there’s
another round to come?
There is no problem!
Since everybody here
are the world’s top gluttons!
Enough that they can’t relax
if they’re not eating, meow!
Exactly!
Kuitaran was just dying for
something to chew on!
Same for my Berolinga!
I was just thinking
we could do with something.
I’ll take it with thanks!
You like it?
What? Really?
As I thought.
They’re showing off that
they have room to spare,
to try and put pressure
on their opponents, meow.
But they don’t know that
it’ll work against them.
Wha— Hey! Morpeko, no!
Hoshigarisu!
You just went and ate them?!
Well, the plan went off
without a hitch... somehow.
Those were special cookies
that will swell up in their bellies!
Hey!
Marunomu!
My Berolinga!
Don’t worry. It just overate.
From those cookies earlier?
I knew it!
Huh?
Thank you for waiting!
These are the Pokémon who
will face the second round!
Hmm? Shouldn’t there be more?
Actually, due to an accident,
Yarukimono, Berolinga, Kuitaran, and Marunomu
were forced to withdraw.
What?
What happened?
However! The remaining line-up
is full of veteran eaters!
Don’t take your eyes off them yet!
They really do look strong!
Go’s going to have a hard time
whoever he faces!
A perfect success.
Now, let’s rig a bit more.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Morpeko
Evil
Electric
The second round will be conducted
in paired battles!
The winner of each
will advance to the finals!
Whoever draws the same color of ball
from the lottery will be battling.
What an ironic twist of fate!
Kaiser Burshamo and Champ Kabigon
will be facing off here!
What?!
But it’s only the second round!
Does that mean the two favorites
are facing one another?
That’s not all.
Those two have history between them.
It’s a well-known fact that Burshamo
made its Eating Contest debut here,
but in that contest,
Kabigon fought it all the way to the bitter end!
You really do know a lot.
Driven by its frustration,
Kabigon entered lots of different contests,
training itself for the day
when it could face Burshamo again!
If the two favorites face off...
...then even the winner’s
not getting off lightly.
The contestants
have taken their seats!
The first table is...
Burshamo versus Kabigon!
Burshamo!
The second table is
Morpeko versus Onigohri!
Can we hurry up and get going?
The third table,
Hoshigarisu versus Betobeton!
So you’re my opponent.
I’ll say a requiem for your hopes.
Whoever drew the ball with a symbol
on it in the lottery...
...gets to choose the menu!
Curry.
Berry pot-au-feu!
Momon tart!
Well then, the second round...
starts now!
The first table is a curry battle!
Both sides have begun eating
with amazing momentum!
Burshamo’s so pretty
when it eats, isn’t it?!
Both of these Pokémon are
previous winners of this contest!
They’re downing the dishes
with the dignity of monarchs!
And, the second table is a piping hot
berry pot-au-feu showdown!
Anger that burns hotter
than pot-au-feu!
Morpeko doesn’t mind the heat at all!
How about its opponent, Onigohri?
You thought Ice types
don’t like the heat?
Well, my Onigohri can
freeze anything and eat it up!
Onigohri, Freeze-Dry!
You fell for it.
How will you eat it
if you freeze it inside the pot?!
No!
Oh, no! Onigohri can’t
eat the berries like this!
A regrettable mistake!
By the way, the rules say you have to finish a dish
before requesting the next one!
Eat as much as you want!
Here comes more servings!
The third table is
a Momon tart battle!
Hoshigarisu looks like
it’s enjoying it,
but Betobeton looks like
it’s struggling!
That Betobeton
doesn’t like sweet food, right?
I realized it earlier.
You came over to pick a fight,
but you left the moment the cookies showed up.
Because you didn’t want to ruin Betobeton’s appetite
with food it doesn’t like, right?
Even if that was the case,
you’re still going to lose.
What?
We’re pros.
We’ve trained and trained so that Betobeton’s
able to stomach any food, even if it hates it.
But how about Hoshigarisu?
No matter how much you like a food,
eat it too much and you get sick of it!
What’s this?!
Hoshigarisu’s paws have stopped!
This isn’t good!
Go!
Competitive eating
challenges your endurance, too!
Keep at it!
I expected that, yeah?
Hoshigarisu, the taste changer!
The trainer commanded Hoshigarisu to
pour Matoma berry juice over the tart?!
What?!
Great work, Go!
You reset the sweet taste in its mouth
with the fierce taste of Matoma!
I-I knew you could do it, Go!
Hoshigarisu is
refreshed and recovered!
By the way,
bringing in spices is allowed!
Each table is in the last spurt!
And stop!
First, the center of attention, the first table.
And as expected, he took the win!
Kaiser Burshamo!
He’s even handsome in victory!
The winner at the second table was
the enraged appetite of Morpeko!
We did it!
And the winner of table three was
the eye of the storm here today!
Hoshigarisu!
Natural, yeah?
You did it!
Go made it to the finals?
Yay!
We’ve basically won already, meow!
Now, the Eating Contest is in its final stage!
The last dish is... Kuchiba City’s new delicacy,
bubbly Achamo manju!
Burshamo, go for it!
Don’t give up, Hoshigarisu!
Fight, fight, Morpeko!
Well then, the final... starts now!
Morpeko’s expression
is as incredible as ever!
It’s fueling its appetite
with its swirling hatred,
taking it out on the Achamo manju!
All right, keep it coming!
Go on, go on!
Hoshigarisu is
chasing after Morpeko!
And still with a smile on its face!
It’s happily enjoying
the Achamo manju!
You’re making good pace,
Hoshigarisu!
The ferocious Morpeko...
Hoshigarisu forging its own path...
They’re both piling up plates!
How will the monarch,
Kaiser Burshamo take them down?!
Huh?
What happened?!
It’s not eating...
In fact, it hasn’t taken a single bite!
It’s unbelievable!
Burshamo...
Burshamo evolves from
Achamo, after all...
Oh, Kaiser...
Is it protecting the weak chicks?!
An unexpected departure
for Kaiser Burshamo!
But... Even that kind side...
I love it!
The shock is spreading!
The winner is going to be
one of the two newcomers!
Yay! Looking good!
Now that Burshamo’s out...
Victory lies in our hands, meow!
No!
The future lies in my hands!
No way!
With a smile like it was never scowling in the first place,
Morpeko stopped eating?!
Hey! You’re nearly there!
Keep going!
What happened to that momentum
from earlier?!
Look, there’s still more manju!
Eat some more!
Eat up, meow!
Is Morpeko finished eating?!
Which leaves only Hoshigarisu!
It’s only one plate behind Morpeko!
If it can break past it,
it’ll be the winner!
This is our chance!
Dig in and pull ahead!
That belly...
It looks painful.
Hoshigarisu’s small body...!
Just one more plate!
But that plate will not fit!
Hoshigarisu...
Can’t you eat anymore?
But, Hoshigarisu’s eyes
have not given up!
It’s boldly tackling
the Achamo manju!
Why go so far...?
Because there is food to be eaten!
That’s the only reason!
Go for it!
You can do it! Go! Hoshigarisu!
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
You...
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
It evolved!
Each and every one of my memories
Yokubarisu’s data will be
added to the Index!
Yokubarisu!
Can always be found inside a Ball
Yokubarisu! Greedy Pokémon!
Normal type!
It has strong teeth and can
chew through the toughest of berry shells!
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
What’s this?! A Pokémon has evolved
during the contest!
And that’s not all! It keeps eating with a ferocious momentum,
shooting straight past Morpeko’s record!
So let’s go somewhere! Take me somewhere, anywhere!
And now, Hoshigarisu—
no, Yokubarisu’s victory is decided!
No need to hesitate! Try!
We did it!
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
You won it!
2. And we’re laughing or crying
I get it, I get it, calm down...
On 3, let’s be friends!
So, Koharu?
I never thought I’d get so invested
in an Eating Contest!
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
Right?!
Congrats, Yokubarisu!
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s keep working together!
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Go and Hoshigarisu achieved a marvelous victory
in the Pokémon Eating Contest.
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
With their prize,
they’re setting off for Isshu next!
I choose you!
I can’t cope with this, meow.
After all this,
I need some comfort food!
Why?
Don’t tell me...
It’s already hungry again, meow?
No way!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
My prize for winning
the Pokémon Eating Contest,
the Isshu all-you-can-eat
gourmet food tour, starts now!
Huh? Where’s Aceburn and Lucario?
We’re not going to lose
to stretchy bounce Pokémon like you!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Close Call with the Pretty-Much-Pikachu!