Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon battler.
In the hopes of battling Dande,
the current Supreme Monarch,
Satoshi is participating
in the Championships.
Trainers from all over the world
are taking part.
They battle other trainers
in their class,
and the results of those battles...
...determine their
current ranking in the world.
Satoshi and Kamonegi once met Rinto,
a trainer with an Earlade, and lost to him.
To hone Kamonegi’s skills, Satoshi underwent training
with Gampi of the Kalos Elite Four.
And...
Here. I’m glad it’s safe.
That leek is what’s most
important to you, after all!
A knight is one who fights to protect their precious lord,
and the weak and powerless.
When one truly treasures another, and fights to protect them,
their strength is magnified manyfold.
The leek led Satoshi and Kamonegi
to form a strong bond.
Satoshi is currently ranked 273th,
which places him in the Super Class.
His path to the Monarch Dande
remains a long one.
Satoshi and his Pokémon
continue their battles, even today!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Leek Master!
Adhere to the Path of Chivalry!!
Looking good, Kamonegi!
Keep closing the distance!
Hassam, this is our chance!
Scissor Cross!
Kamonegi! Use Detect!
Crossroad Kill!
It hit!
You did it!
Hassam! You did great!
Oh... Sarunori,
do you want to battle too?
Satoshi, Kamonegi...
You two are really in sync.
We are noble knights, after all!
Next stop: Leek Master!
Is that really how
being a Leek Master works?
Hey, if we say it works, it works!
Satoshi, let’s go to
the Pokémon Center.
Hassam and Kamonegi
are both tired out from the battle.
You’re right.
Return, Kamonegi!
Return, Hassam.
Pikachu?
There’s something in there,
isn’t there, Sarunori?
Madatsubomi! Flower Pokémon!
Grass/Poison type!
It prefers hot and humid
environments!
It moves very quickly
when capturing prey with its vines!
But that Madatsubomi
looks kinda worn out...
That looks really soothing!
That reminds me, back then...
It got better!
That was great, Sarunori!
That means Sarunori’s powers
even work on Pokémon!
Yeah.
What is it, Sarunori?
You’ve already made friends?
Do you want me to...
This is great. Catch it!
Okay! Hold on, Sarunori...
Monster Ball, go!
Great!
Madatsubomi’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught Madatsubomi!
I hope we’ll be good friends,
Madatsubomi.
Thank you for waiting!
Hassam and Kamonegi
should be all better now!
Thank you, Ms. Joy.
Thank you.
All right, come on out,
Kamonegi!
Glad you’re feeling better!
This is an official
battle announcement.
You’re...
Hang in there, Kamonegi!
Oh, yes.
I’ve battled you before.
Yeah! It’s been a while, Rinto!
Huh.
So you’re participating in
the Championships?
But I didn’t get
a notification last time...
I had only just entered at the time,
so I was still in the Normal Class.
So now you’re in the Super Class?!
Yes. I see you are, too.
Has Kamonegi been well?
Better than well!
He’s even had training at Gampi’s place,
one of the Kalos Elite Four!
Oh, so you’ve been to
the Castle of Chivalry?
You’ve heard of it?
We even got Knight Medals!
We also went through
some harsh training there.
It brings back memories,
huh, Earlade?
Rinto! Let’s battle!
Me and Kamonegi
have both powered up!
It won’t go like it did last time!
I should hope so.
I look forward to
seeing your potential.
Yeah! We’re gonna shock you!
The Pokémon World Championships
has approved this Super Class battle!
The match-up is Competitor Rinto
VS Competitor Satoshi.
Thanks, Go.
Huh?
I wouldn’t be having this battle
if you hadn’t suggested going to the Pokémon Center.
Right. Win it for me!
Yeah!
Pikachu,
you’ll be watching us too, right?
This battle will be a 1v1.
Both sides, send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3!
2!
1!
Go!
Go, Earlade!
Aim to be Leek Master!
Battle, start!
I’ll have you demonstrate
how much you’ve improved.
Bring it on!
Consecutive Cut!
Satoshi! Don’t let him control
the pace of the battle!
I know!
Earlade, brush it off!
Crossroad Kill.
Use Detect!
Psycho Cutter.
Satoshi and Kamonegi have improved,
but Rinto and Earlade are still one step ahead!
They changed tactics and
went straight for a counterattack...
Detect, huh?
But since you battle with brute force,
if your leek gets deflected even once,
its weight throws you off balance.
You truly are inadequate.
If you’re gonna keep calling them inadequate,
why don’t you tell them what they’re lacking?!
I’m no Gym Leader.
You can find the answer for yourself.
Well then, this time it’s my turn.
Earlade, Infight!
Counter it! Crossroad Kill!
Detect!
Feint!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Earlade
Fighting
Psychic
His leek...
He knew Feint...
That means he’ll just break through it
if Satoshi uses Detect...
You lost the will to fight?
Without... that leek...
Hold on.
What?
Kamonegi!
You can still use that leek!
Remember our training
with Mr. Gampi!
The Gilgard!
Satoshi...
I see... Gilgard, huh?
Earlade, let’s see
what they can pull off.
Come on! The sword and shield!
Gilgard! King’s Shield!
Gilgard! Sacred Sword!
All right! That’s it!
Aim to be Leek Master!
Can he... battle like that?
That mockery of a knight
could never beat my Earlade.
Psycho Cutter!
Block it, Kamonegi!
Now! Crossroad Kill!
We’ll use Crossroad Kill, too!
So you’re still just
relying on brute force.
Wow! He’s wielding
the sliced leek like a pro!
Looking good, Kamonegi!
Now he can’t move.
But Earlade can’t, either!
On the contrary.
Earlade’s in
the perfect position to attack.
That’s right! Earlade can...
Psycho Cutter.
Satoshi!
He’s just toying with him!
Earlade’s barely even taken any damage!
I wonder what Mr. Gampi would say
if he could see you now.
Are you okay, Kamonegi?
You got my hopes up about your potential...
But I must say, I’m a bit disappointed.
You’re still far too inadequate a foe
for my Earlade.
Will you continue the battle?
Stare...
Yeah! We’re gonna keep going!
Oh, is that a change of attitude I see?
I know how hard
Kamonegi has trained!
I know more than anyone
that he can do better!
Let’s get stronger and stronger,
together!
Me and Kamonegi, we’re both inadequate,
but that’s why we’re gonna get stronger!
I believe in Kamonegi!
You good to go, Kamonegi?
Verified that Kamonegi
wishes to continue battling.
Here we go,
Rinto! Earlade!
Then you leave me no choice...
Earlade. Crossroad Kill!
Detect!
Consecutive Cut!
Infight!
All right!
That connected!
Yes... Finish him with Infight!
What?
Th-That’s...
He evolved!
What’s that...?
Negigaknight! Spot-Billed Duck Pokémon!
Fighting type!
The evolved form of
Galarian Kamonegi!
Only Kamonegi that have survived many battles
can attain this evolution!
Negigaknight!
He responded to your feelings
by evolving.
What a knight!
Surpassing himself
to protect his lord...
He has my respect.
Earlade! Crossroad Kill!
We’ll use Crossroad Kill, too!
You’re still feeling
the damage from before?
Then, Earlade!
Let down your guard!
He took the hit... on purpose?
Good! This is Earlade’s ability.
I get it.
So that’s why he lowered his guard.
The ability Heart of Justice.
Being hit by a Evil-type move,
such as Crossroad Kill,
set off his strong sense of justice,
and raised his attack power!
Here it comes!
Negigaknight!
Let’s get stronger and stronger!
Mr. Dande is waiting for us!
Crossroad Kill!
Earlade is unable to battle!
Negigaknight wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
Whoa, I won!
You did it, Satoshi!
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
184th!
You have shown me your answer.
We clashed with everything we had...
but we couldn’t win.
Perhaps we, too,
are still inadequate.
Thank you very much.
Here’s hoping we’ll both
keep getting better!
Yes!
His evolution into Negigaknight
was so inspiring!
I know, right?
And the way you quipped back at Rinto,
telling him you believe in Kamonegi!
Your words protected Kamonegi!
And in response, Kamonegi evolved!
To protect you, Satoshi!
That true strength of a knight
that Mr. Gampi mentioned...
You really showed it off in that battle!
R-Right...
Are you okay,
Negigaknight?
You see?!
He saved you from yet another pinch!
Now that’s chivalry!
Really?
The ardent bond between Satoshi and Kamonegi
led him to evolve into Negigaknight.
The Pokémon World Championships...
Look forward to Satoshi’s next battle,
as the fierce clashes continue!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
From plumbing to Pokémon-sitting,
there’s zero problems we can’t solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!
A Plusle and a Minun!
They’re really cute.
Wha—?!
Nyarth!
For crying out loud...
Let’s save him, Go.
Plusle... Minun...
I’m going to do my best!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
There’s Zero Problems We Can’t Solve!
The Plusle and Minun Handymen!!