Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
It’s finally here!
What is?
The e-mail from Project Mew!
Really?!
Huh? What’s going on?
Haven’t you heard?
Some people put together a deep-dive search team
for Mew, and they’re recruiting new members.
Go is facing their membership test
after Professor Okido recommended him.
Well? What does the e-mail say?
Are you heading out on a Trial Mission?
“Visit our laboratory
at the base of Mount Tengan in Sinnoh.”
Since when do they have a lab there?
Let’s not sweat it
‘til we’re there.
Yeah!
Wait, you’re coming with me?
You kidding me?
I said I’d cheer you on!
Thanks!
Then, here goes...
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Let's Go! Project Mew!!
Mount Tengan, Sinnoh Region
Following
Project Mew’s instructions,
Satoshi and Go have gone off to
the foot of Sinnoh’s Mount Tengan.
What lies in store for them?
Is that really it?
The map says
this should be the right place...
But that doesn’t really
look like a lab.
Shigeru!
Oh? Who else would it be
but Satoshi, and...
Uh...
Go!
So you’re trying out, too.
I heard the news.
That’s why I’m here!
Well, seems even an inept trainer can try his luck
if he has a recommendation from a professor.
But only what you do
from here on counts.
What are you implying?
I’m saying Project Mew
is not exactly going to be easy.
Well, try your best,
at the very least.
He makes me furious!
That’s Shigeru for ya...
Hello!
Excuse me!
What’s wrong, Manene?
Hi! I had an e-mail
telling me to come here...
Oh, good timing!
Th-This is heavy...
Is something wrong?
There’s a trick to opening this...
Easy... does it...
Hah... So heavy, so bulky.
This is why I hate paper documents...
Is that... Mew?!
Let me see!
Everything in this room
is data on Mew.
Everything?
Yes. But it’s not enough.
For every book here,
I’ve read dozens more,
but the mystery only deepens.
Searching for Mew...
It makes me feel like
I’m losing myself deep in a maze.
But at the same time,
it’s strangely nostalgic.
I never did introduce myself.
I’m Hodaka.
The leader of Project Mew.
Leader?!
Go! Nice to meet you!
Professor Okido told me
about you.
You can handle the rest.
Right.
The woman Shigeru was talking to!
The name’s Asahi.
As you are aware...
Project Mew is an enormous project
aiming to conduct an exhaustive search for Mew.
We will conduct the search
atop Table Mountain, on this island.
Composed of sedimentary rocks
dating back two billion years,
it’s the world’s largest mountain by surface area,
at roughly 40,000 square kilometers,
and it’s over 3,500 meters tall.
Awesome! I wanna go there!
Where is that island?
Is Mew there?
Save your questions for the end.
She’s pretty strict...
Just wait for now.
The project will take place during the one week
where it switches from wet season to dry season.
When the week is over,
the dampness returns to the area,
covering it in a thick fog
and making exploration impossible.
Any questions?
Um... About Mew...
Details about Mew are confidential.
If you have any other questions,
then go ahead.
No questions, then.
Next, about our recruitment.
Prospective members have to clear
the Trial Missions we assign.
That’s what Shigeru was doing!
The missions test your knowledge
as a Pokémon Trainer,
your overall capturing skills,
orders and partnership in battles,
and your teamwork with other trainers,
among other things.
What was that?
Silence, please.
Right!
Upon clearing a Trial Mission,
a token will be sent
to the Challenger’s Smartphone Rotom.
The candidates with the most tokens
when the testing period ends will pass.
This time,
we’re looking for three people.
Together with the two
already selected,
the official active Mew search team
will be made up of five Chasers.
Chasers...
They’ve already chosen people for it...
Are you one of them, Ms. Asahi?
Yes. The two already selected are me
and one other, a man named Tsurugi.
Tsurugi...
Any other questions?
Yeah!
Can I help?
Teamwork with your allies
is an important criterion evaluated in the missions.
It’s fine.
All right!
It should nearly be time.
We’re flying?!
This is the ice field
north of Mount Tengan.
Go. We will have you catch
an Alolan Kyukon in this area.
Kyukon! Alolan Form!
Fox Pokémon! Ice/Fairy type!
Possesses a calm demeanor!
It lives on a secluded snowy mountain
where a deity resides,
so it was revered as the deity’s incarnation
before it was identified as a regional form of Kyukon!
A mountain where a deity resides?
Lanakila Mountain in Alola!
But that means
there won’t be any of them here...
I’ve given you your mission.
It’s up to you to decide
what you’ll do next.
I’ll catch it, no question!
That’s what I like to hear!
Your time limit is six hours.
Make sure you’re back here by then.
Right!
Let’s go.
Yeah!
Everyone, help us out!
Well, I wasn’t expecting it
to be easy to find...
Where’s it hiding?
Oh, they’re back!
Hmm... No luck, then?
Return for now.
Thanks!
That just leaves Hassam...
That’s Hassam’s voice!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
There it is!
Good job, Hassam!
It’s beautiful...
Go! Are you okay?!
Yeah!
But what’s going on...?!
The Index said it had
a calm demeanor...
It’s really angry...
Satoshi!
What’s good against an Ice/Fairy type?!
Steel type!
Okay! Hassam!
Use a Steel-type move!
Metal Claw!
Hassam!
Return, Hassam!
The Kyukon...!
Go! This is crazy!
We’re gonna get blown away...
I have to come up with something!
Go!
Satoshi!
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Sarunori...
Pikachu...
Oh, that’s right... We...
We were caught in the blizzard...
A Manyula!
Did they rescue us?
Excuse me...
Looking at weaklings annoys me.
Huh...?
As soon as the blizzard ends, leave.
I have something important to d—
You’re disqualified.
Were it not for me,
you’d be dead.
Both you and your Pokémon.
Hold on!
What do you mean, “disqualified”?
He’s probably part of Project Mew.
Isn’t that right, Mr. Tsurugi?
You can go ahead
and forget that name.
Hey, Mr. Tsurugi...
Is he really disqualified?
Um...
Can I ask you one question?
Why is an Alolan Kyukon here?
Pokémon Hunters.
They poached it for money,
but their airplane crashed
while carrying it.
It fled up here.
I get it. That’s why it acted like that
when it saw us...
Then, if you catch it...?
I’ll return it to Lanakila Mountain.
So that’s it...
As you promised, leave.
No!
What?
There’s still time
before the deadline.
And Mr. Tsurugi,
you’re going to look for Kyukon, right?
What of it?
I want to get Kyukon
back to its home, too!
Me, too!
How will you find it with no clues?
I thought of something earlier.
If it used to live on Lanakila Mountain,
then it might want to live somewhere
that looks like Lanakila Mountain, yeah?
“Looks like”?
Look, over there!
That looks just like
Lanakila Mountain!
Okay, come on.
No luck...
Look closer.
It was camouflaging itself.
Kyukon!
We want to take you
back to your home!
So let us catch you!
Monster Ball, go!
Let’s go, Aceburn!
Lightning Speed!
That’s Magical Shine!
Aceburn!
Are you okay?
Blaze Kick!
Now it’s using Aurora Veil?
Don’t give up!
Smash through it with Pyro Ball!
Monster Ball, go!
What?!
I didn’t expect to see you here.
What’s that?!
Regice! Iceberg Pokémon!
Ice type!
It cloaks itself with frigid air
of negative 200 degrees Celsius!.
It is said to have slept in a glacier
for thousands of years!
Thousands of years?!
I think I heard something about
its body being formed during an ice age.
Regice is an important Pokémon
for studying the origin of Pokémon as a whole.
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Go! Leave this to me!
Thanks, Satoshi!
Kyukon!
I want to help you!
Please, let me catch you!
Kyukon!
Hold on!
Trust me!
Come back to Alola!
Back to your home,
Lanakila Mountain!
Are you sure?
Here goes.
Kyukon: Alolan Form’s data
will be added to the Index!
Satoshi! Pikachu!
Stand back.
Destroyer Beam?!
Let’s go.
What...?!
I’ve never seen that Pokémon before!
Wulaosu. Single Strike Style.
Martial Arts Pokémon. Fighting/Evil type.
The evolved form of Dakuma.
A strong believer in the one-hit KO.
Its strategy is to leap in close to foes
and land a devastating blow with a hardened fist.
Dark Blow.
Wulaosu. That’s enough.
I’ll come back for you.
Behave yourself until then.
It’s time. We’re heading back.
Right!
I’m warming back up...
I’ve verified the Alolan Kyukon.
You can leave the rest to us.
Right. Please take care of it!
Go, Satoshi.
Thank you for rescuing Kyukon.
It’s nothing...
I was just focused on getting it
back to Lanakila Mountain.
Also, I should tell you this.
What you cleared
was not an official mission.
It was a test to determine
if you were fit to enter Project Mew.
What do you mean?
In other words, only now
has Go been accepted as an official Challenger.
Oh! So that’s what Shigeru meant
when he said it wasn’t gonna be easy!
But Mr. Tsurugi told me...
Quiet.
Are you doing it? Are you not doing it?
Answer me that, and only that.
I will! Please accept me!
That’s great news, Go!
Even I’m getting fired up now!
Yeah!
But I’ve only just made it
to the starting line!
Good enough!
Don’t let Shigeru beat you!
Right!
Congrats, Go.
Th-Thank you!
Tsurugi, I hear Regice appeared.
I’m analyzing the data now.
Diligent as always, I see.
It’s no coincidence that you were the Chaser
with the best score!
Um, Professor Hodaka!
Mr. Tsurugi said that Regice is an important Pokémon
for studying the origin of all Pokémon.
Yes. That is what I believe.
Is that connected with Mew?
Have you ever given it any thought?
What are Pokémon?
Where did they come from?
That’s what I want to solve:
the world’s biggest mystery.
And I believe the key is Mew,
who holds the genes of all Pokémon,
and is thought to be
ancestor to all Pokémon.
That’s why I’m meticulously
studying Mew!
And that’s the ultimate goal
of Project Mew!
Wow!
I really wanna be a member!
Yeah! And I’ll help you!
Okay...
While we head back to the base of Mount Tengan,
shall we look over Regice’s data together?
Yeah!
Go was finally able to become
a Project Mew Challenger.
His next task will be his first
Trial Mission!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Oh, no!
We all got split up!
Okay, Pikachu!
Let’s look for everyone!
Huh? Morpeko?
Nyarth?
Eevee?!
Huh? Where’s Sarunori?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Underground Maze Shuffle Panic?!