Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
A letter for me?
Yeah. It says it’s from
the Isshu Region!
Isshu?!
Thanks, Negigaknight!
Oh, Pikachu!
It’s from Iris.
Who?
She’s a friend from
when I traveled through Isshu.
She’s training to be a Dragon Master.
She says
“Let’s have an official battle!”
Looks like Iris entered the Championships recently,
and she’s in the Super Class!
Ooh! A showdown between
traveling companions!
Yeah!
Isn’t that exciting, Pikachu?!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Dragon Battle!
Satoshi VS Iris!!
Satoshi’s friend Iris
invited him to battle her.
Satoshi and Go immediately
flew to Isshu,
to meet Iris in Soryu City.
Soryu City, Isshu Region
Of course,
Go made the most of his return to Isshu...
Monster Ball, go! Go!
Baope and Hiyape’s data
will be added to the Index!
Okay, now I just need Yanape.
Right. Monster Ball, go!
Oww!
A person?!
Ugh... Who did that?
Oh, sorry!
I just thought you were a Pokémon...
Well, I guess you don’t often
find people napping in trees...
Wait, I overslept!
Thanks for waking me up!
Maybe that was a Pokémon...
Soryu Gym...
I haven’t been here in a while!
Oh, Kibago!
You think it’s Iris’s?
Ahh... Satoshi,
it’s nice to see you.
Mr. Shaga!
Is that Iris’s Kibago?
No, this one is my partner.
Iris is waiting for you inside.
Thanks for letting us
use the Gym today!
Satoshi!
Oh, Go! How’d it go?
Catch anything?
Yeah, it was great!
Though I mistook a girl for a Pokémon...
Huh?
Mr. Shaga, this is my friend Go
and his Sarunori.
Oh, hello.
I am Soryu Gym’s
Gym Leader, Shaga.
Shaga, Gym Leader and
Headmaster of Soryu Academy.
He is also Iris’s mentor.
This is an official
battle announcement.
Oh, here it is!
It would seem she’s ready.
Hey! Iris!
Huh?
Emonga!
I’ve been waiting for this, Satoshi!
Iris?!
What’s with the outfit?
Pretty, right?
Iris is currently
the Isshu Region’s top trainer.
In other words,
she is our reigning Champion.
You’re that...
Oh, you guys!
Hi! Sorry about earlier...
Don’t sweat it!
Iris!
I haven’t seen you in so long!
Ooh, Pikachu!
You’re still so soft!
So? Whaddaya think?
I’m the Champion of Isshu!
Was that a shock?
Yeah! It was!
All right!
My surprise worked perfectly!
So this is Iris...?
Since her journey with Satoshi,
Iris has battled Dragon trainers
from far and wide,
and continued to meet and
learn about Dragon Pokémon.
With belief in her Pokémon,
she has risen to become Champion.
Huh...
I don’t think I’ve reached my goal,
even if I am the Champion.
I’m still not a Dragon Master,
anyway!
I’ve wanted to keep testing myself,
so that’s why I entered the Championships!
A battle with
Isshu’s Champion...
I couldn’t ask for
a better opponent!
I’m getting fired up!
I knew it!
I thought you’d say that.
Soon as someone talks about battling,
you’re raring to go.
You’re such a kid about it.
Hey, you’re a kid too!
Hey, I’m no kid!
I’m the Champion, y’know!
You two...
Weren’t you about to battle?
Ahh! I’m sorry, Sir!
Now, Satoshi!
Try and take on my Dragon Army!
Yeah!
I’ll fight dragons with dragons!
It’s so cute!
Satoshi, you caught a Kairyu?!
It’s so soft and squishy...
It’s going to be a Dragon battle?!
Soryu Gym is a Dragon-type Gym.
It’s a fitting choice for a battle here.
So there you go, Pikachu.
Cheer me on, though, okay?
Huh? What’s going on?
Iris can understand
the feelings of Dragon Pokémon.
Whaa—?!
It’s really kind, isn’t it?
Yeah! And strong!
Wow... She’s right!
Let’s do our best. Both of us.
Ah!
Looks like it’s been
waiting all this time.
The Pokémon World Championships
has approved this Super Class battle!
The match-up is Competitor Satoshi
VS Competitor Iris.
I’m gonna beat you and
make my ranking shoot up!
My ticket to the Hyper Class
is on the line here!
I’m not gonna lose!
This battle will be a 2v2.
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
3!
2!
1!
Go!
Kairyu! I choose you!
Go! Kairyu!
Don’t worry.
He’s nice, even if he doesn’t look it.
You say that, but that stare
is really creepy...
Satoshi! I’ve been super looking forward
to our battle today!
Yeah! Me, too!
If I battle with you,
not only will I get stronger,
my Pokémon will, too!
And we’ll get to
know each other even better!
Let’s give this all we’ve got, Iris!
Okay, Satoshi!
Battle, start!
Let’s go! Dragon Dive!
Kairyu! Destroyer Beam!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Emonga
Flying
Electric
You okay, Kairyu?
They struck immediately...
That Kairyu has been a brawler
since before she caught him.
Working in harmony with Iris
has only honed his battle sense.
Let’s go! Dragon Claw!
Now, that’s more like it!
Thunder Punch!
Hurricane!
You’ve got it!
Keep it up, Kairyu!
Ice Beam!
Blow it away with Hurricane!
Yow!
Whoops...
Don’t worry about it.
Continue the battle.
Kairyu! Dragon Dive!
Counter it! Dragon Claw!
Kairyu!
It really is fast...
Return for now, Kairyu.
That was close...
What do you think?
This is how a Champion battles!
I’m not giving up yet!
Uonoragon! I choose you!
Hey, wait, hold on!
We’re in the middle of a battle!
That’s a Dragon type?!
No way!
Pokémon can’t be that cute!
Apparently it’s a new species
discovered in the Galar Region.
I haven’t seen one before, either.
So you’re Uonoragon?
You’re so charming!
Uonoragon!
Let’s battle!
Kairyu! Dragon Dive!
Jaw Bite!
Whaaat?!
All right!
What’s this?
Whoa...
Thunder Punch!
What’s wrong?!
Use Thunder Punch!
His head’s jammed in its mouth,
so he can’t hear her commands...!
Ice Fang!
No way!
Good work, Uonoragon!
Spit him out!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
Come back, Kairyu!
He really threw off our pace...
But... I’ll hone my mind
and become one with my Pokémon!
Go, my trump card!
This is Ononox!
Ononox! Axe Jaw Pokémon!
Dragon type!
Its resilient tusks can even slice through
thick, sturdy steel columns!
Iris!
That Ononox...
Did your Kibago evolve?!
Yeah! He’s risen to become
my strongest partner!
Is that right...?
He’s really grown!
Now, Ononox! Dragon Pulse!
Water Gun!
Uonoragon...
Psycho Cutter!
Uonoragon is unable to battle!
He’s strong...
Return, Uonoragon!
Thank you.
You gave it all you had.
Kairyu gave us a hint!
“Beware of its mouth!”
I can’t risk getting close
to Uonoragon.
And so I finished it off
from a distance!
Now that’s the Iris I remember!
But the match isn’t finished just yet!
I’m counting on you, Kairyu!
Ononox is still unharmed,
but Kairyu is still damaged from the previous battle.
Satoshi’s in quite the pinch...
Now! Dragon Dance!
Then follow it up with
Dragon Claw!
Ononox! Reversed Scale!
Kairyu!
Satoshi! After rampaging
with Reversed Scale, it’ll be confused!
Now’s the best time
to strike back!
Kairyu...
It’s not confused...
Heheh!
Isn’t my Ononox awesome?
He hit his own head
when attacking, remember?
That shook off the confusion!
That way you can’t take him out
while he’s confused!
That’s possible...?
It’s the fruit of
their hard work together.
Kairyu! We’re not gonna give up!
We can still do this!
That’s right!
We’ll show you how we battle!
Kairyu...
Iris...
Is that the thing from before...?
Kairyu... You should relax more.
Kairyu...
You really love Satoshi, don’t you?
That’s why you
try so hard for him.
You’re really kind.
Back when my Ononox was a Kibago,
he was kind, and a little shy, too.
But as he learned more and more moves,
he found battling more and more fun!
And when he’s having fun,
I’m having fun, too!
So you should
have fun battling, too!
If you do that,
Satoshi’ll have fun, too!
That’s it!
You’ve got it, Kairyu!
Kairyu... Did you talk about
something with Iris?
It’s a secret!
You’re good to go, then?
Let’s go for it! Wide Breaker!
Dragon Claw!
Psycho Cutter!
Kairyu! Use Hurricane on yourself!
On itself?!
He’s come up with something!
All right...!
He used Hurricane as a barrier?
This is how Satoshi battles!
You’re having fun now,
right, Kairyu?!
Go on, get really excited!
Why’s she cheering us on?!
I wanna show Kairyu
how fun battling can be!
Because I want our battle
to heat up even more!
Then I’ll show you
what a heated attack looks like!
Keep building up the Hurricane!
Dragon Pulse!
Swallow it up with Hurricane!
Kairyu’s power can
affect the weather at times.
But to alter it this much...
I’ve got your Dragon Pulse!
What?
Th-That’s...
Incredible.
They took on the energy from the Dragon Pulse,
and used it for a new move!
But that means... No way!
Go! Dragon Meteor Shower!
Reversed Scale!
Ononox is unable to battle!
Kairyu wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
We did it, Kairyu!
That was an amazing battle, Satoshi!
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
Thank you, Ononox.
Let’s keep working hard,
together.
This battle between
Dragon Pokémon...
...was truly complex and impactful.
Sir...
Still... I lost.
Oh! 99th!
I got into the Hyper Class!
Keep up that momentum
and go-go, yeah!
Congratulations, Satoshi.
Iris...
Thanks!
We’ll make it to the Hyper Class soon enough,
so wait for us, okay?
Yeah. Let’s battle again sometime!
Best wishes! It’s a promise!
Emerging victorious from his fierce fight with Iris,
Satoshi has finally risen to a new class.
What sort of fierce rivals await him
in the Hyper Class?
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Go! This is bad!
Look at Flabébé’s flower!
It’ll be okay, Flabébé.
I’ll find you a new flower.
It’s said that Flabébé are drawn to flowers,
Floette tend to flowers,
and Florges devote their lives to
protecting flower gardens.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Flabébé's White Flower
Flabébé’s White Flower