Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the—
Okay, okay, okay, okay!
Good evening
from across the waves!
Um... Wait...
What’s happening?
Don’t you
“What’s happening?” me!
It’s our time to shine!
Speaker shift change!
What...? But, I haven’t—
Move it, move it, move it!
Everyone,
can you hear my voice?
‘Kay then,
let’s do the title call!
C’mere, Kojiro, Nyarth!
Follow my lead!
Ready, and...
“Team Rocket’s
Secret Kingdom Radio”!
...starts now!
Huh? What?
The BGM!
Play the BGM, meow!
Huh? That’s such a pain...
Sure...
All right! Tonight’s the maiden voyage of our
late-night live show, “Team Rocket’s Secret Kingdom Radio”!
I’m the main personality,
Musashi!
And...
Huh?
Oh, my turn.
Um, I am...
This is personality number two,
Kojiro!
And...
The super personality,
Nyarth, meow!
Hold on a sec!
If you’re the super personality,
then I’m, uh...
The super hyper per—
main-per-personality!
What’s a main-per, meow?
I don’t get it, meow...
Also, what’s with me being
personality number two?
Because you’re my assistant,
obviously.
Surely we’re all
main personalities!
That’s what we agreed on
beforehand!
Did we do that?
We did!
Oh, you know
this always happens.
Live radio shows
are where demons dwell!
You never know what’ll happen when you’re on-air,
so you gotta roll with the punches!
That just now made it clear
that the demon here is you, Musashi!
Hey, you two!
Argue about that later.
We gotta explain why we’re doing this show, meow!
Oh, that’s right!
‘Kay! Kojiro, take it away!
R-Right!
This “Team Rocket—”
“Team Rocket’s
Secret Kingdom Radio”...
...is a web radio show aiming to recruit lots of new allies—
a.k.a. Team Rocket agents— around the world!
She took my line again...
She’s a demon, meow...
Anyway! Team Rocket
is a wonderful evil organization!
And as for all its wonders, the main-super-hyper-main-per-per-per-per-per-per...
...sonality, me, and her merry men, will deliver them to you with a bang!
No, we’re gonna blast them
into your listener hearts!
Wait...
How come Musashi
can read the script so effortlessly?
It’s the enormous passion
she’s putting into this radio show, meow.
And so...
“Life is short,
a maiden be Musashi!
“What ever should I do?”
Hey you,
sitting there thinking that...
If you’re hesitating,
just leap in with a big “bang”!
Cause we’re Team Rocket!
And then we’ll...
Get some new agents!
Well, now it’s time for
tonight’s opening number!
“Ichi, Ni, San”!
Take it away!
It’s “One, Two, Three”...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
A New Program!
Team Rocket's Secret Kingdom Radio!!
If I do say so myself...
That was the best live show ever!
Sure, you got to
have it all your way...
After a point,
I couldn’t get a line in, meow.
The ending was basically
a one-woman show.
‘Cause you two
couldn’t keep up the beat!
Beat?
A radio show
needs to flow like one!
I mean, the BGM might trick you into thinking
you’ve got a good talk rhythm going...
...but that’s the lowest of the low
for a radio personality!
A crummy personality!
You’ve gotta summon the waves
from deep in your throat...
...and have those waves
carry your words and feelings to the listeners!
Now, basically, the same idea
can be applied to acting, so...
...for a great actress like me,
it’s as easy as breathing!
A free talk that flows forth
like water, meow...
So, then...
Let’s get to planning
the second episode!
What?!
We’re doing this radio thing again?!
Of course we are.
It was an order from Sakaki!
Okay, Nyarth!
Read out that order!
“Recruit lots of new Team Rocket agents
around the world!” ...is what it says, meow.
That’s why we need radio!
Radio goes out
all around the world!
We can spread waves of evil
far and wide,
dye all of our listeners
in the colors of Team Rocket, and then we’ll...
Get some new agents!
Right?!
Well, when you put it that way,
radio seems like good idea.
Ain’t it?
Hey, Rotom! Tell me how many
sign-up applications we got, meow!
Huh...?
Lemme see...
Zero.
Huh?
And the number of live listeners
you had was... zero.
Also, the number of hits
you received post-airing was also... zero.
Zero?! For all of them?!
Dahhh...
Musashi?
What’s wrong, meow?
Well, isn’t that just perfect!
In that case, we’ll just have to run
a super popular radio show...
...and make every single person
in the whole world join Team Rocket!
All done.
I’m at a good stopping point
with my server maintenance, too.
It’s wound up
getting pretty late.
Hmm?
Huh?
What’s wrong?
Oh, it’s nothing,
I just got a notification.
A notification?
For what?
Listening to the radio
is a hobby of mine.
The radio?
So I’ve set things up to display
notifications for recommended shows.
The radio, huh?
There was a time when I used to
listen to the radio on occasion myself...
Whoa...
The reception was bad, so I would put the radio
on my balcony and pull the antenna all the way out!
You did?
These days, there’s plenty of web radio shows,
so you can listen anytime and anywhere.
They don’t take messages
through postcards and faxes anymore, right?
It’s generally all e-mails.
Now that sounds convenient.
Still, to tune the dial at a certain time,
on a certain day, every week...
That had its own appeal.
It was like you had
a special appointment with the DJ.
Yeah, yeah!
I know what you mean!
That’s exactly why
I like live shows.
It’s like you as the listener and the show
are connected while you’re tuned in,
almost like there’s an invisible bond
being sent out worldwide through the waves!
Now you’ve made me
want to listen to the radio again, too.
Please do!
It’s... done...
Y-Yeah...
We cobbled it together
somehow, meow...
With this,
tonight’s episode two will be perfect!
“Gather With a ‘Wha-Bam,’ Evildoers!
“For Here is a Perfect Evil,
“and Over There Blooms a Lovely Evil!
“Yes!
It’s Team Rocket’s Secret Kingdom Radio...
“Alpha Returns... Z!”
‘Kay, that marks the start of...
“Gather With a ‘Wha-Bam,’ Evildoers! For Here is
a Perfect Evil, and Over There Blooms a Lovely Evil!
“Yes! It’s Team Rocket’s
Secret Kingdom Radio Alpha Returns... Z!”
I’m the super personality,
Musashi!
I’m the extreme personality,
Kojiro!
And I’m the SS-tier personality,
Nyarth, meow!
This is a live web radio show aiming to recruit new agents
to the evil organization Team Rocket!
Tonight, for our second show,
we’ve already made some changes!
You can’t miss a moment
of the show, meow!
So...
“Gather With a ‘Wha-Bam,’ Evildoers!
“For Here is a Perfect Evil,
“and Over There Blooms a Lovely Evil!
“Yes!
It’s Team Rocket’s Secret Kingdom Radio...
“Alpha Returns... Z!”
...starting now!
Cut to commercials, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Sign-up applications, zero...
Tonight, I think we failed because the new
“Let’s! Nasty Plot Shiritori” segment didn’t take off...
And you know
who suggested that segment...
It was Kojiro.
W-Well, whenever we do it,
it always gets us motivated!
So I thought it’d be grea—
Or, actually...
This show name is too long!
How about we do that “...or, ‘whats-it,’ for short!”
thing you see everywhere?
Good suggestion.
I think we need some
original greeting for the show, meow.
Wouldn’t it be nice
if we had some nicknames, too?
Ooh, me!
Go on, Kojiro.
Actually, I made us
some memorabilia!
Memorabilia?!
So what’s that?
Bonk.
Items exclusive to the show, given only to
listeners whose messages we read, meow!
Crown cap-shaped badges!
Wh-What do you think?
Great!
They’re just so radio!
The listeners are gonna
love these, meow!
R-Really?
Th-Then I thought
maybe this would be good, too...
A Premier Ball!
Isn’t that a precious
part of your collection?!
If it’ll make our listeners happy...
Kojiro!
You’re a true personality!
All right! Now I’m motivated!
Time for a fault-finding and
plans-for-the-next-episode meeting!
Let’s do it!
Yeah!
And so,
through meeting after meeting,
the live Team Rocket Radio show
underwent many little changes,
and became popular
in radio fan circles.
“Wha-bam Z!”
Everyone,
let’s “wha-bam” tonight!
Wha-bam, hyah!
Tonight is episode 56!
That’s quite a long-running show...
I’m personality
Princess Number Seven!
This is Mentor Blue Hair!
And I’m Charm Head-no-suke, meow!
This is a live web radio show where the motto is
“to make friends with everyone across the world”!
Tonight!
Just like every night!
We’re starting
tons of new segments!
First up is...
“What’s inside the Pelipper?”,
meow!
And second...
“Morpeko’s ASMR time!”
A-S-M-R?
A-S-M-R, what’s—?
Of course, our popular segment, “Solving your
worries with a ‘wha-bam bam’!” is coming up, too!
And with that, let’s go to
our listeners’ messages segment!
Wha-bam name “Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately,”
thank you for all of your messages!
Thank you kindly!
“My daughter is giving all her attention
to Pokémon, and none to her daddy.
“How can I make her
care about me again?”
Wait, isn’t this a request for advice?
That’s Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately
for you, meow.
Submitting his problems to the listeners’
messages segment... That’s a master at work!
Well, um, but...
Isn’t this, uh...?
Nothing you can do about
someone being interested in Pokémon.
Pokémon like Eevee are really cute,
after all, meow!
That’s right.
If I had an Eevee at my side,
she’d get all my attention!
Daddy just can’t compare to that!
You said it.
It’s only natural.
Uh— No, no, no,
that’s not the point.
What should he do to fix it?!
I’ve got it!
Why don’t you learn about Pokémon too,
for your daughter?
I see!
Then why not go all the way
and become a Pokémon Professor?
Good suggestion.
There you have it,
Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately...
Set your sights on becoming
a Pokémon Professor, for your daughter!
If you do that,
you’re bound to capture your daughter’s attention!
Try your best!
Wow...
Now there’s a regular listener!
This sounds like a fun show!
How many crown cap badges
is that now?
24... No, no, it’s... 25, meow!
No way!
And you know what that means...
Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately
has entered the listener hall of fame!
Amazing! Congratulations!
If you make it to 30 or so,
we might have to call you our script writer.
“Master at work,” “regular,”
“hall of fame”...
And a success story of going from
listener to script writer...
It’s an avalanche of words
that tug at my heart!
For the first time in a while...
...I think I’m gonna get serious!
Next up...
“What’s inside the Pelipper?”
A segment where we try and guess
what’s hidden inside Pelipper’s beak by touch alone!
And our challenger
is Mentor Blue Hair!
I’ll do my best!
All you listeners... Listen to Mentor Blue Hair’s
reactions... and try and guess with him!
I’ll never get used
to having to do this each time...
Excuse me...
This is...
Flu— Fluffy...?
It’s... fluffy.
And...?
Yeah, yeah, hold on...
And...
Ah!
Uh... It’s... moist?
What is this?
Ouch!
The answer was a Morpeko!
Did you get it right too,
listeners, meow?
Then, next up is
“Morpeko’s ASMR time”, meow!
Me! Me! Me! Me!
I looked into it!
ASMR are these comfortable
but addictive great-feeling noises, right?
Mm-hmm,
you’ve got the gist of it, meow.
So then... Ahh!
Now... Morpeko’s going to eat something...
Okay? So can you behave?
...so all the listeners at home,
try and guess what it’s eating by the sound!
Got it, got it!
Okay, here goes...
Here!
N-N-No! What’re you doing?!
Don’t eat those!
Meow! It ate ours, too, meow...
What sounds like that
when you eat it?!
We were going to
enjoy those after this...
A-Anyway, could you tell
what it was eating, listeners?
No way.
There’s no way to know...
It was just this crazy “vrrrrr” sound!
The answer was...
The answer was...?
Pudding à la Mode!
Pudding à la Mode?!
Pulling ourselves back together...
Next up, a mini-mini segment!
“Head-no-suke’s
tongue twisters!”
This tongue twister
was sent to us by...
Wha-bam name
“The Strong, Rugged Rock Man”!
All right!
They read my message!
And my idol, Princess Number Seven,
even said my name...
Your voice is so lovely tonight,
as always...
Now, I’ll say it
three times in a row, meow!
Traversing tunnels with Tornelos,
tak—
One more try, meow!
Traversing tunnels with Tornelos,
taking time to rest with Tornelos!
Success!
Great job!
I’m... so happy, meow...
Now, we’ll announce the listener whose e-mail
wha-bammed its way into our hearts the most!
Wha-bam name “Nervousçoise!”
“I know some children
who have these amazing dreams.
“One who dreams of being
a Pokémon Master,
“and one who dreams of catching every Pokémon
and working his way up to Mew.
“Princess Number Seven,
Mentor Blue Hair, Head-no-suke,
“if you wouldn’t mind,
could you give them a message?”
Hear that?
What enormous dreams, meow...
Yeah!
Mm-hmm.
Oh, but...
The thing about dreams...
The bigger they are, the more worth it
they are, and the more exciting!
That’s right, meow!
I’m really rooting
for their success, meow!
Me, too! I am, too.
If they ever run into trouble,
I hope they’ll rely on Mentor Blue Hair!
There will be sad times and hard times
ahead, too, I’m sure...
But you can count on us,
and Nervousçoise, to be on your side!
You better treasure those dreams!
Thank you so much
for the message!
Mentor Blue Hair’s Premier Ball,
and the show novelty crown cap badge,
will be delivered to you by Pelipper
as soon as the show ends!
That was episode 56
of “Wha-bam Z.”
That’s all for tonight!
Your companions were
Princess Number Seven,
Mentor Blue Hair...
...and Charm Head-no-suke, meow!
Through this and that...
...what a great feeling!
Morning...
Good morning.
Morning!
Good morning!
Morning, Mr. Renji.
You seem more cheerful than usual.
Huh? Really?
Did something good happen?
Yup!
This little...
Huh?
Is that...?
Oh, that’s just a badge.
Just your ordinary everyday badge.
Director Sakuragi!
Let’s wha-bam tonight...
Wha-bam, hyah!
Huh?
Don’t tell me, Renji...
Yes!
That’s right...
Right after you suggested I listen to the radio,
I discovered them!
I found them yesterday!
Is that...?!
It’s a Premier Ball!
Where did you get that?!
Oh, you know...
Are you... Nervousçoise?
I see.
Then it’d only be polite
for a master to reveal himself.
You couldn’t be...?!
Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately?!
Mm-hmm!
Through this and that...
...What a great feeling!
What is all this?
No idea, but...
They’re having fun, so whatever!
“Wha-bam Z!”
Let’s wha-bam tonight...
Wha-bam, hyah!
Hey, hey, listen to this!
The other day...
Musashi’s group completely forgot their initial goal
of recruiting new Team Rocket agents around the world.
Afterwards, Sakaki harshly scolded them,
but they couldn’t forget the fun of hosting a radio show,
and still hosted “Wha-bam Z”
occasionally.
Their super popular radio show
was legendar—
Hey! What are you doing
butting in on us?!
Oh, I...
Were you listening to a thing I said?
No, I, uh...
I wasn’t listening.
That’s no good!
Even if you’re the narrator,
you still have “do”s and “don’t”s, meow!
I’m very sorry!
Hey, you can apologize later.
Here, take this.
Read out our first message.
Huh? You want me to read it?
Very well, then.
The first message...
This message is from wha-bam name
“The Radio Sommelier”...
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Ooh, there’s a trusty pal!
He’s like a big brother
to everyone.
They’re fighting!
Stop it, Hagigishiri!
We have to do something!
Did you think of something?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Help us,
Big Brother Wanpachi!
Help Us,