Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Fossils are enchanting!
The largest-ever Tatetops,
restored from a fossil!
All the good little kids,
come see this enchanting sight!
The largest-ever...
Tatetops...
Awesome!
Let’s check it out, Go!
Yeah, let’s!
To the Museum of Science!
When are we going?
Right now?
What should I do?
Of course!
Hmm?
Your personal research project?
Yeah...
How about researching fossils?
Fossils?
You can join Satoshi and Go.
Huh?
All right!
Let’s go, right now!
See ya later!
H-Hey!
Enjoy the enchanting
mysteries of the ancient!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
A Miraculous Restoration,
The Fossil Pokémon!
Museum of Science, Nibi City, Kanto Region
This is the Museum of Science in Nibi City.
Many people have come here to
observe the Fossil Pokémon Exhibition.
A real live Omunite!
Look, Pikachu! A Kabuto!
Daddy, it’s a Kabutops!
Look, Go, a Kabuto!
Satoshi, it’s a real live Omunite!
Whoa, a real Kabuto!
Whoa, an Omunite!
Man, I wanna catch
all the Fossil Pokémon here!
Wait... So where’s the Tatetops?
Probably over there.
The line for the largest-ever Tatetops exhibition
is closed for the day.
No way!
Closed?!
I wanted to meet...
...the real live Tatetops...
Guess you just have to give up.
But it looks like
they’re doing something over there.
Fossil excavation!
Right now, you can keep one of your
excavated fossils as a souvenir!
If it’s in good condition, there’s a good chance
you can have it restored!
Fossils are enchanting!
You hear that?
Does that mean a chance at
getting a Fossil Pokémon?!
Sounds fun! Let’s do it!
Yeah!
We’re in!
Hey, hang on!
Look here!
I got something!
Hmm... I don’t think
that’s a Pokémon fossil.
I’ve had it!
Who was the genius that said
we could get loads of Fossil Pokémon here?!
You, meow.
It was you.
Me? Well, then, who told me?!
Whatever. I’ll just make
a Pokémon from stone.
Don’t sulk.
Sheesh...
I got some kind of fossil!
The brat boy?!
What kind of fossil?
Some kind of fossil!
Doesn’t look like a Pokémon.
Is that even a fossil?
Fossils are enchanting!
Fossils are records of history dating back
hundreds of thousands, even millions of years!
They are filled with enchantment!
Chief!
We met in Isshu, right?
Enchanting, isn’t it?
No! I am the president
of the Museum of Science!
Please, call me President!
Twinkle!
President...
That’s the fossil of
a Pokémon’s footprint!
It proves that this Pokémon
walked this very ground long ago!
Truly enchanting!
It was a footprint?
So, do you know what this is?
A fang?
Isn’t it a horn?
Some kind of claw?
Correct! This is a Claw Fossil,
from a Pokémon known as Anopth!
From Anopth?
Anopth is believed to have used its extending claws
to catch prey hiding among rocks on the seafloor.
It is truly enchanting!
Cool...
Fossils are records that mark the locations
where long-gone Pokémon once lived.
So they’re like a natural
Pokémon Index?
Exactly!
With a fossil as pristine as this one, it might be possible
to restore it to its old self using the restoration device.
Well? Do you understand
how enchanting fossils are now?
Yeah!
All right! I’m gonna get my own
Fossil Pokémon, for sure!
Me, too!
I guess I’ll try searching, too.
If you find anything,
bring it to the restoration room.
I’ll evaluate it for you.
Got it!
You hear that?
Sure did. Let’s drop
the search for fossils...
...and nab the restored
Fossil Pokémon instead, meow!
Then Sakaki will be delighted!
Looks like there’s
something in here!
Pikachu.
Iron Tail!
Let’s do this, Golugh! Go!
Golugh! Let’s search for fossils!
Huh? What’s up?
What could this be?
The shape looks like a Shellder...
But it might not be...
Could it be
a brand-new discovery?!
Go, what do you think...?
All right...
I’ll get the president
to look at this.
I’m coming with you.
Thanks.
Go, time’s up.
Huh? When did...?
Hey, Go!
Sheesh...
Too bad it wasn’t a new discovery.
Yeah. But I’ve got plenty of material
for my research project.
What’s this?!
This is no fossil.
It is something even more incredible!
This is Amber. Ancient tree resin
that has hardened and turned to stone.
And not just any Amber,
it’s Secret Amber!
Secret Amber?
Indeed. Unlike regular Amber,
it holds the genes of
a Pokémon from its era within.
Genes?
You could call them
the blueprints of life.
We can restore old Pokémon with far more accuracy
from these than we can with fossils!
That’s awesome!
Let’s give it a shot!
Please do.
Leave the enchantment to me!
All right!
That should do it.
Now we just have to
wait until tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow, huh?
Then let’s all spend the night
at the Pokémon Center.
What Fossil Pokémon
do you think we’ll get?
Maybe an Omustar?
Or Kabutops?
Or maybe something
even greater!
I can’t wait for tomorrow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kabutops
Water
Rock
It’s going smoothly.
I’m sure we’ll find a happy,
healthy Pokémon here tomorrow.
Truly enchanting!
Mr. Enchanting finally left.
It’s been so long since we snuck in.
I feel totally stiff
from hiding so long, meow.
He said it’d be done
in the morning, yeah?
That’s quite the wait.
But we just gotta be patient, meow.
I can’t wait
all the way ‘til morning!
So this dial controls it...
Bingo!
Perfect, meow!
Well done!
A simple restoration device
is no problem for the mighty Kojiro...
Isn’t this, like, kinda bad?
Wh-What?
Hey!
What was that sound?
I don’t know.
But that smoke seems to be coming
from the Museum of Science!
President!
It’s you three!
What happened?
The restoration device
was destroyed!
What? Oh, no!
What about my Fossil Pokémon?!
It’s already restored.
But this is strange...
It shouldn’t be ready yet.
Go, there’s something
over there!
Go!
Where are you headed, Go?!
That’s my Pokémon!
I’m coming, too! Pikachu!
Wait!
Over there?
Where are you?
Hey!
Go!
What’s up?
There’s something there.
Stand back, Koharu.
Oh... Okay.
Greetings.
It’s you guys!
If you say “It’s you guys!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
So you were the ones
who destroyed the device?!
We were planning to offer up
some Fossil Pokémon to Sakaki...
But then the machine up and exploded!
What a piece of junk!
But if we just nab Pikachu instead,
there’s no problem!
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket Capsul-et Secret!
I wonder, what’ll I get?
The Poison Needle Pokémon,
Nidorino!
The Rock Pokémon, Gorone!
Koharu, find Go!
I’ll deal with these guys!
Okay!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Nidorino! Venom Shock!
Gorone! Rollout!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Was that...?
Rotom, who’s that Pokémon?
Ptera! Fossil Pokémon!
Rock/Flying type!
A widely accepted theory is that it went extinct
due to a large meteor impact!
In ancient times,
it ruled the skies!
Ruled the skies...
That’s so cool!
Ptera, listen to me!
Rabbifoot, use Double Kick!
Rabbifoot!
Are you okay?! Come back!
In that case...
Golugh, go!
Guard yourself!
We’re gonna stop it from moving!
Luster Cannon!
Another Luster Cannon!
Golugh!
Guard!
Ptera used to rule the skies...?
I can believe it!
But that’s all the more reason
to win and make it my partner!
Go!
Satoshi’s in trouble!
Satoshi?
It was Team Rocket who destroyed the device!
Satoshi is battling them right now!
I’ve got my hands full, too!
Nidorino! Poison Needle!
Fall back, Pikachu!
Don’t let him escape!
Use Tackle!
Pikachu!
Use Electric Net on those trees!
He blocked his own path, meow!
Now slip through the web!
What an awful feeling!
You did it, Pikachu!
How is Golugh?!
It’s fine!
I figured it would use Iron Head.
Golugh, hit it back
with an Arm Hammer!
Luster Cannon!
Go!
Go, don’t!
It’s dangerous!
You were scared, yeah?
You woke up in a world
you didn’t know...
But this era isn’t all bad.
You should take your time
and get used to it, together with me.
All right...
Monster Ball, go!
Ptera’s data will be
added to the Index!
You got it?
Yeah! It’s my new partner!
Ptera, go!
Happy to have you, Ptera!
Whoa, it’s a Ptera!
I see... So that’s how you caught it!
Yeah! I had so much fun!
Me, too!
Same!
Go caught Ptera,
which was restored from the Secret Amber.
Satoshi and Koharu have grown a bit
through their encounter with Fossil Pokémon.
Next time, let’s go to
another new adventure!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Our next adventure
is in the Johto Region!
The stage is Tamba Gym!
It’s our rematch with Ms. Saito!
I got back into the Super Class!
Please battle me!
I accept your challenge.
How will you deal
with that powerful Octolock?
Just wait and see!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi Versus Saito!
Overcome Octolock!!