Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Riolu!
Use a flurry of Vacuum Waves!
Dodge them, Barrierd!
Riolu! Force Palm!
Barrierd, you use Reflector!
Good, Riolu!
Let’s do this, Kamonegi!
Super slow ball!
Not yet!
Draw it in!
All right!
Satoshi! Go!
Director Sakuragi!
I have a present for you two.
A present?
Tickets to an official Pokémon World Championships
Master Class battle!
You mean one of Mr. Dande’s battles?!
Exactly!
All right!
I’ll catch more Galar Pokémon!
Kamonegi, you come, too!
All right! Our destination is Galar...
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
A Heroic Legend!
Dande's Ultimate Battle!!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Shoot Stadium, Galar Region
Welcome to the world’s
greatest Pokémon Battles!
Oh, no! We’re late, and all because
you had seconds for lunch!
You had extra dessert,
remember?!
Satoshi, hurry!
Right!
Everyone’s so hyped up!
I ate a bit too much...
I know.
You wanna see the battle,
too, right?
Oh, right.
The Championships have
over 10,000 participants.
Among them, only the eight highest-ranked
can enter the Master Class!
To show our respect for these eight,
we refer to them as the Masters Eight!
Today is a battle
between these greats!
It’s time for the battlers to enter!
The expert who charged his way into the Master Class
right after joining the Championships...
Current rank: 7th!
He is our very own Galar Region
Dragon Gym Leader, Competitor Kibana!
He looks crazy strong!
So that’s Mr. Dande’s opponent?
And who else would his opponent be?
Born and bred in Galar,
never having experienced a single defeat...
This ultimate trainer continues to extend
his flawless winning streak!
Ranked 1st in
the Pokémon World Championships!
Galar’s very own superstar:
Competitor Dande!
You may use one Pokémon each!
The reason I signed up
for the Championships...
...was to put
your undefeated legend to an end!
I’m honored.
You should enjoy the tense, still air on the battlefield
and the cheering and yelling from the audience, too!
No, this won’t be the kind of flashy match
that’ll get the audiences fired up.
They’ve got a severe battle
in store!
That’s great!
I’ll enjoy this to the fullest.
Both sides,
bring forth your Pokémon!
Go!
Go forth!
Competitor Kibana
sends out Duraludon!
And Competitor Dande sends out
his absolute ace, Lizardon!
I knew he’d go with Lizardon!
I’ve never seen that Pokémon before!
Duraludon! Alloy Pokémon!
Steel/Dragon type!
Its body is made of metal so beautiful
it appears as if it had been expertly crafted and polished!
Let the battle begin!
Now, it’s Champion time!
Bring the storm, my partner,
Duraludon!
Metal Claw!
No way?!
Metal Claw rages forth, displaying a lightness
that defies its heavy appearance!
Lizardon, show them your claws, too!
Dragon Claw!
Dragon Claw?!
He’s changed up his moves
since last time!
Iron Defense!
It stopped it?!
Talk about defense!
Another Metal Claw!
Dig!
Duraludon takes damage!
Brick Break!
Duraludon,
counter with Stone Edge!
Duraludon counters with
a super effective Rock move!
Duraludon!
Your strength does not disappoint.
I’ll wipe that calm smile
off your face!
Let’s finish this, Duraludon!
Steely Resolve!
He unleashes the top-class Steel move,
Steely Resolve?
What kind of move is that?
Steely Resolve is a move that sacrifices the user’s stamina
in exchange for immense destructive force!
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
The two moves clash!
Steely Resolve hits its mark!
Oh, but...
Lizardon stands strong!
I thank you!
You have lit the fire in Lizardon’s soul!
Then let’s make this
a proper show!
Let’s go, Duraludon!
Kyodaimax!
Kyodaimax Duraludon
makes its appearance!
Very good!
I’m not finished with this battle.
And I won’t let anyone finish it for me!
I’ll show you what Lizardon
can really do!
It’s Kyodaimax time!
It’s Kyodaimax Lizardon!
Awesome!
They’re both so cool!
Let the winds blow!
Stream forward, Sandstorm!
Let’s go! Dai Rock!
Dai Knuckle!
Don’t give up!
Roar, my dragon!
Dai Steel!
I’ll show you a true Champion time!
Kyodai Hellfire!
Now, enjoy the climax!
Duraludon is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is Competitor Dande!
So strong!
Yeah... Too strong!
You were great, Lizardon.
We proved that we’re
the strongest once again.
Thank you for your support,
everyone!
Take a nice, long rest.
My dream is...
...to help make the trainers of the Galar Region
as strong as they can be.
I expect great things from
the Dragon Gym you run, too.
I guess me and the Gym guys should sharpen and polish
each other some more, and then I’ll challenge you again.
I will be the one
to end your undefeated legend!
No, it’ll be me!
I’ll beat Mr. Dande and become
the strongest Pokémon Trainer!
Hey... Even you, Pikachu?!
Satoshi...
Of course!
I’m waiting for you!
What’s this? Chairman Rose,
the one who raised Dande, is in the stadium!
He watches with a wide smile!
I see... So that’s Mr. Dande’s...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Duraludon
Dragon
Steel
You think this is a statue of Mr. Dande?
It kinda looks like his supreme pose,
but I’m not sure.
It was something like this, yeah?
No, no, like this!
Like this?
You gotta look more heroic,
like Mr. Dande!
Dande as the hero, huh...?
Oh, don’t mind me.
I was just talking to myself.
Um...
Is this statue of Mr. Dande?
Oh, no! It’s of a legendary hero
famous throughout Galar.
Hero?
Yup.
Long ago... a great black storm
covered the Galar Region.
Giant Pokémon ran rampant...
Giant Pokémon?
You mean Daimax?
But they were defeated by
a single young hero bearing a sword and shield.
The statue here is meant to depict
the young hero of that legend.
Really?
A great black storm...
Was it like a typhoon
or gigantic thunderclouds?
We still don’t know what it was.
Did the events of this legend
actually happen?
Who was this hero,
and where did this sword and shield go?
What sort of link
does it have to Daimax?
Investigating all that stuff
is my homework.
It’s, like, so heavy.
Homework? For school?
No, no!
It’s homework from my grandmother,
who’s a Pokémon Professor.
I’m her assistant...
technically.
Um, I’m Satoshi.
This is my partner, Pikachu.
It’s crazy cute!
I-I’m Go.
This is my partner—
Oh my gosh!
This one’s super-cute, too!
...Rabbifoot...
We’re from Kanto.
We study all kinds of things
about Pokémon as research fellows.
I see!
I’m Sonia.
Nice to meet you!
A black storm...
Giant Pokémon...
And the legend of a hero...
Sounds really cool!
Hey, you two!
Is there a Pokémon Center around?!
It’s right over there.
Th-Thank you!
What happened?
There’s this huge, weird thing
on the bridge just up ahead!
Gah!
Huge, weird thing?
Let’s have a look!
I don’t see anything...
Yeah. Let’s go back.
Sure.
Kamonegi?!
But that thing it’s carrying
is ridiculously huge!
Kamonegi! Spot-Billed Duck Pokémon!
Fighting type!
It carries a leek more than twice as long
and heavy as itself with it at all times!
It’s still a Kamonegi, though...
That’s its Galarian regional form!
The same Pokémon can,
depending on its birthplace and habitat,
exhibit slight differences
in its appearance!
This is called a regional form!
No, leave it to me!
Now! Monster Ball, go!
Guess I’ll battle it, then!
Come out!
All right! A Kamonegi battle between
its Kantonian and Galarian forms!
Crossroad Kill!
It used Crossroad Kill, too?!
Not good...
Kamonegi, guard!
Kamonegi!
In one blow?!
Return!
So you’ve just been forcing
trainers crossing this bridge to battle you?
Fine! I’ll take you on!
Riolu!
You came out on your own?
I see. You wanna fight, huh?
Riolu! Vacuum Wave!
Another Crossroad Kill?!
Riolu, use Force Palm!
Shadow Clones!
When’d it get that?!
It’s the results of our training!
Follow it up with
a Vacuum Wave combo!
Is it planning to fight us
with just Crossroad Kill?!
Use Shadow Clones again!
What?!
Rotom, what’s that?
It’s Brutal Swing!
Riolu!
Looks like it used up
all its strength on that move.
But Riolu looks to
be worn out, too.
No. Riolu’s fine!
I know you can still go on.
Stand up!
Come on, Riolu!
That’s it! You can still stand!
Come on, this is too much!
I believe in you!
Believe...?
Riolu still hasn’t given up.
So I’ll believe in Riolu!
Riolu!
Satoshi, here it comes!
I know.
Time for the results of our training:
Part Two!
Riolu! Reversal!
Awesome! That did it!
No, not yet!
Hang in there, Kamonegi!
Stand up, Kamonegi!
Why are you cheering Kamonegi on?!
It hasn’t given up yet, either!
Now, stand up!
See! I told you so!
Well done, Kamonegi!
Now, let’s finish this!
Right, Riolu?
We’ve restored your Pokémon
to full health.
Yessan, if you would...
You still wanna go on?
You really love battling, huh?
Well in that case,
wanna come with us?
Riolu, Pikachu and the others...
You could get stronger in my team!
You accept?
All right...
Go, Monster Ball!
I got a Galarian Kamonegi!
Come out, Kamonegi!
Satoshi gained a new
companion in the Galar Region.
When will he get to battle
the ultimate trainer, Dande?
Right back to battling, huh?
And will Go,
who couldn’t catch anything today...
It’s not fair for you guys
to get all the cool parts!
...manage to catch
more Pokémon in Galar?
Go, Riolu! Kamonegi!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’ve never seen
that Pokémon before...!
It’s called Messon...?!
It disappeared...!
Where’d it go...?!
Team Rocket...!
We don’t mind giving it back to you...
if you’ll give us Pikachu in exchange...!
Messon...!
We’re gonna save you...!
Next time... on Pocket Monsters...!
Sobbing Messon
Sobbing Messon...!