Satoshi and Go have arrived in Galar
to accomplish a particular task.
At Shoot City Station, they boarded
a Ghost Train carrying Ghost-type Pokémon.
Together with a mysterious boy
wearing a mask,
Satoshi and Go managed to calm down
a rampaging Mikaruge.
Then, they finally arrived
in Lateral Town, in Galar.
Lateral Town, Galar Region
Now, what could
this particular task be?
I can’t wait!
Let’s do our best, Gänger!
You’re both really excited, huh?
Yeah! I mean...
So that’s Kyodaimax Gänger...
It’s really cool! Right?
Director Sakuragi!
How can I make my Gänger Kyodaimax?
Hmm... Good question...
Why don’t you try visiting Onion,
the Gym Leader of Lateral Town’s Ghost Gym?
Onion at the Ghost Gym!
We’re gonna have him
teach us Kyodaimax!
Still, I never knew Lateral Town
had two Gyms in it.
Ms. Saito’s Gym is one of them, and then
there’s the one just around the corner... Huh?
That’s the Ghost Gym?!
This... is the right place...
But I don’t see a door anywhere...
Let’s just try calling him!
Excuse me!
Mr. Onion, are you there?!
We wanna ask you something
about Gänger!
Maybe he’s not here?
Don’t yell my name out...
so loudly...
Huh?
That boy from yesterday...
Oh, so you’re Onion!
Hey—
Wha...?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gänger Goes All In!
The Road to Kyodaimax!!
Oh, you really surprised us!
You didn’t answer at all, Onion!
And we had no idea
how to open the door.
Then, next to this stain
that looked like a face, you...
Satoshi!
Hmm?
It looks like Onion’s
trying to say something.
Oh, sorry! What is it?
What you said...
Huh?
Wanting to ask me about Gänger...
Right! You see...
We want to Kyodaimax!
You... want to, as well?
I see...
Where are you going?
It’s too cramped here, so...
The stadium.
Saito!
Satoshi.
Here for another battle?
No, today I’m here for
Kyodaimax training with Gänger.
We’re having Onion help us!
Is that so?
Give it all you’ve got.
Yeah!
Okay, give it a try...
Okay!
Let’s go, Gänger!
Let’s get huge! Kyodaimax!
Huh? But that’s...
No, that’s not Kyodaimax Gänger...
Go on! Go for it!
Almost there, Gänger!
It looks like it’s trying to force
a Kyodaimax-ish image.
Satoshi.
That was a shock.
That Gänger can only Daimax.
No matter how far you push it,
it can’t Kyodaimax.
But if it drinks Dai Soup,
it can Kyodaimax.
Oh, I think I’ve heard of that!
Here it is!
If a Pokémon drinks Dai Soup
made from Dai Mushrooms, it can Kyodaimax!
Hear that?
Then let’s have you drink
that Dai Soup and Kyodaimax, Gänger!
So... Where can we find
Dai Mushrooms, Onion?
In the woods...
Got it! Come with us!
B-But...
They won’t be easy to get...
Huh?
Why?
Those woods are home to tons
of Ghost-type Pokémon...
They can all be very quirky...
Quirky...
They’ll try to stop you.
It’ll be fine!
Nothing’s gonna stop me from getting ‘em!
A g-graveyard...?
Are there Dai Mushrooms here?
Yeah.
There are Galar Particles
gathered here.
Right in the back.
Those are Dai Mushrooms.
Hey, those quirky Pokémon
you mentioned earlier...
The stones in the graveyard...
There’s Galarian Sunnygo
mixed in with them.
Huh?
Sunnygo! Galarian Form!
Coral Pokémon! Ghost type!
Sudden climate change wiped out
this ancient kind of Sunnygo!
If you mistake it for a stone and kick it,
it will curse you!
So...
You must...
never kick them...
But we don’t even know
which ones are Galarian Sunnygo...
How can we...?
I just had a great idea!
We can float over
to the Dai Mushrooms!
Then we can get ‘em
without kicking any Galarian Sunnygo, right?
Y-Yeah, that looks like it...
might work...
I’m counting on you, Gänger!
Just be careful, Satoshi!
If you happen to fall off...
I’m fine, I’m fine!
Just... a little further...
All right!
All done!
That’s a Galarian Sunnygo.
Sorry about that.
Th-This isn’t good!
I-I-It’s gonna curse you!
Sunnygo: Galarian Form’s data
will be added to the Index!
I just barely saved it...
Glad you got my back, Go!
With your help,
I got the Dai Mushrooms!
Now we can make
our Dai Soup...
Not yet.
Those won’t be enough
to make Dai Soup.
Mushrooms! Hey, mushrooms!
You found some?!
I don’t see any Ghost Pokémon...
Okay! Let’s go, Gänger!
Oh, that’s...
I got ‘em, no sweat!
What’s that...?!
Ohrot! Elder Tree Pokémon!
Ghost/Grass type!
It extends thin roots from the tips of its feet and
ties them into the trees of the forest to control them!
No Pokémon in these woods
hates humans more than Ohrot.
What?!
Satoshi, hurry this way!
It’s after us, too?!
Run for it, you guys!
We’ve gotta get away!
We made it out, somehow...
Now we have two clusters
of Dai Mushrooms.
So, will this be enough?
No...
You’ll need a little more.
Dai Mushrooms!
...with something on them?
It’s using the mushrooms
as a pillow!
Yeah.
This one likes Dai Mushrooms.
Draunch! Caretaker Pokémon!
Dragon/Ghost type!
It can fly at 200 kilometers per hour!
It battles alongside Drameshiya
and dotes on them!
Drameshiya...
Is that this guy?
It’s like it’s still half-asleep!
That’s really cute.
Oh, it woke up.
Without a Drameshiya on its head, it gets so uneasy
that it may try to use another Pokémon as a substitute!
Hey, stop that, Sarunori!
What now?
What indeed...
Sarunori!
It’s trying to shake you off!
Hold on tight!
We’ve gotta do something...
You have to give that one back to it.
Got it.
Draunch!
Your Drameshiya is over here!
Satoshi! Watch out!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Draunch
Ghost
Dragon
Draunch!
Your Drameshiya is over here!
Satoshi! Watch out!
Thanks, Gänger!
You okay, Sarunori?
Now, don’t go falling off again.
Sorry for disturbing your nap.
That tickles!
Hey, Draunch...
That boy wants to have
your mushrooms.
Are you sure?
It says yes.
Really? Thanks!
Now we can make the Dai Soup.
We did it, Gänger!
Yay!
Now it just needs
to stew overnight.
Thank you, Onion.
I didn’t do anything.
This was all you.
Yes, you really
worked hard today.
Are you sure you didn’t hurt yourself
when you stopped that Draunch earlier?
That’s a relief, then.
Hey, Onion...
Can you speak with Pokémon?
That’s right! On the Ghost Train,
you knew what Mikaruge was saying.
Same with the Draunch
and Drameshiya.
Yeah!
You don’t...
...think I’m weird?
No way!
If anything, I’m jealous!
Huh?
I mean, Satoshi, you can work out
what Pokémon are trying to say too, right?
Yeah.
Sometimes when we’re battling together,
our hearts go “clang!” and connect,
and “bang!”, it’s like we start
thinking the same things.
Oh, of course.
Clanging and banging, right...
You’re weird.
Anyway, I never would’ve
made it this far without you!
So now you can leave
watching the pot to me!
It’ll be safe and sound with me!
That’s more like
sleeping soundly...
Satoshi is rather fun.
Yeah. He’s a lot of fun,
and a really nice guy!
You can go to sleep.
I’ll watch the soup.
Okay, got it.
You mustn’t open that.
Don’t worry.
You and Satoshi worked really hard
collecting those Dai Mushrooms.
I know they’ll make for
a great Dai Soup.
I think I finally get why you kept saying
you wanted to get stronger.
You want to stay
by Satoshi’s side, right?
You’ve been through lonely times,
but now everything is looking up.
Now that you’ve met someone who really
cares for you, and works together with you.
Th-That’s enough.
I know you’re happy.
Hey, I get it...
Dai Soup!
Go ahead.
Now go and give it a try.
Let’s go, Gänger!
This is unusual.
I don’t see you helping
someone very often.
Let’s get huge! Kyodaimax!
That’s Kyodaimax Gänger!
We did it!
It worked perfectly, Satoshi!
You really... managed it...
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait! Wait!
Please refrain from running
to catch the train.
Onion?
You came to see us off!
Hey! Uh...
I had so much more I wanted
to talk about, but um, how should I put it...?
Thanks for everything, Onion!
See you again!
See ya!
Yeah. Until next time.
The shy Onion.
With his help,
Gänger managed to Kyodaimax.
We’ve seen the beginning of huge memories,
and a huge friendship.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Roentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Roentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Roentorar
Electric!
Showers
Roentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
For every meeting,
a parting is sure to follow.
Everything that exists
will disappear in the course of time.
And that is what makes
all of the bonds that connect us...
...each so precious,
and each so painful.
Do you remember...
...that place,
where we first met?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Your Name is Françoise