Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
It’s a hot day with
clear skies over Kuchiba City.
On days like these...
Awesome!
It just keeps on shaving!
Electronic shaved ice machines
are amazing!
I’ll have a large portion!
Then I’ll have an extra large!
Is it really that exciting?
Of course it is!
Just look at this powdery, fluffy ice!
Huh? It stopped?
I wonder why.
It worked!
But then it stopped again.
Hey, look at that, Go!
The lights are acting up?
Could it be Gänger playing tricks?
It might just be a blackout.
So this is where you were!
Director Sakuragi!
What’s with the electricity?
Listen up! We detected
strong biological energy!
This is proof that a rare Pokémon
has appeared!
A rare Pokémon?!
Isn’t that...?
A massive thundercloud...
Strong biological energy...
A rare Pokémon...
I got it!
Thunder is coming!
Huh?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
VS Thunder!
A Legendary Raid Battle!!
Thunder! Electric Pokémon!
Electric/Flying type!
A legendary Pokémon that is said to live in thunderclouds!
It freely controls lightning bolts!
Director Sakuragi!
We’re in position!
Thunder hasn’t shown up yet, though.
I see.
But the data indicates a high probability
that it will emerge at the port.
Can you stay there
and keep investigating?
Be careful, though!
Of course!
Awesome! So Thunder’s in there?
I can’t wait to meet it!
If I’m going to catch it, we’ll end up
in an aerial battle, for sure.
So my only choice
is this one... Flygon!
I get it!
But I’ll be the first to battle Thunder!
Wh-What are you saying?!
I’ll battle and catch it!
I will!
No, me!
Me!
Not a chance! It’ll be me!
Huh? The thunderclouds...
What?!
Thunder?! Where’s Thunder?
We didn’t get to see Thunder...
That cloud was so huge,
I was sure Thunder would be in there...
Thunder, you know?
Thunder?
Satoshi. Have you ever heard the question
of whether the Egg or the Pokémon came first?
Simply put, whether Pokémon Eggs
or Pokémon themselves appeared in this world first.
Sure...
Continuing with that line of thought,
the Index mentioned Thunder living in thunderclouds.
Does it really live in thunderclouds,
or do the thunderclouds form around it?
Um, all right.
I get what you’re saying!
Pokémon are still
wrapped up in mystery.
Nobody’s come up with a clear answer.
Koharu!
You’re taking the bus home today?
Yup.
Dad said he’d probably be late
because the blackout caused a lot of trouble.
I see.
Seems the institute is okay
because they have backup power,
but that everything in the refrigerator
has gotten warm.
But this is weird though.
Mom told me the power’s
been running just fine at home.
Huh?!
So the blackout’s only right here?!
Seems like it.
It’s kinda cool, huh?
Like taking a deep breath.
Like, inhale! Then exhale!
What if...?
Good news, you two!
Thunderclouds have started forming
near the port again!
So Thunder might be in them?
That’s right!
Can you go investigate?
Of course!
C’mon, Go!
Go?
We go this way!
But the port’s over there!
I came up with an answer
to the “Egg or Pokémon” question!
...I think.
Well, I mean, probably... Maybe...
It’s just my gut feeling, but...
In any case,
this is the way we should go!
Not “my analysis”,
but “my gut feeling”?
I feel like he’s becoming
more and more like Satoshi.
Where are we?
The Unmanned Power Plant,
which supplies Sakuragi Institute with electricity.
I see.
There’s no thunderclouds,
but you think Thunder is here?
Didn’t I tell you?
I think the Pokémon came first.
Even if there’s no thundercloud,
I reckon Thunder is in here!
Come out, Thunder!
Team Rocket?!
Brat boy?!
What are you doing here?!
That’s our line!
No, ours!
Were you guys responsible
for the blackout?!
What are you talking about?
We’re innocent!
Yeah, meow!
We were just here to scout out the place
as a potential second Team Rocket base, meow!
So you’re doing bad stuff
either way!
You got a problem with that?!
Was that...?!
Thunder!
Thunder?!
The Legendary Pokémon, Thunder?!
F-F-F-For real?!
For real?!
There it is!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Thunder
Flying
Electric
It’s Thunder!
It really was here!
Oh my gosh! Oh my gosh!
It’s a real live Legendary Pokémon!
So cool!
Electricity’s gathering around Thunder!
I knew it!
Thunder was stockpiling energy
from the Power Plant,
so the energy was coming and going,
like breaths of air!
Ah! So that’s what it was!
All right! Then...
Let’s battle, Thunder!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Us, too! Come on, Rabbifoot!
And us!
Yeah!
Capsules, c’mon!
All right! All right!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
I wonder, what’ll I get?
The Drill Pokémon, Saidon!
All right!
Got a real tough-looking one!
The Trap Pokémon... Maggyo?
Well.
Got a real useless-looking one.
Rabbifoot!
Pikachu!
Now it’s gonna attack us, meow!
Oh, dear! A direct hit?!
It’s over just as quickly
as it began?
It’s fine, meow!
Both Saidon and Maggyo are part Ground type,
so they’re immune to Electric moves, meow!
Which makes them the perfect pair
to battle Thunder, right?
Yeah!
Can you believe it?!
We might actually win against
a Legendary Pokémon, meow!
Go, Saidon! Horn Drill!
Maggyo! Water Gun!
H-Huh?
What are you doing?!
You’re going completely
the wrong way!
Use Horn Drill on Thunder,
understa—
That was close!
Well, this is hopeless.
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Pikachu!
We’ll use Lightning Speed, too,
Rabbifoot!
Rabbifoot! Are you okay?!
It’s gonna use Thunder again, meow!
I wanna battle it some more!
I wanna catch it!
This is a golden opportunity,
and yet...
Is there nothing we can do?
What are you gonna do, meow?
I guess for now...
...we have no choice but to...
...join forces!
Raid Battle time!
Yeah!
Rabbifoot!
Lightning Speed!
Saidon! Follow along!
Pikachu! Ride on Maggyo!
Thanks!
That really helped!
Don’t waste time talking! Attack!
Of course!
Saidon! Rock Blast!
Use Double Kick, Rabbifoot!
Now! 100,000 Volts!
Hey! Hold it!
You’re not getting away!
It’s on the roof.
Let’s chase it!
Whoa, there!
We’re done playing nice.
We have but a single goal.
To catch Pikachu, meow!
You keep moving, Go!
But...!
It’s fine! Just hurry!
Chase down Thunder!
All right!
Give it your all!
Byesy-meow!
Of course!
Flygon, go!
Now! Dragon Claw!
Flygon!
So sorry we use Pokémon
that are immune to Electric moves!
You see? Pikachu’s
out of electricity, too!
We might actually win, meow!
As if I’d lose!
Are you okay?
Well, then...
Dragon Breath!
Yeah!
Go!
No good, huh?
How should I fight it?
What an awful feeling!
Go!
Satoshi!
Keep going.
Your battle isn’t over yet,
right, Go?
Of course not!
Flygon! Carry Rabbifoot and fly!
Flygon! Get as close
to Thunder as you can!
All right! Now, Rabbifoot,
use Double Kick!
No good!
It doesn’t have enough reach!
Rabbifoot!
You just wait right there, Thunder!
We’re coming for you!
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
Now Flygon, use Dragon Meteor Shower!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
Rabbifoot?!
Each and every one of my memories
Awesome!
Get it, Rabbifoot!
Now use Double Kick!
Can always be found inside a Ball
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be friends!
That wasn’t Double Kick!
It’s Blaze Kick!
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Rabbifoot!
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
Please, work...
Monster Ball, go!
I choose you!
Could it be...?
You got Thunder?!
It didn’t work?
Thunder is summoning
thunderclouds!
Oh, no!
Pikachu!
Are you okay, Pikachu?!
Pikachu got all energetic...
Satoshi!
Look at that!
What’s this?
Electric-type Pokémon are gathering.
I see! Thunder’s sharing
the lightning with everyone!
“How are you all doing?
Because I’m doing great!”
Something like that.
Oh... Right. I get it?
You really don’t, do you?
I don’t...
But I kinda feel like I do, anyway!
It’s leaving!
But I want to catch it!
Guess I gotta give up for today.
But...
The battle with Thunder
was so much fun!
I know, right?
See ya, Thunder!
Let’s battle again!
Have a look at this data.
There was a storm growing over the sea
to the southwest, early this morning.
It was logged as colliding with
a mysterious biological energy and then vanishing.
You think that “biological energy”
was Thunder?
Most likely.
It probably went to the Power Plant to rest,
being weakened from the storm,
and received electricity there.
So the thunderclouds appearing near Kuchiba City
were caused by Thunder showing up.
Um... Right.
Thunder may be found
inside thunderclouds,
but it can also create them itself!
And Thunder doesn’t just control lightning,
but can gain strength from it as well.
Yeah!
I got some valuable data
thanks to you two!
Thank you!
Go, this is kinda complex, but...
Wh-What?
Does the bath come first,
or the super delicious evening meal?
What do you think?
Well...
Of course the delicious meal
comes first!
I know, right?!
Though they couldn’t get
the Legendary Pokémon, Thunder,
Go and Satoshi did get
an exciting new discovery!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an "N", you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U’u!
’
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori!
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Pokémon really are mysterious!
Yeah! You think you know all about them,
but they can still surprise you!
That’s what makes them so cool!
Wait... Go!
Wh-What’s that?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Half a Numacraw.
And... It looks like
there’s another one, too!
Two-in-One Special!!
Operation: Dub Pikachu!
Half a Numacraw.