Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
And then,
we’ll have the camera here...
Then, with some nice green
from the trees in the back...
Okay then!
Then, Satoshi and Go...
Can you come over here, then?
Sure!
Now then!
I’ll roll the cameras, then.
Then... five seconds...
Three... Two...
Hello to all the viewers at home!
Today, I’m at the Sakuragi Institute
in Kuchiba City!
At this institute, we find a pair of research fellows—
or special lab assistants—who are just ten years old!
Let me introduce you.
These are Satoshi and Go.
Hi!
Nice to meet you.
Hey! Sarunori!
H-Hey! Hey!
S-Stop that!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Depression of Jimeleon
Satoshi and Go are in the middle of
being interviewed at Sakuragi Park.
They’d make a “boink” over there,
then another “boink” over here!
But it was all because someone
had messed with the Digda’s home!
And “vwoosh,” we solved it!
That sounds amazing!
Here you have research fellows Satoshi and Go.
Let’s wish them the best in their future endeavors!
Now, to finish up,
please tell us about your dreams!
My dream’s to make it to the top
in the Pokémon World Championships,
beat the Supreme Champion,
Mr. Dande...
...and then,
become a Pokémon Master!
A Pokémon Master?
My dream is to catch every Pokémon,
and reach Mew!
Every Pokémon?
Come on over, everyone!
Catching Pokémon
helps you understand them.
If I understand every Pokémon,
I can reach Mew,
who holds the genes of every Pokémon!
In any event, I hope you’ll both work hard
to achieve your dreams!
That’s all for today!
See ya!
Then, cut! Okay then!
Thank you!
Jimeleon’s data will be
added to the Index!
Jimeleon?!
Jimeleon? Isn’t that
the evolved form of Messon?
Then does that mean
my Messon evolved?!
Correct!
I wish I could’ve seen it happen!
Let’s go and see it!
Yeah!
Hey! Jimeleon!
Where are you?
Come out, Jimeleon!
What a mess...
Even as a Messon,
it loved to hide...
Then we’ll just have to look all around!
Aceburn might know where it’s hiding!
Aceburn!
Messon evolved into Jimeleon.
Can you help us look?
Jimeleon!
Are you here?
It hasn’t turned up,
even after all this searching...
What if it’s hurt, or...?
Aceburn!
Did you find Jimeleon?!
Right, so it’s that way?
In there?
Hey, Jimeleon!
Come on out if you’re in there!
Is it really there?
Sarunori?
H-Hold on!
I’ll go check, too.
It’s really damp in here.
There’s mud everywhere.
What are these things?
What was that?
Sarunori,
I said hold on!
Jimeleon!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Jimeleon
Water
So this is where you were.
I called and called and you didn’t show.
I was worried you were hurt.
Isn’t it great?
You’ve evolved and now
you’re as big as me!
Wh-What are you doing?
Oh, that’s right.
You can shoot Water Gun from your hands now!
Um, Sarunori!
C’mon. Satoshi and Koharu are waiting, too.
Come on out!
It’s not good for you to stay
in a dark and damp place like this.
I’m trying to help you here.
Just come back out!
Hey! Go!
Are you okay?
Jimeleon...
Aceburn?!
Seems like Jimeleon
doesn’t want to leave.
Jimeleon...
You want to be like that Inteleon, right?
You will be!
I know how great you are!
So let’s train together
and make that dream happen!
Well? How about
coming outside to do that?
Aceburn, don’t force it!
So this is Jimeleon?
Yeah! Isn’t it cool?
Yeah. But also a little bit...
Jimeleon?
Go, over there!
Jimeleon! Wait!
Jimeleon!
What? Jimeleon ran away
from the institute?
Yeah.
We pulled it out of a cave, then it got
this sad look on its face and ran off somewhere.
Is that so?
Kikuna, put Jimeleon’s Index entry
on the main monitor.
Right away.
Jimeleon. Water Lizard Pokémon.
Water type.
It keeps enemies out of its territory
by laying traps everywhere.
Highly intelligent
but also very lazy.
Very lazy?
In some cases, evolving can
completely change a Pokémon’s personality.
That’s right... Back when Hibunny
evolved into Rabbifoot...
And then when Rabbifoot
evolved into Aceburn...
But I— and I bet Aceburn, too—
we only brought Jimeleon out to try to help it...
Go... If my Pokémon weren’t happy,
I’d do anything to cheer them up, or cheer them on.
I think I’d do that, too.
Hmm... Perhaps Jimeleon was secluding itself in its den
and that’s why it didn’t want to leave.
Secluding itself?
But why?
It’s possible it turned more wary,
and wanted a place to relax.
Could also be
preparing for the future.
Caterpie is a simple example.
Caterpie evolve to Trancell
and shut themselves away in hard shells, right?
I think that’s part of the preparations
to evolve into Butterfree and fly off into the sky.
Then does that mean Jimeleon’s in seclusion
to prepare for its next evolution?
We can’t say for sure.
Is this a common Jimeleon trait,
or is it unique to your Jimeleon?
Either way, just as Trancell
have their own appeal,
Jimeleon must have
its own quirks, too.
Finding their unique charms and publicizing them
is our job as researchers.
Here’s what I think...
It’s a living creature.
Wouldn’t you say that fact alone is marvelous?
Go! Where are you going?!
I have to go
look for Jimeleon again!
I’ll go, too!
Me, too!
It’s getting dark outside,
so be careful!
Any luck?
No good, I couldn’t find it.
If it stayed invisible,
it could be really difficult to find...
I get that...
I was hoping Wanpachi’s nose would help.
The scent seemed to just
drop off after a while...
Gah... It’s already dinnertime...
Where could it be?
I’ll try looking this way.
Satoshi, Koharu,
you head back without me.
Huh?
Go!
Thanks for the help!
Why...?
We’ll stay with you.
Trying to act all grown up...
You still haven’t changed.
You might be right...
What is it, Go?
Huh...? Oh.
I was wondering why Jimeleon was ignoring me.
I suppose it might have some reason for secluding itself...
But I wish I could understand
what that was.
So I’ve just been asking myself
“Why? Why?”...
Why?
Why is it?
You can tell me.
Go?
What is it?
Back then, I...
So maybe Jimeleon...
Go!
I’m sorry...
for forcing you out of there.
I remembered something.
When I was younger, I didn’t like playing
with the other kids, so I was always alone...
And then my teacher asked me...
Go... Why don’t you play
with everyone else?
If you won’t tell me,
I can’t know.
You can tell me.
Why is it?
I didn’t even know why myself...
So being asked “Why? Why?” over and over...
It just made me frustrated...
Even if I went home, my parents are usually at work,
and it’s hard to ask my grandma for advice...
So, with nobody to turn to,
I just gazed at the stars.
And then I thought maybe you were
feeling the same way, and came up here...
I’m really glad I found you here!
It means you’re just like me.
I’ve been rethinking things.
If you don’t understand something,
that’s fine.
If you can’t answer right away,
So... Jimeleon,
whatever you want to do, it’s all fine.
Stay in your den as long as you want
without worrying about me...
Then someday, when you do feel like
being around someone...
I... I’d be happy...
if you let me in.
Huh? Why am I...?
Jimeleon...
I’ll be with you in spirit,
even when we’re apart!
Come on. Let’s go.
The Director’ll be waiting.
Yeah.
Any luck?
It’s there. It came back!
That’s great!
Yeah!
Then let’s get going!
I’m starving!
Yeah.
Everyone!
I’ll play with you later, okay?
You too, someday...
Neither too close,
nor too distant.
Perhaps this compromise is another good way
for trainer and Pokémon to connect.
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Eevee!
Do you want to meet Showers?
I’d like to learn more
about Eevee’s evolutions, too!
Why don’t you enter the race?
The Kids Marine Athletics Race
is tomorrow.
Sounds fun!
Yeah, I’ll do it!
We can enter, too!
Challenge! The Pokémon Marine Athletics!!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters: