Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Hey!
We’re back!
Satoshi and Go have returned
from an investigation in the Isshu Region.
Let me introduce you all
to your newest playmate!
This is Dredear!
Be good to her, okay?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Heracross Loss,
Lovey-Dovey Kaiross
Here.
That just leaves...
Huh? Kaiross?
It’s time to eat!
Huh?
Kaiross is acting weird?
Yeah.
She doesn’t seem happy at all.
She keeps sighing, too.
I wonder if something’s
weighing on her...
You know what always cheers me up?
A good battle!
Or, wait...
Didn’t she not like battles?
I know!
If I get Heracross to encourage her,
she might cheer up!
Ooh, Heracross and Dredear
are already good friends!
That looks more like “madly in love”
than “good friends”...
Heracross likes
the sweet scent of flowers...
Which means
he likes Dredear, too...
Could it be...?
That’s why Kaiross is upset!
She thinks Dredear stole
her beloved Heracross!
Wha—?!
Hey, Go!
Kaiross!
Hey, wait!
She does look pretty sad...
What should I do?
I can’t just tell Heracross and Dredear
to not be friends with each other...
What happened?
She’s probably thinking,
“If only I had flowers like Dredear”...
Ah...
Kaiross... You’re a lovely girl,
and you’re really kind.
There has to be something
I can do for her!
Go!
What I’d do is eat with her,
and then train with her!
No, I think we need to be
a bit more considerate...
“Pokémon Flower Arranging Class
looking for students.
“Are you interested in discovering the wonders
of flowers alongside your partner Pokémon?”
That does sound interesting.
Right?
If I go there,
I might even get to meet Leafia.
Can I go?
Yes, go ahead.
Hooray!
Isn’t that great news, Eevee?
That’s it!
Go?!
The wonders of flowers
with Pokémon!
If Kaiross learns all about flowers,
that could help her get along with Heracross!
Ooh!
That could work!
Huh? What’s going on?
Oh, so Kaiross
has a romantic rival.
That’s why I want to cheer her on.
And that’s why you’re going
to a flower arranging class!
Yeah, I don’t see why not.
But it’s being held at Tamamushi Gym.
Isn’t that a Pokémon Gym?
The Gym Leader’s Ms. Erika.
She uses Grass types.
Wait, Satoshi, you know her?!
We went and battled her before,
right, Pikachu?
Wow...
Tamamushi Gym, Kanto Region
So this is Tamamushi Gym...
Something here smells
really nice!
Excuse me! We’re here to participate
in the Pokémon Flower Arranging Class.
Okay. If you could
fill out this form, then.
Pikachu,
do you want in, too?
Welcome to Tamamushi Gym.
I am the Gym Leader here.
My name is Erika.
We’re excited
to learn with you today.
Likewise.
Hmm?
If I’m not mistaken,
are you not...?
I’m Satoshi!
Right, Mr. Satoshi!
You helped rescue the Pokémon
that time the Gym caught fire.
I’m ever so grateful
for your help that day.
It was nothing...
Huh? Is that true?
So, am I to understand you are all here today
for the Pokémon Flower Arranging Class?
And your partners are
Pikachu, Eevee, and Sarunori.
Oh, no.
My partner today will be...
My, a Kaiross!
Oh, dear.
Um... Is the aroma in the air
coming from the flowers?
It smells great!
Here at Tamamushi Gym, we research the aromas that
Pokémon and flowers emit and make perfumes from them.
We extracted that scent
from the leaves of this Leafia.
Leafia. Verdant Pokémon.
Grass type.
Just like a plant,
it uses photosynthesis to produce clean air.
There’s a popular perfume
made from its leaves.
My, my,
what’s this now?
She’s not sure what she wants to evolve into,
so we’re trying to learn as much as we can.
Oh, is that so?
In which case, you must ensure
you set a good example, Leafia.
Pokémon Flower Arranging
is a new form of art,
in which you decorate Pokémon with flowers
to portray becoming one with those very flowers.
First, choose a flower you like
and trim it as needed.
Then decorate
your partner Pokémon with it.
How would you like to decorate
your precious partner?
What sort of arrangement
would your partner like?
Make sure that you
fully understand one another.
That way, the arrangements you make together
don’t merely show off your love of nature and art,
but also deepen the bonds
between you and your partner.
Wow!
It’s so pretty!
What do you think, Kaiross?
You can use flowers like those
to make yourself prettier, too.
I bet you want to try, right?
It’ll be great, Kaiross!
Yeah!
Once Heracross sees how beautiful
you’ve become, even he will...
Yeah!
He’ll love you so much
you’ll become a couple!
“Become a couple”?
Are you trying to use Pokémon Flower Arranging
to make someone fall in love?
Oh... No, uh...
Were my motives impure?!
What a wonderful idea!
Nurturing love between Pokémon...
Please, let me help
however I can!
Wh-What a relief...
Okay then, everyone, pick whatever flowers you like
and decorate your partners however you wish!
Okay!
When we came upon
a Flower Arranging class,
hoping to catch ourselves
plenty of Pokémon...
Finding the brat boys
are at the same place...
What a surprise, meow.
Today will be the day
we catch Pikachu!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Leafia
Grass
What flowers would you like, Eevee?
Are you saying
you want the same flowers as Leafia?
I get it.
Let’s give it a try!
How about this, Pikachu?
Oh, those are nice, too!
This is getting fun!
Let’s add loads more, Pikachu!
This looks like something
Heracross might like!
Yeah!
It looks pretty good on you!
Oh, you like it?
Okay, let’s work with that
as the main flower!
You can help me too,
Sarunori...
Huh?
Hey!
Don’t just go playing around!
Honestly...
What?
I think that’s going
a bit too far...
Ex-moose me, dearie.
Let us in on this Pokémon
Flower Arranging too, dearie.
What she said!
We’d appreciate it!
P-Purr, meow!
Come on over.
Your partners are Sonansu and Nyarth,
is that right?
Sonansu and Nyarth?
Ack!
Purr, meow...
It couldn’t be.
When they let their guard down,
we snatch Pikachu, dearie.
Your wish is my command!
It’s not bad,
but it’s still missing something...
Let’s see...
Buds, huh?
But if they’re not blooming...
So, if I put this flower here...
And then, on your back...
Oh, this is hard...
I’m sorry, Eevee!
Huh?
It didn’t come out
too pretty...
What went wrong?
The moment we get a chance,
we grab it, dearie.
Yeah, I know.
Look at this, Nyarth.
Sorry!
Don’t worry about it, meow.
Huh?
Don’t worry about it, meow-I said!
Don’t worry about it, meow-dearie!
Right...
Pokémon each have their own
nature and characteristics.
Lively Pokémon go well with
bright and bold displays.
Meeker Pokémon are better served by
graceful and calm displays.
Why not try coming up with performances
that make the most of their characteristics?
Make the most
of their characteristics, huh...
Can I use these, too?
Coming up with performances...
Hmm...
That’s it! I’ve got it!
All of you look like you’ve had
plenty of fun with your partners.
Now then,
let’s take a look at the results!
First up is...
Huh?
Excuse me,
where are you going?
Ack!
W-We just thought we’d go
and pick some flowers, dearie!
That’s right. We’re picking flowers,
you simpleton!
I beg your pardon!
Dearie, dearie!
I wonder what
they came here for.
With the brat boy
sticking by his side,
we don’t have any hope of
sneaking out Pikachu...
This is such a pain.
Let’s just grab him by force!
Right.
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
What’re we gonna get?!
The Bloom Sickle Pokémon,
Larantes!
The Nurturing Pokémon,
Hahakomori!
Begin the operation, dearie!
You got that right!
Now then, Koharu, proceed.
Right. Eevee!
My!
You went for an arrangement matching Leafia’s
that also takes advantage of Eevee’s characteristics.
You’ve made Leafia happy, too!
Oh, that’s great!
Wow...
They look identical!
Very well, you’re next, Satoshi.
Yeah!
Pikachu!
What?
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Amazing!
How gorgeous!
A performance only
an Electric-type Pokémon can do!
I thought that’d make the most
of Pikachu’s characteristics!
Pretty good.
But I’ve got the better idea!
Right, then.
Go, please start.
Right!
Kaiross!
That’s so cute!
It is!
It’s not done yet!
For the finishing touch,
go for it, Sarunori!
It’s beautiful!
That’s marvelous!
You must deeply understand
both Kaiross and Sarunori to create this!
If only Heracross
could’ve seen this, too...
Actually, I brought
Heracross with me, too!
Really?!
They’ll be face to face!
I can’t wait!
Even I’m getting excited
to see this.
Come on out, Heracross!
Pikachu!
What’re you doing?!
If you say “What’re you doing?!”
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
Gah, I knew it!
I thought you were strange!
We’ve grabbed Pikachu, meow.
And we’ll be taking
the rest of the Pokémon, too!
Hahakomori! String Shot!
I will not let you
do as you please in my Gym!
Leafia! Leaf Cutter!
Pikachu!
Break out with Iron Tail!
Larantes! Leaf Blade!
Heracross! Chaotic Jabs!
Leafia! Leaf Cutter!
Yeah!
Eevee! Leaf Cutter!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Larantes! Petal Blizzard!
Solar Beam!
Here it comes, Heracross!
Kaiross?!
Good work, Kaiross!
Scissor Cross!
What an awful feeling!
Awesome!
You did it, Kaiross!
Oh, her flowers...
Kaiross...
Looks like Kaiross’s courage made Heracross
fall in love all over again!
Yeah.
I’m happy for you, Kaiross.
They really do
make a lovely couple.
Everyone, thank you for today.
Always remember the love of flowers
and Pokémon in your hearts.
Always!
Thank you!
Oh, and for you, Koharu...
This is Leafia’s perfume.
I’m hoping you and Eevee
will find a good answer someday.
Thank you!
Through trying their hand
at Flower Arranging,
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu
have deepened their bonds with their Pokémon.
Whoa!
What are you doing?!
U-Uh... Maybe it’s a hug?
You’re so strong, Kaiross!
It appears there may still be more trouble
in store for Kaiross’s love...
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Now, for our next adventure!
Let’s go!
What should we be doing
as Team Rocket agents?
Part-time jobs day in and day out
to gather operation funds?
A daily routine of “do mission,
get yelled at, write apology,” meow?
Hey, why don’t we just
quit Team Rocket?
Huh?
Team Rocket’s
not all there is to life!
What?!
It’s finally time to choose!
The cogs of a new fate...
...have begun to turn, meow!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Farewell! The Team Rocket Wanderers!