Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Here we go, Lucario!
Bursting with life!
Mega Evolution!
This is it!
We’re not giving up!
Wood Hammer!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Ahh! Haribogue!
Haribogue is unable to battle.
Lucario wins!
As such, the winner is
Gym Leader Corni!
Corni!
Oh, Satoshi!
Nice fight!
Lucario, that’s the key to
getting stronger!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Lucarionite!
A Great Adventure on Mega Island!!
Shala City, Kalos Region
Satoshi and Go have come to Kalos
to visit Corni, the Gym Leader of Shala Gym.
Corni and Lucario
are as strong as ever!
That was amazingly cool,
Ms. Corni!
Oh, you really thought so...?
What’s with the
“You really thought so”?
Grandpa...
Only lately have you even started
behaving like a proper Gym Leader.
Gah. He’s always so critical...
Go, are you still devoting yourself
to catching Pokémon?
Yes! Thanks for before.
Satoshi, congratulations on
entering the Hyper Class.
Thank you!
We’d better not fall behind either.
Corni, I wanna Mega Evolve
my Lucario!
So I can win my way through the Hyper Class,
and the Master Class after that!
Okay, got it.
I know the two of you can do it.
Right, Lucario?
Here, take this.
A Mega Glove?
So that’s a Key Stone...
Thanks, Corni!
Sure.
Try putting it on.
Okay!
Looks like it could Mega Evolve
any second!
No, no, it certainly couldn’t.
For a Pokémon to Mega Evolve,
the Key Stone held by the trainer,
and the Mega Stone held by the Pokémon need to resonate.
Every Pokémon that Mega Evolves
has its own Mega Stone.
In Lucario’s case,
you’d need a Lucarionite.
Satoshi, Lucario...
You’ll have to search
for that Lucarionite together.
Satoshi receiving the Key Stone just now
has enhanced Lucario’s Guiding Waves.
Oh, it can sense it...
Naturally,
it’s pointing toward Mega Island.
Yes.
Mega Island?
That was quite impressive.
It picked up the location of
the Lucarionite straight away.
This proves that you’ve
already formed a tight bond.
Satoshi and Lucario were drawn to one another
when it was just an egg, after all.
That’s Mega Island.
The island suddenly appeared one day.
We’ve learned that many Mega Stones
can be found there.
And that’s why it’s called Mega Island.
That may explain why wild Pokémon
that can Mega Evolve tend to gather there.
There’s lots of Pokémon there?!
Gyarados!
Now this feels like a real adventure!
Mega Island, Kalos Region
Okay, then...
See you later!
Right.
Take care out there!
Corni, watch after them, will you?
Leave it to me, Grandpa!
We found the Lucarionite already?!
Let’s check it out!
It’s moving!
Stop!
Huh?
A Yamirami?
What?! What’s happening?!
No, no, no, no!
You okay, Lucario?
How do we get back up?
We can have our Pokémon help!
Pikachu, get my Monster Balls!
Pikachu, mine too!
Kairyu and Flygon...
Corni, get on Flygon.
Okay, I’ll give it a try.
Kairyu, can you get us, too?
Oh, a Yukinooh!
So the Yukinooh’s
what made all that ice...
I gotta say though...
Mega Island’s really cool!
Satoshi,
don’t forget why we’re here...
Oh, I know! Right, Lucario?
Lucario, can you sense
where the Mega Stone is?
Oh, a Bohmander!
A Pidgeot?!
Satoshi!
Go! Lucario!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Lucario
Steel
Fighting
Go... Lucario...
Being in the air
can be dangerous...
Kairyu, return.
Thanks, Kairyu.
They went over that way...
I hope Flygon finds them.
Let’s hurry and find them!
Yeah!
Hot, hot, hot, hot...
What even is this place?!
Flygon!
Watch out! Return!
Of course,
Steel types are weak to Fire.
Well, then...
Go, Hiyape!
Rain Prayer!
How’s that, Lucario?
Now we can run
straight out of here!
This is my chance to catch it!
Monster Ball, go!
Bakuda’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught Bakuda!
Aceburn, help us out!
Pyro Ball!
Okay, let’s hurry out of here!
Everybody okay?
Aceburn, Hiyape, thanks!
I’d better call Satoshi.
Huh? I can’t get through...
Lucario?
The Key Stone...
It must be Lucario’s Guiding Waves.
Satoshi, can you sense anything?
Lucario...
It’s Lucario!
Was that Satoshi?
Is Satoshi okay?!
I felt Lucario,
through its Guiding Waves!
Really?!
Your bond’s incredible!
I saw Go and Sarunori
inside its Guiding Waves, too.
They’re all together!
Let’s go, Corni!
To Lucario, right?
Lucario found the Mega Stone!
I could feel it!
What?!
If we head for the Mega Stone, we’ll meet up with Lucario and Go!
The Guiding Waves are incredible...
I get it, Lucario!
I can sense it too!
It’s smooth...
What is this place...?
It’s the Steel Forest.
The Steel Forest?
Lucario!
I could sense your Guiding Waves!
Satoshi, Lucario thinks
something’s here...
The Lucarionite?
So the Lucarionite’s
inside this thing...
We’re gonna get it out!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
The Lucarionite?
Why isn’t it falling?!
Oyoyoyoyo!
Oyoyoyo! Correct!
There’s an astute guess!
The Mega Evolution Sage,
that would be me!
The Mega Evolution Sage?!
What’s that about?!
And he’s floating!
Oyoyoyo, there’s a new face.
If you want this Lucarionite,
then take it from me!
Houdin...
We never agreed to any of this!
Don’t worry, Go.
I’m taking your challenge!
You’ve got it!
Oyoyoyoyo!
The fight for the
Lucarionite starts now!
He’s really throwing me off...
The Mega Evolution Sage,
everyone’s hero, unveils his powers!
Now! Mega Evolve!
Mega... Houdin...
Let’s go, Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Psycho Beam!
Shadow Clones!
Oyoyo... Fire the spoons!
Go for it!
Tri Attack!
The move paralyzed it!
Oyoyo, that was a success.
Tri Attack’s a move that can deal out
a burn, a freeze, or paralysis.
It can still keep going...
Lucario, jump!
Lucario, hang in there!
Jump again!
You can do it!
Oyoyoyoyoyo!
We got the Lucarionite!
All right!
Congratulations!
You did it, Lucario!
That was amazing!
The Mega Evolution Sage,
everyone’s hero, was actually...
A little surprise of mine!
Satoshi and Lucario,
you have a marvelous bond!
Thank you for
guiding them here, Corni.
You always go too far, Grandpa...
Huh?
You knew about this, Corni?
Seriously?!
Oyoyo! Oh, this was fun.
Perhaps I should do it
again sometime.
Satoshi and Lucario’s newfound power,
Mega Evolution...
...is sure to have a great impact on their upcoming
Pokémon World Championships Hyper Class battles.
Let’s get stronger, Lucario!
My next opponent in the
Hyper Class’s been decided!
Ms. Saito?!
A third battle, huh...?
I’ll beat her this time!
Let’s settle the score, Lucario!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
My next Hyper Class opponent
is Saito, once again!
This is your third battle.
And the battlefield is in Galar.
She might even use Kyodaimax!
Yeah.
But we’ve got
Mega Evolution on our side!
Lucario, let’s go!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Rival Showdown!
Satoshi VS Saito!!