Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Wow!
There’s so many vegetables!
Don’t they look tasty?
They’re fresh from the farm,
so they still have leaves and dirt on them.
Huh...
The vegetables came with a letter from Endo,
a student of Sakuragi’s.
He says that he took up farming
two years ago.
Supposedly, Digda and Dugtrio suddenly turned up
in his fields recently, and they’re causing him trouble.
Digda! Mole Pokémon!
Ground type!
It chews on plant roots underground!
It can cause damage to certain delicate vegetable crops!
Dugtrio! Mole Pokémon!
Ground type!
The evolved form of Digda!
These triplets have super effective teamwork!
We can go scope out that!
I really want to catch
Digda and Dugtrio!
I thought you’d say that.
Huh? Koharu?
Good morning!
I decided to have Koharu
help you out this time.
Say hello to Endo for me.
Sure! I’ll thank him for
the vegetables, too.
I’ll see you later, okay?
Go and investigate thoroughly,
and don’t forget to have lots of fun.
Yeah!
It’s huge!
Eevee, look at this.
It’s a really nice view!
Yahoo!
Huh? Hey!
Why are you running?!
Wide, open spaces
just make you want to run!
Yeah!
What?!
Well, whatever.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hands-On Agriculture Studies!
Where is Digda?!
Here it is!
We’re here, we’re here.
Eevee! Are you okay?
It’s a Biriridama!
Biriridama! Ball Pokémon!
Electric type!
Usually found in power plants!
It resembles a Monster Ball!
All right, I’m gonna catch you—
Hold on! Sorry... But that’s my precious partner
who helps me tend to the fields.
Mr. Endo?!
Hi, Koharu.
Thank you for coming all this way.
It’s been such a long time.
You’ve really grown! When I was at Sakuragi’s lab,
you were still only this tall!
And you’re Satoshi
and Go, right?
Nice to meet you,
and welcome to Endo Farm.
Nice to meet you.
A pleasure to meet you.
Okay then,
let’s go put your bags inside.
Before I show you the problem area,
try some of my prized fresh vegetables.
Go on, pick whatever you’d like.
All right!
Huh, so this is how
tomatoes are grown.
You never knew that?!
N-No, I knew it was a thing.
I’d just never seen it before...
Go ahead, take a big bite!
Thanks for the food!
It’s really tasty!
It’s more like a fruit
than a vegetable!
It’s sweet and smells great!
That makes me really happy!
I took up farming
hoping to see smiles like yours.
Both research and farming
give you the satisfaction of helping people out!
Go on, have some more!
Thank you very much!
I’d never get tired of eating these!
This soil is great!
Oh, you can tell?
Well, I look after the
flowers at school.
What I do is I crush molted Gorogna shells
and use them as fertilizer!
Huh?
Ack!
Thanks for the treat!
So, Mr. Endo. Where are the Digda and Dugtrio?
This way. I’ll show you.
This is the largest field
here at Endo Farm.
Currently I’m growing carrots here.
Oh, the Biriridama from earlier!
It’s pulling out weeds!
Yeah. And it’s much better at it than me.
It’s really dependable.
You’re amazing!
Are you okay?
I’m used to this...
Could this be...?
There! Digda!
No way!
Over there, and over here!
There’s so many Digda!
You can see my issue.
For some reason, Digda suddenly started
showing up in my field not too long ago.
Biriridama watches for them,
but can’t keep up with them...
With them running around, the carrots will get ruined.
What’s more, we’re on harvest season...
So being at my wits’ end,
I asked the Professor for help.
For now, we need to do something
about the Digda.
I’ll chase ‘em out with a battle!
And I’ll catch them!
Huh?
Where’d they go?!
They’re hiding under the soil.
See?
So they are...
If you’re going to catch the Digda,
it’s okay to pull up the carrots.
Now’s the perfect time
to harvest them.
All right. Let’s do it!
Yeah!
Aceburn, help us out!
Where’d you go, where’d you go?!
This is kinda fun!
Whoa... I’m covered in mud!
Your clothes are always gonna get dirty in the fields.
Don’t worry about it!
Makes sense...
Yeah, I guess they would!
You’re not getting away!
Here!
Satoshi, it’s heading your way!
All right, it’s here!
Dugtrio!
All right! Monster Ball, go!
Over there!
Huh? Where?
This way!
Where exactly?!
There’s too many of them...
I can’t keep track!
There!
Sorry, Satoshi...
Go, did you just try
to catch Satoshi?
I caught a Satoshi!
Of course I wasn’t!
They left...
Yeah...
We failed...
That was a great help!
Thanks to you,
we’ve harvested a lot of carrots!
How about we leave the rest
for tomorrow?
Sure...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Dugtrio
Ground
I get the feeling that Dugtrio
was kinda like their leader.
Yeah. If I catch it,
maybe the Digda will stop coming.
I thought of something...
What is it?
The Dugtrio and the Digda were really coordinated
in running away, weren’t they?
Compared to them, we were all over the place.
Maybe that’s why we didn’t have any luck.
I get it...
Teamwork, huh?
What if we have someone overseeing everything
and giving us commands?
You’d be perfect
for doing that, Koharu!
Right!
Huh? M-Me?
It’s all up to you, Koharu.
We’re counting on you.
Okay. I’ll give it a try!
All right!
Everything’s ready.
Hey!
Okay!
I see... So you’re going to
give them instructions from here.
Yeah!
I can watch over the whole field, predict where
the Dugtrio and Digda are going, and tell Go and Satoshi.
I set up those flags
thinking some markers would make it easier.
You’ve really
thought this through...
They’re here!
Yeah!
Digda!
It’s headed for the blue flag!
All right.
The blue flag!
Over there! It’s close!
Here!
Leave it to me!
Go!
Digda’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught a Digda!
Good job, Go!
Okay, it worked. That’s great!
There’s still plenty more!
Yeah.
Dugtrio!
The leader’s turned up!
The red flag!
Head for the red flag!
The fastest one is Dugtrio!
Get ahead of it!
Got it!
There it is.
Now!
Go!
Dugtrio’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
I caught Dugtrio!
Great!
Oh, thank you so much,
everyone!
Superb teamwork out there.
Easy!
Now maybe the Digda
will stop coming to the field.
I wonder about that...
They’ve run off for now, but...
What could’ve caused the Dugtrio and Digda
to suddenly turn up in the field?
They used to live on the hill
across from the farm...
But they never came to
the fields before.
Maybe we can figure something out
if we take a look at that hill!
Yeah. Let’s go!
Yeah!
This isn’t good, meow.
Fields feel so nice...
Napping under the sun is the best!
You said you saw the brat boy nearby,
but all you wanna do is nap, meow!
When you see some wide, open place...
You just stop caring about the details...
You all slacking off like that is why we ran out of food,
and I had to resort to growing some, meow!
Hyper Automated Farm Work Machine:
Nyarth Scarecrow #2, you’re up, meow!
I’m giving them lots of water,
but they’re just drooping over, meow.
That means we need...
Music, start, meow!
Listening to music makes plants
grow better, meow!
What’s this noise?!
It’s so loud!
If this was happening,
I’m not surprised the Digda would run away from it!
What’s going on here?!
If you say “What’s going on here?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
So you’ve come, brat boys!
Huh? What was that?
I can’t hear a thing!
Darn it, meow!
Music, stop, meow!
So you drove the Digda
out of their home!
Give it back to them,
right now!
Hah! You’ve got some nerve,
cutting into our relaxation time!
Well, I was getting
sorta bored of the fields...
Stealing suits us more than
sleeping in fields anyway!
We’ll be taking that Pikachu!
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
Clatter clatter!
What’re we gonna get?!
The Mole Pokémon, Mogurew!
The Mouse Pokémon, Sandpan!
Then I’ll use this one!
Dugtrio! Dig!
Mogurew! Drill Liner!
You use Drill Liner, too,
Sandpan!
Ground Stomp!
Huh? What’s going on?
I can’t tell! I can’t tell!
A battle of epic proportions
must be unfolding, meow!
Are you sure?
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
All right, now! Sand Hell!
Wh-Wh-What?
We couldn’t be...
What an awful feeling!
The soil’s really soft.
It’s a great color...
Thanks for the food!
Go on, eat as much as you want!
I made loads of dishes
with the carrots you picked!
This curry’s full of carrots!
The cake looks tasty, too!
I’ll have seconds!
Sure.
Those’re the guys
that were with Dugtrio.
I get it. The Digda will have a hard time
without their leader.
Here.
I’m leaving Dugtrio with you.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I have this one already.
And I learned something
when looking through some information.
If a Dugtrio digs through a field,
it leaves the soil perfectly tilled and ideal for planting crops!
In some regions,
they are used on farms!
So I think it’ll make a good partner
for you, Mr. Endo.
I see... I couldn’t ask for
better help with the fields!
I’ll be growing even tastier vegetables than before,
so would you help me with that?
I’m counting on you!
What?
Koharu?
Wide, open spaces
just make you want to run, right?
Yeah!
You really...?
Wait for us!
The trio of Satoshi, Go and Koharu
went investigating together.
It looks like their display of teamwork
has made them even closer friends.
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Big news!
The Legendary Pokémon
Suikun has appeared!
I absolutely wanna see it!
Let’s go right away!
Huh? Those guys are...
Pokémon Hunters!
Suikun’s really weakened!
In that case... Monster Ball, go!
Suikun’s data will be
added to the Index!
Huh?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
I Caught a Legend?!
Find the Guardian Deity of Water, Suikun!!