This is the Eevee Evolution Laboratory.
Today, Koharu’s Eevee
is having a medical checkup.
Everything is in order.
She’s the picture of health.
That’s a relief.
So, what have you and Eevee
been doing lately?
We went to meet a Nymphia!
I even entered a contest
as a Pokémon Perfomer with her...
...and she performed with Fairy Wind.
Fairy Wind, hmm...?
I’d have loved to see
your performance.
Then we went to meet
the Eevee of a friend in Alola, Suiren.
One more choice.
The Eevee path.
Huh?
Staying an Eevee.
Like Satoshi’s Pikachu.
Satoshi’s Pikachu?
I get it!
So Eevee have nine paths, not just eight!
Suiren taught me something.
Eevee has lots of possibilities!
Yes, yes, you have that right!
And so, you two have met...
Eevee, and... Showers,
Thunders, Booster, Eefee...
Blacky, Leafia, Glacia, Nymphia...
Each of her evolved forms.
Right!
And did she show interest
in any of them?
Of course!
Or well, how do I put it?
She loved all of them...
...and couldn’t seem to choose
between them.
I see...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Koharu and Eevee,
The Possibilities Are Endless!
Sis!
Dinner’s ready!
Dad... Why is it
that Pokémon evolve?
Humans evolve by growing older year after year
and growing up slowly little by little, right?
But Pokémon evolution
is completely different...
Don’t they just wanna
get stronger?
That could be the case.
Some Pokémon might evolve
to become stronger.
The more I think about evolution,
the less sure I am about whether
Eevee wants to evolve or just stay as she is...
Amazing!
Huh?
You really are having
great experiences alongside Eevee!
Don’t tease me.
Oh, sorry.
“Why exactly do Pokémon evolve?”...
That’s something even we Pokémon Professors
consider an age-old question.
Really?
Taken to extremes, you could say there are
as many reasons to evolve as there are Pokémon.
As many as there are Pokémon?!
Each and every human being
is one of a kind.
A unique existence of their own.
It’s the same idea.
Now I’m even less sure...
Oh, I know!
Koharu! Why don’t we
go camping this weekend?
Huh?
Camping! Yay!
I’d love to go! It’s been a while since
we last went out for a relaxing nature walk.
Come on, Big Sis, let’s go!
Sure!
We’re off.
We’ll head there as soon as
soccer club’s over.
No! Wanpachi,
you’re going with me!
Take care of them, Wanpachi.
Okay, we’ll see you later.
See you later!
Koharu? Are you awake?
Are we there?
No...
I wanted to drop by somewhere
on the way.
What a big forest!
Is this the place
you wanted to drop by?
Yeah.
Lots of Pokémon
live in this forest.
Ah, Butterfree!
I bet Go would be really excited
if he saw this forest.
Satoshi, too.
When Go’s done with Project Mew and
Satoshi’s done with the Masters Tournament,
we’ve gotta bring them here!
Ooh, that’s a good idea!
Shh!
It’s so cute!
Nyoromo. Tadpole Pokémon.
Water type.
The spiral on its belly is its internal organs showing through,
and its direction is said to differ by area.
It’s headed towards the pond.
Eevee!
Oh, my...
Where did you come from?
Mr. Enoki!
Sakuragi!
I haven’t seen you in so long.
That’s my Eevee you have there.
Oh, I see, I see. Here.
Oh, Eevee...
It evolved!
Nyorozo. Tadpole Pokémon.
Water type.
Capable of living in or out of water.
Its body surface is always wet and slick.
Staring at the swirl on its belly
causes drowsiness.
Koharu, Mr. Enoki here
is this forest’s caretaker.
He took care of me a lot
when I was young.
When you were young?!
He still helps out
with my research, even now.
Oh, I really don’t do much.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, I’m Koharu.
Sakuragi Koharu, huh...?
That’s a nice name.
You’ve grown this
into a marvelous forest, Mr. Enoki.
Thank you.
It’s taken this long to do it.
Forests can grow?
Yes... This forest was made
by humans planting trees.
Back when your father was a kid,
the trees hadn’t grown this tall...
...and there weren’t
so many different flowers.
Does that mean there
were less Pokémon, too?
Sure does. Not anywhere near
as many as there are now.
Still... When I was young,
this place felt like an enchanted forest.
“Madatsubomi. Flower Pokémon.
Grass/Poison type.
“It prefers hot and
humid environments.
“It is quick at capturing prey
with its vines.”
...it says! It’s amazing!
“Amazing” is right!
And not just the Pokémon!
Me, you, the plants...
They’re all amazing!
I’m amazing too?
Yeah!
Just being alive’s amazing,
all on its own!
It is?!
So you went through
experiences like that, too!
That was back when I was
about as small as Sota is now.
And now,
that boy is a Pokémon Professor.
How time flies...
Oh!
That reminds me, Sakuragi,
one time you rescued a Pippi, right?
Huh? Tell me about that!
I remember that day well.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pippi
Fairy
Stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
Don’t bully it!
“Pippi. Fairy Pokémon.
Fairy type.
“Its behavior and appearance
are adorable.
“It is said that happiness will come to those who
see a gathering of Pippi dancing under a full moon.”
Pippi are supposed to live
deeper in the mountains...
This one might be lost.
Are you lost?
It’ll be okay. There, there...
After that,
I came here every day
so I could visit Pippi.
Here!
Then, once Pippi could walk again,
we walked around
the forest together.
Look! Those are cherry blossoms!
sakura
Aren’t they pretty?
Their name is just like mine.
That’s why I love cherry blossoms!
That’s Pippi’s
Finger Wiggle move.
You never know what move
will come out—
So I was going to say,
be careful...
I-I-I-I’m a-a-a-all r-r-r-right...
The days I spent with Pippi
were so much fun.
But, in the end...
It was time to say goodbye.
Pippi...
Pippi!
That’s Petal Blizzard!
Cherry blossom petals!
Thank you, Pippi!
It must have been saying thanks.
Giving you its thanks.
I wonder how
that Pippi’s doing now...
Who knows...?
But I hope it’s doing well.
It has to be!
I think you’re right.
Now, then...
We should head to the campsite.
Sorry, sorry!
Delicious!
How pretty!
The moon’s full and round.
Eevee?
Wanpachi?
What could it be?
Shh!
I can hear it...
Hear what?
We might be incredibly
lucky tonight!
Those voices...
Pippi?
Yeah.
Tonight’s a full moon,
so I thought there was a chance...
Sometimes, Pippi gather and dance
under the full moon,
holding an evolution ritual.
Using Moon Stones!
There’s an old legend that says
happiness comes to those who see Pippi dance.
This is a very important
ritual for them.
Let’s watch,
but no disturbing them!
Come along, now.
There’s a Pixie, too...
Huh?
Oh, no!
Golbat!
In the middle of their ritual...
How could they?!
They’re coming back!
Eevee!
Eevee...
Got it.
Eevee, use Psychokinesis!
Look! The Pippi!
Thank you for showing us the ritual!
Huh?! R-Right...
Dad! Could that Pixie have been...?
Yeah!
Can’t sleep?
No...
Sorry, sorry.
Did I wake you up?
Those evolving Pippi
were so beautiful.
Beautiful, mysterious,
and warm, too...
I... think I understand it a bit now.
What you said about there being
as many kinds of evolution as there are Pokémon,
and each and every one
being unique.
You do?
Were you happy
to see that Pippi again?
Happy doesn’t begin to cover it!
Experiencing a miracle like that,
it really makes me want to...
...make a world where people and Pokémon
can cuddle up close and live happily together, forever!
Which is why I have to
keep up my research!
It reaffirms that conviction of mine.
Huh?
There’s something cool
about you today, Dad!
R-Really?
You’re nothing like
your usual self.
I-I see...
Oh, well...
As long as I’m cool for today...
Dad!
Huh?
I want to learn more about
Pokémon evolution!
Not just because of Eevee...
Though that’s part of it...
Right now,
I just want to learn a lot more about it!
Then, you can just start by walking.
Together with Eevee.
Of course, there may still be
many paths for you to choose from.
If you reach a crossroad,
just listen to your own feelings.
Listen to them
and choose your next path.
After all, your possibilities are...
Plenty?
Plenty doesn’t cut it!
They’re endless!
Our possibilities are... endless!
Eevee...
Let’s always be there for each other!
Today, and its events, have etched themselves
deep inside Koharu’s heart.
With their steps ever so slightly
firmer than before,
Koharu and Eevee will keep moving
ever forward.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Next Time :  "The Climax Begins!   Satoshi's Masters Tournament!!"
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Breaking news!
Pokémon World Championships News!
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
The Masters Tournament,
the fest to crown the world’s strongest, has begun!
Cameras dive behind the scenes
of these fierce fights!
Greeting someone new is always fresh
Catch the secrets behind the competitors’ might
and find out what to keep your eyes on, only on our show!
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
Will we find out the secret of how dark horse
Competitor Satoshi sped through the ranks?!
2. And we’re laughing or crying
Don’t miss the next episode!
On 3, let’s be...