Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Galar Region
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Commander Pikachu!
Head Forth, Tairetsu!!
The Pokémon in Sakuragi Park
are as lively as ever.
Everybody! Chow time!
Okay, I get the message!
Here, Sarunori.
Oh, Raichu, you’re helping out?
Easy does it, Sarunori.
Wait your turn.
Lined up like that,
they almost look like a Tairetsu.
Tairetsu?
Tairetsu are Pokémon
that always work together in groups of six.
Huh...
So it’s like a Tamatama?
You got it.
The six have perfect teamwork,
so they act like one Pokémon!
What?! I wanna see that!
You’ll have to go
to the Galar Region, then.
The Galar Region...!
We’ve gotta go, yeah?
You bet!
They should be around here...
Let’s see...
A Monster Ball?
What’s it doing here?
What’s wrong?
Nothing...
I thought it was a Monster Ball,
but it’s a Pokémon...
Is that a Maggyo?!
Maggyo! Galarian Form! Trap Pokémon!
Ground/Steel type!
It lures prey in with its conspicuous lips
as it lies in wait in the mud!
It clamps down on them
with its jagged steel fins!
Monster Ball, go!
Maggyo: Galarian Form’s data
will be added to the Index!
I caught a Maggyo!
Let’s keep going!
Tairetsu must be around here too!
Let’s find it!
Yeah!
Okay, mix au lait flavor?
Hold on there just one minute.
Oh, there it is!
Tairetsu! Formation Pokémon!
Fighting type!
One is the captain,
and the other five are the troopers!
The captain’s orders are absolute!
So the one at the front
is the captain...
He was right...
They’re in perfect sync!
They’re battling over there!
Tairetsu’s strong!
Amazing teamwork...
What is it, Go?
Is it just me, or is there something off
about that Tairetsu?
Huh?
You’re right.
They’re not moving as one.
Maybe the team
hasn’t been together for long...
Sarunori!
Don’t do that, Sarunori!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Satoshi! You look after the rest!
Got it!
Oh, there!
Sorry about that.
That leaves...
Okay, just wait there!
Stop!
Barely caught it.
What’s that?
Oh, sorry...
Satoshi and Pikachu
hit you too hard...
You weren’t used to
battling yet, huh?
The others must be worried,
so let’s head back!
What’s wrong?
Are you feeling depressed
because you couldn’t fight properly?
Well, that happens,
doesn’t it?
You’ve only just
become a team, right?
You just have to practice, yeah?
One, two, three, four, five...
Okay, they’re all here.
Settle down.
Go’s looking for your captain.
What’s going on now?!
Stop!
Just hold on, Pikachu.
Now, break it up...
I said break it up...
Hey!
Come on...!
What am I supposed
to do with you?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Koorippo
Ice
Hey, let’s head back.
It’s the six of you together
that make a Tairetsu, right?
So basically,
you need to be clearer with your orders.
I know!
Aceburn, Raichu,
Baope, Hiyape, come on out!
And can you
help us out too, Sarunori?
Show it how you
lead a team, Aceburn.
Huh...?
That wasn’t supposed to happen...
They can get along,
and work together, really...
Better to just
dive right in and try it.
You ready?
We’ll practice giving orders!
Don’t worry. You can do it!
It just comes down to practice.
Just be confident
and give them your orders.
Trust that everyone
will follow you!
Just give it a go!
Okay, that’s it!
You’re doing great!
Seeing them like this,
it’s like Pikachu’s become their captain.
Sorry, sorry...
Go’s been a while...
Yeah. You’ve got it!
Be confident,
and trust that they’ll follow you!
Now you just need to try it
with the troopers!
Satoshi!
Go!
Did you find the captain?
Huh?
What’re they doing?
I had them help
with a little training.
Huh? Pikachu?
These guys won’t
leave Pikachu alone...
With the captain missing,
I guess they panicked and
stuck to the nearest Pokémon, Pikachu.
Go on, captain!
Whoa! They’re doing it!
You could say that.
You don’t have to
stick to anyone.
What do ya know?
They’re better than before.
Right? They’re nearly there.
What?!
What Pokémon’s this?
Koorippo! Penguin Pokémon!
Ice type!
It drifted in on the flow of ocean waters
from a frigid place!
It keeps its head iced constantly
to keep it cold!
I wonder if it’s lost.
Looks like they’re gonna battle!
Perfect!
Experience is the best teacher!
Go for it!
All right!
You’ve got it!
Whoa, they’re in perfect sync!
They’re fortifying their defenses with Protect!
That’s a great decision!
The ice...!
Ooh... So that’s what its face
looked like inside that.
It ran off.
Whoa, you really were acting
like one Pokémon!
And that is a true Tairetsu!
Great work!
Yeah. Keep working together
as a team now, okay?
Okay, we’ve got our data
on Tairetsu.
Let’s head back, then.
What’re they doing?
Huh?
I think they’re saying
they wanna come with you.
Really?
Okay!
Monster Ball, go!
Tairetsu’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught a Tairetsu!
Thanks for all the help,
all of you!
Galar’s really a fun place!
I get stoked just thinking about
all the Pokémon here I haven’t seen yet!
Let’s come back here
for more research!
Go has caught new Pokémon
in the Galar Region.
But... What happened
to that Koorippo?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, for our next adventure!
Go!
People are suffering
from nightmares in Sinnoh?!
Let’s check it out, Go!
What?!
Our family vacation’s canceled?!
Then... We should go on our own.
But I’m a bit worried...
It’ll be fine, it’ll be fine!
Who are you?
Let’s go together!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Darkrai: A Midsummer Night's Dream
Darkrai: A Midsummer Night’s Dream