Lugia brought Satoshi and Go together.
They became research fellows
at Kuchiba City’s new Sakuragi Institute,
where they solved the mystery
of the Fushigisou march.
They once again found themselves thrilled
by the wonders of Pokémon.
And today, they greet
another new morning at the institute.
Look at this, Go!
It’s a huge discovery!
A huge discovery?
You can brush your teeth
really fast if you do this!
Not bad, Pikachu!
But I can do it faster!
You’ll make yourselves
dizzy doing that.
I’ll be fi—
Spinning... Spinning...
Everything’s spinning...
Thanks.
Morning, Barrierd...
So dizzy...
Let’s go, Satoshi!
Go?
Hold on, Go!
What about my breakfa—?
Director Sakuragi!
Good morning, everyone.
Hey! This data!
It says there’s a phenomenon
where Pokémon grow gigantic!
Huh?! What?!
That sounds cool!
Now, now, calm down.
That phenomenon has been observed
in the Galar Region.
The Galar Region?
Director Sakuragi!
I wanna go there!
Me too!
Very well...
It’s a great opportunity!
You can see Pokémon gigantification
with your very own eyes.
Etch the experience
into your minds and bodies.
All right!
Just you wait, Galar Region!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Let's Go to the Galar Region!
A Meeting With Hibunny!!
There it is!
The Galar Region!
Where? Where?
Shoot City, Galar Region
Hmm...
From here, we should...
Go! Which way now?
We need to change
to the Wild Area train.
The ticket counter is...
that way!
All right!
I said it’s that way!
What?!
The next train
leaves in three hours?
Um... Are there any
other ways to get there?
There is a bus,
but the next one’s in six hours.
Seriously...?
Well, nothing we can do.
So how about
we find something to eat?
I’m in!
Let’s see, what’s nearby...?
This way!
I smell something good.
You really do have sharp instincts.
Wh-Wh-What are these
nice-smelling little thingies?!
They’re the Galar Region’s
famous scones—
Hey! Gimme some of these
nice-smelling little thingies!
Open your ears.
Delicious!
Pikachu, if you eat that fast, you’ll—
You really are so alike!
It was just so tasty, y’know?
And I have more,
ready for if I get hungry later!
What?
A rock?
It came flying over here, didn’t it?
It’s a Pokémon!
Gotta get the camera!
Right.
Hey! My backpack!
This one ran off too!
Were they working together?!
After them!
Hey, your ticket to the Wild Area
was in that backpack, wasn’t it?
Yeah!
Err... Which way?!
It’s a decoy?!
The backpack’s that way!
They’re gone!
Satoshi, you go that way!
Right!
Uh... This way?
A dead end?!
Don’t tell me...
I’m lost!
Incoming call from Go.
Go!
Shh! Quietly!
They’re—
Wait! Let’s see what
they’re doing.
Kusune! Fox Pokémon!
Evil type!
Aided by the soft pads on its feet,
it silently raids the food stores of other Pokémon!
Hmm... Kusune, huh?
No data found for this Pokémon!
What?! Does that mean...?
It’s a new Pokémon species?!
Awesome!
A new species! A new species!
It looks like that one’s the leader.
Yeah.
It really cares for its friends...
Aww... What a great guy!
It shared its food with them!
Wait! Those are my little thingies!
Not good! They heard us!
Gimme back my backpack!
I said...!
Give it back!
Oh, no!
Pikachu!
Want a battle?
We’ll take you on!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Time to battle!
Iron Tail!
I saw those earlier!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Now, Pikachu! Electroweb!
We did it, Pikachu!
Thanks!
You’re a fun guy!
Oww!
You’re not half bad.
That was a nice kick earlier, too!
Wait, are you...?
Hey! Stop!
Will you stop?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hibunny
Fire
You again, huh?
You have got to stop
causing trouble!
Hold on, sir!
Sorry! That’s my Pokémon!
What? This one? It’s yours?
Yes! I’ll tell it off,
so it won’t cause trouble again!
So... please forgive it!
I’m really sorry!
For goodness’ sake...
Why did you lie like that?
You knew I lied...
It was obvious.
But even Hibunny was surprised
that you’d lie for it.
Hibunny?
That’s its name?
That’s right.
Hibunny, then...
Rotom,
show me data on Hibunny.
Hibunny! Rabbit Pokémon!
Fire type!
Once it’s raring to fight, the pads on the backs of its feet
and on its nose radiate tremendous heat!
Its legs are said to bring luck!
It has a white body!
But that one’s brown.
It covered itself in dirt.
What?
But why would it do that?
Those Kusune have lived in this city
for a long time.
They shied away from others,
and... how should I put it?
Well, they’ve always been
pretty hostile.
But then...
...Hibunny arrived.
It was brown,
having covered itself in dirt.
I bet it was trying to
fit in with them.
Who did that?!
Somewhere along the line,
it became their honorary leader.
I see...
The Kusune haven’t
gone hungry ever since.
But nevertheless...
I realize they’re just trying to live,
but they’re still causing a nuisance.
Could it be that...
...you’ve resigned yourselves
to living like this?
Don’t give up!
The world is a huge place!
If you just want it bad enough,
you can go anywhere!
Meet all sorts of people too!
So...
Get out there
and give everything a try!
He’s right, you know!
I mean, he acts all smug about it,
but it’s a new idea for him too.
Hey! I’ve always thought that!
You sure?
Yes, I am!
Oh, also...
Apparently your legs bring luck!
So if anything bad happens...
Just give it a good kick
with those strong legs!
Don’t say that!
What’re you gonna do if it kicks you?!
Oh, no!
Satoshi! It’s time for the train!
Let’s hurry!
Thank you, sir!
Thank you!
Go! Hurry up!
Right!
The leader of the Kusune...
was a Hibunny?
Yeah! A really interesting one!
And the Hibunny you met deliberately
covered itself in dirt to look like a Kusune?
That might be why the Smartphone Rotom
didn’t recognize it at first!
I imagine so.
It was a very intriguing tale
for sure.
Thank you!
Next we’re going to see
huge Pokémon in the Wild Area!
Right. Take care of yourselves.
Yeah!
I’m hungry... I was running around
chasing after those guys...
That’s right...
They ate them all...
The nice-smelling little thingies!
When did you get those?!
The scone man gave me some.
And I bought this milk tea!
You genius!
Let’s eat up!
Diggin’ in!
Go and Satoshi met Hibunny,
a tricky yet interesting Pokémon.
Next time, more dreams and adventures
await in the world of Pocket Monsters!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
All right, let’s go find
a giant Pokémon!
I’m sorry. I decided that
the first Pokémon I catch will be Mew.
Huh? What’s this?
Run!
Kabigon Grows Giant?!
The Mystery of Daimax!!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Kabigon Grows Giant?!
The Mystery of Daimax!!