Satoshi and Go
came to the Galar Region...
...to watch the Supreme Monarch
Dande’s battle.
After the match, the two encountered
and battled a Galarian Kamonegi,
and Satoshi ended up catching it.
What new encounters await them today,
on the second day of their trip?
It’s Galar’s famous Curry Rice!
Boiled Egg Curry and
Kyodaimax Curry!
There’s Plenty-of-Potatoes Curry
and Tropical Curry, too!
Shoot City, Galar Region
Let’s dig in!
It’s totally amazing!
It’s like it’s melting on
my tongue!
Huh? What’s up?
Picking up from yesterday?
Hey, you can battle after we’ve eaten!
What’s this?
I’ve never seen
this Pokémon before!
It’s crying!
Maybe it’s still a kid?
I wonder what this Pokémon
is called...!
Satoshi...
Why are you crying?
I dunno...
My tears just won’t stop...
But you’re crying, too...
Huh? Me too? Why?!
It vanished!
Did it run away...?
Let’s find it!
Yeah!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Sobbing Messon
Where could it have gone?
Hey, Go.
You gonna catch that Pokémon?
Yeah! The way it hides itself
reminds me of Mew.
I just gotta catch it, yeah?
What seems to be the matter?
Ms. Joy!
And...
Yessan! Emotion Pokémon!
Psychic/Normal type!
These intelligent Pokémon use the horns
on their heads to sense the emotions of others!
Males will act as valets for those they serve,
and the females are particularly good at babysitting!
Are you searching for something here?
There was a Pokémon
we’d never seen before, but it ran away.
It looks like it can
become invisible.
Invisible?
It was about this big...
And it had a crest like this,
and a twirly tail.
Oh, that must have been Messon.
Messon?
Yes. Many can be found living
in areas with lush nature.
They’re incredibly timid,
so you hardly ever spot Messon in cities.
I wonder if it got lost.
Lost?
If it’s timid...
Does that mean it got afraid and hid?
Perhaps. Messon becomes invisible
when it touches water,
so it might be hiding over there.
A fountain?
Messon, are you there?
I’m Go. I really like your ability!
Wanna come with me?
We’re not angry
that you ate our breakfast.
Heck, if you join us,
we can eat together!
Not there, huh...?
It might have run
somewhere far away.
And here I wanted to catch it!
Oh, no...
I just tossed a valuable
Monster Ball without thinking!
Messon’s data will be
added to the Index!
What?!
No way! It was right there?!
Hey... Where are we?
Not a clue.
Probably somewhere in Galar,
if my calculations are correct, meow.
And we had such a great plan
to catch Pikachu, too...
Then we got blown away,
and after this...
...and that...
...and all kinds of stuff,
we end up in Galar?!
There’s no way Pikachu
would be here!
What? Show me, meow!
What’s up?
There’s Pikachu, meow!
The brat boys are there, too, meow!
Seriously?!
Seriously, meow.
Our ship has come in!
Messon! Water Lizard Pokémon!
Water type!
When it touches water, its body color changes
to blend into its surroundings!
Because of its timid personality, it can sometimes
turn invisible from its own fluids, such as tears or sweat!
So that’s why it disappeared
when it cried.
Aren’t you glad
you managed to catch Messon, Go?
Yeah.
Hey, Riolu, what’s wrong?
What’s that?!
Sunahebi! Sand Snake Pokémon!
Ground type!
As it digs, it swallows sand and stores it
in its neck pouch, to spray out later!
All right!
I’ll catch this one, too!
Monster Ball, go!
Didn’t work.
I’ll battle it, then!
The Water-type Messon
would be a perfect match, yeah?
That’s right!
I wanna see Messon battle!
Go, Messon!
There it is!
Rotom, what moves
does Messon know?
These!
It vanished!
Sunahebi looks confused!
Messon! Water Gun!
Messon!
Once it comes out, use Pound!
Keep it up, Messon!
You’re totally visible
because of the sand!
Messon! Disappear again!
What’s wrong, Messon?
It looks troubled.
Maybe it can’t
disappear at will?
Again!
What is this?!
It’s said that Messon’s tears
pack the chemical punch of 100 onions!
I see!
Wait, Messon! Return!
It ran away... didn’t it?
We gotta get it back!
Yeah!
Where’d it go?
Well, it can turn invisible...
There’s loads of people crying!
It’s that way!
We’ll look over here.
We go this way, Rabbifoot!
Huh? Where’d it go?
Think this looks suspicious?
Oh, that’s not it!
So this is where you were.
I’m sorry I scared you, Messon.
Wait, don’t cry!
We won’t do anything to you!
Okay, Messon?
We really have to do something about
that “chemical punch of 100 onions” thing.
Oh, of course!
Go! Find it?
I did! But it fled into the river.
It probably swam downstream!
Okay! Let’s search along the river!
Where are we?
We lost sight of Pikachu...
He’s definitely somewhere
in the city, meow.
How do you expect us
to find him in that huge city?!
What’s that?
A Pokémon.
Yeah. One I’ve never seen before.
Who’s that, meow?
Morpeko...
Morpeko?
What kind of Pokémon is that?
I just... don’t feel like
explaining it today.
Cut the attitude and
just do your job!
Stop! You’ll break it!
Our rations!
What’re you doing
stuffing your face?!
It got away!
A dine-and-dash?
Are you kidding me?
What’s that?
Messon. That’s a Messon.
Messon!
Where are you?
That voice!
There’s no doubting it, meow!
It’s the brat boys and...
...Pikachu!
They said “Messon! Where are you?”,
didn’t they?
That’s right.
They’re looking for
this thing, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Messon
Water
Messon! Are you there?
Please come out, Messon!
That’s weird...
Did it go even farther?
It’s my fault.
I just forced Messon to battle
without considering how it felt.
Of course it’d run away
from a trainer like me.
Go.
Just try harder next time then,
once we find it!
You only just caught it, right?
You can’t expect everything
to work out right away.
Satoshi...
I guess you’re right!
Messon, where are you?
Right here!
What?
Where?
If you ask us
“What? Where?”
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
Could this perhaps be
what you’re looking for?
Messon!
How’d you end up
with Team Rocket?!
We don’t mind
giving it back to you...
If you give us Pikachu
in exchange!
Huh...? Weren’t we laughing...?
So why are we crying...?!
I don’t know, meow...!
Anyway, we just want Pikachu!
Trade us it for Messon!
Are you kidding?!
You’re not getting Pikachu!
But we’re taking Messon back!
Awful! You’re just awful!
We can’t have either?!
How could you be so cruel?!
Poor us, meow!
It kinda feels like...
...we’re the bad guys...
Aaah, just stop crying already!
Your crying makes us cry, too!
If you won’t hand him over...
Then we’ll just take him by force!
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
Secret!
Time to battle!
Go!
The Magnetic Field Pokémon,
Jibacoil!
The Plate Pokémon,
Armaldo!
We’re gonna save Messon!
Rabbifoot! Double Kick!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Riolu, you use Shadow Clones!
Armaldo! Metal Claw!
Jibacoil! Supersonic Waves!
See? This is what you get
for not handing over Pikachu!
Why would you try so hard to get
this weak crybaby Pokémon back, anyway?
Are you complete morons?
Be quiet! Messon might be
a crybaby, but it is not “weak”!
Hang on, Messon!
I promise I’ll save you!
You feisty little brat!
Jibacoil, keep firing your
Supersonic Waves!
Messon...
I’ll save you right now!
Messon, are you there?
I’m Go. I really like your ability!
Wanna come with me?
What?
It got out, meow!
That’s why I said
not to use a cheap cage!
We couldn’t afford
a better one on our budget!
There!
Messon, over here! Run!
Kojiro, it’s getting away!
Hold it!
Messon!
Good job, Armaldo!
Again!
Satoshi, take these!
Look at that!
Jibacoil isn’t crying at all!
Neither is Armaldo!
...Or so we thought,
but it’s crying its eyes out!
Those are its eyes?!
But that must mean
the brat boys have it just as bad!
I see... Goggles, huh?
Yeah!
Since it said
“the chemical punch of 100 onions”,
I thought back to
Barrierd cooking!
Guess we owe
Barrierd our thanks!
That’s right!
No way!
Go, now’s our chance!
Yeah! Let’s fight back!
Riolu! Vacuum Wave!
Rabbifoot! Ember!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
Messon.
I’m sorry I tried to
make you battle.
Next time I’ll make sure to ask
if you want to battle or not first.
Your timidness
taught me something.
You’re always alert, right?
That way you can always protect yourself
or your friends if need be!
And so you may be timid,
but you’re not weak!
You are strong!
No! Don’t cry!
Go has caught Messon,
and strengthened their bond just a tiny bit.
Satoshi and Go’s adventures
will continue!
This is the absolute pits.
We couldn’t catch Pikachu, either.
What a huge waste of time, meow.
Huh? Pikachu?!
What?!
Oh, just that thing again?
It’s saying “Gimme food!”, meow.
We’re out of food!
You ate everything we had.
Scram!
Oh, dear...
I’ve got kind of an...
...awful feeling...
No way!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
W-Wait, Wanpachi!
We should look after it
at home until it can fly again.
Is this the Mamepato
the Director mentioned?
What’s wrong, Wanpachi?
Koharu’s taking care of Mamepato,
and Wanpachi’s jealous.
Jealous?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Jealous Fit!
Wanpachi's Feelings
Wanpachi’s Feelings