Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
I’m back!
I’m back, Wanpachi.
Come on out, Eevee.
Thanks for waiting!
Have you been a good boy?
What is it, Eevee?
Welcome back, Koharu.
I’m back, Dad.
Can you come here a moment?
Welcome back, Koharu.
Nice timing!
What is it?
Hey! Have you been
finding fossils enchanting?
The president of
the Museum of Science?
Apparently he has a request for you.
About investigating fossils!
In the Wild Area! The Wild Area!
Over in Galar?
Ex-aaactly!
You can find rare fossils in Galar,
according to a rumor I heard.
I’d like you to go and investigate
what these rare fossils are like!
I’ll do it!
Me, too!
I can meet lots of Pokémon
in the Wild Area! Right, Aceburn?!
What will you do, Koharu?
I have school, so...
You want to go?
Dad, I want to go too!
Satoshi and Go left for Galar to investigate the fossils...
and Koharu went along, too.
Now, what sort of encounters
and adventures await them?
What’re you looking at?
An e-mail from the teacher.
She’s asking me to write a report about the trip
to make up for missing lessons.
Huh, that’s great!
Yeah!
All you can see is clouds...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Galar's Fossils!
Stick 'em Together!!
The Wild Area, Galar Region
Aceburn, go!
Whoa!
There’s so many Pokémon!
What? Um... What’s that...?
Gantle. Ore Pokémon.
Rock-type.
It relies on sound to
monitor its vicinity.
When angered, it will attack
without ever changing the direction it’s facing.
Eevee!
Aceburn! Blaze Kick!
Harden, huh?
Aceburn!
Lightning Speed!
Monster Ball, go!
Gantle’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right, Gantle caught!
Great!
Go! Thank you!
And you, Aceburn!
Now, let’s go!
Yes!
Wait for me!
You get that.
This must be it!
Okay, time to dig!
Aceburn!
Let’s get stuck in together!
We should go too, Pikachu!
Eevee!
We’ll look for fossils, too!
Banbadoro! Double Kick!
Eevee!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
You okay?
Yeah! Thank you!
Oh, somebody there?
Sorry ‘bout that.
What’s with that
“Sorry ‘bout that”?!
I’m Gasattsu.
Here to dig up fossils.
You lookin’ for fossils too?
Yeah!
We heard we could
find rare fossils here...
Okay, this way.
What is this?
A hand? A foot?
Is this... a tail?
Ain’t they great?
This isn’t a complete fossil,
am I right?
Right. But dig here and there,
and we’ll probably find the whole thing eventually.
I see you’re as rough as ever.
You took your time. You’re late!
Well, I forgot to
set my alarm clock...
You’re so careless...
Who’s that?
A fellow researcher, Ukattsu.
Hello!
Hello.
Ukattsu,
let’s get the investigation started.
Got it.
I forgot my pickaxe!
You’re so careless... Here.
Um... We can help, too!
It’ll go faster if we’re all digging!
That would help.
Can we ask for your help, then?
Yeah!
This is heavy...
You’ve got it!
What’s this?!
Looks like a fossil of a foot.
Isn’t that great?
Eevee! You did a great job!
How do these fit together?
I’m not even sure
which way they face.
It’s like some sort of puzzle.
That’s the mysterious thing
about Galar’s fossils.
Mysterious?
I think the right answer might just be some odd match-up
that completely defies all prior ideas!
Here’s my prediction.
This, and this make one Pokémon.
This area used to be a seabed. So it would’ve needed
limbs that can move through water easily.
And since it swam deep in the ocean, this Pokémon
needed a physiology that could eat prey above it.
I named it Uochilldon!
I was just thinking...
I’d match up this one and this one.
My hypothesis is...
This area was plains,
with nothing but short shrubs.
So bird Pokémon would need to run more than they fly,
ending up with a stronger lower body.
Like this!
I named it Pacchiragon!
Ooh!
Looks like it could be right,
or just as easily be wrong...
It really is mysterious...
We’ve found all the fossils we need.
Why don’t we restore them straight away?!
Yeah.
This one isn’t shutting properly.
Hey, be more careful with that.
Okay, it’s shut.
You’re so rough with things...
My Pacchiragon is...
this one and this one.
Huh? Wasn’t that my Uochilldon?
I’m sure it was blue...
No! Mine was blue.
Yours is light blue.
Huh? Light blue?
I thought it was the blue one...
Well, they’re pretty much the same thing!
Hurry up and get the machine!
Ta-daah!
This is the fossil restoration device!
With this, we can restore the fossil pieces
to their original form.
Amazing, right?
The principle is
the same as Monster Balls.
They’re turned into light—
Don’t bother with the explanation.
Nobody gets it anyway.
Ugh!
The withdraw button... On!
All right.
Now I just press
the emerge button...
No, the restore button!
Oh, whoops.
You’re so careless...
Now the fossil pieces will be
converted to light particles and reconstructed...
Or more simply,
put together like a puzzle...
Then they’ll appear,
fully restored!
So, how long will that take?
Two hours.
No, maybe four hours.
What should we do
while we wait?
How about making
something to eat?
I’m in!
Great idea! A camp meal!
What should we make?!
When you cook in the Wild Area,
you’ve gotta have...
Curry!
Let’s make a great curry together!
Yeah!
Do you think this looks good?
Don’t worry! It just needs to be hot enough
to dissolve everything!
Right!
Momon berries and Mago berries...
Huh, so if you grind them enough,
they have a milder taste!
Don’t worry!
Cook it enough and it’ll all dissolve!
That’s how you have hafta make
Wild Area curry!
Make sure you stir it properly
so it doesn’t burn, okay?
I know!
You’re so rough...
Where’s the curry roux?!
I brought it.
Look over there.
Huh? That’s chocolate...
Oh, no! I mixed them up!
You’re so careless...
Oh, sorry, Eevee.
I’m making a tasty dessert with some Moomoo Milk,
so just wait a bit longer, okay?
Hmm... Now for some sugar...
For a curry, you need
some kind of secret ingredient...
We could do with one of those,
but what...?
I’ve got it!
Huh?
Where’s the whipped cream?
Go! Have you seen it?
I haven’t!
I wonder where it went...
And it’s done!
Special whipped cream curry!
What is this...?
That was my...
I used it as the
secret ingredient!
Um, it’s...
hardly “secret”...
So rough...
Well, why don’t we just try it.
H-Here g-goes...
Delicious!
It’s pretty good, isn’t it?
It’s not bad.
We’re finished!
We sure ate...
My belly hurts...
You had too many extra servings...
What’s that?
The fossil restoration is complete!
Really?
Great!
Okay, out they come.
Don’t press the wrong thing.
It’s the emerge button, remember?
Right, right...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gantle
Rock
Whoa!
They were really restored!
But don’t they look different
to the predictions?
Yeah...
And that’s the mysterious thing
about Galar’s fossils!
Huh?
It doesn’t quite match my hypothesis,
but look what potential they had!
I’ll call it Pacchilldon!
It lived in the ancient seas,
and must have chilled and stored its prey with its icy body!
That hypothesis
changed quite a bit...
What’s this?
Well, those are Galar’s fossils.
Aren’t they mysterious...?
If I had to name it... Right!
Uonoragon!
With its powerful legs and jaws,
it was unrivaled on land!
But it overhunted its prey,
and went extinct.
Yeah, that has to be
what happened!
Huh! Nice to meet you,
Uonoragon!
That was close.
Why?!
Looks like it likes him.
Are you sure about that?
It won’t stop...
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Dodge it!
Satoshi!
Oh, dear!
Aceburn, melt the ice
with Pyro Ball!
Thank you, Eevee!
You okay, Koharu?
Yeah!
I need to calm it down!
How far are you gonna run?!
Gantle, go!
I’m counting on you, Gantle!
Stop running, Uonorago—
So cold...
Are you okay?
We’ll manage...
Why isn’t it moving?
That’s... Charge!
Here it comes!
So... you just wanted to swim?
I see!
Hey, why don’t we go
have a look around?
Gantle! Harden!
Gantle! Stone Edge!
It managed to withstand that?
It’s got some guts!
Look out!
Stop!
Huh? Satoshi?
Move!
Are you okay?
That was a shock...
You’re not hurt anywhere?
Stop it...
All right.
Looks like it’s calmed down.
Yeah!
Looks like it likes you.
Are you okay?
Thanks to you. Thank you.
So hey, what do you think?
Would you look after
these fossil Pokémon?
Huh?
We can?
Sure! We have our new data now,
so we’re satisfied. Right?
Yeah!
Pacchilldon!
Will you come with me?
Let’s be friends,
Uonoragon!
Monster Ball, go!
Pacchilldon’s data will be
added to the Index!
Uonoragon’s data will be
added to the Index.
Uonoragon...
Pacchilldon...
I’ve caught you!
You’re both amazing!
I see!
Pacchilldon and Uonoragon...
They’re truly mysterious
fossil Pokémon!
Aren’t they just enchanting?
Thank you very much
for your report.
Sure!
Bye then!
So, how was it?
Great! I had so much fun!
I hope I can go again sometime!
Don’t you agree, Eevee?
All right!
Let’s write that report together!
“In the Wild Area, Eevee and I
experienced a lot together.
“First, we...”
Hmm...
Good night, Eevee!
Satoshi and Go have caught
new fossil Pokémon.
And Koharu has learned how fun it can be
to go on an adventure with a Partner Pokémon.
Many more encounters are
in store for them!
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
All right! Today, more training!
Look, Satoshi!
Kamonegi’s brimming with power!
My Kamonegi is aiming to be
a Leek Master!
A Leek Master?!
Here comes a championships trainer!
Of course, I’ll take on
the Championships challenge!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Kamonegi's Great Trial!
Kamonegi’s Great Trial!