Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Ooh!
You can see it now, Regina.
That place with all the lights
is Kuchiba City.
I bet you’ll make
lots of friends there.
I already...
Hmm?
Nothing.
Take care out there!
See you later.
Come on, Satoshi,
just enjoy yourself!
I don’t see this going well...
It’ll be fine!
I’ll tell them all about
what makes you so awesome!
That’s what
I’m worried about...
Relax, relax!
Trust me on this one!
When I heard the topic was people you’re friends with,
your face immediately sprung to mind.
Guess that makes sense.
Still, going to school with you
feels a little weird...
Come on, seeing you in person
is the best way for them to see how funny you are.
“Funny...”?
You’re hilarious, Satoshi!
“Hilarious,” huh?
Friends...
I’m happy for you, Go.
A Glacia?
How lovely!
Glacia. Fresh Snow Pokémon.
Ice type.
One of Eevee’s
possible evolutions.
By controlling its body heat, it can freeze
the atmosphere around it to make a diamond-dust flurry.
What is it, Mieze?
Let go.
Mieze?
Hey, Koharu!
We’re gonna leave you behind!
I’m coming!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Ice Queen and Glacia
...and what does the inside
of Satoshi’s head look like?
It’s pretty much just stuffed
with Pokémon and Pokémon battles!
That’s not true!
It is, though.
I think about other stuff, too!
Like what?
Like, uh...
What we’re having
for dinner tonight.
This is more like a comedy act
than a presentation...
Oh, and this is
the most important point.
Satoshi can understand
how Pokémon feel!
You can too, though.
Like with Aceburn or Sarunori.
I think our ways of understanding them
are a bit different.
You have this sort of...
animal instinct?
Animal? Hmm...
Yeah, I know just what
he means!
And that is all for my presentation
on my friend, Satoshi.
That was a great presentation!
Satoshi, since you’ve come all this way,
you should spend the day here and enjoy yourself.
Sounds good!
Who’s that?
Good to see you!
I was getting worried.
I’m sorry.
Everyone, this is Regina,
a transfer student!
She’ll only be here for a short time
while her parents are working here,
but I hope you’ll all
be kind to her.
Yeah!
Regina, here we leave our Pokémon
in the Pokémon Garden.
Can someone show her?
I can find it by myself.
But we can’t have you
getting lost...
Miss!
I’ll show her!
Thank you.
If you would, then.
My name’s Koharu.
Shall we go?
Your Glacia is really pretty.
What was it, “Mieze”?
How do you know that?
Oh, sorry...
I happened to see you
this morning.
I wanted to say hello,
but I lost sight of you.
So I’m glad to have the chance
to meet you!
Look, over there
is the Pokémon Garden.
Everyone!
This is my friend Regina,
and her Glacia, Mieze.
Be nice to them.
Eevee is my partner, Pikachu is Satoshi’s,
and Sarunori is Go’s.
Oh, I’ll introduce you
to Satoshi and Go later.
Hey, let me join in!
Nice to meet you, Mieze.
Mieze...
Wait for me here.
When it’s time to go home...
You can come here
during lunch break!
When it’s lunch time,
I’ll be back to check on you.
See you, then!
Satoshi and Go live
at my father’s research lab.
Research lab?
A Pokémon research lab.
It’s called
the Sakuragi Institute.
Sakuragi...
Sakuragi Institute?
Yes, an institute in Kuchiba City
with a good reputation.
Oh, then that’ll be perfect.
We can have them
examine Glacia.
Oh, welcome back.
Regina!
Where are you from?
How long
are you gonna be here?
I want to know
all about your Glacia!
C’mon, you guys.
Settle down.
I can’t move!
Nyah-nyah! Ice Queen!
Ice Queen! Ice Queen! Ice Queen!
Better watch out!
The Ice Queen can freeze anything!
No, I’m not an Ice Queen!
But you look exactly like her!
Ice Queen! Ice Queen! Ice Queen!
Mieze?
I’m sorry for freezing you.
Don’t worry about it!
Right!
No harm, no foul!
A Glacia?
It has an enormous amount of power
it uses to freeze things.
Anything it dislikes,
it freezes.
Which is why she hasn’t been able to make friends,
and has had to transfer schools again and again.
That must weigh on your mind.
Professor Sakuragi,
would you consider examining our Glacia?
We’re worried...
We don’t know
if we can let them stay together.
You suspect
there’s something wrong with Glacia?
That’s not something
we can say.
But...
We want her to have friends!
As long as Glacia is with her,
she’ll always be alone.
Please, can you help us?
Right?
She’s gone...
That was such a shock...
Ta-daah!
Let’s eat lunch together!
With Eevee and Mieze, too!
Fair enough...
Then how about tomorrow?
I’ll be gone tomorrow.
Huh? What do you mean?
Exactly what I said.
Oh, no...
But we’ve only just
become friends!
Mieze is my only friend.
Bye. The teacher wants to see me.
Regina.
Regina?
Yes?
Miss!
Koharu?
And Go, and Satoshi...
What’s going on—?
We have a request.
Please don’t kick Regina out!
That Blizzard earlier
was an accident!
I saw it,
so I know what happened!
Glacia was just
trying to protect Regina!
So please!
Now why would I do that?
She just transferred here today,
so there’s a lot she won’t be used to.
I was just telling her
all about the school.
You were?
Oh, dear.
Weren’t you listening, Regina?
I thought...
It would be like always...
Oh, is that all?
You were fretting
over nothing, Koharu.
Sorry.
I guess I jumped to conclusions.
Still, I’m glad she’s okay.
Yeah!
Let’s eat lunch together!
Come on out, Mieze.
Mieze, stop!
Mieze?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Glacia
Ice
Is Mieze going to be okay?
Don’t worry, don’t worry!
Koharu’s right!
Leave it to the Director!
It’s gonna be okay!
Everyone...
Its condition is stable.
It should stay here
and rest for today.
Is Mieze sick?
You’re taking
very good care of Mieze.
I could tell by seeing
the test results.
But...
But?
This here is its temperature data,
which is alarmingly low.
Glacia are known to have low body temperatures,
but this is still far too low.
I hear Mieze has frequently
been making powerful Blizzards.
It’s likely over-exerting itself and ending up
unable to properly control its body heat.
If it keeps pushing itself too far,
then Mieze will...
It’s my fault... It’s...
Regina...
The first time Mieze
created a Blizzard like that...
...was when I was being bullied
for looking like the Ice Queen in a picture book.
Then, when similar incidents
happened again and again,
Mieze would always
come and save me.
Not long after, Mieze was always on edge,
making sure nobody tried to hurt me.
Always, constantly.
I knew...
I knew I shouldn’t...
But I just hid behind it.
I’m sorry...
I’m sorry, Mieze!
You’ve always protected me,
but I never did the same for you...
That’s not
what a friend would do...
You are friends.
You’re a precious friend to Mieze.
It only gets so angry
because you’re its friend.
It comes from the heart.
Regina!
We were shocked
when the school phoned us.
It happened again?
Mieze?
Is Mieze okay?
So there was
something wrong with Mieze?
No, there’s nothing wrong with it.
Huh? What do you mean?
Papa. Mama.
Mieze... was protecting me all along
so I wouldn’t be bullied.
And... Mieze pushed itself too hard.
It can’t keep going on like this.
All because
I hid behind Mieze...!
Regina...
So that’s what happened...
I’m sorry I never realized...
I’m going to get stronger.
I’ll get stronger,
so that I can protect Mieze.
That’s the spirit, Regina!
Great!
We’ll be cheering for you!
Thank you,
Go, Satoshi, Koharu.
Mieze!
What a relief...
So Regina had someone all along.
She had a friend.
Today, Regina has something
to tell you all.
Everyone...
I’m very sorry!
I’ll be more careful
in the future,
so please forgive
Mieze and I!
That’s not all. Regina and Mieze
have a present for everyone here today.
Mieze and I like to make
ice theme parks to play in.
I thought that playing together with everyone
would be much, much, much more fun, so let’s make one!
Satoshi and I
are gonna be Regina’s assistants!
All right!
Come on out, Uonoragon!
You’re up, Dugong!
Pacchilldon!
Pacchilldon! Powder Snow!
Uonoragon! Water Gun!
Mieze!
Dugong!
Icy Wind!
Pacchilldon, use Ice Fang!
Let’s have fun, everyone!
Woo-hoo!
Yahoo!
Let’s put the skate rink here.
Mieze! Ice Beam!
Eevee?
Sometimes, she manages to pull off
her evolved forms’ moves.
Really?
That’s wonderful!
Yeah!
Go! Satoshi!
A package arrived
from Regina!
Let’s have a look...
It’s a snow globe!
With Mieze inside!
Oh, it’s so pretty...
Koharu, what about the letter?
Oh, right!
“How have you been, Koharu?
“On that note,
how are Satoshi and Go doing?
“I’ve been doing great.
“Mieze hasn’t sent out...”
Mieze hasn’t sent out
a single Blizzard ever since.
Oh, I mean those
really powerful Blizzards.
I’m really into
Pokémon battles now.
Go, Utsubot!
We’ll come and visit during school break,
so look forward to it!
“Regina.”
Of course we will!
So Regina’s started battling.
Next time we see her,
we’ll have to...
Have a battle with her!
Koharu and Eevee
met Regina and Mieze,
and witnessed the deep bond
between people and Pokémon.
“Hopefully someday,
we can be as close as they are...”
...Koharu thought
to herself.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
It’s here!
A Trial Mission!
Very well.
I can lend you my equipment.
However!
You have to help out
with my work.
Work?
Treasure hunting!
It’s your turn to
have your dreams come true.
Go catch that wild Kingdra!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Trial Mission!
The Deep Sea Diving Research Team!!