Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Sheesh... I get it already, Mom...
You say that,
but are you really eating properly?
I am.
I know you’re busy with work,
but you should come and visit sometime.
Sure, sometime.
Do you have a special someone?
If you do, you should introduce us someda—
Oh, gotta go!
Sorry, I’ll call you when I can!
Kikuna?!
Sorry, Mom.
See you later.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Love is a Koduck
Today, there is bad weather
in Kuchiba City.
It is also rather cold.
You’re so energetic, Eevee!
But thanks to that, you’re keeping me warm.
Actually, I wonder if there are Pokémon
that don’t like the cold...
I’m back, Dad.
Welcome back, Koharu.
You’re leaving now?
Yeah. Oh, I’m always so excited
to see the newly-researched findings.
Director Sakuragi,
will you be all right?
The bus’ll be here soon.
Oh, right!
Okay, I’ll be off.
I’ll leave the rest in your hands.
Right.
See you later!
Kikuna, are Go and Satoshi here?
Yes, they’re in the park right now—
C’mon, Go!
I told you to wait, Satoshi!
Oh, Koharu.
What is it?
Today’s forecast says
it’s going to snow!
And snow improves the odds
of seeing Ice-type Pokémon!
My chance to catch them!
Go!
I’m coming!
See ya.
When are you coming back?
Not until I catch something!
Whaaa...?
Did you have business with them?
I wouldn’t call it business,
but this morning...
Wait up, Wanpachi!
What’s going on this early...?
Sis!
Wanpachi?
Come on, Wanpachi...
What’s wrong, Sota?
I’m sleeping over
at Nami’s tonight.
Oh, you are?
Everyone’s bringing
one of their family’s Pokémon,
so I wanna take
Wanpachi with me, but...
Wanpachi,
can you go with Sota?
Please?
Thanks!
Yes, I understand.
I’ll try and do it.
Yes. Okay then,
I’ll be going.
Oh, Koharu.
Did something happen?
Yeah... An illustrator I know
sprained their wrist...
What? Are they okay?
Apparently it’s nothing severe,
but they have magazine illustrations
due in two days,
so they asked
if I could draw them instead.
Um... You think you can make it?
They need three or so pieces,
so I should be okay if I start now.
So I’m really sorry, but you’ll have to get
takeout or something for dinner, okay?
Got it. I’ll figure something out,
so you do your best, Mom!
Thank you!
So I thought I might have dinner
with Go and Satoshi.
Is that so?
With how they were,
they might not be back for a while.
Gänger, you shouldn’t scare people.
Oh, that really scared me...
Maybe it’s in a bad mood
since Satoshi left it behind?
So what’re you going to do, Koharu?
Wait for Go and Satoshi?
Oh, given the occasion...
Could I watch you work?
Sure, go ahead!
Right. Yes.
If you could send us that data
straight away...
Yes...
Kikuna!
Where was that thing?
In the folder
with yesterday’s date.
Ah! I see it,
thank you so much.
Okay. Excuse me for a minute.
Seems something’s wrong
with the park’s air circulation system.
Shall we take a look?
Sure.
It has been a cold day today.
Maybe that got it busted up...
It was hiding in there?
This is it.
Messon probably hit this when it hid.
Yep, all okay.
Kikuna’s really cool, isn’t she?
Yes! Thank you very much.
I’ll be in contact. Goodbye!
That’s today’s work done.
Go and Satoshi still aren’t back?
Looks like it.
Oh, well. Let’s just get
something to eat by ourselves, Eevee.
Why not come home with me?
Huh?
I’d be all alone at home too.
Wanna have a girls’ night?
You don’t have school tomorrow, right?
You can stay over with me.
Oh, but, I...
Leave the braiding to me.
I’ll teach you some
easy-to-do hairstyles, too.
Really?!
Yeah!
Th-Then I’d love to!
Okay. I’ll call your mother
and let her know.
I’ll leave the rest to you, Renji!
Oh, sure!
Eevee, we’re having a sleepover
at Kikuna’s place!
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
What would you like for dinner?
I’ll eat anything!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
Let me know
if you see anything you’d like.
And skip the slow send-off
Sure!
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
We sure bought a lot!
Each and every one of my memories
Yeah!
Can always be found inside a Ball
We’re here. This is my home.
Stop that, Eevee!
I’m sorry. It’s a little messy...
...but I’ll tidy it up now!
Go on, make yourself at home.
Uhh... Sure...
So this is Kikuna’s place...
You really like Koduck,
don’t you?
Yes.
Something about looking at them
relaxes me.
So I tend to buy
Koduck merchandise, too.
You could just become
a Koduck’s trainer...
Just looking at them
is enough for me.
And...
Come on,
let’s eat while it’s still hot!
Oh, let me help!
There’s no Ice-type Pokémon
out here...
Temperature, humidity, pressure...
These are the best conditions, just as predicted...
So why?
Let’s go back.
No! I’m not leaving
until I catch something!
Let’s just go back.
I’m starving...
I can’t wait ‘til we get back...
Let’s just get something.
Now you’re talking!
What do we get?
It’s cold,
so maybe ramen?
Sounds great to me!
Don’t do that, Eevee!
Sheesh...
It really did start snowing.
Do you think
Satoshi and Go are okay?
I-I’m sure they are.
Is something wrong?
I-It’s nothing!
Okay, let’s eat!
That man...
Is that Kikuna’s boyfriend?
Is that why she collects
Koduck merch?
I need to know!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Koduck
Water
Wow, it smells great!
Let’s eat!
Delicious!
Really? I should try one, too.
Tattsu-tei’s dim sum
has no equal!
Would you like to try one?
Looks like Eevee
likes them, too.
You’re already such good friends.
No, we have a long way to go.
I’d like to be closer,
but I’m not sure how to go about it...
Then why don’t you try asking
Satoshi and Go for tips?
No, I can’t...
They wouldn’t be any help.
What?! You don’t even know that?
You gotta be all “whumph” and “mmmph”
and “ahh...” with your Pokémon!
Oh, these look great, too!
One soy sauce ramen!
Coming right up!
This is the best!
Yeah.
I like to think the restaurants here
serve the tastiest food you’ll find.
They really do.
A Koduck?
You’re right.
That’s your Koduck?
Yeah, it’s mine.
It’s weird to see one
wearing a scarf!
It doesn’t like the cold.
That’s its favorite scarf.
It never lets go of it.
I see.
Koduck! Duck Pokémon!
Water type!
It is troubled by constant headaches!
The more pain it’s in,
the more powerful its psychokinesis becomes!
I-It couldn’t be...!
Koduck!
Koduck... It’s okay, it’s okay.
Sorry about that.
Let me get you something
to make up for the scare.
Oh, but...
I wanted to have the miso, too...
Okay, then I’ll get you that.
What?! Are you sure?!
I’ll have some more food, too.
What about you two?
Oh, sure!
I’m stuffed!
Then I guess you don’t have
any room left?
You bet I do!
There’s always room for sweets,
isn’t there?
They all look tasty...
Then why don’t we have
half of each?
Sure!
Delicious!
They smell so nice...
Right?
They’re called essential oils.
You can soak a cloth in them and leave it in a room,
or put it in your closet to add scents to clothes.
What’s your favorite, Koharu?
Hmm... Maybe this one?
That one uses oil
extracted from Roselia flowers!
Or if you like sweet scents,
you can even get
Amakaji- or Cuwawa-scented oils.
Pokémon research has its uses
even with stuff like this.
It really does!
Oh, Eevee...
Kikuna, this...
It fits perfectly!
That’s great!
I bought it because it was cute,
but it was too small for me!
I... I see...
I’m turning off the lights.
Okay.
That was fun.
It’s nice to have girls’ nights
every now and then.
I’ve learned a bit
about your private life,
and I was really shocked
to find out you were so bad at cleaning!
Please, pretend you
never saw that!
Kikuna... You work hard,
you’re beautiful,
you’re a huge inspiration for me...
I’d like to be someone like you.
It’s not like it’s always been
smooth sailing for me.
One time I messed up so badly
that I almost gave up on being a researcher.
You did?
It was this enormous catastrophe.
Back when I was a student,
I was supposed to do
a research presentation at a conference.
I was hoping it would be well-received
so I could become a researcher.
But the day of the conference...
I lost the data I was going to present.
What?! S-So what happened?
Of course,
I couldn’t do the presentation.
I was really depressed.
I felt terrible,
thinking I couldn’t be a researcher.
And then...
Sorry, my Koduck...
...must’ve thought
you looked cold.
C’mon, Koduck.
Let’s keep going.
Maybe we should make it
a bit bigger?
Easy does it...
Come on, moving around
will warm you up.
Thank you.
Can I help, too?
Yeah, that’d be great!
Right, Koduck?
Now you’ve done it!
Here goes!
I was able to forget how cold and depressed I was
just getting to play around with them.
And that motivated me to keep trying
to become a researcher.
All that happened to you...
Whenever I’m feeling down,
that photo cheers me up.
Koduck merch helps bring back
memories of that day,
so I end up buying whatever I find.
What about that man?
I haven’t seen him since.
I wonder how he’s doing.
Kikuna...
See you then, Koharu.
Thank you for having me.
Oh, they’re back.
Hey, Koharu.
Morning!
So, did you catch any Ice Pokémon?
No luck.
It was really cold out there...
So we had a hot meal
and came back...
I see.
The guy who was sitting next to us
bought us two bowls of ramen!
He was so kind.
He had a weird Koduck with him.
Huh?
It was wearing a scarf.
He said it didn’t like the cold.
Was the scarf Koduck-patterned?!
Yeah, it was... Why?
Where is he now?
No idea.
Koharu?
I want to meet him!
It’s not like
we know where he is...
Hey, forget about it.
This is impossible.
We didn’t even get his name...
And he didn’t say
where he was going.
I’m sure Kikuna
wants to see him...
Koduck?
Oh, the one from yesterday!
That means...
Sorry!
H-Huh? You guys...
The ramen guy!
It’s a miracle.
Um...
There’s someone
I’d like you to meet!
Huh?
Ms. Kikuna!
Oh! Koharu!
Ms. Kikuna! I found him!
Hey, easy...
Um...
I...
...never thought
I’d see you again...
I’ve longed to see you, Koduck!
Huh?
The scarf you gave me back then
was so warm.
Playing together in the snow
made me so happy.
Ever since then,
the thought of you has kept me going!
Thank you!
Koharu?
What is it?
Oh, you’re that snowman girl!
So it was Koduck
you wanted to meet...?
Did something nice happen?
Yes, an emotional reunion!
I got lots of photos, too!
Thank you, Koharu!
People and Pokémon...
Everyone has their own unique way
of meeting and bonding with others.
But once forged,
those bonds are sure to become...
...an everlasting
source of comfort.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Wait, why are you still
holding that pose?
Well, uh...
I can’t pull my hand off it!
Gokurin!
I’ve never seen life signs
like these before.
Is it a new Pokémon?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Panic! The Gokurin Ball!!
Two-in-One Special!!
Come on, Kamukame, The Turtle Race!
Come On, Kamukame, The Turtle Race!