To decide who will advance
to the Masters Tournament,
Satoshi will have a Promotion Match
against Kibana, ranked 8th.
And today,
that battle is finally at hand.
Knuckle City, Galar Region
Aren’t you excited,
Pikachu? Lucario?
I was wondering who it was.
If it isn’t my challenger for today.
Huh?! Mr. Kibana?
So, why are you here so early?
Guess I just couldn’t sit still.
What about you, Mr. Kibana?
This place is my home turf.
Am I not supposed to be here?
Man, I never thought
you’d make it up this far.
But this is as far as you get!
I’m winning this.
I didn’t come here to lose!
Mornin’, Satoshi, Kibana.
Mr. Dande!
What were you doing,
sleeping there?
Well...
I didn’t want to be late
for your battle.
Guess I got here
too early instead!
You, too? Really?
I’m gonna win the battle today for sure,
and then I’ll battle you, Mr. Dande!
Yeah.
I’m looking forward to it.
You hear that, Pikachu?!
Now, show me a battle
that can’t be topped!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
VS Kibana!
The Battle for the Masters Eight!!
Let’s put our all
into cheering for him!
Ladies and gentlemen...
The world’s greatest Pokémon Battles:
the Pokémon World Championships.
The title conferred upon
the top-ranked eight: the Masters Eight.
With that title on the line,
the final Promotion Match of the season will now begin.
First up, and currently ranked 9th...
His battles are impossible to predict.
From the moment he entered the Championships,
he raced his way up here in the blink of an eye.
Competitor Satoshi,
from Kanto!
Satoshi!
And his opponent...
Currently ranked 8th,
the Gym Leader of our Knuckle City.
The Dragon Storm who conquers battles
with his passionate heart and cool-headed tactics...
Competitor Kibana!
Mr. Kibana sure has a lot of fans...
R-Right.
We can’t be outdone!
Satoshi! You can do it!
This match will decide
who advances to the Masters Tournament...
What sort of battle will we witness?
You must be excited, right, Champion?
The stadium is oozing
with their ardent fighting spirit.
This is going to be
an incredibly fun battle!
This match will use
the Masters Tournament Regulations.
You may each use three Pokémon.
There is no limit on match length
or switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all three of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, you are allowed a single use of only one
of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolution.
So Satoshi’s planning
to Mega Evolve Lucario, huh?
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Here we go!
I choose you!
A Dragon showdown!
Competitor Satoshi’s first choice is Kairyu,
and Competitor Kibana’s is Flygon!
Let the battle begin!
Dragon Claw!
Dragon Dance!
Steel Wing!
Dodge it!
Flygon launches a stunningly fast
barrage of attacks!
Yet Kairyu has raised its speed and attack
with Dragon Dance...
...and dodges by the skin of its teeth!
Your Kairyu’s real impressive.
You’ve trained it well.
Happy to hear that from you,
Mr. Kibana!
Aren’t you happy too, Kairyu?
But don’t think you can best me
when it comes to Dragon types.
Let the winds blow!
Stream forward, Sandstorm!
Sandstorm...
This isn’t good.
Kairyu’s going to keep taking damage
in that storm!
Kairyu, calm down!
Dragon Claw!
Kairyu!
Steel Wing!
Kairyu is at the mercy
of the elusive Flygon!
What will
Competitor Satoshi do now?!
Kairyu, can you keep going?
Okay! If we can’t find it,
we’ll just do this ‘til we hit it...
Kairyu! Use Dragon Meteor Shower!
There! Hurricane!
Found it!
Dragon Claw!
Kairyu catches it!
Flygon!
But Flygon immediately gets back up
and vanishes back into the sandstorm!
Again?!
Kairyu!
Use Dragon Meteor Shower again!
I won’t fall for that twice!
Steel Wing!
Kairyu is unable to battle!
Competitor Kibana
is as tough as you’d expect!
The Masters Eight
are a nigh-insurmountable wall!
Kibana’s a trainer whose hunger
for victory surpasses all others’.
That makes my battles with him
all the more thrilling!
Kairyu, you take a nice rest.
Gänger...
I’m counting on you!
Competitor Satoshi’s
second Pokémon is Gänger!
No matter what he picks,
no one can escape from my Sandstorm!
Steel Wing!
Gänger, dodge it!
Ice Punch!
Dragon Claw!
Flygon is toying with Gänger!
If I can’t do something
about this sandstorm...
He’s completely helpless...
It’s over for you!
Crunch!
Gänger!
Crunch! It’s super effective!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gänger is down and not moving!
If he loses Gänger,
Satoshi only has one Pokémon left.
Mr. Kibana’s still unharmed.
Satoshi’s at an overwhelming
disadvantage!
Can you keep going, Gänger?
Somehow,
it managed to stand back up!
That’s the trainer who fascinated Dande
for you, huh?
You said you wanted to battle Dande,
didn’t you?
The Champion you so admire.
But that’s not gonna be enough!
What’s your reason
for wanting to battle Dande?
It’s gotta be to win!
I’m not gonna lose
to admiration without backbone!
I’ll topple you,
and I’ll topple Dande!
I’m gonna be the Champion!
That’s right. I...
...admire Mr. Dande,
and I’ve wanted to battle him for ages!
But that’s not all!
I wanna beat Mr. Dande!
That’s why I can’t lose here!
Sorry, Lucario.
I’ll Mega Evolve you next time!
Let’s go, Gänger!
Huh?!
He couldn’t be about to...?!
Let’s get huge!
Kyodaimax!
Whoa, Competitor Satoshi’s Gänger
has Kyodaimaxed!
Gänger!
Suck up the Sandstorm!
Kyodai Phantom!
Crunch!
Dai Fairy!
Flygon is unable to battle!
Competitor Satoshi pulls Gänger
out of a crisis using his wits!
Wow! Satoshi!
We did it, Gänger!
You did well, Flygon.
You’re up next...
Numelgon!
Competitor Kibana’s
second Pokémon is Numelgon!
I’ll show you the reason
they call me the Dragon Storm.
Numelgon!
Use Rain Prayer!
Now rain, too?
His strategy of controlling the weather
to steer the battle in his favor...
This is Competitor Kibana
at his best!
When you’re all heated up,
the cold rain really soaks into your skin...
Numelgon, use Thunder!
Gänger!
Surf!
Hydro Pump!
Kyodaimax Gänger
has no way to fight back!
Gänger!
Okay... Got it.
What’s wrong?
Not gonna switch?
Then I’ll take the invitation to defeat it!
Surf!
What’s this?!
It brushed away the Surf!
Great work, Gänger!
Gänger!
Yeah! We’re gonna win!
Go for it! Dai Fairy!
Hydro Pump!
Numelgon and Gänger
are both unable to battle!
Both went down at the same time!
Even the effect of Rain Prayer has vanished!
Thank you, Gänger.
Have a good, long break,
Numelgon.
Satoshi and Mr. Kibana...
Their next Pokémon are their last ones!
I’m counting on you, Lucario!
Here we go, Duraludon!
Competitor Satoshi’s
third Pokémon is Lucario.
Competitor Kibana goes for his
absolute ace, Duraludon.
And Competitor Kibana
still has his trump card of Daimax.
We’re not giving up
‘til it’s over!
We’re gonna win this!
Awesome fighting spirit...
I can tell you’re serious!
And that’s why I’ll go all out to beat...
and crush you!
Duraludon!
What?! Already?!
Bring the storm!
My partner!
Blow the whole stadium away!
Kyodaimax!
There’s Duraludon’s Kyodaimax!
Let’s go, Lucario!
Shadow Clones!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
One more Guiding Wave Sphere!
Dai Steel!
Dodge it!
Lucario!
You’ve fought well
to make it this far.
But...
This is where it ends!
Roar, my dragon!
Time for my ultimate attack...
Kyodai Decay!
Lucario!
No...
I can’t let it end here...
Don’t you agree, Lucario?
What is that...?
This is what he trained
with Gekkouga...
No...
It’s even bigger!
I can feel it...
Our Guiding Wave...
Linking everything...
Lucario! Kyodai Guiding Wave Sphere!
Duraludon! Dai Rock!
Let’s go!
Duraludon is unable to battle!
As such,
the winner is Competitor Satoshi!
We did it!
Lucario, we did it!
Lucario topples the Kyodaimax Duraludon
with a supremely gigantic Guiding Wave Sphere!
He won...
Satoshi!
Satoshi... Kibana...
Thank you for showing me a battle
that couldn’t be topped!
You did your best, Duraludon.
I lost.
Thank you, Mr. Kibana!
Oh, I know.
Got a moment?
Huh?
C’mon, smile!
I’ll be the one to topple you,
and Dande.
So...
You better not lose
to anyone else first.
Right!
Attaboy.
And so, this season’s
Promotion Matches are through.
The Competitors advancing
to the Masters Tournament have been determined.
First we have our winner today,
who has just risen to 8th place, Competitor Satoshi.
In 7th...
The Champion of Isshu,
Competitor Iris.
In 6th...
The winner of the Kalos League
Miare Tournament, Competitor Alain.
In 5th...
The Champion of Kalos,
Competitor Carne.
In 4th...
The Champion of Kanto and Johto,
Competitor Wataru.
In 3rd...
The Champion of Hoenn,
Competitor Daigo.
In 2nd...
The Champion of Sinnoh,
Competitor Shirona.
And, ranked 1st...
The undefeated, unbeatable Champion,
Competitor Dande!
The dream tourney
where these mighty eight will compete...
...the Masters Tournament...
...is nearly here!
Emerging victorious in his fierce battle with Kibana,
Satoshi advances to the Masters Tournament.
From here on, he will partake in
heated matches against even stronger foes!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Your mission this time is survival.
Have Pokémon Battles with the other Challengers,
and come out on top.
Give it your best shot, Go!
So this is Sea Kinsetsu...
There were this many Challengers?!
Go!
Tokio?
Watch out,
we have plenty of strong rivals.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Battle Royale of Betrayal!