The second match of
the Masters Tournament Semifinals.
A full battle between the Champion of Sinnoh, Shirona,
and the first Champion of Alola, Satoshi.
Although Satoshi began
by sending in Kairyu,
Shirona’s tactic of skillfully switching Pokémon
made short work of her.
He even went on to lose Gänger.
But while his ace, Pikachu,
fought hard to bring a comeback into sight,
Pikachu was shockingly taken down
by Mikaruge’s Drag Along!
Launching a desperate counterattack
with Uonoragon and Negigaknight,
he managed to drive off
Roserade and Milokallos.
Yet he ultimately found himself with
only one Pokémon left: Lucario.
And then, Shirona...
Tower over all, white wings!
Daimax Togekiss!
Its wings are spread wide,
as if to cover the entire battlefield!
But what a shock! Who could have guessed
Competitor Shirona would use Daimax?!
It’s so huge...
even that smile feels creepy...
Even Pikachu had trouble with it.
How’s he gonna beat it now?!
I don’t think the brat boy’s
winning this, meow.
I never imagined she would pass up
Mega Evolving Gaburias...
How are you gonna
fight back, Satoshi?
Let’s go, Lucario!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Semifinals IV - "Shock"
Let’s go, Lucario!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
Competitor Satoshi faces
Daimax Togekiss with Mega Lucario!
Now, let’s see how strong
Satoshi and Lucario’s bond is.
Mega Evolution versus Daimax...
Now this is a Masters Tournament!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Togekiss! Dai Jet!
Dive in!
He’s running through it?!
Rush in, Lucario!
Another unbelievable tactic...
Lucario!
Swat it!
It swatted Mega Lucario’s Guiding Wave Sphere
like it was nothing!
Daimax is so strong!
Oh! Daimax Togekiss’s speed
has just risen from the effect of Dai Jet!
We’re not done yet!
Bullet Punch!
Dai Jet!
Jump, Lucario!
What a powerful bound!
It dodged the Dai Jet
and even jumped over Daimax Togekiss!
It’s super effective!
Awesome!
All right! Looking good!
We did it!
Togekiss!
Togekiss doesn’t falter!
What incredible endurance!
Oh! And the repeated Dai Jet
has made its speed rise again!
Lucario! Charge up your Guiding Waves!
Dai Jet!
We’re not done yet!
What do you think
you’re doing, brat boy?!
You’re gonna lose!
You gotta get a grip!
Not good! Not good!
Not good!
Don’t worry!
Satoshi trusts Lucario!
This isn’t going to beat them!
Lucario!
Togekiss, swat it!
This attack...
has gotta... hit!
Kyodai Guiding Wave Sphere!
Guiding Wave Sphere hits its mark!
Both sides are still in the battle!
That Guiding Wave Sphere was incredible!
Yeah... But I can’t believe it withstood that move...
from Mega Lucario, at that!
It’s like Satoshi is evolving,
even during this very battle.
Yeah. He really showed off
the strength of Guiding Wave.
But he’s up against the Champion of Sinnoh.
Brute strength won’t be enough here.
Ms. Shirona...
I’ve decided something.
What is it?
Once this tournament’s over...
I’m retiring from battles.
Huh?!
Ms. Shirona...
I’m really having fun,
Satoshi, Lucario...
Now, Togekiss!
Let’s heat things up even more!
Look at how well Togekiss can move,
even after taking such a big attack!
Bullet Punch!
It’s so fast!
So all those Dai Jets
were leading up to this after all...
Yes.
And the increase in speed
will let it launch moves faster, too.
Lucario, hang in there!
Now!
God Bird!
Lucario! Shadow Clones!
Counter it with Guiding Wave Sphere!
Bullet Punch!
Togekiss is unable to battle!
Return, Togekiss.
You truly fought well.
Thank you.
We did it!
Putting its all into a Bullet Punch,
Mega Lucario marvelously tucks away the win!
He beat Togekiss!
You did it, Mega Lucario!
No way... He really beat it...
Just maybe, he might actually...!
Brat boy!
Show us a “might actually,” meow!
Their bond is
what let them claim victory.
Now, let’s see if they can do it again.
Win or lose,
the next bout will decide it all.
Don’t let your guard down, Satoshi!
One more...
Pikachu...
One more win
and we beat Ms. Shirona!
I’m glad we get to
battle together once again.
Now...
Dance in the heavens, Gaburias!
Now, Competitor Shirona is also on her sixth Pokémon.
We’ve finally reached the climax.
Whoever wins this showdown
will advance to the finals!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gaburias sustained damage
in her battle with Negigaknight.
Mega Lucario’s going right into battle again, too.
They’re on equal footing.
Lucario!
This is our last battle!
Let’s give it all we’ve got,
‘til the very end!
Gaburias...
Looking at Satoshi...
...reminds me of back
when we traveled together.
Everything we saw
felt brand new...
The breadth of the world...
...and the depth of its legends
awed us...
When we were challengers,
ever pushing ourselves.
What a time it was.
We’ll be the ones to face
Competitor Dande!
Scale Shot!
Lucario, jump!
Bullet Punch!
Amazing! Amazing, Mega Lucario!
It rushes straight in without even flinching!
This zeal... I’ve longed for
a Pokémon Battle like this!
Good job, Lucario!
Follow up with Guiding Wave Sphere!
Gaburias!
Guiding Wave Sphere and Scale Shot
cancel each other out!
Lucario!
She doesn’t let her guard down
for a moment...
She makes every move—
every movement— purposeful.
But... If I can beat Ms. Shirona...
I can get stronger!
Dragon Claw!
Bullet Punch!
What an intense exchange of blows!
Neither side is budging!
Charge!
Lucario!
Gaburias, stay strong!
They’re both at their limits!
It’s turned into
a fierce battle of attrition!
Now! Dragon Claw!
Reversal!
Gaburias is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
The fierce fight goes to
We have our finalists!
I won...
I really won...
Lucario!
We did it, Lucario!
We beat Ms. Shirona!
He went and did it!
The finals’ll be
Big Bro and Satoshi!
And it’s gonna be
an incredible battle, yeah!
He... He...
He made it, meow!
Now there’s
an upset for the ages!
He beat the Champions of
Hoenn and Sinnoh! What a...
...Champion Killer!
Huh? Wasn’t our goal...
...commentating
to make some dough and...
...catching strong Pokémon?!
Satoshi... Well done!
Expanding in tow
With Lucario’s Guiding Wave...
The smiles that we wear
Your thoughts?
Now I’m fired up.
I better make
the finals match a blazing one.
Gaburias...
You battled marvelously.
Thank you.
Satoshi.
Thank you!
I should be the one thanking you.
Huh?
All the aspects
you and your Pokémon showed me...
You’ve made me realize
that I still have much more to learn.
Thank you, Satoshi!
Let’s battle again, sometime.
Sure!
The finals are now all that remains for
the Pokémon World Championships Masters Tournament.
Ranked 8th in the Masters Eight;
the first Champion of Alola, Competitor Satoshi.
His opponent is ranked 1st in the Masters Eight;
the Champion of Galar, Competitor Dande.
Now, which one of them will reign
as the top Pokémon Trainer?
Competitor Satoshi? Or Competitor Dande?
Look forward to finding out!
Good work out there.
I lost...
I take back what I said
about retiring from battles.
I thought you’d say that.
I could never quit something
so passionate and so fun.
I have much to master
in battling and in research!
Now that’s the spirit!
Come on out, everyone!
Thank you for today!
You were all really cool!
Next, we’re finally gonna battle
Mr. Dande!
We’ll cheer you on
with all we’ve got too!
We’ve made it this far
and now we’ve gotta win it!
Let’s win this tournament!
Having taken down the formidable Shirona,
Satoshi advances to the finals.
His destined duel with the undefeated Champion Dande
is nearly here!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Next Time :  "GO FOR DREAM!   Go's Road to Mew, His Dream!!"
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Urgent message from Project Mew!
Reading out message!
Greeting someone new is always fresh
“I’m sending important data
pertaining to the search for Mew!
“It may be critical for our mission’s success,
so be sure to look it over, everyone!”
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
2. And we’re laughing or crying
GO FOR DREAM! Go’s Road to Mew, His Dream!!
On 3, let’s be...
Don’t miss it!