Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
The Pokémon World Championships...
A trial to crown
the greatest Pokémon Battler.
Satoshi is currently ranked 99th.
He has finally entered the Hyper Class.
His first opponent will be
Denji from Sinnoh, Nagisa City’s Gym Leader.
Denji is a powerful Electric-type battler
who Satoshi previously faced...
Nagisa City, Sinnoh Region
...when his travels around Sinnoh
led him to Nagisa Gym.
I’m glad we have the chance
to battle again.
Me too, Mr. Denji!
Oh, that’s...
An Alolan Z-Ring, right?
Is that an Electric-Z in there?
This?
It’s a Z-Crystal
made just for me and Pikachu.
You and Pikachu...?
Now I’m even more excited
for today’s battle.
Let’s make it a great one!
Yeah!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
A Super Electromagnetic
Hyper Class Battle!
The Pokémon World Championships!
Nagisa City, the city of the sun,
is the perfect place for a battle this hot!
Sarunori, give them
your best cheer, yeah?
Today, we have
a Hyper Class battle!
And here we have
our two trainers for today’s match!
Currently ranked 27th,
Sinnoh’s strongest Gym Leader: Competitor Denji!
Wow!
Denji sure is popular!
His opponent is a Hyper Class newcomer,
currently ranked 99th: Competitor Satoshi!
Not much enthusiasm
for the away team...
And this battle will be a 3v3!
All right, both sides send out
your Pokémon at the same time.
Go!
Lucario!
Roentorar!
I choose you!
Go!
Roentorar! Gleaming Eyes Pokémon!
Electric type!
It can see through solid objects!
It can track down prey trying to hide behind thick walls!
Battle, start!
Electric Field!
He deployed an Electric Field!
That makes Electric-type moves
more powerful!
I thought you might start
with Electric Field...
Satoshi’s got a few tricks
of his own!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Rising Bolt!
Lucario!
The combo of Electric Field
and Rising Bolt broke through!
That’s so powerful!
Return, Lucario!
Rest up for a while.
That Electric Field is nasty...
Next up... Gänger!
I choose you!
Competitor Satoshi’s
second Pokémon is Gänger!
Roentorar! Bark Out!
It dodged the Bark Out!
What?!
Psychokinesis!
Night Head!
Good job, Gänger!
All right! You can do this!
What a tricky Gänger!
Roentorar can’t move a step!
Return, Roentorar!
Your Gänger
is quite the opponent.
Not much can bewilder
my Roentorar like that.
Gänger!
Go bewilder ‘em some more!
So... how will you fight this?!
Competitor Denji’s second pick
is a Spin Forme Rotom!
Commonly called Spin Rotom!
Rotom! Spin Forme! Plasma Pokémon!
Electric/Flying type!
It has taken over a fan
that has a special motor!
Huh? A fan?
Air Slash!
Use Night Head!
Both of them are
gliding through the air like it’s nothing!
What a fascinating battle!
Gänger! Ice Punch!
EM Wave!
Gänger!
EM Wave makes a direct hit on Gänger!
The Ice Punch didn’t connect!
Paralyzed, huh?
The paralysis status condition...
Now! Evil Eye!
The Evil Eye hit!
This move gets stronger when
the opponent has a status condition!
Competitor Denji overpowers Competitor Satoshi
with combo after combo!
Gänger!
You okay?
Gänger is unable to battle.
Even though it put up a good fight
against Roentorar, Gänger quickly goes down!
Return, Gänger!
Thanks.
You held your ground well.
Oh? The Electric Field’s effect faded!
We better not let Gänger down.
I’m counting on you next!
Pikachu!
Competitor Satoshi’s
third Pokémon is Pikachu!
Pikachu, huh?
It’s a battle between Electric types.
Electric moves can’t deal
much damage to Electric types.
How will they contend with this?!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
He learned Electric Net?
He caught it!
100,000 Volts!
Return, Rotom!
Go! Elecible!
What...?! Already?
Competitor Denji’s
third Pokémon is Elecible!
And right off the bat,
it activated its ability, Electric Engine...
...taking no damage at all!
And when Electric Engine
absorbs an Electric attack, it speeds up!
Elecible...
Now, you’ll get to see
how much faster you’ve made Elecible!
Fire Punch!
Pikachu!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
It’s so fast!
It’s capable of that kind of speed...?
Elecible! Thunder and Lightning Pokémon!
Electric type!
A single Elecible can provide enough electricity
for all the buildings in a big city for a year!
Iron Tail!
We’ll use Iron Tail, too!
Competitor Denji’s Elecible
uses Iron Tail with two tails!
What?!
Do it!
Pikachu can’t get close enough!
What a fearsome
twin-tailed Iron Tail!
Return, Pikachu.
You okay?
Lucario! Go for it!
Competitor Satoshi
switches from Pikachu to Lucario!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Fire Punch!
Wild Bolt!
Shadow Clones!
The Wild Bolt hits
nothing but thin air!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Hit them back!
Thunder Punch!
Oh, no...
Oh? Lucario is paralyzed!
Thunder Punch took effect!
Return, Elecible.
Go, Rotom!
Use Evil Eye!
Competitor Denji skillfully swaps out
his Pokémon to pressure Lucario!
The Evil Eye hit hard!
Lucario can barely move!
Lucario!
It’s now or never... Reversal!
Air Slash!
Lucario gets back up
and lands a Reversal!
The less stamina the user has,
the more damage that Reversal deals!
A spectacular blow!
Rotom: Spin Forme is unable to battle.
All right!
Ooh... The cheers for Satoshi
are getting louder!
Make everyone cheer
even louder, Satoshi!
Good job, Lucario!
Can you keep going?
The Guiding Wave Pokémon
lives up to its fame.
It even shook off
its paralysis with that attack.
Is Lucario going to
win this for him?!
Go! Roentorar!
Competitor Denji sends out
Roentorar once again!
Two left... I know what Pokémon
Mr. Denji has.
Time to finish this quick!
Electric Field!
And there it is!
He takes control of the field again!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Rising Bolt!
Lucario!
Roentorar!
Roentorar and Lucario
are unable to battle.
An incredible double knockout!
Now the battle comes down
to Elecible against Pikachu!
They took each other out...
Thanks, Lucario.
That was a great battle.
This is the last round, Pikachu.
I’m counting on you...
Pikachu!
Go! Elecible!
Both are Electric-types.
Electric attacks won’t do much.
And Elecible’s ability, Electric Engine,
means Pikachu is in for a bad time!
Iron Tail!
Wild Bolt!
How can they be that strong?!
Elecible is completely unfazed
by Wild Bolt’s recoil damage!
Pikachu! You okay?
Electric Field’s effect has faded!
But it’s so huge compared to Pikachu...
What now, Satoshi?!
Elecible! Use Iron Tail!
Meet it with Iron Tail!
Pikachu lands a spectacular blow!
The enormous Elecible stumbles!
You’re quite the opponents,
Satoshi and Pikachu.
Your intensity... Your ferocity...
It just makes us even stronger!
Yeah!
Of course you wanna
use Electric moves!
There it is!
The bond between
Satoshi and Pikachu!
The Sato-Pika-Z!
The Z-Move...
I’ve been waiting for this.
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Pikachu!
10,000,000 Volts!
So that’s 10,000,000 Volts...
Elecible! Absorb it all
with Electric Engine!
A standoff against
10,000,000 Volts of power!
What’s this?!
Elecible is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
I won!
We did it, Pikachu!
It’s over!
Competitor Satoshi
emerges victorious!
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
Taking down Competitor Denji,
Competitor Satoshi rises to 64th
in the Hyper Class!
You battled well, Elecible.
Satoshi!
You did it!
Go! Thanks for cheering for me!
Mr. Denji!
That was a shocking
10,000,000 Volts.
It even overpowered
Electric Engine.
When I heard you were
gonna be my opponent,
I wanted to win
with the strongest Electric move!
You might just become
the eye of the storm...
...that shakes up the Hyper Class...
No, even the Master Class.
The Master Class?
Yes. Shirona, the Champion of Sinnoh,
is part of their ranks.
Ms. Shirona?
In Sinnoh, Satoshi has overcome
his first Hyper Class match.
But he still has
many tough enemies ahead of him.
Now, who will he face next?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Bad news, Director Sakuragi!
What’s wrong, you two?
What’s wrong... you say?
The data... The Pokémon data
you put so much effort into collecting is gone!
What?!
Shishi... Shishishi!
Let’s start with just one, shi...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Sakuragi Institute Is Under Attack!