Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Aww...
I was so close to catching it...
You’ll get more chances.
Great timing.
You have a call waiting, Satoshi.
It’s Arabesque Town’s Gym Leader.
Huh?
It’s been a while, hasn’t it?
Oh, the quiz lady!
She was a Gym Leader...?
Yes. My name is Poplar.
I’m inviting you two to a special tournament.
A tournament?
Huh? Me, too?
I hear Dande’s taken
quite a liking to you two.
That’s why I chose to invite you.
Is Mr. Dande gonna be there too?!
Naturally.
I’ll do it!
I guess I could catch some
Galar Pokémon while I’m there...
I’ll go too!
Good. Okay, I’ll be waiting!
I might get to battle Mr. Dande!
Chances like these
don’t come along too often.
Go and do your best.
Sure!
I’m coming too!
There, there.
I know, I know.
I’d love to spend more time with you,
but I need to get going. See ya!
By the way...
Which way is Arabesque Town?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mawhip's Sweet Battle?!
Arabesque Town, Galar Region
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu have arrived
in Arabesque Town, in Galar.
It looks like they’ve taken a little detour
on the way to the tournament.
It tastes great!
The rumors were true.
The pâtissier here makes amazing cakes!
Right, Eevee?
So this is why you tagged along.
Can you blame me?
I really regretted not coming here
last time we were in town!
Thanks for telling us
about this place, Koharu!
It’s like it tastes of happiness.
The cream is what’s really special.
Look, that’s the pâtissier and
his partner Mawhip over there.
The flavor of Mawhip’s cream changes
depending on how well she gets along with her trainer.
Huh...
Mawhip! Cream Pokémon!
Fairy type!
When Mawhip is content, the cream it secretes
from its hands becomes sweeter and richer!
The pâtissier and Mawhip here
must be really close partners, then!
These are amazing dipped in cream!
Huh?
Oh, is that a Pokémon? It’s cute!
Think it came in here
hoping for some cake?
Who’s that Pokémon?
Mahomil! Cream Pokémon!
Fairy type!
Its body is made of cream!
It was born from
sweet-smelling particles in the air!
Whoa, what’s that for?
Do you want me to catch you?
Okay... Monster Ball, go!
Mahomil’s data will be
added to the Index!
I caught a Mahomil!
Nice to meet you, Mahomil!
Good for you, Go!
Ahh, Sarunori!
Eevee, stop!
Stop it!
Hey!
Do you want some cake?
Here.
Do you want something bigger?
Maybe it wants
the decorative candy atop the cake?
Huh?
This?
Looks like you were right!
I didn’t think you’d be
that happy, Mahomil!
I’m happy I made a new friend, too!
You’ll end up tripping...
Huh?
Is that...?
Already?!
Mawhip’s data will be
added to the Index!
What a surprise!
Mahomil evolve if you spin them around,
just like whisking whipped cream.
She must’ve been very happy
that you gave her that decorative candy.
I’m sure you’ll make great partners.
I get it...
Nice to meet you again, Mawhip!
Hello!
Oh, you’re here.
What kind of tournament
are you doing today?
The whole way here
I’ve been really excited!
Is Mr. Dande here yet?
Just settle down.
Come this way.
Oh, right.
The Gallop and Ponyta
you met in the forest are doing fine.
Really?
Gallop!
I’ve been wondering how they were.
That’s great to hear!
Mr. Dande!
Huh?
It’s Mr. Kibana...
If Mr. Kibana of the Masters Eight is here too,
this must be a huge tournament...
Oh... Weren’t you...?
I’ll beat Mr. Dande and become
the strongest Pokémon Trainer!
You’re that energetic kid
from back then!
What’s your name?
I’m Satoshi!
This is my partner, Pikachu.
I see. So you’re the Satoshi
that Dande’s been talking about.
Yeah!
But...
Dande himself isn’t here...
Did he make a run for it...?
Mr. Dande wouldn’t run away!
He’d never run from a battle!
Huh? I’d be running too,
if only I could.
You’re not getting away.
I know full well that if I ran
I’d just be asking for trouble.
I’ve never been able to
disobey this old hag. Or rather...
Maybe we should be getting back...
Right...
You’ll also be competing,
of course.
Huh?!
Us, too?!
You even have the perfect Pokémon.
Sorry, I ended up being late.
You took your time, Dande...
Oh, you’re here too, Satoshi?
Mr. Dande,
I’ve been looking forward to seeing you!
I really wanted to battle you!
Well, that’s up to
Ms. Poplar, I guess...
Huh?
So, what sort of game
have you got for us today, Ms. Poplar?
All of you had better
prepare yourselves.
Hosted by Poplar, loved by everyone!
The first Mawhip Everywhere
Decor Tournament starts now!
What’s that mean?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mawhip
Fairy
What’s a Decor Tournament?
Some sort of battle?
Umm...
You’ll each team up with
one of these Mawhip and decorate cakes.
Look at all the Mawhip!
There’s so many different ones!
They’re colorful!
Their decorative candies
are all different, too.
A Mawhip’s trainer
affects the taste of her cream.
What does the cream of
a strong trainer taste like?
What about a kind trainer?
Or an excited trainer?
Doesn’t it make you want to
taste them all...?
More nonsense...
Ms. Poplar holds tournaments
at the drop of a hat
Sometimes they involve battles...
But not today, I guess.
I really wanted to battle Mr. Dande...
Always give it your all!
Whoever has the most fun wins!
Mr. Dande...
Yeah!
It looks kinda fun!
I’ve never made a cake before.
Have you?
With my mom, at least.
Now, each of you should
pick your Mawhip partner.
I’ll use my own Mawhip, of course.
I’m counting on you!
Uh...
Oh, would you mind
being my partner?
Think you can work with me
and give it all you’ve got?
What’s this?
You’re running away?
When Dande’s so eager?
Wh-Who’d try and run?
I’ll never say no to a challenge,
and I’ll never lose!
Now, you stand out.
You’re perfect for me!
What do you think?
Great photo, huh?
Hmm...
They’ve got a great sweet scent!
This one smells the best!
She’s a Caramel Mix.
That settles it!
Mawhip,
please be my partner!
Okay, looks like everyone’s
made their choice.
Now then... To your positions!
And... Start!
Here goes!
Let’s do it!
Pour a generous amount of
whipped cream over the sponge!
Use a palette knife
to flatten and spread it!
Rotate the turntable to cover
the sides with cream as well!
Looks like the start is
the most important...
Thanks, Mawhip!
Give us some
super tasty cream, Mawhip!
Wow!
Now, I just need to cover it in this...
Okay!
Huh?
My mom taught me that when the cream’s too runny,
you should whisk it while cooling it with ice.
Makes sense...
Thanks, Koharu!
Okay, Sarunori!
Hold the bowl for me!
Now this is fun.
I’m gonna make
the world’s tastiest cake!
Go wild, my partner!
This cream’s really good!
It smells great, too!
All right! It’s covered!
Go for it, Pikachu!
And turn!
That’s it! Eevee, you’ve got it!
Hey, Sarunori!
Stop snacking on the cream!
That was really helpful, Mawhip.
Thanks!
Oh, Sarunori!
Some of these...
And I’ll add some of these too!
So? Makes for a pretty picture,
doesn’t it?
That was a lot of fun.
How about this?
I based it on Mawhip.
It looks tasty!
Now that’s pretty good!
Really? How’s yours?
Well...
Sarunori licked off all the cream...
Look at my cake, too!
Ta-daaah!
Hmm... It’s very... unique.
That doesn’t look tasty.
Okay, looks like everyone’s done.
Let’s try it.
It has a strong sweetness
with quite the kick.
But it has a rich flavor,
and a fragrant aroma.
The taste I would expect
from the champion’s personality.
I’m glad you like it.
A flashy appearance,
and complex flavors beneath.
At first glance, the gaudiness
may give you pause,
but it’s a reliable, unquestionable
top-class cake underneath.
Didn’t I tell you?
I’ll never say no to a challenge,
and I’ll never lose!
My Pokémon ate it all...
If your friend is content
with the cream already,
it shows you and Mawhip
will get on well together.
Right!
You have a kind heart
that truly values Pokémon, don’t you?
I can tell just from the taste.
I see why Ponyta and Gallop liked you.
Thank you!
Now, the last cake...
Well, this is quite creative...
Mawhip made tasty cream for me!
So I wanted to
make the cake real tasty!
There’s a thrill to
a taste which you can’t even predict...
And a mysterious taste
that makes you hungry for more!
How intriguing!
Does that mean it’s tasty?
Now I want to try it, too...
I know! I’ll battle you!
Battle?
Wait, what’s going on now?!
You’re the trainer behind this cream.
I bet your battles are also intriguing.
Just like that?
I’m the host of the tournament.
I am the rules!
Hurry up, everyone!
Get to your positions!
Right!
Well, I should know to expect
her crazy ideas by now, but still...
Satoshi’s bound to give her
an intriguing battle, though.
Go for it, Satoshi!
Go for it!
I’ll be the judge, then.
Both sides, send out your Pokémon.
Pikachu, I choose you!
Come on out, Mawhip!
Yet another Mawhip color...
Battle, start!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Iron Tail!
Keep up the Iron Tail!
That Pikachu’s pretty fast.
But...
Okay! Great work, Pikachu!
My, my, you certainly are hasty.
It didn’t work?!
Take a good look
at your own Pokémon.
I get it! The Iron Tail got weaker
because of all the cream stuck to it!
I never knew you
could use it like that...
Now then, why don’t we get started?
Attract!
Magical Shine!
Pikachu!
Is it over?
Can you keep going, Pikachu?
Magical Shine!
Electric Net!
All right!
My, you’re not half bad.
Are you prepared?
I’m going to have some fun with this.
There!
Kyodaimax Mawhip!
Kyodai Finale!
Pikachu!
That’s it for him.
You okay, Pikachu?!
Pikachu Kyodaimaxed, too?!
Hmm...
Now this is getting interesting.
Now that’s a surprise!
Pikachu!
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Pikachu?
What’s going on?
That’s no Kyodaimax.
He just ate the cream
and grew fatter...
He’s Bloatmaxed!
Whaaat?!
My, my, looks like it’s over.
Won’t make for a nice photo,
but how’s the taste...?
This is...!
Satoshi’s cake...
It tastes great!
Yeah, that’s true!
They each taste different,
but each one is tasty.
I’m glad I held this tournament.
Now then, when should I
schedule the second one...?
Huh?
Mr. Dande!
I’m gonna win my way up
through the Championships so I can battle you!
I’m looking forward to it.
Yeah!
Go has caught a Mawhip.
Satoshi has once again
resolved to battle Dande.
Their adventure together
continues.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokallos
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
You’re the Champion of Sinnoh,
Ms. Shirona, yeah?!
We heard it was always night in this town
and came to check it out.
Someone in the town told us a certain Pokémon
might be involved, so we came here to investigate.
A certain Pokémon?
Py became a star.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Py That Became A Star