Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Go! You look good in that uniform!
Yeah? Well, I look good
in everything, you know!
Let’s get going already.
I’ll be off, then.
I’m off.
See you later!
So there you were.
A Fire Stone.
Still no evolution today, I see.
We still don’t know that for sure.
What’s up next?
A Thunder Stone.
Why won’t you evolve?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Koharu and the Very Mysterious Eevee!
How come you haven’t
caught any Pokémon, Koharu?
I have Wanpachi.
Wanpachi belongs to
the Director, yeah?
I’m talking about catching
your own Pokémon.
Maybe I won’t.
You won’t?! Why?
People make it out like I have to catch Pokémon
just because I’m a professor’s daughter.
It doesn’t feel right.
I had that happen to me in a class about
our future aspirations a while back.
Ah...
Uh, sorry, then.
Don’t worry about it!
My mom told me that a day will come
when I’ll get to decide my own path.
I’m sorry for making you apologize.
Go! Koharu!
Good morning.
Good morning!
I kept my promise perfectly, yeah?
Promise?
To make sure to be at school
when there’s a test!
And promises should be kept!
I’ll see you in the classroom, then.
You promised her that?
Well, yeah.
Oh, right. Don’t forget to
leave that Pokémon in the garden.
Messon!
Go, Aceburn!
Take care of Messon
until I come back, yeah?
Look...
It’s a mountain of treasure!
There’s so many Pokémon
at this school!
We’ll take them all
for Team Rocket, meow.
It’s settled.
There! There she is!
Hey! Hold it!
Don’t run away!
Wait, special Eevee!
Wanpachi!
Why does Wanpachi
run off on his walks...?
There?
Wanpachi... and an Eevee?
Hold on!
Eevee!
Who’re those guys?
Yeah. Let’s follow them!
Sneakity-sneak...
I am an actress.
There is no role I cannot perform!
Yeah! I can even play a cute
and spry pwetty widdle schoolgirl!
That’s an actress’s fate!
That is my fate!
Spry, huh...?
Nobody uses that word
anymore, meow...
There she is!
Is this right...?
It’ll have to do.
Next question...!
Oh! I studied this with Renji!
All right! Thanks, Renji!
Miss!
What is it? Koharu?
Ah, uh, um, dad’s, uh, pachi...
Oh! Well, hurry back!
Wanpachi!
What’s wrong?
Where’s that Eevee...?!
Once we find her,
she’s not getting away again!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Eevee
Normal
We... completely lost
track of Wanpachi...
Isn’t this Koharu and Go’s...?
What is it, Koharu?
Why’d you call me out here?
Shh!
Wanpachi?
An Eevee?!
That’s why I went, shh! Shh!
Sorry. But why do you
have an Eevee, Koharu?
Uh...
Eevee’s an amazing Pokémon,
with eight confirmed evolutions!
Eight?! That is amazing.
So, why are you hiding?
It looks like she’s being chased...
Huh?
By them!
Where are you? Eevee!
Come on out!
Yeah...
They do look suspicious.
See?
Don’t worry. I’ll look after you.
Eevee!
Where are you?!
Got it. I’ll do something
about them.
Huh?
Koharu, you run
when you get the chance!
Go?
What’s wrong?!
Old lady, are you visitors here?!
Old lady?!
No, it’s more, umm...
Should I call a teacher?!
Oh, no...
You don’t need to do that...
Don’t tell me that
you’re trespassers?!
Let’s go, Wanpachi.
There she is! Eevee!
Run for it, Koharu!
Thank you!
Whatta wot of suction powah!
Hey! Don’t get in our way!
That’s why we have hyper mode!
What a big catch!
Success, meow!
What are you doing?!
I saw that!
The Pokémon were fighting back!
The bwat boy?!
And Pikachu...!
Owww...
We thought that might happen,
so we dug a pit,
and good thing we did, meow!
Hold it!
What now?
Brat boy #2?
And a brat girl?!
What’s this?
You’re not getting away!
Hand over Eevee!
We will not!
Yeah! We’re not letting bad guys like you
take this Eevee!
Go?
Oh, no, we’re not bad guys...
It’s a misunderstanding!
We’re researchers from
the Eevee Evolution Laboratory.
The Eevee Evolution...
Laboratory?
Hey! Go! Koharu!
Are you there?!
Satoshi?
Those guys up there sucked Pokémon up
into a machine!
The Pokémon are gone...!
Messon! Aceburn!
Give the Pokémon back!
If you say “Give the Pokémon back!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
So they were Team Rocket...!
Capsules, c’mon!
Ready, set...
Rocket...
Capsul-et...
I wonder, what’ll I be getting?
Secret!
Huh? Why’s nothing coming?
Is it not working?
Stop it, Kojiro!
No luck?
Hey! Pelipper!
No Monster Balls came out!
You’d better take responsibility for this!
You hear that?!
Still, it’s not going to come back...
It came back!
So you will take
responsibility? Great!
Okay! Kojiro, you command it!
Huh?
Wanpachi...
All right.
Good job! Go for it, Wanpachi!
Pelipper! Wing Attack!
Wanpachi! Spark!
Wanpachi!
Eevee?
Eevee...
You want to battle?
What are you doing, Kojiro?!
Hurry up with the next move,
have, have it do something!
Pelipper, use Hydro Pump!
Hydro Pump is
a super strong move, meow!
Wanpachi! Eevee! Spark!
Did you... see that?
Y-Yeah...
You did great,
Eevee! Wanpachi!
Now’s our chance...
Let’s get out of here...
Quick, meow!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Aceburn! Messon!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
You did it, Pikachu!
We’ve caused you
so much trouble.
We’re very sorry
for everything.
Oh, don’t worry, it seems these two
misunderstood what was going on.
Sorry...
Oh, it’s nothing.
We’ll be off then.
Eevee?!
This Eevee
really loves Koharu, huh?
It appears so.
She’s a pretty mysterious Eevee.
She won’t evolve whatever we try.
She won’t evolve into
any of the eight Pokémon?
Right.
Eevee have unstable genes in general,
so maybe that one’s genes are more unstable than most.
Or perhaps... Maybe she’s hesitant,
unable to decide what path she should take.
Hesitant...
Though that’s not
a very scientific perspective.
Hey, Koharu...
If you wouldn’t mind,
do you think you could look after Eevee?
Huh?
You want to stay
with Koharu, don’t you?
Eevee...
If you say it’s okay...!
Thank you.
So your first catch
is an Eevee, huh?
Here!
She’s telling you she’s ready!
Eevee...
I want to stay with you, too!
That’s your first catch!
A great success!
Come on out, Eevee!
They’ve already made friends!
That’s great to see.
Koharu. I put a Rotom in here.
A Smartphone Rotom
for Koharu?
Go on, try it out!
Right!
Eevee!
Eevee. Evolution Pokémon. Normal type.
It has a very unstable genetic makeup.
This Pokémon conceals many different possible evolutions.
Many different possibilities
for evolution...
Maybe she’s hesitant,
unable to decide what path she should take.
Let’s take things one step at a time.
Together.
Koharu caught Eevee,
and finally became a Pokémon Trainer.
Many possibilities stretch out
before them.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’m Gasattsu.
Here to dig up fossils.
You lookin’ for fossils too?
Yeah!
You’re late, Ukattsu!
Well, I forgot to
set my alarm clock...
You’re so careless...
Ta-daah!
The fossil restoration device!
With this, we can restore
the fossil pieces!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Galar's Fossils!
Stick 'em Together!!
Galar’s Fossils!
Stick ‘em Together!