Satoshi, who dreams of
becoming a Pokémon Master...
And Go, who has found his goal of
catching every Pokémon to work his way towards Mew.
A fun and exciting life with Pokémon
awaits these two again today!
Slowly... Slowly...
Why am I doing this?
It’s good for your health,
so why not?
Kung-fu exercises with everyone,
first thing in the morning!
Geez...
This is pretty tough.
How is Barrierd so steady?
Its torso must be in shape.
Hibunny.
Don’t push yourself too hard.
L-Like this?
What? Like that?
That’s supposed to
be an example?
No, I’m sure this is...
I just heard a weird noise.
Wait, aren’t Trancell’s insides...?
A-A-A-Are you okay?!
Dad, calm down!
That’s a rock!
Trancell, are you hurt?!
What a relief.
Go!
Let’s go to the Hoenn Region!
What?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Fierce Battles in the Hoenn Region!
Face the Battle Frontier!!
Battle Frontier, Hoenn Region
The Battle Frontier
Glass Flute Cup!
A place of fierce battles
and strong battlers!
Bring two Pokémon and win your way
up the ranks in Single Battles!
The winner gets this set of
five colored Glass Flutes!
Come join the Battle Frontier Glass Flute Cup,
and let’s have some Pokémon Battles!
I see.
And?
Who did you enter?
Pikachu and...
...Barrierd!
Barrierd, huh?
Wait, Barrierd?!
Can it even battle?
What’s with that bizarre smile?!
“Putting that aside...”
No, I can’t put it aside!
I’m worried!
Who did you enter, then?
I’m going with Hibunny and...
Who’d be the best at battling here...?
Kaiross! You!
You want to go, Strike?
Strike, huh?
This is gonna be loads of fun!
I’m really getting fired up!
You really love
Pokémon Battles, don’t you?
Yeah! It’s hard to explain,
but I kinda feel like I can do anything
when I’m with my Pokémon!
What about you?
Well... I’m not really sure yet.
Look at you,
saying stuff like that again.
You came with me, didn’t you?
Only because you signed me up
without asking!
Besides...
A Pokémon?!
Let’s get it, Hibunny!
We’re gonna catch ourselves
some Hoenn Pokémon!
I see...
It’s Hariteyama!
Is it participating too?
Hariteyama. Arm Thrust Pokémon.
Fighting type.
They love to compare their freakish strength—
strength enough to send a truck flying with a single slap.
What?! A battle already?!
If that’s how it is,
I’m not gonna lose!
Hey, you.
Yeah?
Could you move?
Sorry!
Don’t sweat it.
Y-You all right?!
Yeah... I’m f-fine...
That didn’t hurt! Not at all!
Monster Ball, go!
Excellent!
Subame’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Subame feeds on Kemusso
that live in forests.
Which means...
If we follow it,
we might meet Kemusso!
What’s this?
I’m Satoshi.
This is my partner, Pikachu.
And this is Barrierd.
I’m Hoji from Fuen Town.
And this is Hariteyama.
Does that mean you signed up
with Hariteyama?
Sure did.
And who else?
Can’t tell you.
Can’t show my hand to
a guy I might end up battl—
Graena!
Go!
Prepare yourself, Graena!
I’ll catch you this time for sure!
Hold it!
This is my Pokémon!
So your other Pokémon is Graena!
Darn it... And here I thought
I’d get to catch a Graena,
but it belongs to this guy...
I’ve got a name, and it’s Hoji!
Anyway, check this out, Satoshi!
You caught yourself a Subame, Go?
Of course I did!
And I’m gonna keep catching
tons of more stuff!
Well, ain’t you cute?
Are you making fun of me?!
No I ain’t.
I just think your sincerity’s cute.
You are making fun of me!
Why me?!
Me again?!
Those two are great friends, huh?
Yeah...
Oh, I got the tournament brackets.
Lemme see!
I see... My first opponent’s
this guy, huh?
I have a name, and it’s Go!
I ain’t losing!
The Battle Frontier Glass Flute Cup
is finally starting!
The first battle is Go from Kuchiba City
versus Hoji from Fuen Town!
Go! Hoji!
Give us a good battle!
S-Sure...
Now, who will they send out first?!
C’mon!
Amazing...
It’s got a totally different vibe
from before.
Evil types are weak to Bug types.
Strike has the advantage!
We can win this match!
But we’d better play it safe!
Let the battle begin!
Boost your attack power!
Strike! Swords Dance!
Fire Fang!
Oh, my! Strike was
caught off guard!
It’s super effective!
Strike is unable to battle!
Graena wins!
Sorry! My plan was bad.
So sorry...
You’re right! We just gotta
win the next match!
Now Competitor Go
sends out Hibunny!
Let’s put some pressure
on them, Hibunny!
Use Double Kick!
Bark Out!
Now, Graena! Crunch!
Hibunny?!
Hibunny is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is Competitor Hoji!
Competitor Hoji is strong!
He advanced to the second round
in an instant!
Well done, Graena!
Hibunny...
Go...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Graena
Evil
We’ve restored your Pokémon
to full health.
Thank you.
Hibunny... Strike...
Go, cheer up.
Catching is better after all.
I’m gonna go look for Kemusso!
Go!
Watch our battles, okay?
Come on, Hibunny, Strike!
Amazing! Satoshi from Masara Town and Pikachu
demonstrate remarkable strength!
Overwhelming strength!
Hoji from Fuen Town
has no equal!
The Battle Frontier Glass Flute Cup
has reached the finals at last!
It comes down to a battle between
Satoshi from Masara Town and Hoji from Fuen Town!
I made it!
You’re up!
What?! Barrierd?!
There’s no way...
It couldn’t possibly beat that thing!
Let the battle begin!
Get ‘em, Hariteyama!
Use Force Palm!
Oh, no!
Dodge it, Barrierd!
They managed to dodge it!
Keep using Force Palm!
Amazing!
Hariteyama keeps launching powerful shockwaves,
but Barrierd is dodging them all!
Good! Keep it up!
It sways from side to side, seemingly about to fall
yet standing strong! Such mysterious movements!
Are these its kung-fu exercises?
Will you stand still?!
Now, Barrierd! Focus Punch!
All right!
Barrierd can battle like that?!
Don’t stop! Use Arm Thrust!
Reflector!
Barrierd guards itself against
Hariteyama’s Arm Thrust!
We’re not done...
Arm Thrust!
Reflector!
When did it...?!
A-Amazing! Hariteyama has been
locked in place by Barrierd’s Reflectors!
We’ll finish it now, Barrierd!
Psychokinesis!
Hariteyama?!
Yeah!
Hariteyama is unable to battle!
Barrierd wins!
All right! You did it, Barrierd!
Strong! So strong!
I have gained a newfound
respect for Barrierd!
You fought well, Hariteyama.
Graena’s up next!
Let’s do this, Barrierd!
Oh, my! Barrierd seems to have
lost the will to fight!
Got it!
Then you can take a nice, long rest!
You’re up, Pikachu!
He switches to Pikachu!
Use Bark Out!
Lightning Speed!
Keep going! Iron Tail!
Graena, use Crunch!
Don’t let them scare you, Pikachu!
Hit them with 100,000 Volts!
Don’t let ‘em, Graena!
Bark Out!
Wh-What a battle!
A breathtaking exchange of moves!
The two have truly earned
their spot in the finals!
You can’t even blink!
This is...
This is a Pokémon Battle?!
You all right, Pikachu?
Let’s finish this!
Graena, use Surprise Attack!
Oh, my! There’s no knowing
where the attack will come from now!
What will you do, Satoshi?
Now! Get him, Graena!
All right!
We’re not done, Pikachu!
Send an Electric Net upwards!
What is Pikachu doing?!
It launched an Electric Net
in entirely the wrong direction!
What?!
Now use Iron Tail!
Dodge it, Graena!
Graena is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
U-Unbelievable!
Satoshi and Pikachu used the force
of Graena’s attacks against it!
Competitor Satoshi achieves
an unquestionable victory!
You did it, Pikachu!
The winner of the Battle Frontier Glass Flute Cup
is Satoshi from Masara Town!
Thank you very much!
Satoshi.
That was the best battle
I’ve ever had!
Yeah, it really was fun!
Congratulations on winning,
Satoshi, Pikachu!
Thanks!
Barrierd, you were really cool too!
Oh, and...
Um...
Pokémon Battles...
...sure are fun, huh?
Yeah!
What’s the deal with these Kemusso?
Go caught them in
the Hoenn Region!
But why are there three?
You never know if Kemusso will evolve
into Karasalis or into Mayuld, you know!
They’re evolving!
What?! Already?!
Just kidding!
Ow!
You deserved that one.
Nice kick!
Experiencing plenty of
different battles,
Satoshi and Go have once more seen
how fun life with Pokémon can be!
Tomorrow, more dreams and adventures await
in the world of Pocket Monsters!
Let’s go!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
A lost Pochama?!
It swam here
from the Sinnoh Region?!
You saved Pochama?
The Drift Ice Race is starting today!
Ooh! Sounds fun!
Go, Tamanta!
You hang in there too, Pikachu!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Don’t lose, Pochama!
The Sinnoh Region Drift Ice Race!!
Don't Lose, Pochama!