Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
All right, I’ll go first!
Sure!
How’s that?!
What is that?
Where’s its face?!
Oh, come on!
It’s right here!
This is its face!
I got this in the bag.
And what do you call that?!
What’s wrong with its body?!
It’s standing like this! See?!
Mine’s definitely better.
No, mine is the best!
Pikachu, which do you think is better?
Mine or Go’s?
Which looks more like Gaburias?
Rabbifoot?
Look, Go!
It’s the ocean!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Farewell,
Rabbifoot!
Mishiro Town, Hoenn Region
Here we are,
in the Hoenn Region once again!
Destination: Mishiro Town!
The Pokémon Center is
right down this road!
Four days here, huh?
We’ve gotta do a thorough job
as research fellows for the Sakuragi Institute!
Yeah! We’ll watch every second
of the Agehunt’s relaxation!
Yeah! We’ll study their
relaxation patterns real carefully...
No, wrong!
We’re not here for their relaxation!
It’s their migration!
Really?
We could see it somewhere along
Mishiro Town’s coastline, right?
Yeah.
Agehunt migration is a rare phenomenon
that can only be observed for a brief time each year.
Study it as carefully as you can!
In order to find
an easier environment to live in,
they fly thousands of kilometers
together with their kin!
Isn’t it amazing?
I’m so excited!
It’s a Kemusso!
All right...
Let’s catch it, Rabbifoot!
I swear... That Rabbifoot...
Hadn’t you already
caught Kemusso?
Yeah... But I want to evolve one again.
Thank you for having us!
It’ll be my pleasure.
Um, we’re here to study
the Agehunt migration.
Do you know where we should go?
I’m not sure,
since the spot is different each year...
But the migration always happens
on days when the northern wind is strong.
Northern wind?
I see!
The Agehunt are heading south,
so they wait for a strong
tailwind from the north to fly!
A headwind would be
more fun, though...
Maybe for a Satoagehunt...
What a wind!
But I won’t lose!
I actually pictured it...
The ocean sure is wide!
It’s massive!
The wind is blowing
from the Southeast today...
That’d be a headwind
for the Agehunt.
So no migration?
Probably not.
But I’m sure they’re
on standby somewhere!
Agehunt! Butterfly Pokémon!
Bug/Flying type!
Its colorfully patterned wings are its most prominent feature,
and its favorite food is the sweet pollen of flowers!
Pollen of flowers, huh?
Let’s check over there!
I-Isn’t that...
A Zigzaguma!
Hey, are you okay?
Hang in there!
It doesn’t look injured...
It was just fine...
What was that?
I’m just glad it wasn’t hurt.
Yeah.
Something wrong,
Rabbifoot?
Gotta do some research...
Not a single Agehunt
to be found...
None of the flowers that might have pollen
were in bloom, either.
Where do we look now?
Kemusso!
What? Where, where?!
There!
I missed it again...
I wanted to evolve it
into Karasalis...
Oh, right. All the ones you caught
last time turned into Mayuld.
Hang on!
Go?
I know... I got it!
Got what?
Karasalis!
We should’ve looked for Karasalis!
I see! Agehunt evolve
from Karasalis...
...and then they migrate!
All right! Any places nearby
where we might find Karasalis?
There’s a grove!
Let’s go looking tomorrow!
Yeah!
I’m so excited,
I’m not sure I can sleep!
Yeah! I’m excited, too!
Of course!
Rabbifoot, where were you?
Rabbifoot...
Delicious! Go, these
Mishiro Croquettes are amazing!
Go?
What’s wrong?
You’re not hungry?
Oh, it’s not that...
Does your stomach hurt?
No, it doesn’t.
There!
It’s a horde of Karasalis!
We did it, Go!
Yeah! There’ll be
a headwind all day,
so there’s a good chance
the migration will be tomorrow!
Then let’s come check tomorrow!
I wonder if the Agehunt will fly?
I can’t wait to see!
How about you, Pikachu?
Oh, yeah... How do you think
the Karasalis evolve?
I think they go like this...
...and then this!
Ooh, like that?
You two really are close...
Would you like one?
I think Rabbifoot’s hungry.
Huh?
Didn’t you have breakfast?
Thank you!
That’s amazing, Rabbifoot...
You can eat that much?
Hey, can I have one?
Hey...
Why?!
I get it! I wouldn’t want anyone
asking me for my precious croquettes, either!
Not even one?
Not a chance!
Oh, come on!
Rabbifoot, I don’t get you!
I don’t know why, but you’ve been
acting like this ever since you evolved!
You don’t follow my lead...
You don’t high-five me...
You don’t even look me in the eyes!
Will you stop reacting like that?!
Sheesh...!
Do you hate me that much?
Reminds me of my son.
I think your Pokémon’s
in its rebellious phase.
Acting all cold and distant every day,
and never being happy with anything you do...
You just have to give it time.
It just happens at that age.
Oh, I see.
Rebellious phase?
Just happens at that age?
I see... I see!
You’ve snuck out
two days in a row...
Where are you going,
and why?
Oh, no... I lost sight of it!
What’s that?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Agehunt
Flying
Bug
Hurry, hurry!
Go, do we still have time?
Yeah!
But the northern wind is
getting stronger by the minute!
The migration is starting soon,
no doubt!
Well?
They’re evolving!
A-Awesome!
This is the Agehunt migration...
Go, are you sure
you don’t want to catch any?
Are you sure
you don’t want to battle them?
I just feel like...
I know what you mean.
The Agehunt migration
was so beautiful!
Yeah.
And we got it all recorded,
so now it’s back home for us tomorrow!
Um, Satoshi...
Actually...
It really did leave.
Yeah.
I lost sight of it
along the way yesterday.
Come on...
You should have said something sooner!
Sorry!
Let’s go!
H-Huh?
We lost sight of it again...
I heard this noise
yesterday, too.
Let’s go!
What is this?
Look!
A... A dance?!
Rabbifoot is teaching them
to dance?
Those apples!
They’re the ones you bought!
Does this mean...?
Has Rabbifoot taken in the Hasubrero
and Zigzaguma as its little brothers?
Huh? Does that mean Rabbifoot...
...became the new leader
around here?
It really can smile...
What?
Is that...?
Dogomb! Loud Voice Pokémon!
Normal type!
It shouts loudly by inhaling air, and then using
its well-developed stomach muscles to exhale!
What’s about to happen?
They stopped dancing!
The Dogomb are
throwing off their rhythm!
Now the Dogomb
have started dancing!
I got it!
This is a dance battle!
They’re fighting over territory
with dance!
There’s more than enough
food and trees to subsist on here.
They’re deciding who gets to live here
through a dance battle!
Rabbifoot wants to help
the Hasubrero and Zigzaguma!
It wants to help them
dance better!
Don’t let Dogomb’s sound
throw you off!
Focus on this rhythm!
All right! Us, too!
Now...
Go!
It’s a dance battle, right?
So let’s dance!
Come on!
Go’s late...
You look so content...
Farewell, Rabbifoot.
Satoshi.
Go! You’re late...
Huh? Where’s Rabbifoot?
I left it behind.
What?!
Didn’t you go to pick it up?!
I did...
But this is for the best.
How is this for the best?!
You know how Rabbifoot
has seemed so bored lately, yeah?
It wasn’t because of some rebellious phase...
I’m sure it was all my fault.
I think it’ll have a happier life
without me.
Is that really
what you’ve decided?
Yeah, I’m serious.
I won’t stop you
if you’re serious. But...
Did you tell Rabbifoot?
Rabbifoot!
Rabbifoot! Rabbifoot!
Rabbifoot... Why?
You smiled...
Okay! I understand!
Let’s be together!
That’s great, Go!
Yeah! Right, Rabbifoot?
Walking at a slight distance...
Dancing passionately...
Rabbifoot can be quite a handful.
But Go wasn’t about to mind
a complicated partner.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Pokémon in Sakuragi Park
are fighting?!
Maybe someone’s been hogging
all the Pokémon food?
Is this Golugh’s Rain Prayer?!
No, Rain Prayer couldn’t do this!
The Mayuld!
Oh, no... They might not be able
to evolve like this!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Massive Panic!
Sakuragi Park!
Massive Panic! Sakuragi Park!