Bari-bari...
Bari Channel
Main MC
Bari-chan
...and I’m Assistant Kikuna.
Assistant
Kikuna
And today,
I’m here to assist Bari-chan.
Bari Channel is
about to begin!
Bari-chan,
glad to be working with you!
Now then,
here on Bari Channel,
we’ll delve into the strange, strange
world of Pokémon and...
Bari-bari
...vigorously...
...investigate its secrets!
The theme for our memorable
first episode will be...
Bari-chan...
I haven’t said what it is yet.
The first episode’s theme
is the following:
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The Sakuragi Institute’s
Seven Mysteries.
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
Seeking a solution!
This is the Sakuragi Institute,
and we’ll showcase some of the
strange things that happen here.
Bari-chan,
do the thing!
The Sakuragi Institute's Seven Mysteries
The Eevee
that doesn’t evolve
The disappearing
Pokémon food
The gnashing
that never stops
Dredear vs Himenka
vs Kaiross
The path of Suicune
An odd guest
at Sakuragi Park
The “Boss Wanpachi”
theory
These are the Sakuragi Institute’s
Seven Mysteries!
Bari-chan,
any of these catch your eye?
Then today we’ll vigorously investigate
the Eevee that doesn’t evolve!
bari-bari
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Koharu and Eevee
The Tracks of Evolution
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The mysterious "Eevee that doesn't evolve"
By the way, Bari-chan...
If we’re going to be reporting about Eevee,
then naturally,
you must know all about Eevee, right?
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The mysterious "Eevee that doesn't evolve"
And so, let’s begin with this!
Eevee Quiz!
We’ll have you take a quiz on Eevee right now!
Eevee Quiz
8 questions total
4 seconds each
Eevee Quiz
8 questions total
4 seconds each
Everyone at home watching Bari Channel,
you should give it a try, too!
Bari-chan, are you ready?
Then...
The Eevee quiz starts! V!
Which one is Eevee?
What type is Eevee?
Answer
Normal type
What Pokémon is Eevee?
Answer
Evolution Pokémon
How many evolutions does Eevee have?
Answer
8 kinds
Which Eevee is female?
The tail has a heart pattern
What about Eevee is unstable?
Answer
Its genes
Which one is taller?
Which one is heavier?
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The mysterious "Eevee that doesn't evolve"
And it’s over!
Good work, Bari-chan!
With that, we’ve gone over
the basics of Eevee.
Evolution is always on your mind
when thinking about Eevee.
And that’s precisely why Koharu’s
Eevee that doesn’t evolve...
Hmm...
...is a mystery, indeed.
So, to begin with,
what exactly is Pokémon evolution?
What is Evolution?
When Pokémon evolve, their appearances
and capabilities change greatly.
Fushigidane
Hitokage
Zenigame
When Pokémon evolve, their appearances
and capabilities change greatly.
Fushigisou
Lizard
Kameil
Fushigibana
Lizardon
Kamex
Barrierd
Manene
Pokémon evolve in many different ways.
Some can evolve into different forms
in different environments.
There are even Pokémon which evolve
differently in different environments.
Evolve in the Galar region
Barrierd
(Galarian Form)
Showers
Thunders
Booster
Eefee
Blacky
Leafia
Glacia
Nymphia
Eevee is particularly easy to influence,
with eight evolutions discovered.
Eevee has eight possible evolutions.
Eevee is particularly easy to influence,
with eight evolutions discovered.
Showers
Thunders
Booster
Blacky
Leafia
Glacia
Nymphia
Eefee
That’s the highest amount
out of any known Pokémon.
Showers
Thunders
Booster
It’s said to be influenced by its surroundings
more easily than other Pokémon.
Booster
Eefee
Blacky
Leafia
Which is why it’s called
the Evolution Pokémon.
Leafia
Glacia
Nymphia
Wait... Huh?
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The mysterious "Eevee that doesn't evolve"
Hey, Bari-chan!
Were you listening?
I guess it was a bit too hard for you.
Then, why don’t we actually
take a look at this Eevee that doesn’t evolve?
Well then, Bari-chan...
Take it away!
This is from just before
Koharu met Eevee.
How come you haven’t
caught any Pokémon, Koharu?
Maybe I won’t.
You won’t?! Why?
People make it out like I have to catch Pokémon
just because I’m a professor’s daughter.
It doesn’t feel right.
Being a
Pokémon Professor’s daughter
colored how people
thought about her.
She’s only ten.
It’s no surprise
she can’t decide on her future.
Miss!
What is it? Koharu?
Ah, uh, um, dad’s, uh, pachi...
Oh! Well, hurry back!
Wanpachi!
What’s wrong?
Like a scene from a fairy tale,
Koharu and Eevee
had a fateful encounter.
They both look like they
fell in love at first sight!
That Eevee...
...had escaped from
a nearby laboratory,
and before long,
it was time for them to say goodbye.
We’ve caused you
so much trouble.
We’ll be off then.
Eevee?!
This Eevee
really loves Koharu, huh?
It appears so.
She’s a pretty mysterious Eevee.
She won’t evolve whatever we try.
She won’t evolve into
any of the eight Pokémon?
Right.
Eevee have unstable genes in general,
so maybe that one’s genes are more unstable than most.
Or perhaps... Maybe she’s hesitant,
unable to decide what path she should take.
Hesitant...
Though that’s not a
very scientific perspective.
Hey, Koharu...
If you wouldn’t mind,
do you think you could look after Eevee?
Huh?
You want to stay
with Koharu, don’t you?
Eevee...
If you say it’s okay...!
Thank you.
Koharu, who doesn’t know
what she wants to be...
...and Eevee,
who can’t decide which path to take.
They’re very alike.
Also, there’s more to this Eevee
than not evolving,
it has another mysterious trait as well.
Take a look at this.
Wanpachi! Eevee! Spark!
And that’s not all.
Everyone, look out!
Showers!
Use Hydro Pump!
Do... Do you want to fire
a Hydro Pump?
Eevee! Hydro Pump!
Eevee used Hydro Pump?!
You did it!
Was that... Copycat?
The Copycat
that the man mentioned...
...is a move that copies
other Pokémon’s moves.
But Koharu’s Eevee...
...only seems to copy moves
of the types of its own evolutions
Rather than “work experience,”
it’s enjoying its own unique
“evolution experience.”
As for this Eevee,
what does Koharu think about her?
She copies her evolutions’ moves?
That’s a real mysterious Eevee.
Bari-chan, don’t get all confused!
Koharu
The one wearing the kimono is Koharu.
Haruhi
And this is Haruhi,
who looks just like Koharu.
It’s confusing,
but hang in there!
Koharu
With that settled,
let’s continue!
That’s a real mysterious Eevee.
Still, despite copying them,
she doesn’t evolve.
Eevee have unstable genes in general, but they said
that maybe her genes are more unstable than most.
Interesting...
And with her being like that...
That’s exactly why I want to
let her choose her own path herself.
And so we’re learning
about lots of things together.
I really get it!
You think just like I do!
These two, they evolved into Eefee
and Blacky on their own.
Really?
Eefee, who’s strong in the day.
Blacky, who’s strong at night.
The pair of them make up for each other’s flaws,
and support each other.
Make up for each other’s flaws...
And support each other...
And humans and humans,
or humans and Pokémon can do the same.
Nobody in the whole world’s
perfect all by their own.
But by making up for each other’s flaws,
and supporting each other,
everybody gets to live life
a little easier.
That’s what I feel,
seein’ how Eefee and Blacky are.
Oh, she sounds so grown up...
For Pokémon Trainers,
it doesn’t matter if you’re
a child or an adult.
By the way, Bari-chan...
Do you remember how many
kinds of evolutions Eevee has?
So close!
The answer was 8 kinds!
But Koharu and Eevee’s future
doesn’t just have eight paths.
This is what happened the first time
Koharu and Eevee went to Alola.
Um, Suiren...
It’s Koharu, right?
With the Eevee.
Yeah!
You see...
I wanted to ask if you could
tell me about your Eevee.
Sure!
Hey, Suiren.
What are you going to evolve Sandy into?
Evolve?
Eevee and I have come across
lots of her evolutions.
But I still don’t know...
...which of the eight
Eevee wants to evolve into.
One more choice.
The Eevee path.
Huh?
Staying an Eevee.
Like Satoshi’s Pikachu.
Satoshi’s Pikachu?
I get it!
So Eevee have nine paths, not just eight!
Lots of possibilities!
Lots of...
Possibilities!
Yeah!
Not evolving
and just staying an Eevee...
...is another possible future.
And with that, we’re one step closer
to solving the Seven Mysteries!
Through her adventures with Eevee...
Through adventures with Eevee———
Koharu’s world expands
Koharu’s world keeps on expanding!
Together, they arrive at the answer———
What answer will
Koharu and Eevee arrive at?
The Sakuragi Institute's
Seven Mysteries
The mysterious "Eevee that doesn't evolve"
Look forward to the next episode!
Today, You’re the Speed Star
And... we’re off!
Today, You’re the Speed Star Radio!
I am your companion,
the guide for all of your journeys, Mr. Narra!
Life is full of up and downs,
and so are Pokémon!
And I hope to give you all a Helping Hand
as you Tackle your daily troubles!
Today, You’re the Star—
The Speed Star!
Oh, a new program started.
Yet again, thank you for the messages
you’ve sent in this week.
Today, I’ll be starting off with a message
from Star Name “Daddy’s A Lonely Ball Lately”!
“Hello, Mr. Narra!”
Oh, hello!
“My daughter, who turned ten,
recently caught her first Pokémon.
“It feels like they’re always
spending time together,
“and I’m glad that she’s found
such a wonderful partner.”
That is certainly worth celebrating.
“She was never very proactive,
“and it feels like now
the Pokémon is encouraging her.
“The other day...”
I’m back!
I’m back, Wanpachi.
Come on out, Eevee.
Welcome back, Koharu.
I’m back, Dad.
Can you come here a moment?
Welcome back, Koharu.
Nice timing!
What is it?
Hey! Have you been
finding fossils enchanting?
Apparently he has a request for you.
About investigating fossils!
In the Wild Area! The Wild Area!
Over in Galar?
Ex-aaactly!
You can find rare fossils in Galar,
according to a rumor I heard.
I’ll do it!
Me, too!
I can meet lots of Pokémon
in the Wild Area! Right, Aceburn?!
What will you do, Koharu?
I have school, so...
You want to go?
Dad, I want to go too!
“With her Pokémon, she went
all the way to Galar for the first time,
“and had all kinds of experiences there.
“She even got to witness fossils being restored,
and had a very satisfying day out...”
So, how was it?
Great! I had so much fun!
I hope I can go again sometime!
Don’t you agree, Eevee?
All right!
Let’s write that report together!
Well, they say kids grow up
at Lightning Speed.
And what’s wrong with that?
So how come
you’re “A Lonely Ball,” hmm?
Ehem...
“Without me even being there,
“when I see she’s growing up
by leaps and bounds,
“as her father,
I’m a bit of a lonely ball.”
Oh, I get it now.
“As she grows,
her worries have grown too.
“Should I be reaching out to her,
or just watching over her?
“Just like my daughter,
I’m unsure what I should do.”
Hmm... I see.
To everyone listening, if you have any opinions
or thoughts, don’t hesitate to send them in.
Now then,
I have a song for you...
...and that was “1, 2, 3.”
Erm... And we’ve already
received some messages.
Star Name
“Nervousçoise.”
“Hello, Mr. Narra.”
Oh, hello!
“I know a girl who’s very similar,
“so I simply had to send in an e-mail.
Oh, thank you for that.
“Even if adults don’t reach out to them,
“sometimes children can still
find answers on their own.”
Koharu, what do
your mom and dad do?
My mother’s an illustrator,
and my father researches Pokémon.
Ooh! He’s a Pokémon Professor?
Yeah.
But I don’t like when people assume
I’m going to be a professor just because he is.
At one point, I was panicking.
I was trying to think of something I wanted to do.
Then I met Eevee,
and realized I don’t need to rush it.
Eevee?
She’s a bit unique.
It’s like she still doesn’t want to decide
what to evolve into.
So she copies the moves of other Pokémon,
and tries out all kinds of things.
Oh!
So earlier she was copying
Pochama’s move!
Yeah.
She seems to really enjoy that.
So I thought that it would be fine for me to hesitate
and just enjoy trying new things, too.
Ah, I see.
My Pochama decided on his own
not to evolve.
Huh?
He seems to want to stay by my side
as a Pochama forever.
At the time, I wasn’t sure
that was really a good idea.
But since then,
I’ve gotten a lot closer to Pochama.
So you’ll be fine, just fine!
Thinking really hard about it
for a long time, then going “Eureka!”...
That’s how the greatest
dreams are born, I bet.
Yeah!
Right, right! Dad shouldn’t butt in,
is that what you’re saying?
Harsh!
Next up, Star Name
“Yellow Lover.”
“Hello, Mr. Narra.”
Hello!
“I also know a wonderful girl
who met Pokémon,
“and began trying all kinds of things!
“Her father is a Pokémon Professor,
and lately,
“even the way they handle Pokémon
is growing more similar.
“There’s something so fascinating
about kids and their parents!”
I think they’re going home.
Back to Full Moon Island
and New Moon Island.
So Darkrai was searching
for the wounded Cresselia.
I thought they were enemies...
But maybe they’ve actually
been looking after one another.
Darkrai gives everyone
nightmares.
But it can’t control that power,
so it always ends up hated and alone...
Maybe Cresselia lives on Full Moon Island
because it doesn’t want Darkrai to be lonely...
That’s amazing, Koharu!
You really understand how Pokémon feel!
If we face each other earnestly,
people and Pokémon...
...can truly understand
one another...
Eevee.
You know,
we might not be Pokémon,
but humans can evolve
bit by bit, too.
And I’m not just talking about kids.
Dads can, too.
Now then, here’s a song to go
with your coffee break...
After the song is the super popular
Eevee Fortunes segment!
Eevee Fortunes after the commercials!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Eevee Fortunes
This week’s Eevee Fortunes! V!
Pick your favorite Pokémon!
Pick your favorite Pokémon
out of these nine!
Oh... I can’t decide!
First up...
Super Happy
Super Happy!
Showers: You can overcome any waves. Happy item: Surfboard
Thunders: An electrifying encounter awaits. Happy item: Diabolo
Booster: Indulge your passion’s fire! Lucky item: Flying trapeze
Eefee: You might see a bright future. Happy item: Couples’ necklace
If you picked Eefee...
You might just glimpse the future!
Your happy item
is a couples’ necklace!
Next up...
Super Lucky!
Super Lucky
Blacky: Midnight is best for thinking! Lucky item: Couples’ necklace
Leafia: You should relax with herbs. Lucky item: Perfume
Glacia: You’ll think of a cool idea. Lucky item: Snowglobe
Nymphia: Everyone will fall in love with you. Lucky item: Ribbon
If you picked Nymphia...
Everyone’s going to
fall in love with you!
Your lucky item is a ribbon!
And, this week’s Super Veevee is...
Super Veevee
Eevee
Every day, you won’t forget about Eevee!
You’ll have happy times ahead!
If you picked Eevee...
You won’t be able to forget about Eevee,
and you’re bound to have happy days ahead!
[Good news] Eevee appears next episode!
And I have good news for you!
Eevee appears in next week’s
Pocket Monsters!
What’ll it be about...?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Oh, man! The more I think about Eevee evolving,
the less I seem to understand...
Koharu, why don’t we
go camping this weekend?
Huh?
There’s something
I’d like to show you.
Show me something?
What is it?
You’ll find out
when the day comes!
What could it be...?
Now I really want to know!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Koharu and Eevee,
The Possibilities Are Endless!