Pokémon World Championships News!
Today, a special on the Masters Tournament,
where fierce fights are unfolding at this very moment!
Scenes from the turbulent first round!
In-depth analysis of the semifinalists!
Shocking battle rankings!
Scenes from the turbulent first round!
You’ll enjoy the Masters Tournament 100,000... 1,000,000—
In-depth analysis of the semifinalists!
No, 10,000,000 times more after watching this show!
Shocking battle rankings!
So, let’s begin!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Climax Begins!
Satoshi's Masters Tournament!!
The Pokémon World Championships!
Pokémon World Championships
Trainers worldwide compete,
aiming to be the number one Pokémon battler!
More than 10,000 trainers entered!
Entrants: Over 10,000
And reigning over that lofty summit are...
...the Masters Eight!
Masters Eight
Replaying the turbulent first round
This summer, the battles between the Masters Eight,
the Masters Tournament, have begun!
With Champions hailing from various regions,
it is truly a festival of dreams!
The first round went from
turbulent match to turbulent match!
Dande
Champion of Galar
Alain
Kalos League Miare Tournament Winner
All eyes were on the first match,
where Competitor Dande faced Competitior Alain.
Scenes from the
turbulent first round!
Kyodai... max!
Competitor Dande's
Pokémon
Competitor Alain's
Competitor Monarch Dande immediately
chose to Daimax, to thrill the arena.
Thanks to the power of Daimax,
Gorillander was on a roll!
But Competitor Alain’s ace, Lizardon,
disrupted its rhythm!
Plus!
Heed my heart’s call,
Key Stone!
Competitor Dande's
Pokémon
Competitor Alain's
Mega Lizardon picked up momentum
by Mega Evolving!
Its Dragon Claw, which has taken down
countless Pokémon, rushed for its opponent’s throat!
But! It was one step out of reach,
paving the way for
Competitor Dande’s victory.
The second match pit Competitor Wataru
against Competitor Carne.
Wataru
Champion of Kanto & Johto
Carne
Champion of Kalos
Have a taste of my
well-trained Dragon moves!
Competitor Wataru's
Pokémon
Competitor Carne's
With his hyper-aggressive dragon brigade,
Competitor Wataru attacked, attacked, and attacked...
...but Competitor Carne used status moves
to bring her opponent to her mercy.
The deciding factor was
Pumpjin’s Halloween!
Adds the Ghost type to the opponent's type
Halloween
By adding the Ghost type
to the dragon brigade,
she threw off
Competitor Wataru’s pace.
Checkmate!
Moonforce!
Competitor Wataru's
Pokémon
Competitor Carne's
After a fierce back-and-forth battle,
the referee’s fan rose for Competitor Carne.
The third match pit Competitor Shirona
against Competitor Iris.
Shirona
Champion of Sinnoh
Iris
Champion of Isshu
Competitor Iris's
Pokémon
Competitor Shirona's
Their battle began
with a surprising twist!
I’ll put my faith in Doryuzu...
...and bet on this attack!
The young Champion of Isshu landed
a low-accuracy one-hit knockout move!
While its accuracy is low,
the foe will be unable to battle if it hits
Horn Drill
Yet the queen of Sinnoh
was unfazed.
Competitor Iris's
Pokémon
Competitor Shirona's
She calmly and clearly continued to corner
her opponent, predictably dominating the match!
Then...!
Gaburias...
Mega Evolve!
Competitor Iris's
Pokémon
Competitor Shirona's
She used Mega Evolution for the very first time
in an official match, overwhelming Ononox!
Competitor Shirona
won the white mark with dignity!
But most tumultuous of all was the fourth match,
where Competitor Daigo faced Competitor Satoshi.
Daigo
Champion of Hoenn
Satoshi
Champion of Alola
Competitor Daigo's
Pokémon
Competitor Satoshi's
Competitor Daigo built upon his core steely defenses
with a variety of hard and soft attacks.
He’s the strongest and most impressive...
Truly, the Champion of Hoenn!
Competitor Satoshi tried to keep up,
but couldn’t quite steal the lead.
At the close, Competitor Daigo
sent out his ace, Mega Metagross.
Faced with its speed and predictive movement,
Pikachu’s paws and tail were tied!
This is Mega Metagross!
It’s predicting every movement
Pikachu makes.
Pikachu!
Competitor Daigo's
Pokémon
Competitor Satoshi's
Driven into a corner,
Satoshi turned to...
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Pikachu! 10,000,000 Volts!
If one attack fails, how about two?!
If two fail, how about three?!
A special Z-Move only Satoshi's Pikachu can use
10,000,000 Volts
With seven attacks
of seven-colored electricity,
he finally caught Mega Metagross!
Competitor Daigo's
Pokémon
Competitor Satoshi's
Competitor Satoshi wasted no time
in seizing this moment of opportunity!
Using Pikachu’s speed for a swift attack,
he conquered Mega Metagross!
Competitor Satoshi
took home the win!
In-depth analysis of the competitors headed to the semifinals
Next up, an in-depth analysis
on the four competitors advancing to the semifinals...
...and the Pokémon you should keep your eyes on,
using our show’s exclusive database!
In-depth analysis
of the semifinalists!
Absolute Monarch
Dande
Attack
We’ll start with this man:
the absolute monarch, Competitor Dande!
Defense
Speed
Tactics
Experience
Surprises
Exclusive Scoop
Everyone knows Competitor Dande is hopeless at directions, including him
On top of the overwhelming skills
of his well-trained Pokémon,
Genius-Level Battle Technique
he employs genius-level
battle technique!
With his unmatched skills of observation,
he doesn’t miss a trick from his foes!
Unmatched Skills of Observation
Without his partner Lizardon, he wouldn't find the arena
His ace is the Flame Pokémon,
Lizardon.
Lizardon
Flame Pokémon
Its greatest weapon
is its Kyodaimax.
He tried to arrange to stay at the stadium during the tournament, but was refused
Clad in blazing wings,
its battles are heated beyond compare!
Star Actress
Carne
Next, the strong and dignified
star actress, Competitor Carne!
Attack
Defense
Speed
Tactics
Experience
Surprises
Exclusive Scoop
Competitor Carne is highly sought after for dramas, movies, and ads
Her precisely calculated, beautifully
composited battles play out like a movie.
Precisely Composited Battles
Competitor Carne is an actress of
a hundred faces, and a hundred strategies!
100 Strategies
Her skilled manager rearranged her schedule for this tournament
Her ace is the Embrace Pokémon,
Sirknight.
Sirknight
Embrace Pokémon
Their eye contact during battle
is a skill born from their close bond.
Fans worry: "Has she cut down her sleeping hours?"
What sort of scenes
will she show us in the semifinals?
Queen of Sinnoh
Shirona
Attack
Defense
Speed
Tactics
Next, the queen of Sinnoh,
Competitor Shirona!
Experience
Surprises
Exclusive Scoop
Competitor Shirona also has an archaeologist side
“Dande the Warrior ”
“Dande the Warrior”...
“Shirona the Wise”
“Shirona the Wise”... A nickname coined
due to her incredible wealth of knowledge.
Her experience, allowing her
to wrest victory from any situation,
She visited Galar's Lateral Town to investigate the ruins
is the highest of the Masters Eight!
Her ace is the Mach Pokémon,
Gaburias.
Gaburias
Mach Pokémon
Its attack, defense, and speed
are all top-class!
She got to bond with Competitor Saito over a mutual love of ice cream
Now with the ability
to Mega Evolve, the sky—
No, the heavens
are the limit for its strength!
Rookie
Satoshi
Attack
Defense
Speed
Tactics
Experience
Surprises
Last, the golden rookie,
Competitor Satoshi.
Exclusive Scoop
Competitor Satoshi: "Pikachu never leaves my side"
His Unpredictability is Number 1
His unpredictability is number one!
He took down the Dragon Storm,
Competitor Kibana, to enter this tournament!
Being momentum incarnate,
he advanced to the semifinals!
He was the only trainer to bring a Pokémon to the opening ceremony
His battle style
can only be called crazy!
“Crazy ”
He’s anything but a safe bet,
For the first time in tournament history, a Pokémon took to the opening ceremony podium
but his explosive power glitters
like lightning!
Connecting heart-to-heart
with Pokémon,
he can draw out powers
nobody can foresee!
Past Episode
Monarch Dande extends his flawless win streak
Gaburias takes to the skies!
A slip up?! The weather turned against him...
One to watch! The PWCS's eye of the typhoon?!
Our program has followed Competitor Satoshi
ever since he was in the Super Class.
One to watch! The PWCS's eye of the typhoon?!
Competitor Satoshi's shocking battles ranked!
Along with telling you which Pokémon to keep your eyes on,
we’ll be ranking his most shocking battles!
Shocking battle rankings!
In third is... Pikachu!
A brand-new form of defense?!
A brand-new form of defense
that sent a stadium into an uproar!
Competitor Saito
Competitor Satoshi
Faced with Luchabull’s swift movements,
and the top-class Flying-type move, God Bird,
Competitor Satoshi
was set for a struggle.
But then,
he came up with a secret plan!
100,000 Volts!
Iron Tail!
Dig into the ground!
Lightning Speed!
The power of the Lightning Speed
is making Pikachu’s body shake violently!
What could this be?!
Turning an offensive move
into a defensive move!
Creating hypervibrations with Lightning Speed,
he reduced the damage from God Bird!
Using an offensive move for defense...
It was a shocking idea!
In second is... Kairyu!
How is that possible?!
A new move invented
Apparently, he even invented
a new move in a crazy way.
So what exactly did he do?
Competitor Iris
Competitor Satoshi
It happened in a battle against Competitor Iris of the Masters Eight.
Dragon Pulse!
Swallow it up with Hurricane!
I’ve got your Dragon Pulse!
They took on the energy from the Dragon Pulse,
and used it for a new move!
But that means... No way!
Go! Dragon Meteor Shower!
Using his foe's move
to make a new move!
Swallowing his opponent’s move with Hurricane
and reforming it into a new move!
Apparently, he’s polished
this Dragon Meteor Shower even further,
raising our hopes even higher.
And finally,
in first place... Lucario!
Oversized Guiding Wave power!
An earthquake ran through the stadium!
What could this oversized
Guiding Wave power mean?!
Competitor Kibana
Competitor Satoshi
Kyodaimax Duraludon was completely unfazed
by Lucario’s attacks.
Having lost all avenues of attack, what did
Competitor Satoshi and Lucario do next?
This is where it ends!
Roar, my dragon!
Time for my ultimate attack...
Kyodai Decay!
What is that...?
Lucario! Kyodai Guiding Wave Sphere!
Duraludon! Dai Rock!
Let’s go!
Oversized!
A giant Guiding Wave Sphere
By focusing their minds, the hearts of
trainer and Pokémon united as one!
Their heightened Guiding Wave
unleashed power beyond scale!
Plus, Lucario also has
Mega Evolution in his arsenal!
You Mega can’t miss it!
Competitor Satoshi surprises us
with each and every battle.
How will he shock us
in the semifinals?
Our program supports Competitor Satoshi!
A Dragon Dive Into Your Heart
Everyone, thanks for waiting!
It’s time for
“A Dragon Dive Into Your Heart Radio”!
Wherever I go,
stories are sure to be found.
Hi! Narray Sean here!
Life is full of up and downs,
and so are Pokémon!
Whether you’re Detecting, getting Detected,
or even Brutally Swung,
all of you who work hard at Reversals
when life doesn’t go according to plan,
Huh, I didn’t know there was a show like this.
let me take another Dragon Dive
into your hearts today!
Thank you for all your
messages again this week!
Today’s first Dive will be into a message
from Dragon name “Silent Boy.”
“A friend of mine is competing
in a huge tournament.
“I want to cheer him on, even if just a little,
so I’m sending in a message for the first time.”
My, you really care for that friend!
“He always has this dazzling smile on his face,
but I hear that he was very depressed and lonely at one point.
“Then, one day...”
Ouch!
Ow...
I’m sorry!
Watch yourself!
What’s this? You still cursed?
That was three years ago.
That plague has left me!
My luck’s perfect now!
You wait here, okay?
Don’t go anywhere, you hear?!
I swear... I never should have
caught that miserable Gänger.
Gänger?!
This is where you were?!
Wh-Why are you...?!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Stay away! Stay away!
Stay away!
I told you to wait there,
didn’t I?
Nothing but trouble comes my way
when you’re around!
I’ve had enough of you!
That’s just cruel!
Shut up, shut up... shut up!
Hey, wait!
Hey!
Gänger...
Being abandoned by its trainer
must’ve been shocking.
“After that, he was caught up with a bad crowd,
and completely closed off his heart.”
Hit by an Evil Eye
when he’s down, huh...?
“What finally saved that friend
were the honest and kind words of a particular boy.”
Forget what your old trainer said.
I need you... right now!
You don’t have to
trust me right away.
But just know I trust you!
“He’s worked hard, trying to
get stronger for that boy ever since,
“and finally, he’s now competing in
a tournament to crown the world’s strongest.”
Now that’s love! That is love!
“You’re a strong, big,
and beloved friend of mine.
“I’m wishing with all my heart
that you’ll fight with your full power.
“Everything will be fine.
So hang in there, Gänger.”
D’aww!
You’re no “Silent Boy” at all!
I’m sure your friend
heard you loud and clear.
Oh, I’ve already had
a comment come in.
That’s like Lightning Speed!
Dragon name, “Man of Steel”...
“Dear Sir Silent Boy.
“Thy care for thy friend
left a deep impression upon me.”
So formal and stiff!
This is too much!
“Though I bid it chance, a student of mine
also competes in a tournament.
“O, the memories.
“The days we strove together,
as I taught to him chivalry.
“That despite his initial vain views,
upon bonding closer with his lord,
“he grew into a reliable knight.”
Psycho Cutter.
I wonder what Mr. Gampi would say
if he could see you now.
Are you okay, Kamonegi?
You got my hopes up about your potential...
But I must say, I’m a bit disappointed.
You’re still far too inadequate a foe
for my Earlade.
Yeah! We’re gonna keep going!
Oh, is that a change of attitude I see?
I know how hard
Kamonegi has trained!
I know more than anyone
that he can do better!
Let’s get stronger and stronger,
together!
Me and Kamonegi, we’re both inadequate,
but that’s why we’re gonna get stronger!
I believe in Kamonegi!
You good to go, Kamonegi?
Then you leave me no choice...
Earlade. Crossroad Kill!
Detect!
Consecutive Cut!
Infight!
All right!
That connected!
What?
Th-That’s...
He evolved!
“Dear lord, and thy friend...
“By finding someone to protect,
my student has grown stronger.
“Now, may I join thee in bidding cheer.
“Glory be to Negigaknight’s future!
“Best regards.”
Perhaps only a handful
may compete in tournaments,
but every Pokémon has its own dramas,
and they’re as numerous as Dragon Meteor Showers.
The show’s not over yet, but right now,
I have a super effective song for you!
Storybook segment after the commercials?!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
“I’m Uonoragon!
“I’m Uonoragon, and I napped too long.
“When I awoke, I was all alone.
“A strange world. Strange creatures.
“But I’ll be fine!
“I have my Strong Jaw!
“I can eat lots of food with it,
“and it makes me friends quick, too.
“Nom-nom over there...
“Nom-nom over here...
“My proud Strong Jaw makes everyone happy.
“I’m Uonoragon, and I napped too long.
“Today, yet again, I’m with my friends,
going nom-nom-nom-nom.
“And they lived happily ever after.”
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The exciting semifinals
are finally about to begin!
Competitor Monarch Dande
and Competitor Carne have arrived!
No matter what happens,
the highlight is Pumpjin! Pumpjin! There it is!
We’re live, you know?!
That reminds me,
the brat boys aren’t here yet...
They probably just got lost somewhere!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Semifinals I - “Sweep”
The Semifinals I - "Sweep"
Let’s all tune in, meow!
Once this tournament’s over...
I’m retiring from battles.
Huh?!
We’re gonna win this,
Ms. Shirona!
Our battle has lit a fire in me!
Hypnosis!
Skillful Tactics
Ms. Shirona...
She’s strong...
Overwhelming Skill
Don’t let Ms. Shirona
set the pace!
100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
A showdown he has dreamed of
But until he stands upon the final stage
He can’t afford to lose
After I beat Ms. Shirona,
I’m gonna get even stronger!
I’ve longed for
a Pokémon battle like this!
Charge!
Let’s heat things up even more!
This is the only thing I’ve got!
Let’s use our full power!
A fierce fight is inevitable