The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The second match of the semifinals:
The Champion of Sinnoh, Shirona,
versus the first Champion of Alola, Satoshi.
Their 6v6 full battle has begun.
Let the battle begin!
Draco Meteor!
Surprise Attack!
Employing skillful Pokémon switches centered
around Mikaruge, Shirona had Satoshi at her mercy.
Kairyu, Gänger,
and even Pikachu were knocked out.
Shirona has four Pokémon left.
Satoshi has three.
How will Satoshi fight back
with one less Pokémon?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Semifinals III - "Valor"
Pikachu, you really gave it your all!
You watch from here.
Satoshi has three Pokémon left.
Ms. Shirona has four.
That gap is huge.
Ms. Shirona is just too incredible.
‘Scu-‘scu-‘scu-‘scuse us!
Hey! Brat boy!
Where’d all your steam
from the first round go?!
Don’t you dare
let us down, meow!
Neither of them have used
Daimax or Mega Evolution yet.
They’re both reading each other.
The question of when to use them
is the key to deciding this battle.
Competitor Shirona and Competitor Satoshi
are both ready to send out a new Pokémon.
Uonoragon, I choose you!
Dance in the heavens, Gaburias!
This time, they’ve both sent out
Pokémon with the Dragon type!
Gaburias...
Is this where she brings out
the Mega Evolution?
All I can do is dive right in!
Ice Fang!
Draw it closer
and use Dragon Claw!
So fast...
Dragon moves are super effective!
Stealth Rock!
Sharp rocks were scattered
across the field!
Return, Gaburias!
Wha—?!
Go, Roserade!
Competitor Shirona
recalls yet again!
Huh? It’s not burned...
It took Gänger’s
Will-O-Wisp earlier...
Hold on...
Could that Roserade...?
Its ability is Natural Cure.
By returning to its Monster Ball,
it recovers from poison or burns.
So that’s why you
returned it before...
Drat!
Then I’ll... I’ll...
All right! Let’s do this!
Jaw Bite!
Poison Jab!
Wow! Both sides took damage!
Oh, no!
Looks like Poison Jab’s effect is slowly
eating away at Uonoragon’s stamina!
That’s not good.
No...
What’s going on?
It’s angry that
it was poisoned, meow.
It’s saying “I’ll take down
that Roserade myself!”, meow.
Huh? Wow, it’s got serious guts!
Go get her, Uonoragon!
Leaf Storm!
Dragon Dive!
And it’s over!
Roserade is unable to battle!
All right!
Return, Roserade!
You fought well.
Despite its suffering,
Uonoragon pulls out a win!
But the effects of the poison
still linger!
Return—
Oh! It’s not going back...
Got it, Uonoragon.
You still wanna battle!
Give it all you’ve got!
Competitor Satoshi
will continue with Uonoragon!
What a hard worker!
How brave...
Uonoragon...
We’re with you, meow!
You consider how Pokémon feel,
so it was only natural.
But that could also
give me a chance at another win...
Graceful spirit of water...
Milokaross!
Competitor Shirona sends in Milokaross,
who played a big role in the first round!
I’ve gotta end this quick,
for Uonoragon!
Dragon Dive!
Charm Voice!
It’s a Fairy move,
super effective on Uonoragon!
Hang in there, Uonoragon!
Milokaross! Do it!
And it’s trapped!
Iron Head!
Jaw Bite!
Uonoragon...
Uonoragon is unable to battle!
Another victory for
Competitor Shirona!
You really did your best.
Thank you!
Uonoragon’s last attack...
That must’ve dealt
a heavy blow to Milokaross, too.
Yeah.
He’s set up his next play.
Amazing, meow...
That’s Daimax bravery!
You fought well!
You’ve left me in tears!
Come on, Negigaknight!
The Stealth Rock?!
Stealth Rock activates!
Negigaknight takes damage from being switched in!
I’ve gotta do something...
Of course! That’s it!
Negigaknight!
Let’s clear the field with just one move!
Brutal Swing your shield!
Go, go, go!
I can’t believe it...
The shield is spinning at an incredible speed,
destroying the sharp Stealth Rocks one after another!
Is that even possible?!
Now this is it!
That’s Satoshi for you!
He really does the unbelievable!
Go, go, go!
Hydro Pump!
Consecutive Cut!
Iron Head!
Iron Head gets blocked!
Consecutive Cut hits its mark!
Charm Voice!
Star Assault!
Negigaknight is enduring
the Charm Voice!
Go!
Milokaross is unable to battle!
Plunging in with a fearless attack,
Negigaknight snatches a win for Satoshi!
You did it, Negigaknight!
All right!
Now they’re both
down to two Pokémon.
The playing field’s even again...
Leave the rest to me, Milokaross.
You can have a nice rest.
Your Stealth Rock counter
was marvelous.
Our battle has lit a fire in me!
All the more reason why
I want to win this.
To win,
and battle Dande in the final!
We’re gonna be the ones winning,
Ms. Shirona.
With this battle,
I’m gonna surpass you!
I call on you again, Gaburias!
Is she going to Mega Evolve this time?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Let’s move! Consecutive Cut!
Scale Shot!
Negigaknight cuts down the Scale Shot
and charges in!
Dragon Claw!
Detect!
Detect succeeds!
Gaburias’s claws rend the air!
Star Assault!
Draco Meteor!
Both sides take heavy damage...
What will happen next?!
Negigaknight!
Negigaknight is unable to battle!
Negigaknight has passed out
still standing!
Refusing to hit the ground, even in defeat...
What a paragon of chivalry!
Return, Negigaknight!
Thank you, Negigaknight.
Competitor Satoshi
is down to just one Pokémon.
Return, Gaburias.
What?!
Another switch?
I really expected her
to use Mega Evolution.
She has a different idea.
This is all I have left!
Let’s use our full power!
Lucario! I choose you!
Competitor Satoshi’s sixth Pokémon,
and his last, is Lucario!
Aceburn?
You mean you want to
cheer on Lucario...?
Lucario!
Aceburn’s watching, too!
Give it your all!
Aceburn...
Lucario!
Let’s make Aceburn proud!
Togekiss,
I call on you again!
That powerful flinching combo brought about
by its ability, Heaven’s Blessings, and Air Slash...
I wonder how Satoshi
intends to handle it.
Competitor Satoshi’s
last Pokémon is Lucario!
How will they measure up
against Competitor Shirona and Togekiss?
Bullet Punch!
Air Slash!
Amazing!
It’s blowing away the Air Slash!
Lucario’s skillful Bullet Punches
block the Flying move!
Jump, Lucario!
All right! It felt that!
As I thought, you’re in perfect sync.
A move born from the bond
that your Guiding Waves forged.
I’m not done!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Air Slash!
Air Slash blows away Lucario
and the Guiding Wave Sphere!
You okay, Lucario?!
Oh? What’s wrong, Lucario?
Has it made you flinch?
Lucario!
This is just like with Pikachu!
No, Lucario will be fine.
Huh?
One more Air Slash!
Bullet Punch!
He’s not flinching!
This time,
he completely repels the Air Slash!
Good job, Lucario!
What incredible Willpower.
Return, Togekiss!
Huh?!
What? Yet another recall?
A Daimax band!
No! She’s not recalling it!
Tower over all, white wings!
Daimax Togekiss!
Let’s do this, Lucario!
With Togekiss Daimaxing,
Shirona and Satoshi’s bout only becomes fiercer.
Will Satoshi be able to find a way to
take it down?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
And so, the semifinals continue!
How are you going to deal with
that supersized Togekiss, Competitor Satoshi?
Huh?
But Competitor Shirona
still has Gaburias, too, meow.
What?!
Then he’s doomed!
Oh, no!
Go for it, go for it, brat boy!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Semifinals IV - "Shock"
The Semifinals IV - “Shock”
Let’s all tune in, meow!