Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Eefee and Blacky...
Eefee. Sun Pokémon.
Psychic type.
Psycho-power builds up in the orb on its forehead
as it bathes in the sunshine.
It is extremely loyal to any trainer
it considers to be worthy.
It is said that this Pokémon developed precognitive powers
to protect its trainer from harm.
Blacky. Moonlight Pokémon.
Evil type.
It is nocturnal, and even in total darkness,
its large eyes can spot its prey clearly.
When exposed to the moon’s aura, the rings on its body
glow faintly and it gains a mysterious power.
Eevee’s really interested.
Next, have a look at this.
A castle?
It’s called Eclipse Castle.
Eclipse Castle’s in Johto, and they’ve cherished
Eefee and Blacky as special creatures for eons.
I’d like to meet Eefee and Blacky!
How about you, Eevee?
Of course! You wouldn’t pass up
a chance to meet your evolutions.
I thought you might say that.
They’re actually about to hold
a festival for the upcoming total eclipse.
A festival?
Sounds fun, right?
Go and have fun.
Yeah!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Moon and Sun, Koharu and Haruhi
Eclipse Castle, Johto Region
So this is Eclipse Castle...
It’s pretty impressive
when you see it up close.
Look!
The crest is Eefee and Blacky!
That’s so cool!
But why is it Eefee and Blacky?
I wonder if there’s some history to it...
You would be right.
Once upon a time,
long, long ago,
in the midst of
the Eclipse Festival,
the lord of the castle was attacked
by someone plottin’ to take over the castle.
But his partners, Eefee and Blacky,
were able to save him.
He made that crest
to celebrate their bravery.
It tells of the day of the eclipse,
when the sun and moon become one.
You know a lot about it!
Of course.
I’m the present lord
of the castle, you see.
What?!
Well, I’ll be steppin’ down
from that position today, though.
Stepping down...?
Huh?
Where’s Koharu and Eevee?
Where are you going, Eevee?
O Sun, please give
us your protection.
Please let the Eclipse Festival
run smoothly.
And, please let me be accepted
by everyone as the new castle lord...
Eevee! Stop!
Eevee!
I’m glad you’re safe...
It’s all thanks to
Eefee seein’ the future.
Thank you for savin–
Huh?
Who are you...?
I’m Koharu.
Name’s Haruhi.
Haru...hi?
Koharu? Wow, it’s not even just our faces,
even our names are so similar.
We came here to see
Eclipse Castle’s Eefee and Blacky.
Aw, that makes me happy.
All this way,
just to see us?
Huh?
I had this good idea.
What a shock...
That goes way past being lookalikes!
They’re like twins!
This is like somethin’
from a dream.
She really looks just like Haruhi...
Naturally, gran. I’m Haruhi, see?
See? They really
did get us mixed up.
Do we really look
that much alike?
You swapped your clothes...?
Meetin’ Koharu on this important day,
the day I might become the new castle lord,
this is like a true
fateful encounter.
She copies her evolutions’ moves?
That’s a real mysterious Eevee.
Still, despite copying them,
she doesn’t evolve.
Eevee have unstable genes in general, but they said
that maybe her genes are more unstable than most.
Interesting...
And with her being like that...
That’s exactly why I want to
let her choose her own path herself.
And so we’re learning
about lots of things together.
I really get it!
You think just like I do!
These two, they evolved into Eefee
and Blacky on their own.
Really?
For Eefee...
One, two, three, four!
Thanks...
She was really loyal to me,
even as an Eevee.
That’s gotta be
why she evolved into Eefee.
And that very night...
One, two, three, four!
The other Eevee, I think he evolved
to Blacky to protect the Eefee he loved.
Eefee, who’s strong in the day.
Blacky, who’s strong at night.
The pair of them make up for each other’s flaws,
and support each other.
Make up for each other’s flaws...
And support each other...
And humans and humans,
or humans and Pokémon can do the same.
Nobody in the whole world’s
perfect all by their own.
But by making up for each other’s flaws,
and supporting each other,
everybody gets to live life
a little easier.
That’s what I feel,
seein’ how Eefee and Blacky are.
Haruhi...
Wow!
You really are the new
lord of Eclipse Castle!
That’s such a deep
and grand idea!
Th-Thanks...
But if the festival today
doesn’t go off without a hitch,
nobody’s gonna
accept me as lord.
It’ll be fine!
Everyone’ll accept you, I know they will!
I got somethin’
I wanna show you.
The guy giving the speech
is Hisashi, the lord.
This painting’s supposed to show a scene
from just before he was attacked.
He got attacked by...
His younger brother, Tsukiya.
His brother tried to dethrone him...?
A sad tale, right?
If I’m the lord, I’m gonna make sure
somethin’ like that never happens again.
Oh, there’s the sign
the festival’s starting.
I gotta get ready.
All right! We’ll cheer you on!
That’s great!
The day is finally here.
This long humiliation will end today.
Oh, my clothes!
I never changed back!
Satoshi and Go,
you go on ahead.
S-Sure.
Ariados! String Shot!
That went well.
What are you doing?!
You stay quiet, Haruhi.
H-Hey!
Eevee!
Yorunozuku, to me!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Eefee
Psychic
This is finally it,
Eefee and Blacky.
Koharu’s taking her time...
Yeah...
Pikachu?
Eevee?
Something might’ve
happened to Koharu!
Haruhi is in danger...
Haruhi...
What’s going on?!
Air Slash!
How did you get away?!
Get away?
What’cha talkin’ about?
What am I talking about?
So she used a double...
A double?
Koharu...?
What did you do to Koharu?!
Or were they twins?
Where’s Koharu?!
If you want her back,
declare me the new lord of the castle!
Who would you be?
Stay back, gran.
Koharu...
Stop, Blacky.
Don’t do anything
until I give the word.
What happened?
Somethin’ goin’ on up there?
Koharu!
Hey!
She figured out where Koharu is!
Say it! The next castle lord
will not be you, but me!
So Koharu will be okay?
If you follow my commands.
Hey, what’s your name?
What does that matter?!
She can’t give you lordship
if she doesn’t even know your name.
It’s Katsuki.
Katsuki...
Say it, then!
Haruhi!
Koharu?
Haruhi! Are you okay?!
Come on out!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Sarunori, we have to
save Koharu and Haruhi!
Hold it, Satoshi, Go.
Do you mind
leavin’ this to us?
But...
This’s an important moment,
that’s gonna decide if I become the lord.
I will become the lord!
How about ya stop yellin’
and we talk, okay?
Talk? Don’t mock me!
Ariados! Poison Jab!
Yorunozuku! Wing Attack!
Ringuma! Arm Hammer!
No helpin’ it... Eefee, Reflector!
Blacky! Bark Out!
Ariados! String Shot!
Eevee, dodge it and Tackle!
Now! Needle Missile!
Eefee, use Reflector again...
So, that’s her mysterious power?
Understood, Eevee! Reflector!
Thanks, Eevee!
Eefee! Wish!
Blacky! Evil Pulse!
Yorunozuku! Air Slash!
Ringuma! Slash!
Eefee’s Wish healed Blacky!
Just like Haruhi said,
they’re supporting each other!
The total eclipse is beginning!
Big chance comin’!
A big chance?
Yeah.
Eefee powers up in sunlight,
and Blacky in moonlight.
So a total eclipse, when the sun
and moon become one...
That’s a once in a lifetime chance
for them both to be stronger!
I won’t let that happen!
Ariados! Needle Missile!
Yorunozuku! Air Slash!
Ringuma! Arm Hammer!
Eevee!
Oh, this time you’re
going to copy Blacky’s move?
Eevee! Evil Pulse!
Eefee! Psychokinesis!
Blacky! Evil Pulse!
You did it!
Ringuma! Yorunozuku!
Ariados...
Katsuki.
My gran’s been lookin’
for ya for years.
Huh?
This castle used to have a tradition of puttin’ the sun
and moon in people’s names.
The “hi”
in Haruhi means the sun.
Hisashi, the lord,
had a “hi” too.
His brother was called Tsukiya.
And you’ve got “tsuki,”
moon, in your name too.
Because you’re descended
from him, right?
Yeah, that’s right!
My ancestor was ashamed of his
failed attempt at becoming the lord!
We’ve lived in secret
for so long!
I got fed up
with living like that.
I decided that I was gonna be
the Eclipse Castle lord, someday!
We’ve finally found you!
I had managed to discover
there was a child named Katsuki...
But please forgive me.
If only we’d found you sooner,
you wouldn’t have had to
endure so much hardship.
What are you talking about...?
Everybody!
I got an important announcement
to make, so listen up!
H-Hey! What are you doing?!
From today, I’m going to be
the new lord of Eclipse Castle!
And Katsuki here says
he’ll be helpin’ me along,
so I hope you will show us
kindness despite our youth!
I never asked for this!
Well, what’s that matter?
Besides, if you go all the way back,
we’re basically siblings.
I don’t need your pity.
This ain’t pity!
Me and gran, we’ve been waitin’ for ages
for our missing “moon” to return.
Think about how Eefee
and Blacky work together,
making up for each other’s flaws,
and supporting each other.
I think that’s
the best way to live.
Even Eclipse Castle...
The sun and the moon,
day and night...
It takes both of ‘em working together
to create a peaceful world.
Squabbling’ll never get us anywhere.
No point staying
bound to the past.
We’ve gotta change
what we can change!
Else we can’t move forward, right?
Let’s be good friends, Katsuki!
Ow!
Eefee, Blacky, and Haruhi taught Eevee
and Koharu an important lesson.
What sort of future— of evolution—
could they have in store?
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
My first Trial Mission
from Project Mew is here!
So? What’s it say?
“Gather Ulgamoth’s golden scales!”
Eggs!
These are probably Melarva eggs.
Melarva will hatch from them
and evolve into Ulgamoth.
He’s about to start
his first Trial Mission.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A Trial Mission!
Ulgamoth's Golden Scales!!
Ulgamoth’s Golden Scales!!