Every Pokémon will belong
to Team Rocket.
Ahh...
What great weather!
Everyone ready for another day of
exciting contest rehearsals?
Huh?
Where’s Pochama?
Come on, Pochama,
why are you sleeping?!
Tomorrow’s the big event.
You need to focus!
Come on, Pochama!
Pochama!
You should be their role model,
but you just keep slacking off.
These days, you keep waking up late
and dozing off after eating...
Hold it!
Pochama!
Excuse me!
That Pochama is my...
Huh?
Pochama?
Oh, no!
Yeah... Yeah...
Got it. We’ll be right there!
What happened?
Hikari’s Pochama was kidnapped!
Kidnapped?!
Hikari was in Sinnoh, correct?
Yeah!
There’s something
I was meaning to report to you.
There’s been an influx of
Pokémon disappearaces in Sinnoh lately.
Huh?! That many?!
And they’re all
completely unexplained.
No time to waste!
We’re going!
I’m going too, Father!
Okay. But look after yourself.
Yeah!
Now that’s settled!
Off to Sinnoh, we...
Go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Dialga & Palkia!
The Space-Time Cataclysm!!
Sinnoh Region
Hikari!
Satoshi...
Koharu and Go, too...
Sorry for the wait.
It’s fine.
At least, that’s what I’d like to say...
But it’s not fine, is it...?
Your beloved partner
was stolen from you...
I thought you might need something,
so I bought these!
Nice and hot croquettes!
Can’t work on an empty stomach, right?
Satoshi...
This isn’t like me...
I’m sorry.
This time, I really will be fine!
Huh? A lookalike?!
Yeah. She even had
the same clothes and hat.
Isn’t that...?
Yeah.
Just recently, we met someone
who looked just like Koharu, too.
There is that saying,
everyone has three identical lookalikes...
I feel like this was different.
She went into this strange, shining hole
while carrying Pochama...
A strange, shining hole?
Yeah.
And she vanished along with it.
Something like an Ultra Hole?
I don’t know...
Then, when I went to see Ms. Junsa...
Actually, there have been
several other cases just like yours.
Based on the witness reports so far,
the holes appear to be connected to some other place,
so we’ve begun calling them Gates
for the time being.
Gates?
Some other place?
Pretty curious...
We’ve hooked us one of
those mega-popular Pikachu!
Following the brat boys all the way
to Sinnoh actually worked!
Team Rocket!
Well then, smell nya later!
You’re not getting away!
Lucario, I choose you!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Pikachu!
Inteleon, go!
Snipe Shot!
What an awful feeling!
Those guys never learn...
Wh-What?!
That’s a Gate!
Prepare for combat.
Team Rocket, again?
When did they get the time?!
They sure are persistent...
Target acquired.
Commence attack.
Evil Pulse!
Inteleon!
Lucario!
Capture them.
Operation complete.
Retreat.
Stop!
Satoshi?!
Hurry!
Satoshi!
Lucario!
Owww...
Are you okay?
Yeah... Where’s Team Rocket?
We lost them...
Satoshi and Koharu aren’t here,
and the Gate’s gone too...
Inteleon...!
That second Team Rocket...
There was something
different about them.
Yeah.
Ms. Junsa said the Gates
could be connected to some other place...
But it looks exactly the same...
Something’s strange though...
Yeah...
Is that...?!
An aurora?!
No, no, no way...
You can’t see auroras here, yeah?!
Does that mean...
this really is some other place?
Hmm...
I know!
If we go to my house,
we might figure something out!
Something?
You’ll see when we get there!
She’s kinda like Satoshi.
This is my house.
Well?
Right... Nothing seems different,
as far as I can tell...
What is it?
When I looked this morning,
the garden was full of blooming flowers.
Flowers, huh...?
Now you mention it, I feel like the park’s flowers vanished
when we went through the Gate, too...
You’re right.
But wait...
That might not be all that changed.
The Pokémon!
Right! They vanished when
we went through the Gate.
I didn’t see any
on the way here, either.
That’s why this all felt so strange!
Something might’ve happened
to the Pokémon.
Sinnoh League, 2nd Place...
This really isn’t my room...
Which means that this Hikari...
Yeah. She’s a different person.
But...
We both had the same partner...
Pochama.
If there’s another Hikari,
then rather than this being some other place...
Someone’s coming!
What do we do?
Well, for starters...
I think our best bet’s to hear them out.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Dialga
Dragon
Steel
...then rather than this
being some other place...
Someone’s coming!
What do we do?
Well, for starters...
I think our best bet’s to hear them out.
She really does look just like you!
Pochama! Oh, what a relief...
I see... You came through the Gate
and into this world...
This world?
Those Gates are doors that
connect this world with another one.
In other words, you and I are the same person,
living in different worlds.
First, please, let me apologize.
I’m very sorry for taking away
your Pochama.
At that moment, I wanted to
return him to you right away,
but I couldn’t.
The Gate had already closed.
I saw your photos.
You’re close friends with
your Pochama, right?
Then, I think you can understand...
How painful it is to have
your Pokémon taken from you.
Also, uh, why does nobody
have Pokémon here?
We didn’t see a single one
on the way here.
Would you come and
meet my Pochama?
Masago Town Pokémon Center
Sinnoh Region
The Other World
Here he is.
An egg?!
My Pochama turned back into an egg.
So did all the Pokémon here.
How...?
One day, strange, shining Gates
began to open all over Sinnoh.
Before long,
strange things began to happen.
Pokémon started forgetting
the moves they had learned.
And, almost like time was
moving backwards,
they went back to their
pre-evolved states.
Then, finally, even my Pochama...
The affected eggs and Pokémon
are gathered here at this Pokémon Center,
and Professor Nanakamado is
trying to discover the cause.
Then one day, a Gate happened to open,
and showed me a Pochama...
Excuse me!
That Pochama is my...
It looked so much like
my own Pochama.
I just couldn’t help myself...
I am sorry.
Don’t worry!
I should apologize, too. I had no idea...
No, I’ve done something
truly unforgivable.
Now, your Pokémon will forget their moves too,
and then, in the end...
I don’t want that to happen!
Never!
Go! Can’t we do something?!
Judging by what we’ve heard so far,
it sounds like space and time
are all messed up...
Space and time...
...are distorted, you mean?
Yeah.
I think there were some Pokémon
that had to do with those concepts...
Dialga and Palkia!
Masago Town, Sinnoh Region, The Usual World
Meanwhile,
as for Satoshi and Koharu...
I wonder if Go, Hikari, and Lucario
are on the other side of that Gate...
Maybe, just maybe,
it could be an entrance to another world.
Another world?!
It was in this novel I read recently.
There was another world just like ours,
and the two were connected by mysterious doors.
So if we go to that other world,
we can get Lucario back?!
Y-Yeah...
And Go and Hikari went there too?!
P-Probably...?
Hey, is there a Pokémon with the power
to go to other worlds?
Hmm... Was there one...?
Oh!
How about Palkia?!
Palkia...
Hey, Rotom.
Can you tell me more about it?
Palkia. Space Pokémon.
Water/Dragon type.
It is said to live in a gap
between parallel dimensions.
Its total control
over the boundaries of space...
...enable it to transport itself
to faraway places or even other dimensions.
I knew it! If we get Palkia to help us,
we might get to that other world!
Yeah.
Any other details?
Further materials are available
at the Mio Library.
The Mio Library...
Let’s check it out!
Yeah!
Mio Library, The Usual World
Koharu! Any luck?
No... I can’t find anything!
Oh! Ms. Shirona!
Satoshi. What a coincidence.
You’re here alone?
Oh, no...
Oh, I’ll introduce you.
This is my friend.
Nice to meet you. I’m Koharu.
Ms. Shirona is
the Champion of Sinnoh,
and she’s also a scholar researching
Pokémon ruins and stuff.
Huh, that’s amazing!
Thank you.
So, what brings you to this library?
We’re here to read about Palkia.
Oh, are you investigating
the recent Pokémon incidents?
Sinnoh is home to
many myths about Pokémon.
The Legendary Pokémon
ruling over space, Palkia.
ruling over time, Dialga.
And the one said to have
birthed them both,
the Pokémon said to be a god,
Arceus.
Ms. Shirona, what do you think
about the recent incidents?
Hmmm...
Distortions in space could be caused
by Palkia’s tremendous power.
So it is Palkia...
You can stop
the dreary detective act!
Team Rocket!
Those are the thieves!
They stole Satoshi and Go’s Pokémon!
Give Lucario back!
Stand by for combat.
Let’s go, Gaburias!
Target acquired.
Commence attack.
Slash!
Gaburias! Dragon Claw!
Reversed Scale!
Capture them!
I won’t let you!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu, what’s wrong?
So, the effect has finally reached
this world as well.
Jararanga!
Pikachu!
Reversed Scale!
Withdraw.
Wait!
Satoshi!
Eevee!
Stop, both of you!
You saw that, right?
I saw the whole thing...
Those guys sure were creepy, meow.
What was that weird hole
they went through?
Speak of the devil, here it is...
Where’s Team Rocket?
They’re gone...
Ms. Shirona, too.
Ahh!
Sorry, Satoshi...
So, is this really another world
that looks just like ours?
Looks like nothing’s changed, to me.
Yeah... But something’s strange...
There’s no flowers!
Huh?
You’re right!
There’s no Pokémon, either!
And look!
We might not be able to get
back to our world without that Gate...
What should we do?
It’ll work out somehow!
Let’s start by looking for Go and Hikari!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
He’s such a positive thinker...
Hey! Excuse me!
Me?!
It’s me?
Satoshi and Koharu have arrived
in the other world.
Meanwhile, Go and the two Hikaris
are researching the distortions in space and time.
Will Satoshi and Go be able to
get their Pokémon back?
To be continued!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
I’m Satoshi!
What’s your name?
I... I’m Satoshi,
from Masara Town...
It’s not just plants and Pokémon
being rewound.
We humans are being rewound, too!
We heard that Palkia might be
making space distort.
If time is also distorting,
then Dialga might be involved, too!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Dialga & Palkia!
The Great Space-Time Clash!!