Having both accomplished a major goal, Satoshi and Go
were enjoying their camping trip with Koharu.
But a slight disparity in their feelings
ended up straining their relationship.
Then, the Legendary Pokémon Lugia
appeared before them.
Lucario, I choose you!
Inteleon, go!
Lugia!
It’s a Raid Battle!
Satoshi and Go!
A New Departure!!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
We’re right behind you!
Aceburn, use Pyro Ball!
It didn’t work?
Hydro Pump!
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Inteleon! Snipe Shot!
Dodge it!
It’s so powerful...
Go!
Yeah. Let’s do this!
Pikachu!
Aceburn!
Lightning Speed!
Aceburn, kick Pikachu!
All right!
Lucario! Bullet Punch!
Inteleon! Aqua Break!
Aceburn!
Let’s hit it with our full power!
Let’s go, everyone!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Lucario!
Wrap it in a Guiding Wave Sphere!
Sarunori! Wood Hammer!
Inteleon, you use Mud Shot!
Pikachu, you use 100,000 Volts!
Now!
Did it work?
Monster Ball... go!
Aeroblast?!
The world...
It really is huge!
Yeah.
Satoshi...
I said I wanted
to go on a journey...
But can I really go out
into this huge world, all alone?
You were there for me all this time,
so anything was possible.
But...
But I’ve just... been worrying...
and worrying...
What are you talking about?
Huh?
You got picked
as a member of Project Mew,
and you even got to meet Mew!
If you’re ever worried,
you should tell me!
After all...
We’re friends, right?
Yeah...
Satoshi!
Here we go!
Lugia just said
“Here we go!”
I heard it, too!
Where are we going?!
Pokémon really are...
...awesome!
This is why, Go!
Huh?
This is why I want to go on a journey!
The thrill and excitement
of meeting new Pokémon?
Yeah!
I wanna see more of them, know more about them,
make friends with more of them!
Yeah, I get it!
I wanna see more, know more,
and make friends with more of them, too!
If that leads me to learn more
about Pokémon and the world,
then I might be able to face up to Mew
and make friends with it!
You wanna make friends with Mew?
That sounds great!
Yeah!
Go!
Satoshi!
I’m going on a journey, too!
Hey!
Go?! Satoshi?!
Koharu!
I see.
I understand how you feel.
Very well!
Go for it and have fun!
Thank you!
I should be the one
thanking you two.
The two of you have helped deepen
our understanding of Pokémon.
Truly, thank you!
Even if you’re gone for a long time,
I hope you enjoy it!
I hope you’ll remember
to keep in touch!
We will!
But are you really sure?
You’ll be losing
two research fellows...
Oh, don’t you worry about that.
We’re going to be
the new research fellows.
Huh?!
Koharu and Eevee?!
Yeah!
I thought I’d like to learn more
about Pokémon and the world, too.
And Eevee has lots of
different evolutions, right?
There could even be more
we just don’t know about.
Though I’ll still be going to school,
so we’ll just be research fellows on the weekends.
I see.
I hope we meet
somewhere out there!
Yup!
The other concern I had were
my Pokémon at Sakuragi Park...
You can leave them with us.
We’ll take care of their needs.
Yup.
Look! Wanpachi’s excited, too!
Thank you!
Good news, huh, Go?
Yeah!
So, when are you going to leave?
Tomorrow!
Huh?!
Here is our report,
Sakaki, sir!
Through our flawless maneuvers
at the Masters Tournament...
...we have discovered the world’s
strongest Pokémon, meow.
Oh?
And where may this Pokémon be?
Within our reach!
If we desire it...
...we could procure it
anytime, meow!
I am counting on you.
Sir!
You hear that?
Sure did!
If he’s counting on us...
When the day comes that our
Pikachu capture operation succeeds...
We’ll be promoted to admins!
Made branch managers!
What a great feeling!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Houou
Flying
Fire
Cleaning’s all done!
All right. Let’s go and feed
the Pokémon in the park.
Okay.
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
Mom! Professor Okido!
Dad! Mom!
Even Grandma!
To commemorate your departure...
It’s a surprise party!
Such nice weather...
What’s that?!
They said it!
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation!
To preserve world peace!
Championing the evils
of truth and love!
We’re the lovely, charming villains!
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
You again?!
Words as bland as “again”
aren’t in our vocabulary!
Until the day we steal Pikachu
and present him to Sakaki, we are forever!
We’ll never stop trying!
For we are Team Rocket!
Musashi, Kojiro, Nyarth, and...
...Sonansu!
They never give up!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
As always, this capsule
blocks electricity, meow—
What an awful feeling!
Hey... Have you decided
where you’re gonna go?
First, I guess I want to tour Kanto.
There’s still places I’ve never been.
How about you?
I haven’t decided.
I’ll walk and walk
and keep on walking,
just going whatever way I want.
I see.
So what path are you taking now?
Straight ahead!
This is great!
The way that you go will determine
the Pokémon you’ll meet, and the adventures you’ll have!
Yeah. And the choice is yours.
Yeah! It’s mine!
Let’s both say it together!
All right!
Ready, and...
This way!
Looks like we part here.
Yeah!
Go...
I’m glad I met you.
Thank you.
Stop it!
What’s gotten into you?
You’re gonna make me cry...
Satoshi...
Thanks for reaching out to me.
We could find something
even more amazing waiting up ahead!
Right!
And that future lies...
Yeah!
...in our hands!
See you!
Yeah!
Go!
Satoshi...
Make sure you find that Mew again
and make friends with it!
I will!
And Satoshi, make sure you become
a Pokémon Master!
Yeah!
Let’s go, Sarunori!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Do you remember
the day we set off from Masara Town?
It was just like this!
The sky, the trees, the Pokémon...
They were all shining so bright!
Yahoo!
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be friends!
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The view from the next town
The wide breathtaking world
It all rushes past with dizzying speed
Leaving me behind
Even the little holes to slip through
that intrigued me so much in younger days
Have I just not been looking for them lately?
But remember, all that forgotten scenery
is still somewhere out there today!
On 1, 2, 3, leap out!
Out of the miserable days of tears,
and out of your Ball
“Where should we go?”, you ask?
The answer’s gotta be “Everywhere!”
No time (No time!) to catch your breath! Try! (Try!)
Why don’t we go?
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be friends!
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
I wonder where those two are right now...
and what they’re up to.
All right! I caught it!
The world of Pocket Monsters
stretches on endlessly...
The lives and adventures of
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu will continue on.
If I say they continue,
continue they will.