Satoshi, who dreams of
becoming a Pokémon Master...
And Go, who aims to
catch every Pokémon.
What kind of Pokémon
will they meet today?
I’m here at the port with the captain
who was saved by the Pokémon Kairyu.
Let us hear what he has to say.
It must have been tough for you, right?
Every now and then, you hear about Kairyu
rescuing shipwrecked people.
I was at my wit’s end!
Kairyu, huh?
I’d love to see one!
That might be difficult.
Huh? Why?
Allow me to explain!
Kairyu is a Pokémon that’s evolved
from Miniryu and Hakuryu.
It’s a very popular Pokémon,
but not many are known to live in the wild.
What, really?
We’re not sure where
its habitat is, either.
Well, there are rumors of an island
where only Kairyu live.
An island where only Kairyu live?!
It’s just a rumor...
About that...
Look.
I compiled all reported sightings
from the past couple of years.
And then...
They all look like they center
around that spot.
Kinda suspicious, yeah?
That really is fascinating.
That settles it, then!
No time to waste!
A hunt for the Kairyu island...
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Kairyu Paradise,
Hakuryu's Trial!
Whoa! Look at all those
Monster Balls!
Well, of course
I’d be fired up, yeah?
I intend to complete Miniryu’s
entire evolutionary line!
I thought about renting a boat
to take us the rest of the way,
but I might as well catch a Pokémon!
There are Dugong around here!
And that means...
We’ve got a ride to catch!
We travel all this way to get a special Kairyu
to offer up to Sakaki...
...and run into the brat boys.
Who’d have guessed?
They said something
about Kairyu, too.
Does that mean
they’re after it, too?!
You gotta be kidding!
They are not gonna steal it from us!
We need to put our plan
into action pronto, meow!
Monster Ball, go!
All right!
One more time!
This one’s tough.
Fine by me!
Here we go!
There!
Go!
What?!
Dugong’s data will be
added to the Index!
Got it!
You did it!
Yeah!
It’s around here somewhere...
Yeah.
Another one!
H-Hey!
What’s wrong, Dugong?
What?! Don’t tell me...
Stop!
You’re not listening, are you?
Go, look!
You’re kidding!
Dugong, we gotta turn back.
What? What?!
Kairyu?
Satoshi, these are Kairyu, yeah?!
Yeah...
They saved us.
Then this must be...
...the Kairyu island!
We got saved by Kairyu!
What a rare experience!
Thank you so much, Kairyu!
All right then...
Monster Ball...
Wait, what? Huh?!
There are no Monster Balls!
Why?!
Oh... Back then...
It seems like we got separated
from that Dugong, too... What did I even...?
Um... Wanna use my Monster Ball?
No, thanks...
You might want to use it yourself...
You’ve become friends,
Pikachu?
Are they trying to show us around?
All right!
Let’s explore the Kairyu island!
There’s Kairyu wherever you look!
Hang on...
Rotom, tell me where we are.
GPS signal not found!
I’ve got no coverage!
Hakuryu!
It’s so pretty!
So that’s how Hakuryu fly!
Hibunny?
What’s that?!
A Miniryu’s cast-off skin?
Where’d you find this?
How far are we going?
Awesome!
There’s so many!
Go! Over there!
Is it evolving?
You can do it!
It’s molting!
This good?
Stretch it a bit more
so we can see its shape better.
All right, that’s good!
Miniryu’s cast-off skin is really valuable.
Boots made from it are a super luxury item.
Really?
But Pokémon sure are
mysterious, huh?
How so?
You know, Miniryu,
Hakuryu, and Kairyu...
Kairyu kinda sticks out.
Now that you mention it, you’d expect it
to become something more like Milokallos.
Right?
Why does it get arms and legs?
What?
Hey, Satoshi. I think I’ve figured out
the secret of this island.
Secret?
Tell me!
Watching the Hakuryu play earlier,
I realized...
Hakuryu is said to have the ability
to change the weather.
It’s a sign of them
releasing their power.
Meaning, this island is constantly surrounded
by storms caused by Hakuryu’s power,
and that’s why nobody’s found it.
Now that you mention it,
that could be.
Or I should say,
you’re awesome!
Well, of course I am, y—
Ooh, it’s the sea!
What?!
Looks like the storm
doesn’t bother them one bit...
That one can’t fly?
Hey! Let’s train together!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kairyu
Flying
Dragon
One more time, Hakuryu!
Ready, and...
Satoshi!
Did you notice the other Hakuryu making
some weird movements before they started flying?
They were twirling around...
Kind of like a dance...
Dance? Could it be
Dragon Dance?
Rotom, what’s Dragon Dance?
Dragon Dance! A focused dance
that boosts the user’s physical abilities!
Bingo! Bingo!
The Hakuryu were using this move
to take off!
All right! Time for
a Dragon Dance, Hakuryu!
I’ll do it, so watch and learn!
You’ll do it?!
Dragon Dance, Dragon Dance...
I know!
Are you sure?
I’ll be just fine!
This’ll let me move in the air!
Pay attention, Hakuryu!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
All right!
Check this out, Hakuryu!
See? You can’t use Electroweb
as a trampoline.
I’m fine.
Pikachu! Do it again!
Electroweb!
Satoshi...
Try again...
We figured out how Hakuryu fly.
I’d better give it
a good demonstration!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Here goes!
That’s it!
Spin some more, Hakuryu!
Come on!
It’s flying!
You did it, Hakuryu!
Hey, you’re heavy!
Hakuryu?
Did something happen?
Hakuryu, I’m coming too!
You’re so slippery...
Dugong! You came back
at just the right time!
I-I got it! I got it, already!
Satoshi!
Yeah!
You go on, Hakuryu.
We’ll be right behind you.
Follow that Hakuryu,
Dugong!
Operation: Pretend to be Shipwrecked
And Lure In Kairyu...
...was a complete success, meow!
Wow, that actually worked.
Of course it did!
With my world-class acting skill,
it was like taking candy from a Bayleaf!
Hey! Quit struggling!
What’s that?!
One of Kairyu’s friends?!
Well then, you can keep each other company
in the cage, meow!
What are you people doing?!
If you ask us
“What are you people doing?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket! Let Kairyu go!
No, thanks!
We did finally catch it!
And then Pikachu shows up...
Our ship truly has come in!
We’ll do a triple catch;
Kairyu, Hakuryu, and Pikachu,
and then we’ll offer them all up
to Sakaki, meow!
Capsules, c’mon!
Rocket Capsul-et Secret!
Huh? Just one this time?
Oh, well...
Get ‘em!
The Float Whale Pokémon, Whaleoh!
It’s huge!
Float Whale Pokémon
Whaleoh
One ball,
but twice as nice, meow!
But the only move it has is Flop.
No problem! A Flop from an amazing Pokémon’s
gonna be one epic Flop, for sure, meow!
Of course!
Well then, Whaleoh, use Flop!
Here it comes!
Quite the epic Flop indeed...
That was scary, meow...
Now, Satoshi!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Well done!
They’ll get away at this rate!
Not happening, meow!
Well, duh!
Whaleoh! Use Flop on Kairyu!
Satoshi!
Hakuryu!
You evolved?!
Now there’s
twice the Kairyu, too...
What a wondrous moment!
Hey! Now’s not the time
to be awestruck!
Let’s catch it!
Whoa, it’s crazy mad...
Would you like to come with us?
Just kidding...
What an awful feeling!
Didn’t expect it to evolve
so quickly...
Hey, Go. I figured it out.
What?
The reason why Kairyu grow arms.
It’s gotta be so they can
protect others!
That sounds pretty great!
Doesn’t it?
Yeah!
All right, let’s go home.
Whoa!
C-Can’t breathe...
Wait, you...?
It wants you to catch it?
Thank you!
That really makes me happy!
Kairyu, I’m looking forward
to working with you!
I got Kairyu!
Incredible!
I can’t believe
the Kairyu island really exists!
Well done!
This announcement will cause
quite a commotion!
Perhaps.
But let’s keep quiet about it.
Why?
It’s such a grand discovery!
I think...
...the mystery surrounding the Kairyu
is part of their appeal!
I can’t breathe!
Satoshi and Go have found
the rumored Kairyu island,
and gained a new friend
while they were there.
The two will aim for their own heights,
as their adventure continues!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Huh?! The desks are flying!
I-Is this a poltergeist?!
No, it’s a Gänger!
Satoshi! Let’s race to see
who catches it first!
All right, you’re on!
Come on! Monster Ball, go!
Koharu!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Koharu, Wanpachi, and
the Occasional Gänger