This is Team Rocket’s hideout.
It looks like everyone’s tired themselves out
having fun, and fallen asleep.
Oh, don’t...
“Your skin’s softer than a Numera”?
That’s too much...
You’re right, though...
Come on!
You’re embarrassing me...
Oh, that was just Nyarth...
Tossing and turning...
The occasional jogging exercise
makes for a nice change of pace!
Huh?
I’ve caught you, Go!
Ahh! Sorry...
What’s going on?! I can’t see!
Are you okay, Go?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Panic! The Gokurin Ball!!
What’s going on? It feels like there’s
something squishy on my face...
Go...
turned into a Gokurin!
Huh? You mean the thing
stuck to my face is a Gokurin?
Y-Yeah. But why would there
be a Gokurin...?
Well, actually, I just saw one
in the bushes here...
I’ve caught you, Go!
And then you
ended up like that.
Yeah.
Wait, why are you still
holding that pose?
Well, uh...
I can’t pull my hand off it!
What?!
It’s stuck tight...
If you pull harder,
it should come off, right?
I’ll help!
No luck?
Nothing we can do. We’d better go back to
Director Sakuragi’s place and have him look at it.
Right.
What is it, Pikachu?
There’s a Gokurin
stuck to me!
Oh, Satoshi! Be careful!
Make sure you don’t touch it!
Satoshi?
I already touched it!
I wonder why the Gokurin
are sticking to everything.
Yeah...
Well, I’m sure we’ll be fine
once we get back to the institute.
Yeah...
Go... You don’t sound happy.
Well yeah, I mean this is just embarrassing,
having you hold my hand like this.
What other choice do you have?!
You can’t see with the Gokurin on your head, right?
Well, yeah...
What?
Something’s going on!
Uh, sorry, what?
It’s a Houdin, a Houdin!
Let’s go watch!
What? Wait...!
Gokurin!
What?! What’s going on?!
Why’s everything squishy?!
Psychokinesis!
We’re flying!
Director Sakuragi,
please look at this.
What are these readings?
I’ve never seen life signs
like these before.
Is it a new Pokémon?
What? What now?
We’re bouncing,
we’re bouncing!
Don’t tell me...
Satoshi, you’re not enjoying this,
are you?! Satoshi?
You are, aren’t you?!
We’re spinning...
We’re spinning again!
It’s a Kabigon!
Director Sakuragi,
the energy readings...!
It’s growing larger than before?!
And this is its predicted route.
It’s heading right for us!
We have footage from the scene
from Renji who went to go shopping.
Bring it up over here!
Right!
What the...?!
Wasn’t that incredible,
li’l Françoise?
There are more photos of it
being uploaded to the Internet.
Try and organize them
into a timeline.
We may be able to
identify the cause.
Roger!
I’ll put the earliest video on screen!
Here it is.
Satoshi?! Go?!
Hello?
Koharu! It’s me! Go!
Go? What is it?
Go!
You have to help us!
We’re rolling around!
Huh?
Wait, it seems like
we’re flying now!
What are you talking about?
Are you okay, Go?
I’m not!
That’s why I’m calling!
Pass me the phone, Koharu.
Huh? Sure.
Go!
Director Sakuragi!
I believe I understand
the situation now.
This was likely caused
by Gokurin’s ability, Sticky Hold!
Huh?! So that explains it.
What should we do then?
Use Gokurin’s Gastro Acid
to release Gokurin’s Sticky Hold.
ieki
Huh? Gokurin’s “Yay”?
iei
No! Gastro Acid!
Their “Yay,” right? Got it!
No, not their—
Use “Yay,” Satoshi!
Come on, we need to
command the Gokurin together!
Got it.
Let’s go.
Yeah!
One, two...
Gokurin!
Yay!
I see. So that’s what happened.
Still, that let us gather
some valuable data.
I never knew that Gokurin’s Sticky Hold
comes loose with a “Yay”!
I said “Gastro Acid,”
not “Yay,” though...
Still...
Wasn’t that fun?!
I guess so.
Yay!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gokurin
Poison
My head...
My head hurts, meow...
Stop stumbling around
half awake, meow.
I need your help, meow.
What? You’ve always wanted
to try cranking this?
If you’re happy now,
hurry up and let me down, meow.
Honestly...
I was having a nice nap.
How did I get stuck in the capsule machine, meow?
What’s in that, meow?
Kamukame, meow.
H-Hey, hold on, meow!
Come On, Kamukame, The Turtle Race!
Maybe I should’ve asked this before following it all this way,
but where is Kamukame going anyway, meow?
I get it! It wanted to play
in the park, meow!
That’s great, Kamukame.
Looks like Naetle’s going to play with you, meow.
Huh? “Don’t make me laugh”?
“Such notions of kinship
are far from my intent.”
“Surrender, small one. For you are
a hundred years too early to outrun me”?!
That Naetle is talking with
the arrogance of a Legendary Pokémon, meow!
“Naetle, you’re the one
who should surrender.”
“Hmph. Those are big words
for such a small shell.”
“Nobody’s getting past me,
whoever they may be!”
Kamukame’s fired up
and ready to go, too, meow!
Could this mean we’re in for
a seriously real serious battle, meow?!
Kamukame versus Naetle...
Yes, at this very moment, a race of pride
between two turtle Pokémon is about to begin, meow!
I completely understand
how you feel!
I’ll be sure to watch
your battle, meow!
Sonansu,
you handle the finish line, meow!
This’d make for such a good video.
It’d be a waste to just watch it happen, meow.
Make sure to
record everything, meow.
Huh? What? Record this?
What a pain.
Stop complaining
and just do it, meow.
It’ll go viral when
I put it on a video site, meow.
Ah, whatever.
Now, all the preparations
are done, meow.
Ready... Go, meow!
Now, which one of them
will reach the goal first?
A Cortoise...
“You think you can have a serious match without me?
Don’t make me laugh.”
It said, barging in, meow.
A Cortoise has joined the race, meow!
Also, hold on. Is it in vogue or something
to go “Don’t make me laugh,” meow?
“Hey, commentating Nyarth,
don’t make me laugh!
“Our race has no need for
your ridiculous commentary!”
What, meow?
“Don’t make me laugh,
my belly hurts!”?
You mean you literally didn’t want me
to make you laugh?
That Cortoise was just
really easily amused, meow?!
Kamukame and Naetle have made it out
of Cortoise’s smog, meow!
Naetle rescued Kamukame, meow!
What an upset, meow!
It saved Kamukame,
knowingly putting itself at a disadvantage...
Naetle...
You’re so kind, meow...
“Pay it no mind,” meow.
“I will outpace you before long.”
The next course is a sandpit, meow!
This time,
a Protoga has butted in, meow!
“Expecting to best me in sand is quite risible.
Don’t make me laugh!”
Seems like “Don’t make me laugh”
really is taking off, meow.
It’s fast!
Protoga’s incredibly fast, meow!
What?
Protoga focused so much on speed,
it forgot to look ahead
and rammed into the edge of the sand pit, meow!
The battle is between Kamukame
and Naetle after all, meow!
What’s wrong, meow?
“Pay it no mind”?
The leaves on its head!
Naetle, you wouldn’t happen to
be thirsty, would you?
“Nay...” But your leaves
are withering, meow.
It’s insisting it’s
not thirsty, meow.
“You...”
“What are you waiting for?
I know you can run.”
“Aiding your foe in battle...
You make me laugh.”
“You’re no foe.”
“We’ve fought our way through this cruel race,
and made it through as comrades!”
“Don’t make me laugh.”
“The real race has yet to begin!”
Naetle can’t even find any words other than
“Don’t make me laugh,” anymore, meow.
But... But... What a heated race
this has been, meow!
Beating foes that barged in,
overcoming all sorts of obstacles...
These two rivals beyond all others,
spurring each other toward ever further heights...
What a wonderful race!
It’s a massive assembly of
turtle Pokémon, meow!
Hey, Sonansu!
The finish line can’t go running away, meow!
Hey! Guys!
You’ve played enough for today.
It’s time to head home!
Who is that
Turtle Master-y old guy?
Don’t tell me, they were all
that Turtle Master’s Pokémon, meow?!
I see, I see.
Seems you’ve been having fun.
A fierce turtle race, huh?
Oh, my, don’t make me laugh!
I get it... “Don’t make me laugh”
was the Turtle Master’s catchphrase, meow.
I get it, I get it, meow!
You win, meow!
Goal! ...meow.
“My victory was certain
from the start”?!
“Don’t make me laugh”?
You’ve caught that
catchphrase too, meow.
Yesterday’s foe is today’s ally.
Kamukame has deepened the bonds
between the Turtle Pokémon.
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N,” you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
One morning, upon waking from an odd dream,
I had become a Gorillander.
Wait, Go, you’ve got
a Sarunori on your arm!
Ooh! How lucky!
Time to catch it!
Huh?
It’s already been caught by someone!
The person who caught it,
could it be...?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Lost Sarunori!
Who is Its Trainer?!
Who is its Trainer?!
The Lost Sarunori! Who is its Trainer?!