I wish Mom could be here, too.
Oh, well. It’s our fault for making plans on the same day
she’d set aside for a karaoke tournament.
Go, you’re awfully quiet.
Are you carsick?
Go.
Are you all right?
She asked you if you were carsick.
Me? I’m totally fine.
Are you okay, though?
You were working late again
last night, yeah?
We worked hard
so we could enjoy this day!
Couldn’t be better!
That’s great to hear!
By the way, why did you decide
to go to Hiwada Town again?
We couldn’t really enjoy our last trip
because of the pouring rain, remember?
So we talked it out and decided...
...that this time, we will create
some happy memories!
I see. Thanks!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Celebi — A Timeless Promise
Hiwada Town, Johto Region
Go went on
a family vacation...
...to Hiwada Town
in the Johto Region.
It’s your turn, Kimawari.
Good day, Sir.
Thank you for having us.
You’re quite welcome.
It’s been far too long.
It’s been... A year? No, two?
Three years!
Oh! The little boy from back then!
Wasn’t your name...
I’m Go!
That’s it! You sure have grown!
He’s ten already.
He’s even become a Pokémon Trainer!
I suppose these two
are your partners, then?
Yes! These are
Rabbifoot and Messon.
I see.
It disappeared!
Long time, no see, Kimawari.
I’ve grown, yeah?
Here’s the cottage key.
When you check out...
Leave it in the mailbox, right?
All right, enjoy yourselves!
Nothing beats the view here!
The air is so fresh,
and it’s so quiet!
We can really relax here!
So, what do you wanna do now?
And they’re already asleep...
They look comfortable.
They must have been really tired.
Shall we go catch some
Johto Pokémon, then?
What Pokémon live around here...?
I can’t believe Mom and Dad
fell asleep the moment we got here!
What do they expect me to do for fun
all on my own in the middle of the mountains?!
A Hoho!
Awesome!
There’s so many Pokémon!
Maybe Mew will be here, too!
All right! I’m gonna find Mew!
Mew! Come out
if you’re there! Mew!
I guess it won’t be that easy to find.
It is a Mythical Pokémon, after all!
Mew?!
Wait, Mew!
Wait!
Mew!
Celebi!
Ow....
And you are?!
What about you?
It was just a Muma?
Oh...
You were just shouting
“Celebi,” weren’t you?
And you said “Mew.”
What a screwup! How could you
mistake Muma for Celebi?
You’re one to talk!
You thought it was a Mew!
Well... I guess so...
So we’re in the same boat.
Okay, I guess we’ll leave it at that.
I’m Tokio from Tamba City.
I’m Go from Kuchiba City.
Nice to meet you!
Same to you!
So you’re looking for Mew?
Yeah. Awesome, huh?
I don’t know...
Seriously? It’s Mew, you know!
But you’re just searching for it, right?
So you’re no different from me.
Hang on!
Don’t get too shocked by this, but...
I’ve seen Mew!
What? For real?!
Yeah!
You know Professor Okido, yeah?
Of course!
The famous Pokémon Professor, right?
One time, at his Pokémon Camp...
I saw Mew!
That’s incredible!
It’s said to live deep in the jungle...
But it’s capable of making itself invisible at will,
so it’s very hard to spot.
But you still got to meet it...
You’re so lucky!
And you know what else?
Mew is said to possess the genes
of all Pokémon.
Yeah, I know.
But you know a lot
about Pokémon!
Sure do! I’ll tell you
whatever you want to know!
Well, then,
what do you know about Celebi?
I know plenty,
but let’s hear what you know first.
Celebi is revered
as a god of the forest.
It appears wherever beautiful forests exist.
Yeah, that’s right!
But the most incredible thing
about it is its time travel ability!
Time travel?
It can travel through time,
and apparently it came from the future.
That's why they say that so long as Celebi appears,
a bright and shining future awaits us.
I see! But, you know...
I got this bright and shining
future right here in my hands!
Don’t make me say it again.
It’s embarrassing.
Sorry.
But I envy you.
You’re confident enough
to grasp the future in the palm of your hand!
You think?
I actually just got that line
from a song Dad was listening to, though...
Nobody can beat me
in confidence!
Even I couldn’t
tell you why, though.
So, have you ever met Celebi?
Um... No, not even once.
I see.
I’ll help you look, then.
What? Are you sure?
Aren’t you searching for Mew?
It’s fine!
I’d like to meet Celebi, too.
Really? Okay,
let’s look together, then!
Yeah!
I suppose we won’t find it that easily.
That must be why they call it
a Mythical Pokémon.
Yeah.
But don’t give up yet.
In times like these...
Ta-daah!
What’s that?
A machine to gather info on Mew
from all over the world!
I thought maybe we can find
things on Celebi with it, too.
Did you make it?
No, my mom and dad did.
Your mom and dad are amazing!
I know, right?
First I just had a desktop computer,
but they made this so I could use it
when I was outside, too.
I see.
Oh! There are reported sightings of it!
Really?
Let’s see...
There’s an old shrine in Ubame Forest,
and they saw Celebi next to it.
Ubame Forest?
Let me check my map.
Got it.
We just gotta go through the cave
behind that waterfall!
What do we do?
What else? Let’s go!
This is Ubame Forest?
I can’t tell where we’d find a shrine!
In that case...
In that case...?
We just gotta go!
Outta my way!
All right!
I’m coming with you!
An Ariados!
Run!
It’s not coming after us.
All right! One more try!
I won’t lose!
Now a Kunugidama!
There’s probably lots more
where that came from...
Definitely.
What do we do?
I know!
Wait here for me, Tokio!
Huh? Where are you going?
I’ll be right back!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kimawari
Grass
Hey!
A Kimawari?
Where’d you get that?
I borrowed it from the janitor
at the cottage I’m staying in.
Kimawari’s Razor Leaf
can cut down that tall grass, yeah?
I see...
What a relief!
Huh? What?
I wasn’t sure what I’d do
if you didn’t come back!
I said I’d be right back!
You weren’t, though!
You really kept me waiting!
Sorry!
But I never break my promises!
That’s just not who I am!
Me, too!
I always keep my promises!
Okay! Resume search!
Resume search!
Kimawari! Razor Leaf!
Good, keep it up!
Another Razor Leaf!
See the shrine?
No.
Let’s look further in.
Kimawari, it’s your turn.
It’s a Kireihana!
It’s so cute!
Never give up!
Of course!
Nothing here. You see it?
No.
Kimawari,
we’re going deeper!
It’s so beautiful.
Yeah.
I just remembered,
when the sun sets, Kimawari...
...comes to a complete stop,
doesn’t it?
Guess this is as far as we go...
We should take a break, too.
It’s the first star!
We’ll probably get to see
lots of stars here.
Yeah. When I look at all the stars,
it reminds me how vast the universe is.
The universe, huh...?
People spread rumors that Starmie
may be an invader from outer space.
And that it uses the seven-colored core of its body
to send electric waves into outer space.
And the moon reminds me of...
Pippi!
On nights with a full moon,
they gather together and dance.
And they evolve
with the Moon Stone.
A shooting star!
Shooting stars remind me of Pi.
Because of its unusual, starlike silhouette,
people believe that it came here on a meteor.
Oh, I forgot a real great one!
Space really reminds you
of Rekkuuza, yeah?
That one’s really cool.
But I think more of Jirachi.
Once every 1,000 years, the light of a comet
and a pure singing voice will rouse it...
...from its near-perpetual slumber.
It wakes for only seven days.
What’s wrong?
I’m getting kinda cold.
Guess we’d better head back, then.
Yeah.
I’m sorry about this.
Isn’t it heavy?
Piece of cake!
We’re going this way. You?
I’m heading that way.
Let’s meet up again
in Ubame Forest tomorrow!
Really? I’d love to!
See ya!
Go!
It’s a promise!
Of course!
We’re friends, yeah?
Yeah! Friends!
Tomorrow!
See ya later!
Did he oversleep?
I even brought hot cocoa
and stew with star-shaped carrots...
You said it was a promise...
You said we were friends...
Tokio, you jerk!
You’re completely drenched!
What happened?
Where’s your friend?
That was our
first and last meeting.
And that’s why I...
Of course.
I’ve got you guys.
All right! Let’s get ourselves
loads of Johto Pokémon!
You guys help me, too!
Cut down the grass
so we can get into the forest!
Strike, use Slash!
And Kamonegi, use Slicing Draw!
Knew I could count on
my Pokémon!
Keep going! Slash!
Run!
Go, Monster Ball!
Ariados’s data will be
added to the Index!
Go!
Kunugidama’s data will be
added to the Index!
Why do I keep thinking of him?
He’s... not my friend anymore!
The shrine!
I’m pretty sure Celebi showed up
near the shrine...
“Go, I’m sorry I broke our promise.”
Huh?
Tokio...
You might not believe me
at this point,
but I really did try to go to
Ubame Forest on that day.
But I caught a fever...
I tried to go back the day after, but...
Go!
I’m sorry.
I know I said I promised.
I know I said we were friends.
I went looking for the shrine again
the next year.
And I finally found it.
Celebi!
If I could meet Celebi,
I was going to ask it...
...to use its time power to send me back to that day
one year earlier so I could keep my promise to you.
But...
That’s why I’m
writing you this letter.
I just wanted to let you know.
I still think of you as my friend.
Tokio...
Go?!
Tokio?
There’s so much
I want to tell you.
Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
The strange, strange creatures
who live on this planet.
You can find them
all over the world,
forming many different
kinds of bonds.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
It seems they’re holding a Pokémon trading event
at the Pokémon Center today.
I want to trade and meet
new Pokémon!
My name is Korotock Koromi!
Sinnoh’s Bug Poké-Queen!
I think there’s something
under here...
Let’s go!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Want to Trade Pokémon?