Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
This is Kuchiba City.
It looks like Koharu and Eevee
are on their way back from school.
Koharu!
Stop that Pokémon!
Whaa?! Stop it?!
Now, Go!
Monster Ball, go!
Biriridama’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Sheesh...
You really gave me a shock.
Sorry. I just had to catch
this alternate-color guy!
Blue Biriridama are pretty rare.
Ooh, that’s a pretty blue.
Watch out, though.
It’ll blow up if you touch it by mistake.
My, what a lika-blue target!
I’m so excited!
I just can’t contain myself!
Hold on!
Oh, sorry...
Your Biriridama was just so beautiful
it pulled me in.
Uh, who are you?
I’m a Blue Pokémaniac from Kalos...
Abel.
I’m visiting Kanto to enjoy this and that,
and everything about blue Pokémon!
A Blue Pokémaniac?
Does that mean
you like blue Pokémon?
Right you are!
Blue is cool and refreshing...
yet it’s also the color of the hottest flames!
Their protean charms have
grabbed me tight and never let go!
Futachimaru!
Discipline Pokémon! Water type!
Strict training is how it learns
its flowing double-hotachi technique!
So that’s why your partner is blue.
My partner adds so much flavor to my life that I could stomach
ten whole plain baguettes without so much as a gripe!
What do you say, kids?
Meeting you here must be
the hand of fate at work!
Why not try Aokatsu with me?
Aokatsu?
Blue Pokémon-related activities,
or Aokatsu for short!
aoi
katsudou
How about some research, then?
I’m in!
Um, I’d rather...
Eevee?
Well then, off to Aokatsu we...
...go!
Whaaat?!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
A Clash?! Blue Pokémania!
Doesn’t it feel like
we’ve been stuck in a rut lately?
We need to enact some huge plan with bombastic results...
something with a bang, a boom!
That’s great and all,
but we don’t have the funds, meow.
Huh? Aren’t those the brat boys?
They are, meow.
Since I came all this way to Kanto,
I made sure to plan everything out
so I don’t miss anything whatsoever!
Wow, that’s a packed schedule!
And naturally, I’m starting with
the Blue Poké-Photo Exhibition!
They have photos featuring blue Pokémon from
all over the world. A must-see for Blue Pokémaniacs!
Huh...
Blue Pokémaniacs, he said.
Guess there’s all sorts of hobbies
out there, meow.
Isn’t this our chance?
Meow?
I mean, maniacs will spend tons
on what they’re into, right?
So, if we make use of that...
We’ll be rolling in operation funds!
I like! I like!
This place is a flood of likes!
With all this blue calling to me
from every angle, I’ll run out of likes!
This place really is full of
blue Poké-Photos.
It’s a little overwhelming...
Oh, Pikachu!
We should look, too.
Yeah.
Non-non, kids!
Encounters like these
are once-in-a-lifetime!
You need to savor them!
So that’s Aokatsu, huh?
Uh, “savor them”?
Admire them and
let your imagination run wild.
For instance, this Oshamari!
See how she has a gentle
yet beautiful blue.
They’re skillful dancers
that love to practice their craft.
But the eyes are
what draw your attention.
She looks as though
she’s lost deep in thought...
Perhaps she’s on a quest...
A quest to find
the reason why she dances!
Then one day,
her worries cause an accident...
Are you okay?
Of course, being wild,
she’ll be wary around me.
But I won’t take advantage
of her vulnerability.
Then some day,
my feelings will truly reach her...
You’re all better now.
Fare thee well.
Oshamari!
I’ll wholeheartedly accept the loving dances
she performs each day for none other than me!
And that will be the beginning
of a wonderful life together!
Wh-When did you grab her...?!
All that from just one photo...
So those are
the fantasies of a maniac...
Simpleton!
Your imagination is far too simple!
You’re forcing your own desires on her!
You’ve lost sight of the true Oshamari!
Wh-What?! Brutus, why are you...?!
Do they know each other?
He does have a blue Pokémon...
Nyaonyx!
Constraint Pokémon! Psychic type!
The defensive instinct of
the males is strong!
It’s when they’re protecting themselves or their partners
that they unleash their full power!
Cease the false allegations!
But I can tell.
Those are the eyes of one
wishing to become stronger!
Perhaps her home was taken over
by some barbaric Pokémon!
Do not cry.
Are you really
willing to give up now?
Follow me!
Your regrets will drive you
to become stronger!
Hang in there!
You’ve nearly overcome your limits!
Aim to be an Ashirène!
Then, at the end of her harsh training,
Oshamari will...
You finally did it!
Hold it right there!
The blue on her tail is too dark!
You need a story dyed
in Oshamari Blue!
Oh, don’t worry.
There’s still a passionate
Ashirène Blue tale to come.
Wouldn’t you agree,
Blue Poké-Miss?
What, me?!
Because she has blue on her clothes?
You’ve got it wrong!
This is my school uniform...
Attention, please!
Do we have any guests today
in need of a little extra Poké-Blue?
Poké-Blue?!
What an amazing glossy luster!
I’ve never seen a
Sonansu like this before!
This beauty is one in a hundred—
no, a thousand!
Why not take a commemorative
photo with our Sonansu?
Can you send the file?!
I’ll make it my new wallpaper!
I’ll put it under my pillow
and have wonderful dreams!
I’ll talk to it when I’m feeling lonely!
I’ll print it on a body pillow!
That’s wonderful.
All right!
Hey, where are you going?
Come back here!
Oh, dear...
It’s your fault he ran away!
You’re the reason
that one-in-a-thousand—
Such amazing blue!
Why did I have to run into him?!
We’ve met a few times before
in offline meetups.
And if I say right, he’ll say left...
If I point up, he’ll point down!
He’s always at my throat!
I guess maniacs come in all stripes.
That’s what happens
when they’re both super fixated.
But! That’s enough
of feeling anxious!
Huh?
What do you mean?
I want to enjoy this trip!
I’m going to flush that bother
down the toilet!
The toilet, huh?
Now, let’s go!
We have blue excitement in store!
Enjoy Aokatsu!
Aokatsu!
C’mon, you can’t just run for it...
Yeah. You have the blue
everyone’s looking for.
Seems like they scared him
like nothing ever has, meow.
Well, they were really imposing...
Don’t worry!
They’re not gonna bite.
So hang in ther— Huh?
It was that bad?!
Well, if you really don’t want to...
...Then we’ll just have to
work something out on our own, meow.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Futachimaru
Water
This is our next destination!
Everything’s all blue...
Very lika-blue, right?
The Blue Pokémaniac bartender
is running a collab café!
These color gradients...!
I kinda like this uniform look!
You’re all starting to get it!
Bartender, bring us those!
Coming up.
Blue Juice from the collab menu!
We can taste blue in a blue space
while observing Poké-Blues!
This is Aokatsu at its finest!
Simpleton!
Once again,
far too simpleminded!
That voice...
Oh! You again?!
We meet again...
You try so hard to be a maniac,
but you weren’t prepared!
Whoa, his food is amazing!
The Fair-exclusive
Crazy Blue Pancakes!
Dough made from Yache Berries,
and if that wasn’t enough, topped with Oran Cream!
A dish that every
Blue Pokémaniac should try!
And for your information, you need to book it
ahead of time, so you can’t order it for today!
What if I didn’t
because I’m a Blue Pokémaniac?
What?!
Thank you for waiting.
The secret menu based on staff meals,
that only true connoisseurs know.
Soaked in Chiigo and Nekobu juice,
then baked in an oven,
the sweet-and-sour
Chiigo Nekobu Toast!
Exquisite!
The simple but moreish
beloved long-seller!
This is what a true maniac
would select!
My pancakes are stuffed with the bartender’s
blue Poké-Love! They’re much better!
There they go again.
They should savor their food more.
Hey, this is pretty tasty.
How could this happen?!
I was so excited to eat it,
but I can’t even remember the taste!
Things did get heated in there...
I wonder why Brutus
keeps finding you...
I think I sort of get it.
Like something enough and you want to prove it,
which just makes you fixate more on it, yeah?
I’d rather just enjoy it
together, though...
Me, too.
Now, next up is a top-choice candy!
Candy?
Yes, that’s the next Aokatsu point!
This is bound to mend
my frayed nerves!
Here, watch this!
A cooling Vanipetit from far away
fell in love with a cool Gekogashira.
Their tale is now available as candy!
Marine-do’s Marbled Candy,
Super Blue flavor.
Every Blue Pokémaniac knows
this masterpiece of a commercial!
And this is where it was filmed!
We are standing on sacred ground!
Huh, I never knew.
The amazing choice of two Poké-Blues as the Marbled Candy mascots!
This goes beyond lika-blue,
this is the birth of lova-blue!
Simpleton!
I didn’t plan to stick my nose in,
but your knowledge is severely lacking.
Again...?
But I guess that’s to be expected!
You’re ridiculing that godly ad?!
Of course not.
But there was only one blue Pokémon
in it, the Gekogashira!
Because Vanipetit is
a white Pokémon!
What?!
The shaded parts of Vanipetit may look blue,
but it’s a white Pokémon!
Classifying it as a blue Pokémon
is a blue-ge mistake!
Objection!
There are many
Poké-Blues in the world,
but is there a single other Pokémon
with blue so pure and clear?!
Hmm... Is Vanipetit blue,
or is it white...?
A hard question for sure.
Oh, we finally found you, guests!
The Sonansu from earlier!
...is what it looks like,
but it’s actually me inside, meow!
It doesn’t thrill me.
My soul is utterly unmoved.
They’re suspicious?!
I’ll just have to appeal
to them with that, meow.
Sonyansu!
Oh, dear me!
My dear Sonansu,
are you not feeling well?
Excuse us!
I’ve had enough!
Why do you always interfere
with my Aokatsu!
What?! You should stop
following me everywhere!
Why do those two
keep finding one another?
Maybe they both
have the same itinerary.
What do you mean?
He said it before, remember?
Since I came all this way to Kanto,
I made sure to plan everything out
so I don’t miss anything whatsoever!
I get it.
Since they’re both
Blue Pokémaniacs,
if they focus on efficiency,
they could end up with identical plans.
No way!
What’s that?
Marine-do’s Marbled Candy,
Super Blue flavor.
Get the commemorative
5th anniversary plush.
You, too?!
In this city,
this sacred ground?!
You planned on getting it?!
Where are they going?
Looks like Koharu
had the right idea.
Let’s go!
Right!
Please stop, customers!
Is this it?
Let go!
Um... We only have one plushie
in today’s stock...
They’re really fighting over it.
I’ll take you home!
They want to come with me!
If you keep pulling...
Oh, dear...
Ripping the lovers apart...
...how could you be so cruel?!
They really don’t get along,
do they...?
From another point of view,
maybe they’re perfect for each other?
Who knows anymore?
But now they’ve crossed a line...
I’ve made up my mind!
I challenge you to a battle!
My pleasure.
...I guess they’re
going to go all the way.
Yeah.
You know the rules, right?
The loser immediately stops their Aokatsu
and goes back to Kalos.
They don’t have to go that far...
I think this could be interesting!
Yeah, it’s a serious battle
between two maniacs!
Hmm?
Time for a Poké-Blue battle!
Let’s go!
A double battle?!
What are they doing?
Maybe it’s a “Blue Poké-Test”?
What’s that?
You know, like blind taste tests
where people guess the food.
It couldn’t be...
You’d never guess something like...
The sky blue Nidorina!
The horizon blue Gomazo!
The aquamarine Gamageroge!
The ultramarine Gureggru!
They got it right!
Awesome!
They really are maniacs!
You’re not half bad.
You aren’t either. But these won’t...
Eevee!
Sarunori!
What’s going on?!
If you say
“Eevee! Sarunori! What’s going on?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Sonansu!
Without Sonansu...
...the motto just fizzles out, meow...
This is all your fault!
What?!
Who are you?!
They’re bad guys
who steal people’s Pokémon!
What?!
This time, we decided
to go back to basics, meow.
The brat boy’s Pikachu,
and the maniacs’ spectacular Poké-Blues...
If we present them all
to Sakaki as a set...
He’ll give us a raise for sure.
Kojiro, get ‘em!
Roger!
We’ll catch them all with one net!
Nyaonyx! Charm Voice!
Futachimaru, save Pikachu
and the others!
Ow!
Thanks, Futachimaru!
Nyaonyx, drag them down
with psycho power!
How dare you try to
lay a hand on our Poké-Blues?!
Your crimes are far too grave!
They were fighting until a moment ago...
This could be good!
Then we’ll have to take them
by force, meow!
Vending, come on!
It’s so lika-blue!
Pelipper, darling!
Come this way! Come here!
Come on down!
You’re running away?!
Now, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
Sonansu!
All right!
Huh? Again?
Oh, no!
It’s time!
Time?
There’s a launch event for a new
Marbled Candy in the next town!
If I don’t hurry,
all the good seats will be gone!
I must be off, too!
Well, this is farewell, kids!
Keep your nice Poké-Blue life going!
Wait up!
There they go.
So, did they end up
becoming friends in the end?
Who knows?
Hobbies and ways of showing love
are as numerous as people and Pokémon...
After spending time
with the Blue Pokémaniacs,
Satoshi, Go, and Koharu’s horizons
have broadened a little.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
All right! I get to battle Mr. Dande!
It’s a tournament at Arabesque Gym!
It must be unrelated
to the Championships.
I’ll take whatever I can get!
Anything’s good as long as
I get to battle Mr. Dande!
But... Don’t you think
this stage smells sweet?
Oh, now that you mention it...
Something smells really good!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Mawhip's Sweet Battle?!
Mawhip’s Sweet Battle?!