Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
Nice!
All right! I caught Koratta!
You did it, Go!
Koratta’s data will be
added to the Index!
I can’t wait for the film shoot!
And the director is
the world-famous Koreda!
It’s a story about
Sirknight twins, right?
Yeah!
The elder sister is played
by a real Sirknight,
but the younger one is apparently played
by a transformed Metamon!
Don’t overthink it.
You’ll do just fine.
This isn’t it!
Who?! Who left this
unnecessary stuff here?!
Sorry! We’ll get it out of here!
Hello!
Welcome. Director Sakuragi
told me about you.
Thank you for having us.
What’s even the point
of talking to you?!
I, a star actress, am saying
I’ll be in your movie!
Get me the director, now!
We’re in the middle of filming...
Hey, hold on!
What are you doing?!
I just want to
meet Sirknight, meow!
Sirknight!
Oh, for crying out loud...
It goes without saying
that you can’t!
Naturally...
We’re starting.
And... Action!
There are two Sirknight...
This is a dream, meow!
One was fake, meow...
Cut! This isn’t it!
Another retake, huh?
Metamon! Transform Pokémon!
Normal type!
It can reorganize its cells...
...to transform into an exact duplicate
of any Pokémon!
“Exact,” it says...
Metamon has been
slipping up a lot lately.
This isn’t it!
This isn’t what I’m looking for!
If you really can’t
turn this into it, then...
Go... Do that!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
I Am Metamon!
I swear, those guys...
Don’t they know
how to treat a star actress?!
They should be nicer
to their fans too, meow.
I’m just glad they didn’t
call Ms. Junsa.
Metamon! Where are you?!
Metamon!
H-Hey! Wh-What?!
What’s up, Musashi?
Just my imagination?
Our Metamon...
...used to be famous for transforming so accurately that
she was more real than the real Pokémon.
Well, I get why she’d want to run.
Director Koreda was pretty intense...
Yes...
But he’s only that strict...
...because he’s taken
Metamon under his wing.
Director Koreda was the one who decided
to hire a no-name Metamon in the first place.
I see...
This work will be her big break!
We have to get her back, fast!
Um... I’ll help!
Me, too!
Thank you.
Then let’s split up.
What’s this?
The Metamon from earlier?
What’s she doing here, meow?
Wait, you ran away, meow?
You did get scolded pretty bad...
Did they fire you?
That’s still no reason to follow us.
How about we make this Metamon
our partner, meow?
Metamon can become anything!
I’m sure she’d be
a great asset, meow!
Now that you mention it...
She would enable us to
carry out new kinds of schemes.
If you’ve got nowhere else to go, then you should
aim to become the star of Team Rocket, meow!
Then show us
a proper transformation.
Try to become an Absol
for starters, meow.
Now try Glacia, meow!
Glacia isn’t that fat, meow...
Third time’s the charm!
Come forth, Bohmander!
See? You can do it
if you try!
Wait, meow...
I can see why she got fired, meow...
Transforming’s the only thing
Metamon can do...
This is a pretty fatal flaw...
Moping won’t get you anywhere!
If you call yourself an actress,
you’d better show some more guts!
When a true actress takes the stage,
her performance better knock ‘em all dead!
Her actress switch
has been flipped...
And she’s entered
mentor mode too, meow...
That’s what you need!
All right!
I’ll give you some training!
Spare me the dumb questions.
Just come with me!
If you wanna get good,
you gotta keep on trying.
That said, it’s time to enact Operation:
Play Magicians and Steal Pokémon!
What happened to
the actress training?
Dunno...
We’ll do a teleportation trick!
Here we have a blue box
and a red box.
We’ll put a Pokémon from the audience
into this blue box.
Then at the count of
one, two, three...
Oh, how strange!
“The audience’s Pokémon magically pops out
from the red box instead!”, get it?
Did it teleport?!
Of course not.
The audience Pokémon stays
in the blue box.
The red box contains Metamon,
who’s transformed into a flawless copy!
Switch the audience Pokémon
with Metamon...
Then we can steal the Pokémon
without raising suspicion, meow!
Hang on. What happens
with Metamon, then?
She can just come back to us
on her own!
Team Rocket members
gotta be able to run fast, you know!
So...
Hello! We’re street magicians!
We’ll make your Pokémon teleport!
Wow! That sounds fun!
This box does not have
any tricks or trickery in it.
And once I finish counting,
Eevee will move over to that box!
Now... one, two, three!
See?
He’s gone?!
Oh, no, don’t you worry.
He’s right here in the red box!
Whoa, that’s...
...not incredible.
This isn’t my Eevee!
Huh? How weird, meow.
Hey, where’d my Eevee go?!
Ta-daah!
Teleportation!
Seriously?
Come on, Eevee.
Operation failed, meow...
Keep on trying!
On to the next one!
We’re street magicians!
Who’s that?!
Your Pokémon will...
That’s not my Pokémon!
...teleport!
Not mine!
We’re performing magic tricks!
All of them failed, meow...
We nearly had it
with that Wooper, though.
Because their faces were
similar to begin with, meow.
What good actress
can’t take a hit?
If you fail,
just try a different approach!
We’re partners, right?
You...
You can do it!
Amazing, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Metamon
Normal
No good, huh?
How strange...
You got it perfectly before.
What’s up?
Hmm... Maybe I was just
seeing things, but...
I feel like you were less tense right here
when you pulled it off...
If she managed to transform
when she was less tense...
Does that mean being nervous
prevents her from doing it right?
Pressure can often
make you freeze up, meow.
What do you do
when you’re nervous?
I don’t even know the meaning
of the word “nervous”!
I was a fool for asking...
I wash my face, meow!
You?
I sniff my own socks!
What?
You’ve been doing that?
Th-The point is, everyone has
their own approach!
So Metamon just needs
some way to calm down!
I get it, meow.
How about you psyche yourself up
with a nice, hard slap?!
That’s a real good motivator!
Give it a try, meow!
Good! You can do it!
Turn into Nyarth!
So close, meow...
But that looked great
for a second!
Keep it up until you’ve got
a firm grasp on success! Again!
What a great feeling, meow!
All right! Now try Sonansu!
Good!
Keep up the pace!
Metamon!
Okay! See? You can do it!
You got it down!
Feels great, right?
I always believed in you!
With Metamon by our side,
we’re unbeatable!
It can turn into a big Pokémon
and give us a ride!
Or into a strong Pokémon
and protect us!
Since it can become any Pokémon,
tailing and infiltration will be a breeze, meow!
I can see it already... A bright future
where we storm our way up the ranks!
I see Sakaki praising me, meow!
With Metamon on our side,
we are now...
Super Team Rocket!
Well then, let’s start by...
...finally catching
the brat boy’s Pikachu!
We’re counting on you,
Metamon!
I can’t believe we still
haven’t found any trace of it...
Where could it have gone?
You two look down.
You should cheer
yourselves up...
...by watching our magic show!
We’re gonna do a super magic trick;
teleporting your Pokémon, meow!
You wanna try, Pikachu?
All right...
You go in this box,
little Pikachu.
There are no tricks
or trickery here.
Now, one, two, three!
Amazing!
How did they do that?
Here’s your Pikachu back.
Hang on...
Is this really my Pikachu?
It’s gotta be, yeah?
No... that’s not Pikachu!
Where’s Pikachu?!
If you ask us “Where’s Pikachu?!...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Super Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
That Metamon...
Great, isn’t she?
She’s our highly promising new member!
Pikachu is ours!
Pikachu!
Rabbifoot, stop them!
Metamon!
Transform into a Bohmander!
There you are!
Manager, ma’am!
Hey! I don’t care if you’re a manager
or whatever! Stay out of our way!
That’s my line! That Metamon is
an actress with a promising future!
Let’s go home, Metamon.
Director Koreda is
waiting for you, too.
He said only you
can play that part.
If you’re not there,
we won’t get anywhere!
She didn’t get fired?
Metamon!
Meta—
Oh, no!
Pikachu’s loose!
Well, for now... let’s scram!
Wait!
You’re not
getting away!
We managed to lose them...
They chased us
all over the place, meow...
Now, then...
We were so panicked that we just
brought her with us, but... what now?
Yeah...
Guess we have no choice.
Musashi?
Kojiro! Nyarth!
Team Rocket’s putting on
the performance of a lifetime!
So Team Rocket kidnapped Metamon
and forced her to follow their orders...
And now they’re demanding a ransom...
What a bunch of monsters!
Metamon... Why?
I see you brought the money,
as ordered...
Where are you?!
Right here.
Metamon!
Stop!
Save the touching reunion for later.
If you want your Metamon back,
then hand over the money!
That’s low, Team Rocket!
Just who... do you think
you’re dealing with?
A ruthless army of villains who’ll
gladly trample love and friendship for our goals...
That’s us,
Super Team Rocket, meow!
Got it?
Then fork over the cash!
Starting today,
we’ll be living like royalty!
We’ll be swimming
in money, meow!
They’re so infuriating!
You wait there.
You brats have nothing to do
with this. Get lost!
Yeah!
Money, please!
Pikachu, we’re getting Metamon back!
Us, too, Rabbifoot!
Hit them with an Em—
H-Hey!
Sonansu, do your thing!
That didn’t do a thing!
That barely even tickled!
If you wanna beat us,
you’d at least need to hit us
with 100,000 Volts!
Yeah! Like, “kaboom”!
You’re so dense!
We told you to use 100,000 Volts!
Get the hint, already!
Not that there’s any guarantee
it’ll hurt us at all!
We’re not the least bit scared
of your 100,000 Volts, meow!
Hey, hey! Come on!
What’s their problem?!
I don’t know, but if you insist!
All right!
Go, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Yeah!
What a great... I mean...
What an awful feeling!
Everything’s all right now.
Oh, Metamon...
100,000 Volts sure does sting...
But that was some great acting
back there, Musashi.
Yeah. It was the best!
Who do you think
you’re talking to?
I’m a star actress!
An actress with
a promising future, huh?
You can do it, Metamon.
It’s time to get started!
This isn’t it!
No! No! Not good enough!
Slap!
Ready... Action!
Cut!
Yes... Oh, yes!
That’s it!
The footage I wanted!
Team Rocket and Metamon...
They may have parted ways,
but the memory of their short time together...
...will surely stay
with Metamon forever.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Go, Satoshi! Wake up!
Did you forget what day it is?
Thank you all for coming to
the Pokémon Orienteering event!
This is an official
battle announcement.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
I’ll catch every Pokémon
to work my way up to Mew!
Lugia’s appeared!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Go Towards Your Dreams!
Satoshi and Go!!