Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
I’m back!
I’m back, Wanpachi.
Go on, Eevee, you come out too.
Welcome back, Koharu.
It’ll be a little while
until I’m finished with my work.
Okay!
I’ll go and read a book
in your room, Dad.
Sure.
What should I choose...?
Huh? Why...?
That’s beautiful!
“The Tale of the Luminous Maze Forest and You”?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Tale of the Luminous Maze Forest and You
Dad, do you have a moment?
What is it?
Can you tell me about
these Pokémon here?
Oh, that’s the Galarian Ponyta
and Gallop.
Huh?! They’re nothing like
the ones I’ve seen!
In the Kanto Region...
they look like this, right?
Huh?
So they’re different in Galar?!
Ponyta! Galarian Form!
One-Horned Pokémon! Psychic type!
Its small horn hides a healing power!
With its Healing Pulse,
any slight wound you have will be healed!
Gallop! Galarian Form! One-Horned Pokémon!
Fairy/Psychic type!
The evolved form of Ponyta!
Brave and prideful!
This Pokémon dashes airily through the forest, its steps aided
by the psycho-power stored in the fur on its fetlocks!
Ponyta and Gallop...
It’s rare to see you asking
about a Pokémon, Koharu.
I guess I was just curious.
I’d like to see them!
I wanna see them, too!
See and then catch them!
Then you should all
go see them together.
All right!
Thank you, Dad!
And so, Satoshi, Go,
and even Koharu,
Luminous Maze Forest, Galar Region
have arrived at
the Luminous Maze Forest in Galar.
It’s like it’s already night!
You could do
a test of courage here!
Hurry up, let’s go.
Oh, it got brighter!
Wow.
What a strange forest!
Yeah!
It’s all just like the book said!
According to Dad,
Galarian Ponyta and Gallop live hidden deep in the forest,
and almost never show themselves!
Apparently, they took on a special form after
absorbing this forest’s mysterious energy over generations.
That sounds really exciting!
If they almost never show themselves,
that just makes me want ‘em even more!
Okay! Let’s get going!
Yeah!
Nemush! Illuminating Pokémon!
Grass/Fairy type!
They scatter flickering spores
that put enemies to sleep!
Nemush, wait!
Wait, Nemush!
What is it?
A Ponyta!
Hold on, Eevee!
Aceburn!
Monster Ball, go!
Nemush’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Good work, Go.
Huh? Where’d...
...Koharu and Eevee go?
Eevee!
No way...
Easy does it...
Ponyta!
Gallop?!
You’re hurt...
It’s just like I saw before...
Are you okay?
You want me to help Gallop?
Is that... Healing Pulse?
It’s hurt badly enough that
even Ponyta can’t heal it...
Did it slip and fall down
into the ravine?
I know!
There was a part in this book
where a Gallop was being healed.
Dew from the rainbow flowers
blooming deep in the forest...
...has a healing energy,
and drinking it makes you better, it says!
Look!
I’ll go and get it!
Ponyta?
You’ll guide me there?
Hold on.
I’ll be back soon!
Calling! Calling! Calling! Calling!
Hey! Koharu!
It’s not connecting...
Huh...
Well, she has Eevee,
so she should be okay.
Even when we used to do tests of courage when camping,
she’d never get scared.
Really?
She’s got more guts
than you’d expect.
So as long as we find her before it gets dark,
she should be fine.
Though, I guess it’s dark already...
It started raining.
It’s just a shower.
It won’t last, yeah?
Go. Look at that.
Doesn’t it look brighter over there?
Never expected to find a town
deep in this forest.
Yeah. Hopefully Koharu’s here too.
Excuse me, you two.
You lack pink.
Sorry.
Hello.
We’re looking for a friend of ours.
Did you see a girl
with an Eevee anywhere?
If you answer my quiz correctly,
I’ll tell you!
Question!
What is my favorite color?
1: Pink.
2: Purple.
Go, what do you think?
She said “You lack pink,”
didn’t she?
That means...
1! Pink!
Bzzzt!
The answer was 2, purple.
Pink is what I like to see in other people,
but it’s not what I like for myself.
Okay, next question.
There’s more questions?
Question! How old am I?
1: 16 years old.
2: 88 years old!
2! 88 years old!
Bzzzt!
Well, you’re not wrong.
But you could’ve been a little more sensitive.
You two, you lack pink
in your hearts!
S-Sorry...
Let me give you some.
Here! Wear this.
I can’t get through.
Go and Satoshi
must be worried about me.
The rain stopped!
Yeah. Let’s go!
Are you okay, Eevee?
Okay, I’ve got to get going, too!
Should we take a little break?
You want a drink too, Ponyta?
Healing Pulse...
Wow!
Thank you, Ponyta!
It’s healed! Wow!
You used Healing Pulse on me?
Thank you, Eevee!
Over there! The rainbow flowers!
We’re nearly there. Let’s hurry!
Wh-What?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Ponyta
Psychic
Beroba. Mean Pokémon.
Evil/Fairy type.
Through its nose, it sucks in the emanations
produced by people and Pokémon when they feel annoyed.
It thrives off this negative energy.
What?! “Mean Pokémon”?
Those are mine!
Eevee!
Hey!
Give them back!
Hey, listen.
Could you please let us through?
We really need dew from
those flowers over there.
What should I do...?
I don’t have time for this...
Eevee?
Looks like they’re all having fun...
Maybe the Beroba just
wanted us to play with them?
Now you’ve done it!
Follow me, Ponyta!
Playing along with their mischief
was really tiring...
Thank you, Beroba!
Now, let’s hurry back to Gallop.
Gallop, drink this.
Can you stand up?
But why?
Your wound’s healed.
Are you low on stamina?
Ponyta, Eevee, go for it!
Make Gallop better!
Gallop!
That’s great!
It’s so beautiful!
Okay, next question.
How much longer is this quiz?
Sorry about this, Pikachu...
You too, Aceburn...
This is the last question.
Who do you think that is,
over there?
Koharu! Eevee!
And a Galarian Ponyta and Gallop!
I trusted the correct answer was to wait here,
rather than move blindly.
And she must be a fine lass.
The cautious Ponyta and Gallop
don’t let just anyone ride them.
Thank you for helping me get here.
You’re awesome, Koharu!
Wait...
They left...
You had to raise your voice...
I’m glad you’re both safe,
Go and Satoshi.
Koharu!
How’d it feel to ride on Gallop?
Great, right?
Y-Yeah...
I knew it!
Must’ve been great
to befriend them, Koharu...
Yeah!
I hope I see them again!
Huh? What was I...
Oh, I fell asleep.
Hey, Koharu!
Come in!
The Director says he’s done with his work!
Oh, right.
Thank you.
Koharu and Eevee have met new Pokémon
and shared new experiences.
They’ll surely never forget the dreamlike
time they spent in the forest.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N,” I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
The Castle of Chivalry?
Apparently they train Pokémon
and their trainers!
I welcome thee here!
I am the Man of Steel
of the Kalos Elite Four, Gampi!
Th-The Man of Steel?!
He’s really intense!
Okay, Kamonegi!
Let’s challenge the Elite Four!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Gampi of the Elite Four!
The Castle of Chivalry!!