That reminds me, Koharu.
Didn’t you say you wanted to meet a Nymphia?
Yeah.
Nymphia is the only one
of her evolutions I haven’t met.
In fact,
I got a message from Kairi.
Kairi...
The man with the Showers?
Yes.
Apparently, there’s a Nymphia and trainer
garnering attention...
...in Pokémon Contests at Minamo City,
where he comes from.
Nymphia. Intertwining Pokémon.
Fairy type.
It sends a soothing aura from
its ribbonlike feelers to calm fights.
If it wraps its ribbonlike feelers around its trainer’s arm,
it can read their feelings.
It does look like
it would be good at Contests!
Want to go and see?
Dad!
Of course!
Right, Eevee?
Actually, Go and Satoshi are
headed to Minamo City right now, too.
Huh?
I want to catch a Tyltalis now!
Like the one Satoshi battled!
So we’re heading off
to Minamo City!
So do you think you can
meet them there?
Okay!
Then, off to Minamo City...
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Eevee and Nymphia!
A Meeting and a Reunion!!
Minamo City, Hoenn Region
This is Minamo City in Hoenn.
When Koharu and Eevee
arrived at the Contest Hall...
Hiiiiii, ev-er-y-bo-dy!
Well then, watch me as
I dive right in again today!
Shining and spinning...
Spinning...
Miracle Ruthia’s Contest Scouting!
This is it!
All righty! I’ll be bringing another
spectacular trainer into Contesting!
Ruthie!
Scout me to be your next boyfriend!
Ruthia!
Let’s see...
You there, watching me with
that baffled expression!
What? Me?
Have you never joined
in a Contest?
Umm, no...
That’s just what I want to hear!
Then let’s get this show on the road!
This is the trainer I’m gonna scout today!
Huh?! Scout?!
And your name is...?
Um, hold on a minute!
I’m not too good with these things...
I just need your name!
Okay?
Aw... Just when I finally
found a Tyltalis...
Are you ready, Koharu?
Strength isn’t all that matters
at this Contest Hall’s Contest Lives.
Koharu?!
You can see a whole new
brilliant side to Pokémon!
A whole new brilliant side...
That’s right!
I bet Eevee has a whole new
brilliant side, too!
That’s what I want you to know!
So here you go! Take these!
A Pass that lets you take part in Contest Lives,
and a Polock Case!
Koharu and Eevee’s story
begins today!
Yep! And this episode
should be titled...
“A Sudden Encounter! Scouted by a Miracle Idol!”
That’s what I’d call it!
That’s all for today
from Minamo City’s Contest Hall!
Bye-bye!
Ruthie!
You’re so cute!
So, Koharu, try your hand at
a Contest for me, okay?
Huh?! Uh, um...
Eevee?
Where are you going?
Fairy Wind!
It’s a Nymphia...
Ooh!
You’re the one
Ruthia just scouted!
Huh? How do you...?
I saw you live on TV.
What?!
Oh no, that’s so embarrassing...
My name is Serena.
This is Nymphia.
Your Eevee’s really cute!
Thank you.
Do you happen to do Contests?
Yes.
So you’re the Nymphia trainer
garnering all the attention!
I don’t know if I’d say that,
but I like to think I’ve been
livening up Hoenn’s Contests with Ruthia.
I wanted to let Eevee see
one of your performances with Nymphia,
so I came here from Kanto!
Let Eevee see?
I see...
I really like that.
Huh?
Eevee choosing what to evolve into,
instead of her trainer choosing for her.
While that may sound easy,
it’s actually quite hard.
Really?
Yeah.
For example, you see Nymphia?
She was an Eevee who
was great at dancing.
I invited her to join us,
saying she’d have more fun dancing with friends.
And so, we traveled together...
Along the way, our hearts united...
Then she turned into a Nymphia...
Yeah!
So, has your Eevee decided?
What to evolve into?
Not yet.
I see.
Ms. Serena...
Just Serena is fine.
You don’t have to be all polite with me.
Just call me Koharu too, then.
What set you down
the path of Contests, Serena?
I’m just like Eevee.
I can’t decide what I want to do.
Then you’re just like
how I used to be.
Huh?
I went out traveling without any sort of dreams
or goals to aim for...
But...
I saw amazing
Pokémon performances,
and they awed me...
Now I hope I can become a performer
who can give strength to everyone who watches me.
Working toward your dream
is so much fun!
Sometimes things might not go too well,
and you get depressed...
but that just gives you so much more joy
when you do succeed!
When you’re talking about your dreams, Serena,
it’s like you’re sparkling...
Really?
Maybe it’s because
I’m with Pokémon.
Incoming call from Go.
Oh, sorry!
Incoming call fro—
Hello?
Koharu, you’re gonna
participate in a Contest?!
Oh, you saw that too, Go...
Um... I’m still not entirely sure.
Well, we’ll head to the Contest Hall
to come join you, then!
See ya!
Got it.
Then, let’s meet up at—
Sheesh...
What will you do, Koharu?
Huh?
Your friends are
coming too, right?
Hmm... What should I do?
Eevee, what do you think?
What about you, Serena?
What indeed...?
“If you’re ever hesitating,
then get yourself moving!”
“Even if you fail,
you’ll still be left with something.”
“Nothing you do is ever pointless.”
That’s what I think.
I can help you get ready!
Right! Let’s give it a try!
Is that it?
Yeah, looks like we’ll make it!
If it isn’t Satoshi!
I thought so.
Do you remember me?
Umm...
If you cannot recognize such a marvel,
you are not worthy to know my name.
See ya then!
Stop right there.
Remember how your friends
Haruka and Hikari entered the Mikuri Cup?
Oh!
Now I remember!
You’re Mr. Mikuri,
the Contest Master!
I knew you could
never forget me.
You see, my niece, the Top Idol, Ruthia,
is performing in Contests...
Excuse me, we have to
get going to watch that Contest...
Apparently it’s about to start.
See ya then!
Now, now,
don’t be in such a hurry.
I have caught every one of your
Pokémon World Championship battles.
Oh, thank you...
While I am not competing,
our meeting today must be a stroke of fate.
Why don’t we have a battle?
Huh?!
I can hold my own against
the Champion of the Hoenn Region.
What?! Against Mr. Daigo?!
Hmph... So you have no problem
remembering Daigo...
No matter.
I am in no way offended.
We don’t have time
to battle right now...
I’d love to!
You’re doing it anyway?!
Now, show me.
Show me the power you wield with your Pokémon.
And I, in turn, shall present you with
a performance of illusions in water by me and my Pokémon!
Oh... What should I pick...?
Go with whatever you like.
Oh, this one’s cute!
But... Maybe a bit gaudy...
That dress was worn by
the “Dancing Girl of Hoenn!”
You’re bound to look good in it, too!
When you’re all dressed up, and standing onstage...
You might just discover a new side to yourself!
And not just you...
The same goes for Eevee.
Ta-daah!
You should dress up too,
just like Koharu!
You’ll be a shining star
on the stage!
Together with Eevee!
Huh?!
Remember,
“if you’re ever hesitating”...
“Then get yourself moving...”
Right?
Correct!
Well, then... Let’s work out
what kind of performance you want to do!
Sure!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Nymphia
Fairy
Now,
the curtain rises on the Contest Live Minamo Competition,
where Pokémon compete with their charms!
First up,
the Normal Rank Performance!
It’s already started...
Good work, Kairyu!
Laglarge, use Muddy Water!
Kinogassa!
Seed Machine Gun!
Tamazarashi!
Aurora Beam!
They’re all incredible...
Is this really going to work?
Koharu.
Serena!
Are you nervous?
Am I ever...
Nymphia and I were just the same,
when we first went on stage.
But performers always have to
keep up a smile!
Right.
But I can’t help thinking,
“what if something goes wrong?”
You’ll be fine!
“You can’t do everything
on your own.”
“Having Pokémon who support you
is what lets you keep going.”
Believe in Eevee!
Yeah.
Let’s do our best together!
The next performer...
...is a Contest newcomer,
making her debut today. It’s Koharu!
Koharu’s on, Satoshi!
Uonoragon!
Use Water Gun!
Take it head-on,
Todoserga!
Koharu’s on, Satoshi...
Now, let’s go, Koharu!
Director Sakuragi!
You have to see this!
Ko-Koharu?!
Thank you, Eevee!
Let’s put everything
into this move.
All of the power
we’ve received from everyone!
Fairy Wind!
Use Tackle on the wind!
She did it!
Let’s hear some warm applause
for Koharu and Eevee’s Performance!
Koharu, Eevee,
you were amazing...!
Wasn’t that incredible,
Director?
I was more nervous
watching her...
Koharu, you were so cool!
Uonoragon,
you did well out there!
Return, Todoserga!
It’s over?
As I trusted,
that was a marvelous battle.
Same for you, Mr. Mikuri!
Now for the next one!
Come on out, Milokallos!
Pikachu, I choose you!
You’re still at it...?
Next up is what you’ve all been
waiting for, Master Rank!
The Top Batter has solidified her popularity
throughout Kalos, and now even in Hoenn!
It’s Serena!
My heart’s pounding!
Here we go, everyone!
Mafoxy! Magical Flame!
Yancham! Evil Pulse!
Nymphia! Speed Star!
Amazing... Amazing!
Mafoxy! Flamethrower!
Nymphia! Lightning Speed!
Yancham! Ice Punch!
Now for the finale!
Finish!
Serena, Nymphia...
They’re all incredible!
The Master Rank,
home of heated battles.
Closing us out is Hoenn’s
Number One Contest Idol...
It’s Miracle Ruthia!
Shining!
Spinning!
Miracle Ruthia’s Special Performance!
Here we go, Tylulu!
White Mist!
Ruthia!
Mega Shining!
Let’s go!
Shine out even more!
Dragon Meteor Shower!
Return, Milokallos.
For you to vanquish me,
an equal of Champion What’s-his-name...
How wonderful it is!
So vexingly elegant!
Yet indeed glorious.
Thank you for the good battle.
I knew you would deliver, Satoshi.
My pleasure!
It was some good practice!
Okay, let’s get going, Satoshi!
Stop right there!
Now...
Accept this Rain Badge.
Huh...
We’ve gotta go!
One more thing!
Take this,
so you may never forget our battle.
Huh.
Many paths now stand open to you.
On one hand,
you could conquer the Championships.
Many P—
Now, for the results!
The victor of the Minamo Competition
Master Rank is...
Two winners tied for the most points!
Ruthia and Serena!
We did it! Congrats!
Great work, Ruthia!
Ruthia!
Serena!
...I will pray that your path
be a brilliant one.
Thank you!
A Tyltalis!
Wait for me!
Go?
If you’d like, please take this.
Is that okay?
Of course!
I’m sure she would be happy, too.
Thank you, Nymphia!
So, what did you think of Contests?
Thanks to you, Serena, both Eevee and I
discovered a new side to ourselves.
Thank you for being there
to push us forward!
It’s nothing!
It’s what a traveling companion of mine
always did for me,
so now it’s my turn.
Hey, what are you going
to do now, Serena?
Oh, actually, Ruthia asked me...
Hey, hey, hey!
Why don’t we start up an idol duo?!
...and I’m not sure what to do.
“If you have time
to spend hesitating...”
“Then get yourself moving!”
Right?
Oh, those two are hopeless...
What’s wrong?
The friends I was supposed to meet.
Oh, well.
I’ll be off.
Right. Let’s meet again someday.
See you, then!
Koharu!
Sheesh, what took you so long?!
I battled Mr. Mikuri!
I caught a Tyltalis!
Satoshi!
Serena!
It’s been so long...!
Doing good?
Yeah, I’ve been doing great!
Pikachu looks good, too.
You know each other?
We used to travel together!
I’m competing in this
Championships thing right now,
trying to become the best battler!
I’m taking part in Contest Lives!
If you’re going to be the best,
I’ll aim to be the best performer, too!
Let’s both do our best!
Yeah! I will!
Satoshi and Koharu,
I’ll be cheering for you both!
Me too! See you again!
Thank you!
Let’s go!
Satoshi and Serena are both giving everything they have
to try and make their dreams come true.
Maybe someday Koharu will
find her own dream, too.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Now, off to the next adventure!
Let’s go!
Next time:
Team Rocket gets free rein!
Free rein to say anything!
Keep an ear out for
my eloquent free talk!
And my handsome voice talk.
And my casual comedic timing!
A new program by Team Rocket,
for Team Rocket agents,
Team Rocket’s Secret Kingdom Radio!
With a rock star attitude...
Let’s catch Team Rocket Agents!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
A New Program!
Team Rocket's Secret Kingdom Radio!!
Team Rocket’s...
...Secret...
...Kingdom Radio!!