The Pokémon World Championships
Hyper Class...
Satoshi is currently ranked 64th.
For his second battle,
he faces Galar Gym Leader Saito,
who he previously battled twice in the Super Class;
first to a loss, then to a draw.
In the middle
of their intense match,
the stadium received a visit from
none other than Champion Dande,
the ultimate goal
Satoshi and Saito wish to reach.
The match between Satoshi and Saito rages on
without a clear winner in sight.
Who will be the victor?
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mega Evolution Versus Kyodaimax
And it lands!
Lateral Stadium, Galar Region
Thinking impressively fast,
Lucario put its strength into its legs
to counter having its arms blocked!
The crowd goes wild!
Return, Lucario!
Go, Negigaknight!
Competitor Satoshi’s third pick
is Negigaknight.
It takes a stance that combines
both attack and defense!
That Lucario’s incredible.
And he went with Negigaknight...
I thought he’d pick Kairyu...
He’s facing her head on.
He wants to beat Saitokins with his own Fighting types!
Man, what a heated battle.
Kyodaimax and Mega Evolution...
When do you think they’ll use them, Mr. Dande?
Shh.
Right now, I’m enjoying this battle
from the bottom of my heart.
You should sit back
and enjoy your role.
Consecutive Cut!
Bullet Punch!
All right!
Come back to me, Kairiky.
Go, Luchabull!
Flying Press!
Crossroad Kill!
Jump!
That Luchabull moved fast!
It dodged Negigaknight!
Brutal Swing!
And it tossed the shield!
What a new and inspired Brutal Swing!
God Bird!
Now, Luchabull has started
storing up energy for God Bird!
Now! Crossroad Kill!
Negigaknight!
Negigaknight is unable to battle.
Competitor Saito
takes the first point!
A knockout blow
from Luchabull’s God Bird clinched it!
Return!
You did your best.
Now rest up.
Pikachu, you’re up!
To replace the downed Negigaknight,
he sends in Pikachu!
God Bird!
100,000 Volts!
Iron Tail!
Dig into the ground!
What...?!
Luchabull...
Take him out!
Lightning Speed!
The power of the Lightning Speed
is making Pikachu’s body shake violently!
What could this be?!
In a stunning turn of events, Pikachu took
the God Bird that finished Negigaknight off!
Still, they both took
heavy damage...
He had even more crazy tricks...
Back when he fended off Ms. Visquez’s attack
at Kuchiba Gym, he only used Iron Tail.
Why would he use
Lightning Speed?
He used its speed
to create hypervibrations.
Hypervibrations?
Yeah.
He took less damage from God Bird,
and even dealt some damage in return.
You astonish me,
trainer of Lucario.
It’s Satoshi!
Are you always training
to use moves like these?
I just come up with stuff
when I’m battling someone!
My head heats up
and goes all “boom” with ideas!
Without any planning?
You impress me
with these improvised tactics,
but your Pikachu impresses me
even more by pulling them off.
Defeating you will certainly
grant me great insights.
Luchabull! High Jump Kick!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
The 100,000 Volts hit their mark!
It’s super effective!
Luchabull is unable to battle!
We did it, Pikachu!
Now, they’re down to
two Pokémon each!
Luchabull, come back to me.
Otosupus...
I ask for your aid!
Pikachu, can you keep going?
What kind of battle
are we in for now?
Otosupus versus Pikachu!
Lightning Speed!
Octolock!
The Lightning Speed strikes!
What?!
Pikachu has been trapped!
You won’t get out of this again.
100,000 Volts!
Is the Octolock making it so Pikachu
can’t find its strength?
The 100,000 Volts fizzle out!
When he’s caught,
he’s done for...
That Octolock
is an ugly move to deal with...
No good, huh?
Pikachu!
Struggling won’t work!
Relax all your muscles!
Give in to Otosupus!
That won’t work.
Otosupus! Infight!
Pikachu!
Pikachu is unable to battle!
Now, Competitor Satoshi
only has one Pokémon left.
You did great. Thanks.
She really is strong...
But...
We’re gonna win this!
Lucario, I choose you!
I won’t settle for a draw again,
Otosupus.
Be careful.
If this drags on,
it won’t have any strength left to face Kairiky...
We’ll finish this in one blow!
It’s a staring match
between the two sides.
Which one
will make the first move?!
Aqua Break!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Otosupus is unable to battle!
You did it, Lucario!
What a piercing fighting spirit!
Lucario wins
the breathtaking exchange!
He won!
He actually beat that Otosupus, Sarunori!
This’ll be the last match-up,
Saitokins...
I give you my thanks,
Otosupus.
It’s time to dig in our heels!
I’ll give this everything I’ve got!
I ask for your aid, Kairiky!
Now, they both have
only one Pokémon left.
Kairiky versus Lucario!
Kairiky and Lucario have both taken
considerable damage so far.
Kairiky.
I can’t recall the last time
a battle made me so excited.
She’s smiling?!
Fine then,
let’s just destroy everything!
Your skill is worthy of respect—
and Kyodaimaxing!
There it is!
We’re finally getting to see
Kairiky’s Kyodaimax!
So outrageously huge!
Now this is a Galarian Battle!
That’s her true ace?!
It’s as overwhelming as ever.
Now, it’s your turn.
Let’s go, Lucario!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Let’s go, Lucario!
The bond between us...
Mega Evolve!
This Hyper Class battle
has been intense!
Competitor Saito
versus Competitor Satoshi!
No... Kyodaimax
versus Mega Evolution!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Dai Steel!
The powers of Mega Evolution
and Kyodaimax collide!
They’re evenly matched!
Force Palm!
Dai Attack!
The Dai Attack lands!
Lucario,
keep going with Force Palm!
It’s unbelievable! Even after taking the Dai Attack,
Lucario bravely keeps up the offensive!
Both sides have endured
yet another hit!
Kairiky!
Increase your Daimax Power!
Power is gathering in Kairiky’s fist!
Here it comes, Lucario!
I’ll use karate along with
my partner’s move, acting as one!
Kyodai Focus Blow!
That move’s the reason
Saitokins and Kairiky have been on a roll.
Lucario! Hold on!
It withstood the attack...
Lucario, jump!
Competitor Satoshi strikes back!
Amazing!
It’s running up Kairiky’s massive body!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Mega Lucario took down the giant!
A world-shaking spectacle!
All right!
Good work, Lucario!
This is where things get scary.
Kairiky is back to normal size,
but its enhanced power remains!
Rush in, Lucario!
Right now, Kairiky can strike critical points
with unmatched accuracy!
Bullet Punch!
Lucario!
Force Palm!
Go!
What’s this?!
Steely Resolve!
Lucario’s Steely Resolve erupts!
Kairiky is unable to battle.
Lucario wins!
As such,
the winner is Competitor Satoshi!
The fierce battle is over!
And what an awe-inspiring battle it was!
We won...
We did it.
Lucario!
You okay?
You did great.
Based on the results of this battle,
the Pokémon World Championships
rankings will be updated!
Competitor Satoshi emerges victorious over
Competitor Saito, and rises to 36th in the Hyper Class!
36th!
Satoshi, Lucario, Pikachu, Negigaknight...
You’re incredible!
You actually beat Saitokins...
How strong are you gonna get,
Satoshi?
Kairiky.
That was a good battle.
You have my gratitude.
In celebration of their daring fight,
the stadium is filled with claps and cheers!
Mr. Dande,
what did you think of today’s battle?
I wish I could’ve seen even more.
Congrats, Satoshi.
You’re ranked 36th!
That’s amazing!
Mr. Dande was watching me.
No way I wasn’t gonna get fired up.
But... he went and left
right away...
No, this is for the best.
We should only meet him
upon the battlefield.
During our bout today,
I realized my heart was dancing.
I won’t be throwing in the towel.
Someday, let us battle again...
Satoshi.
Looking forward to it,
Ms. Saito!
Just Saito is fine!
Okay, Saito!
That means Ms. Saito...
...acknowledged Satoshi!
Satoshi and Saito’s Hyper Class battle
came to a close with Satoshi’s victory.
But the path to Monarch Dande
remains a long one.
Who will be his next opponent?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Showers
Rentorar
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Showers
Rentorar
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Rentorar
Electric!
Showers
Rentorar
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Evil
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Choroneko
What type is this Pokémon?
Ev
Evi
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Evil
What type is this Pokémon?
Choroneko
Togepi
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fa
Togepi
Fair
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Fairy
What type is this Pokémon?
Togepi
Wooloo
Nor
Norma
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Wooloo
What type is this Pokémon?
Kumashun
Ic
Ice
Kumashun
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
What a pretty Glacia...
That girl with her...
is she a transfer student?
I wonder what happened.
Glacia’s angry.
Huh?
It’s a Blizzard!
Looks like we did it again...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Ice Queen and Glacia