Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
This is Sakuragi Park.
As usual, Satoshi and Go
are looking after the Pokémon, when...
Oh, Koharu.
What’re you doing?
Dad asked me to take photos
of the Pokémon here.
Oh, the regularly scheduled photos.
We take those sometimes, too.
Huh, is that so?
What should I snap next?
You want to guide me,
Wanpachi?
Ooh, there’s a trusty pal!
Let’s see where he’s going, Go!
Yeah!
Oh, Wanpachi...
He’s like a big brother to everyone.
Sarunori?
Where have you been?
Oh, you lost your stick?!
Thank you, Wanpachi!
He really is everyone’s big bro!
Great work, Wanpachi!
What’s wrong?
All right!
Let’s follow Wanpachi!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Help us,
Big Brother Wanpachi!
Kaiross?
What’s she doing?
She doesn’t look too happy...
It’s Dredear and Himenka.
What a sweet scent!
Who’s this?
Heracross?
Oh, dear...
Heracross got seduced
by Dredear’s sweet scent.
That’s happened before,
hasn’t it?
Yeah.
Don’t worry about it, Kaiross.
He’ll be back to normal
before long.
Wanpachi?
Where are you going?
Huh? Hiyape?
Is he trying to say,
“Wake up!”?
Isn’t that nice, Kaiross?
Ah!
Not again!
Are they going to be okay?
They’ll make up
before long, yeah.
Totally.
It’s Koratta!
Now what?
They’re fighting!
Why are you fighting?
Yeah, why?
You need to get along!
Golugh, what happened?
Poppo, Koratta, and the others
are usually playing here...
Did the Rock Pokémon
take their space?
They don’t look like
they’ll budge, either.
What a mess...
Wanpachi?
Again?!
Did you think of something?
Isn’t this...?
That’s it!
This is where the Rock Pokémon
usually play!
But the water...
What’s that noise?!
It’s hurting my ears!
Hagigishiri!
Was Hagigishiri
making that noise just now?
I wonder if it’s annoyed
by the dirty water...
Of course...
That would send the Rock Pokémon running.
Stop it, Hagigishiri!
We have to do something!
But what can we do?
It’s too loud!
I can’t think!
Wanpachi?
Vibrava!
It couldn’t be...
You’re kidding!
What?!
Supersonic Waves!
It’s so loud!
Huh?
The noise is gone.
But how?
Vibrava’s Supersonic Waves and Hagigishiri’s gnashing
might be canceling each other out.
Can that really happen?
When a wave combines
with its exact opposite, the sound vanishes.
Like positive and negative
summing to make zero.
Wow!
The power of science is amazing!
Great job, Wanpachi!
But we can’t leave things like this.
We have to do something
about the polluted water!
Yeah.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Vibrava
Dragon
Ground
You okay, Pikachu?
It’s all slimy!
Look, Satoshi!
There’s more all over!
What is it, Wanpachi?
Namakobushi?
Is this slimy stuff
what polluted the river?
No, it couldn’t be.
Namakobushi’s slime is a mucus
that covers its body, so it wouldn’t pollute the water.
It probably just fled
from the polluted river, too.
Let’s investigate some more!
Yeah!
That came from where Golugh is!
They’re still going at it...
Not just that...
It’s gotten worse.
They’ve settled down for now...
But we have to find the cause,
and quick!
Let’s go upstream!
Yeah!
Vibrava’s looking pretty tired!
Let’s hurry!
Yeah!
Namakobushi!
Just hold on a little longer!
We’ve gotta hurry!
Yeah!
In the end,
we didn’t find anything...
There wasn’t a pile of trash
or anything...
And it doesn’t look like
the Poison-type Pokémon did it, either...
Hmm...
Wanpachi?
Did he find something?
Betobeta!
Why is it here?
So that’s what
polluted the water!
Hey! Come outta there,
Betobeta!
Looks like it’s not budging...
All right!
It came out!
Sorry.
The water gets polluted
if you stay there.
Where did Betobeta live originally?
It used to be in a cave.
Yeah.
Let’s take it back there.
Is this the place?
Yeah.
Betobeta likes trash and sludge,
so it was living here
where it wouldn’t trouble anyone.
“Kero”?
Keromatsu?!
Why is Keromatsu here?
Maybe...
Betobeta gave its home to Keromatsu,
since it’s new here...
So that’s what happened!
You’re really kind, Betobeta.
Oh, but...
Where will Betobeta live, then?
Right... We can’t let it go
back to the waterfall...
I know!
We can all build a new home
for Betobeta, together!
Yeah!
All right! You all ready?
We’re counting on all of you!
Hey, you still not ready? C’mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I’ll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I’m fumbling blindly through the days
When I don’t even know what the next second will bring
Now if we just put some water in,
it’ll be finished!
What’s that?
On 1, 2, 3, leap out!
Out of the miserable days of tears,
and out of your Ball
“Where should we go?”, you ask?
Suikun...
The answer’s gotta be “Everywhere!”
No time (No time!) to catch your breath! Try! (Try!)
Why don’t we go?
1. Leap the language barrier
2. And go beyond the borders
Rain Prayer?
to discover a new you
If I were to collapse, to fall to my knees
I’ll do what I always did
Straighten my shadow out, like the setting sun
even though I may be taller now
Let’s go! It’s only after the rain...
Let’s go! ...that you see a rainbow in clear skies
I’ve known that since that day
Satoshi, look!
Have you, have you perhaps maybe
grown up without me noticing?
In the right-side pocket
of your dusty old clothes
You left the handheld adventure
that was everything to us
The memories from those days
are now looking for you!
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
So let’s go somewhere! Take me somewhere, anywhere!
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let’s have a fight!
1. Once the battle’s done
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be friends!
What a gentle rain...
Yeah.
Any day and every day, that’s always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let’s go! Every time you trip and fall
Let’s go! You pick yourself up by my side
Okay, Betobeta!
This is your new home!
I choose you!
Suikun must’ve seen
just how hard Wanpachi was working.
Yeah!
Sometimes,
Pokémon just really amaze you.
Even if they’re far apart...
The stronger their feelings are,
the closer they’re connected.
Feelings can get through to them.
Your feelings, too, Go.
Well, I can hope.
See you, Suikun.
It looks really happy!
The Rock Pokémon
got to go back home, too.
Everyone’s all back to normal.
Ah, what a relief!
Thanks for all your work,
Wanpachi!
Wanpachi played a big role in helping
the Pokémon of Sakuragi Park.
They even saw Suikun for the first time in a while.
What a wonderful day!
That’s it for today’s chores!
Koharu,
did you get some good photos?
Yes, they’re great!
I snapped lots of shots
of Wanpachi working hard, too!
An official battle date and time
has been set.
A Masters Eight Promotion Match.
Your opponent is Competitor Kibana,
ranked 8th.
Mr. Kibana, huh?
A Promotion Match?
If Competitor Satoshi wins this battle,
their rankings will be swapped,
and he will join the renowned Masters Eight,
the eight strongest in the Pokémon World Championships.
Huh...
That’s incredible, Satoshi!
The day’s finally come.
Yeah!
Satoshi blazes with fighting spirit for his battle
against Kibana. How will their battle end?!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Satoshi is currently ranked 9th
in the Pokémon World Championships!
I’m finally gonna have my Masters Eight
Promotion Match!
You’re facing Mr. Kibana, right?
If we’re gonna win, Lucario,
we’ve gotta get stronger!
And to do that...
Let’s go see Gekkouga!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Lucario and Gekkouga!
The Guiding Waves of Destiny!!