Satoshi, who dreams of
becoming a Pokémon Master...
And Go, who aims to
catch every Pokémon.
What kind of Pokémon
will they meet today?
Whoa! Big news!
What?
It’s Houou! Houou appeared!
What?!
I see... There were
Houou sightings, huh?
Yeah!
People were talking about it online!
Houou is deeply connected with
the ancient folklore of the Johto Region.
I know! And it’s supposed to be
really hard to find!
Yeah. Very few records of it remain.
It’s a Legendary Pokémon
shrouded in mystery.
And that legend has
finally shown itself!
The sightings were all reported
around Enju City in Johto.
If we go there,
we can meet Houou...
I’ve always wanted to
battle Houou someday!
What?
I want to catch it!
What?!
You two really are interesting!
Even when dealing with a Legendary Pokémon,
you talk about battling and catching it!
Go, let’s head straight for Enju City!
Yeah!
Let’s go!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Vow From That Day!
The Johto Region's Legend of Houou!!
Enju City, Johto Region
We’re here!
Enju City!
All right! Let’s find Houou!
Satoshi! It looks like Bell Tower
had the most sightings!
Knew I could count on you!
Just you wait, Houou!
I was looking into it, and Houou had
a peculiar legend about it...
Otachi! Scout Pokémon!
Normal type!
It stands on its tail
so it can see a long way!
All right, I’ll catch it!
Monster Ball, go!
Otachi’s data will be
added to the Index!
Got it!
Go... Isn’t finding Houou
more important?
That’s...
Houou!
I can’t believe
we found it so quickly!
Pikachu!
Use 100,000 Volts!
It was that easy?
Are you all right?
An Onidrill and a Hinoarashi?
That explains why it was so easy.
How could you do that?!
Sorry! I thought it was Houou.
Don’t tell me the Houou sightings were...
Um... Well...
Kurio!
Grandpa...
I thought as much.
You seeing Houou the other day
was also a lie, I suppose?
I told you, Houou doesn’t exist.
It does exist!
Houou does exist!
You must have been tricked
by Kurio’s fake, too.
That’s not it!
On the day I set out
to become a Pokémon Master,
I saw it with my own eyes!
You just thought you did,
didn’t you?
Grandpa...
That’s what he says now,
but Grandpa used to say
he’d met Houou.
Look at this, Kurio!
This is Houou’s
Rainbow Feather!
Legend has it that happiness will come to
whoever holds this feather!
That’s incredible, Grandpa!
You met Houou?
I did. Though back then, the clouds were in the way,
so I couldn’t get a good look at it.
Next time,
I want to see it up close!
He kept going on journeys
to try and find Houou...
But one day,
he came back all of a sudden...
He was completely down,
with no interest in finding Houou anymore...
Hey, Grandpa? Aren’t you going
to look for Houou?
There is no Houou.
No matter how hard I looked,
it would never show itself to me.
It never existed in the first place.
That’s how legends are.
I’m tired of chasing dreams.
I can’t believe this thing
tricked me for so long...
And that’s why I...
...want Grandpa to look
for Houou again, and to cheer up.
That’s why you had Onidrill and Hinoarashi
pretend to be Houou?
But aren’t you just
lying to him?
I guess I am...
Then let’s find the real Houou!
Great idea!
But how?
Grandpa tried for decades
but couldn’t find it!
You see, according to all the data
I’ve gathered so far...
The legend of Houou says that...
What?
...if you climb to the top of Bell Tower and wave
the Rainbow Feather in the wind, Houou will appear!
Grandpa said he tried that
several times!
But that it didn’t work...
I see...
Well, anyway,
we can’t just leave now.
Let’s go in!
This is...
Houou!
Yeah!
Come to think of it...
The picture we saw at the Sakuragi Institute
had a rainbow in it too, yeah?
It did! And when I saw Houou,
there was a rainbow in the sky, too!
Maybe the rainbow is the key!
The rain clouds will
pass the Johto Region soon!
With a rapid shift from rain to clear skies,
and the sun low in the sky...
...there’s a high chance
a rainbow could appear!
Then we wait for the rainbow
at the top of the tower and wave the Feather?
But where’s the Feather?
Hey, Kurio!
Wait a second!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Onidrill
Flying
Normal
Kurio’s been a while...
Don’t worry!
Satoshi! Go!
Will you let go of me, Kurio?
Just please, come with me!
Even if you climb the tower now,
Houou won’t appear.
You’re wasting your time.
Don’t say that!
For starters, you don’t even
have the Rainbow Feather, do you?
Actually...
...it’s right here!
I thought I threw it away!
I kept it safe!
It’s your treasure, after all!
C’mon, let’s give it a try!
Let’s do it!
The rainbow won’t wait!
Oh, fine! You just want me
to come with you, right?
Don’t get your hopes up, though.
This is pretty exciting!
Go!
Wh-Wh-What is this?!
Be careful, Grandpa!
I can’t get my foot loose!
What’s going on?!
Look!
Weren’t we
climbing the Bell Tower?!
Satoshi, go check
what’s going on!
Okay, leave it to me!
Can you get up, Grandpa?
Come on, grab on!
I’m fine.
You gave it your all, Kurio!
Of course! If I falter here,
I won’t get to meet Houou!
What is going on?!
GPS signal not found!
It’s no use!
Hoho! True Sight!
We’re back!
Look!
Odoshishi and Muma!
That was all their illusions.
I see!
Muma! Night Screeching Pokémon!
Ghost type!
It startles people and
gathers their fear as its energy!
Odoshishi! Big Horn Pokémon!
Normal type!
Staring at its antlers
creates an odd sensation!
Not gonna happen!
Monster Balls, go!
Nice! Great!
All right!
I got Muma and Odoshishi!
You did it!
Muma and Odoshishi’s data will be
added to the Index!
Amazing, Go!
That was nothing!
I’m gonna catch every single Pokémon!
What? All of them?
Yeah!
I see light!
It’s up there, huh?
Does this mean...?
It’s fine!
Here!
Grab on!
Thank you!
Grandpa!
The rain’s stopped!
Now all we need is the rainbow!
Yeah!
Houou! Show yourself!
Hey! Here we are!
Hey!
Come forth!
Houou! Show yourself!
Houou!
Hey! Here we are!
Show yourself! Hey!
The rainbow!
All right!
Houou!
Come forth!
Grandpa?
Kurio...
Thank you.
You...
No, all of you taught me!
Houou!
Grandpa!
Houou! I’ve come to find you!
Come forth! Show yourself!
Houou!
Hey!
Show yourself!
Houou!
Houou! Come forth!
Please!
It’s hopeless. Let’s give up...
...for today!
Grandpa?
I’ll start searching
for Houou again tomorrow!
Kurio, you help me, too!
Yeah!
All that shouting
made me hungry!
Me too!
Want to eat at our place, then?
What? Can we?!
My special curry
is a real masterpiece!
For real?! I wanna try it!
Yahoo!
No fair, Satoshi!
Hey, children! Houou...!
What about Houou?
Houou does exist! Right?
Yeah!
We told you so!
Oh, Grandpa!
Of course!
I see... I didn’t expect the sightings
to have been something like that!
Yeah!
We couldn’t meet Houou,
but we sure had fun!
Yeah!
I won’t give up!
I’ll catch every Pokémon,
and then Mew!
I won’t give up on my dream of
becoming a Pokémon Master, either!
Someday, I will catch Mew!
I will be a Pokémon Master!
There is no shortcut
to your dreams.
What’s important is to
keep rising to the challenge!
Satoshi and Go burned this lesson
into their hearts!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Apparently there’s an island
populated entirely by Kairyu!
What?! I really wanna go there!
All right!
A hunt for the Kairyu island...
Let’s go!
Look at all the Kairyu!
There’s Hakuryu
and Miniryu, too!
All right! I’m gonna complete
Miniryu’s evolutionary line!
What’s up with that Hakuryu?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Kairyu Paradise,
Hakuryu's Trial!
Hakuryu’s Trial!