Ahh, what a nice day!
Following the wind,
following their whims,
Satoshi and friends’ journey continues.
What Pokémon
will they meet today?
That’s a Delibird!
It’s pretty unusual
to see one of those out here.
We’re starving...
...our feet ache...
...and we don’t have anything
to report to Sakaki...
That’s Dellie the Delibird!
Oh? Why are you here?
Boxed lunches!
Digging in!
Thank you for the food!
Ah, I’m stuffed, meow.
Hey, hey, you got seconds?
Wha—?!
Pururill! Pumpjin! Koromori!
Megayanma! Habunake! It’s been so long!
Maaiika! Manene! Morobareru!
Deathmas! Muscippa!
It’s a great big gathering
of our Pokémon, meow!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Team Rocket's Counterattack!
Musashi. Kojiro. Nyarth.
Sakaki, sir!
These are the Pokémon
you caught across various regions.
Take charge of managing them.
S-Sir!
That is all.
Thank you, meow, Delibird!
Give our regards to Sakaki!
Thanks for the boxed lunches!
Sakaki will be expecting us to prove our worth
with all these Pokémon, meow.
All our Pokémon, huh?
This takes me back...
This face, that face, so many missions...
I wonder if they’re all
doing well, meow...
For all our graduated Pokémon...!
And to repay Sakaki’s kindness...!
Archenemy Pikachu,
we’re gonna get ‘chu!
We’ll be the Team Rocket
Revengers, meow!
Awesome! That sounds evil!
What a cool name!
Now we just need
to plan an operation, meow.
Ooh, I know, I know!
I have a good idea!
Right, Manene?
Mane!
Hmm, yeah!
Then why don’t you tell us
about this operation of yours?
It’s a Manene.
Pikachu, what’s wrong with it?
It looks like
it’s begging for our help.
But Pikachu’s wary of it...
Wh-Whoa... Hey.
Pikachu, we should help it.
Are you okay, Manene?
You ready? Here’s the plan.
First, you go to the brat boys,
and act out “I’m being chased by Team Rocket!
Help me!”, making them trust you.
Nod, nod, nod...
And here’s the pose
to really sell it!
Manene!
All right!
That’s the spirit!
What’s that?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket!
What do you want?
Manene!
You used to be so bad!
How could you turn nice?!
You make me so sad!
Huh? What’s going on?
I get it...
This is Team Rocket’s Manene!
Huh?!
So that’s why Pikachu
was wary of it.
That thing...
It betrayed us and ran off
to try and meet Junsa in this forest!
Selling us out to the police...
It’s a disgrace to villains everywhere, meow!
Hand Manene over, meow.
If that’s what’s going on...
There’s no way I’ll give it to you!
Would the outsider
stay out of our business?
Team Rocket never forgives traitors!
We’ll catch it and sentence it
to Chaotic Scratches, meow!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Manene!
Don’t go thinking we’re done with you!
We won’t give up, meow!
We’ll be coming back for you!
You don’t have to bother!
We need to hurry to Ms. Junsa!
We don’t have a moment to waste!
So... I have a favor to ask,
li’l Manene.
Once you meet her, please,
tell Ms. Junsa all about everything
that I, Takeshi, did to protect—
Ow, ow, ow...
Let me dream...
Okay, okay,
you can dream when you’re asleep.
I’m going numb!
Manene,
we’ll take you to the meet-up spot.
Come with us!
Morobareru?!
Everyone, get down!
Once Manene has their trust,
it’s your turn, meow.
Separate them one by one, meow.
Mushroom Spores!
They’ll put us to sleep!
Runpappa, use Water Gun!
Why’d they just attack like that?
Either they think
we’re invading their turf, or...
...they’re Team Rocket in pursuit!
Huh?
Satoshi and Kasumi,
you go on ahead.
I’ll figure something out here.
Got it!
Takeshi, be careful!
Yeah!
Runpappa, use Wobbly Dance!
Lalala La-la-la - Oh, what a wonderful
Lalala La-la-la - string of letters!
Lalala - And I mean
...Lalala - And I mean...
“G”
“I”
“R”
“L”
“S”!
I’m quick to fall in love
I know I am!
Which way?
That way?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Latias
Psychic
Dragon
A Pururill!
100,000 Volts!
A Deathmas?!
Hitodeman, use Water Gun!
Satoshi, keep going!
I bet they’re members
of Team Rocket, too!
Kasumi...
Got it.
Koduck!
You’re gonna fight?
Huh?
Gah... Hey, calm down!
Manene, is it even farther?
Pikachu!
Go! Goukazaru!
Mach Punch!
Muscippa and Pumpjin!
Pikachu.
You take Manene.
I’ll hold these guys off!
Make sure it gets to Ms. Junsa!
Go, Luchabull!
Let’s go!
We’d never let you get away,
li’l Manene.
Team Rocket never forgives traitors.
Accept your punishment, meow.
Manene, prepare yourself!
Now, meow!
All right!
Fire!
Huh?
Meow?!
No way!
It was going so well
up until now...
Maaiika!
Ah, well!
Manene! You did a great job!
Leave the rest to us!
Guys! Don’t you dare
let Pikachu get away!
Shing!
We’ll all attack, meow.
Get ready!
What was that?
Goukazaru, Luchabull,
come with me!
The signal, meow!
They figured out our plan?!
Let’s catch Pikachu quick
and retreat!
Let’s catch him, too!
Fire!
Flare Drive!
Pikachu!
Behold the Team Rocket...
...Revengers!
These guys are super strong.
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Romanticism”!
Hand over Pikachu right now, meow!
The “ke” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Keenness”!
Argh... What’s going on?
Manene!
Didn’t you leave Team Rocket?!
The little “c” in “Team Rocket” between the two stands for...
That was a complete lie, meow.
“‘Course, we’re villains!”
“Come on, come at us!”
It was an act
to isolate Pikachu, meow.
“Clearly, Pikachu’s too strong, meow!”
You fell hook, line, and sinker
for Manene’s masterful performance!
“What an awful feeling!” we scream as we blast off,
Manene!
and beneath us we see a little, tiny Earth,
Now, Revengers!
Let’s nab each and every one of ‘em!
forests, mountains and Pokémon...
They all blend together! What a great feeling!
Wherever we land,
we’ll have a meal to prepare ourselves for tomorrow
Dodge it!
We look up and see the shining moon
Here it comes!
You deal with it, Sonansu!
We look each other in the eye and laugh together
We’re the invincible Team Rocket!
Tricking crying children into silence...
Team Rocket!
A Namakero!
Satoshi?
Did Satoshi just... float?
Yeah...
It’s you, isn’t it, Latias?
Latias?!
How?!
That’s the one from before!
Huh? Wh-What ever is the matter...?
Punishment, meow?
What an awful feeling!
Wow...
Sorry for the scare.
Ugh...
How did our plan fail, meow?
Manene’s acting was perfect.
Kojiro, weren’t you slow
to fire the net?
You’re blaming this on me?
That was because you two called out
“Now!” and “Fire!” at a bad time!
It wasn’t my fault, meow!
You sure about that?
Musashi, you got greedy
and told us to nab them all.
Huh?! But that’s just
what you do in an operation!
Your senses of evil
have gotten numb, haven’t they?!
Huh, meow?! There are things
you should never say, meow!
What’s with you?!
What’s wrong with you?
This is it for us, meow.
Yeah, it’s the end of the line.
The end of the line indeed.
See ya!
I’m glad to see you again!
That vision I saw of Pikachu...
That was you, wasn’t it?
Thank you.
Satoshi did tell us that he met
a wounded Latias before running into us.
So this is the Latias.
Yeah.
Latios!
Latias...
What was that?
A vision of Latios shown by Latias.
What is going on?
Pa-pa para para para para para!
Pa-pa para pa-pah! (That’s right!)
P-Q-R-S-Team Rocket!
At last we get back to our hideout,
the exhausted Team Rocket
What caused our failure today? Right!
Review meeting’s starting!
Let’s quickly think back
to our battle of the day
If only we’d have done that then, meow... Right!
Review meeting’s over!
Five seconds and we’ve worried for long enough
More important is food to prepare for tomorrow!
(Yahoo!)
Our motivation is grow-grow-grow-growing higher
Our future’s open-open-opening up, the optimistic Team Rocket!
(Th-Th-Th... That’s right!!)
Pa-pa para para para para para!
Pa-pa para pa-pah!
P-Q-R-S-Team Rocket!
The optimistic Team Rocket!!
(Thaaaaat’s right!!)
Latios! We’re here to save you!
Latias is worried about you, too!
We want to help you!
I know you can’t trust humans,
but I want you to trust us!
No! Latias, no!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi and Latios!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!