Satoshi, Pikachu, Kasumi, and Takeshi
continue their aimless, free journey.
They have arrived
at a certain port town.
What a big town!
Looks like we’ll get to relax
at a Pokémon Center today.
We need to restock
on Potions and food, too.
Konpang! Konpang!
Over here!
Caught me off guard...
Haven’t gotten better at dealing with
Bug Pokémon, huh?
Ooh, a Hariteyama and a Bakuuda!
Hey! Do your best!
Hurry! Hurry!
The show’s not going anywhere!
Show?
Hey, look!
Zenigame!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Burn!
The Zenigame Fire Squad!!
“The Zenigame Fire Squad Show”...
Once upon a time, in his travels with his friends,
Satoshi caught Zenigame.
He now serves as leader of
the Zenigame Fire Squad,
and takes part in “Fire Chief for a Day” events
and disaster prevention drills in different towns.
That’s right,
I’ve heard it’s really popular.
Wow...
I bet he’s working really hard!
I wanna go see him, too!
Oh yeah,
these two gotta know, too.
Come on out!
Fushigidane, Lizardon, look!
It’s been forever, hasn’t it?
Let’s go cheer
for Zenigame together!
These guys are so famous.
We made the right choice forcing our way into being
their managers once we realized how popular they are.
We get to sell lots of tie-in merch
and rake in the dough, meow!
Don’t be shy! How about some
Zenigame Fire Squad pep merch?
We have pin badges, portraits,
and posters, too!
Excuse me!
Yes?
The brat boy!
What sort of pep merch
do you have?
O-Of course, we have exclusive fans,
glow sticks, cheering costumes, and more, haha...
Ooh...
That looks great on you, Pikachu!
It’s starting!
Ah-hah, hah, and more hah!
What’s this?
If you ask us “What’s this?”, “Pika?”...
We’ll tell you out of
sympathy for the world!
To prevent fire safety!
To preserve the world’s infernos!
Championing the evils of fire and smoke!
We’re the burning,
hot-hot-hot villains!
Musafire!
Kojiflame...
The Team Blaze duo
races through scenes of fires!
Like complete combustion,
a burnt-out tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow...
Team Blaze?
I feel like I’ve seen them
somewhere before...
Hey, hey,
we’re gonna start a fire!
Ready, set...
Blaze!
Ah-hah, hah, and more hah!
It’s really them!
So cool!
Zenigame!
So you show yourself,
Zenigame Fire Squad!
You can do it!
Good job, Zenigame!
Eep! We give up!
Team Blaze surrenders!
We’ll never do evil ever again!
Just kidding, meow!
They’re incredible!
They seem more like
heroes of justice than a fire squad.
There you have it!
The Zenigame Fire Squad were cool, huh?
Next, we have handshake sessions
and photo shoots!
Don’t forget to buy your tickets!
Okay! Line up, line up!
We should go, too!
Yeah.
Zenigame, cutie!
Shake my hand!
The merch sold out in moments, too!
Then all that’s left is...
...getting out of here quick
and having a good meal, meow!
All right! Today’s handshake sessions
have now concluded!
Whaaa—?
That Zenigame’s a friend of ours!
Couldn’t we just have a moment...?
No, no! After this, they’re heading back
to that hotel and have lots to do,
so off you go, off you go.
They must be busy,
being so popular.
We really wanted to say hi...
Thank you!
Thank you.
My! Your show was
a big success again today!
Making us proud,
Zenigame of the Zenigame Fire Squad!
The perks of having
good managers, am I right?
Hey, hey!
Keep the food and drinks coming!
Goes without saying,
but bring us more, too, meow!
Hey... That one
doesn’t look happy, does it?
It’s not sick or something, is it?
It said, “Am I not
your friend anymore?”, meow.
Huh? What’s that mean?
Beats me...
Oh! That hotel!
The Zenigame might be in there.
Why don’t we have a quick look?
Let’s.
Wow! It’s gorgeous!
I wonder where the Zenigame are...
What a racket...
What’s going on?
It’s the brat boys again, meow.
Don’t tell me they’re here
to take Zenigame back...
That’s not funny!
Oh, over there!
I’m very sorry!
No one’s allowed past here!
Huh?
All we want is to
talk to Zenigame.
We’re his friends.
N-O!
Hold on a sec!
Wh-What are you fighting for?!
Calm down!
Don’t be like this
when we haven’t met in so long!
Okay, Zenigame?
Zenigame...
What’s happened to you?
H-Hey, Pikachu, stop!
Not you, too!
Satoshi!
We told you, no entry!
Wh— Hey! Wait!
Lizardon! Fushigidane!
Hey, Zenigame...
Zenigame...
They’re getting away.
R-Right...
What was that about?
Hey, couldn’t this be our chance?
Pikachu and pals
are vulnerable, meow.
That’s a good point.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Zenigame
Water
They were cheering
for him earlier...
What made them fight?
I don’t know...
Zenigame seemed stubborn too
for some reason.
Hey, Lizardon, Fushigidane...
Cheer up.
You should make up with Zenigame.
We’re all friends
who traveled together...
This could have been
a heartfelt reunion...
They don’t suspect anything...
Not a thing...
On top of making lots of money
with Zenigame...
...we can catch Pikachu
and laugh like kings, meow!
Fire!
What an awful feeling!
What an awful feeling:
part two!
When you realized Konpang was gone,
where were you?
It was when I was crossing
that intersection...
Understood.
I’ll see if I can find it.
Ms. Junsa!
Is something wrong?
Yes...
A Pokémon is missing.
Let me accompany you
in your search.
Huh? N-No, I’ll be fine.
Don’t be shy!
Meeting like this...
could only be fate!
For you,
be it fire, water—
Okay, okay... Don’t bother her
while she’s working...
Double the straight men,
double the punishment...
Thank you for your cooperation.
Look! It’s a fire!
Isn’t that the
warehouse district?!
Oh, no!
What’s all this noise about?
Hey, what’s that smoke?
It’s a fire!
Are you okay?
What’s happened to you?
Seems the fire started
in the warehouse district!
This is bad...
We need to get the guests to safety!
It’s the Zenigame Fire Squad!
You can do it,
Zenigame Fire Squad!
Zenigame!
Stand back!
Keep away from the warehouse!
I’ll help you
with the evacuation!
Thank you.
Everyone! Stand back!
We should help Zenigame!
Got it!
Fushigidane! Lizardon!
Pikachu, let’s go!
You’re up!
Help us put out the fire!
Koduck, Udeppou, use Water Gun!
Nyorotono, use Hydro Pump!
Don’t give up, Zenigame!
I know you guys
can put this out!
A leader can’t stumble
when it counts!
Whoa, awesome!
Kasumi, connect this
to the water main, please.
Okay!
Thanks, Pikachu!
Oh, no!
Satoshi! Over there!
Put it out before it spreads!
Go out!
Please go out!
Fushigidane!
Lizardon!
You’ve almost got it!
There’s Pokémon up there!
Konpang!
Not good... Lizardon!
Zenigame, Fushigidane,
you come, too!
Counting on you!
Get as close as you can!
Zenigame, use Water Gun!
Fushigidane, use Vine Whip
to rescue Konpang and the others!
All right! Good work!
Hey, could that be...?
Y-Yeah!
We did it!
You’re incredible, Zenigame!
We never did find out
why they were fighting.
Well, they’ve made up now,
so all’s well that ends well.
What a relief.
There you are!
Double the Ms. Junsas,
double the joy!
So then, those managers
took the Zenigame Fire Squad without telling you?
Yes. I’m glad I finally
found them again.
Allow me to donate
the merch proceeds to this town.
I appreciate it.
They’ll be used to rebuild the warehouse.
Zenigame, you’re heading
to the next town, huh?
They have lots of people
waiting for them.
Do your best,
Zenigame Fire Squad!
Zenigame!
Let’s battle together again sometime!
Hey!
Whoa!
Wait!
Zenigame’s fans?
They really are famous.
I was right!
It’s Champion Satoshi!
Sign this!
Let me take a photo!
Huh? Me?
Guess we had a famous face
in our midst, too.
Shake my hand!
Let me hug Pikachu!
Ms. Kasumi! Mr. Takeshi!
I’m popular!
Bidding the Zenigame Fire Squad farewell,
Satoshi and friends set off once again.
What sort of Pokémon
and adventures await them?
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
This is bad!
Pikachu’s with Team Rocket!
What?
The brat boy is headed here?
How do you know that?
I don’t know how,
I just do!
Right. You don’t know,
but you can tell.
I’m on my way, Pikachu!
Pikachu, wait, meow!
Where are you going, meow?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
And, We Gaze at the Same Moon!
And,
We Gaze at the Same Moon!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!