Latios!
Latias...
What was that?
An enigmatic scene of Latios
shown by Latias.
What could it mean?
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Satoshi and Latios!
That just now...
It had to be dream sharing.
A power that lets us see
what Latios sees, through Latias.
Latias!
Where’s Latios right now?
Satoshi?
What is it?
Got it, Latias.
Everyone, return!
Latios is in trouble.
Let’s go!
All right!
Let’s follow her on Haganail!
Go ahead!
Have you been watching over us
all this time?
That time...
You were the one
who saved me!
Thank you!
What’s this?
Latios!
Who’s that?
Don’t think you can escape me.
Latios, look out!
Latias, what happened to Latios?!
She can’t tell?
I’m really worried.
That guy riding the Sazandra...
...must have been a Pokémon Hunter.
The sun’s setting.
It’s too dangerous to keep going.
We should rest for a while.
Got it.
Just wait, Latias!
Latios will be okay!
He won’t lose to
some Pokémon Hunter!
He’ll contact you again!
First time at HQ in ages, meow.
Just you wait, meow.
I’ll become a Team Rocket legend
even if I have to do it alone, meow!
Here I am again.
Just you wait...
I’ll become a Team Rocket legend
even if I have to venture by myself!
I will be a Team Rocket legend!
Here, Satoshi.
Oh, thanks.
You said that Latias was injured
when you found her.
Could she have been attacked
by that hunter?
Yeah. Then Latias somehow
escaped on her own.
Maybe Latios gave her
the chance to get away.
Yeah.
Hey, why don’t you eat with us?
You’ll have lots of flying
to do tomorrow.
We’ve gotta save Latios!
You can’t battle
on an empty stomach.
Gotta make sure
you’re fully recharged.
So you like it?
Latias?
What? What’s going on?
Latias!
All right, let’s go!
Return, Haganail!
Latios!
He’s suspicious of us.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Latios
Psychic
Dragon
Latios, hear me out!
My name’s Satoshi.
I want to help you!
Pikachu!
Crunch!
Let’s go, Kasumi!
Yeah!
Scale Shot!
Let Latias and Latios go!
Thank you for guiding me
all this way.
Even bringing me a Latias.
As it turns out,
luck was still on my side.
What are you saying?!
This isn’t funny!
Why, this is their destiny.
They’re beautiful—
meaning they’re valuable.
So many people desire them!
Sazandra, Dragon Pulse!
Yes... That’s right.
If you move,
you know what happens to Latias.
First, though... Will be you!
Stop!
Satoshi!
Stay out of my way!
Latios!
Move it!
You’re finished.
Latias!
Dragon Pulse!
100,000 Volts!
Go, Haganail!
Stone Edge!
Electroweb!
Causing trouble again...
Latios, follow me!
Go, Ohsubame!
Follow that hunter!
Are you okay, Latios?!
Just stay still for a second.
We need to treat your wounds!
I want to save Latias.
You do too, right?
Let’s go, Latios.
So fast!
Hurry, Haganail!
Over there.
So they’re here.
Ohsubame!
Great work, Haganail!
Where’s that guy?
Hey, do you get the feeling
that hunter led us here on purpose?
Yeah. Haganail, use Smack Down!
You’re in my way!
How could he?!
No way!
Here, you can’t fly freely.
So what will you do?!
Satoshi!
Destroy that mechanism!
If you do, Latias and the others
will go back to normal!
Got it!
Latios, fire a Guiding Wave Sphere.
Don’t worry. I’ll handle Latias.
Dragon Pulse!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
Now you’ve done it.
Dragon Pulse!
Wait, Latios!
You need to be...
...crushed into the ground!
Don’t be reckless, Latios!
How about battling by my side?
I wanna take him down, too.
Interesting!
What, are you Latios’s trainer now?
I’m not holding back!
Psychokinesis!
Psychic moves won’t work!
Crunch!
They vanished?!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Amazing!
The Psychokinesis was a ploy
to throw Sazandra off its guard.
We did it, Latios!
How dare you...?
How dare you? How dare you?
How dare you?!
Ms. Junsa!
All’s well that ends well.
Think about what you’ve done!
Right... I won’t do it again.
You’re leaving already?
But your wounds haven’t—
Let’s battle together again sometime.
I wonder what kind of home
they’re heading back to.
Hmm...
Some place of repose,
untouched by humans... perhaps.
Maybe I should head back, too.
Latias... Latios...
Satoshi’s meetings and partings with them
were etched deep into his being.
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
My dream...
to be a Pokémon Master.
The day I met Pikachu
was the day our journey began.
The world still has loads of Pokémon
I’ve never even seen.
I wanna befriend them all,
and make lots more friends...
...and after that, I bet...!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Rainbow and the Pokémon Master!
Pikachu, let’s stay together forever.