Well, Hanada City’s this way.
Okay. Got it.
I had a lot of fun
traveling with you again.
Yeah.
Please tell the Sisters of Hanada Gym
that Takeshi sends them his kindest regards!
Too close! Too close!
Precisely!
I want to get closer to the—
I’m going numb...
Satoshi! Takeshi! Bye!
See ya!
Take care!
All right, then...
It’s this way to Nibi City.
I’ll be off, too.
Okay. Look after yourself.
Let’s go, Gureggru.
See you, Satoshi!
Yeah! Let’s travel together again!
With their journey concluded, Satoshi and Pikachu
return to their hometown, Masara Town.
Home isn’t far now.
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
The Rainbow and the Pokémon Master!
I’m home, Barrierd!
I’m home!
Oh, my!
Welcome back.
And first...
Woo-hoo!
Ah... This feels great...
Now you’ve done it!
All right...
I’ll use Hydro Pump!
How about Bubble Beam?!
Then I’ll use Whirlpool!
Pikachu, dinnertime.
Oh? What’s that Pokémon food?
Takeshi gave it to me.
Takeshi was with you?
Kasumi, too.
Are they all doing well?
Yeah! They haven’t changed a bit.
Wait till I tell you all about
how much fun we had out there!
I even met Zenigame.
You know about him, right?
The one with the sunglasses. Oh, and...
Now, now, Satoshi.
Eat up before it gets cold.
Right. Time to dig in!
I wonder how they’re doing...
Latias and Latios.
Hope we get to see them again.
Satoshi.
Satoshi, I’m speaking to you!
Weren’t you going to visit
Professor Okido today?
Oh, that’s right!
Pikachu, let’s go!
Hold it.
You’re going out just like that?
Pajamas’ll get you in a jam.
I’m heading out!
Satoshi!
What?
New shoes! Wear them!
Huh?
Uh... These are fine for today.
Gonna get going!
Oh! Satoshi, Pikachu!
Good morning, Kenji!
Where are you going?
Running an errand for the professor.
I’ll be out for a bit, so look after the place.
You can count on me.
Oh, yeah!
Are the Hitokage, Zenigame,
and Fushigidane here yet?
He said he’d show them to me
before giving them to the new trainers!
They only just arrived.
He was going to give them a checkup.
I wanna see! I wanna see!
Pikachu, let’s go!
Okay, Marill.
We should get going, too.
Hmm...
Where could it have gone?
Dear, what a mess.
Good morning, Professor!
Oh, you’re here!
Zenigame! Fushigidane!
Huh? Where’s Hitokage?
I can’t find it anywhere.
I took my eyes off it
for a moment, and...
Huh?!
Maybe it ended up outside.
I’ll go look!
Let’s have everyone help out.
Hey, Hitokage!
Hitokage, where are you?!
In there?
Hitokage!
You’re not hurt, are you?
You’re gonna be okay.
Come on up!
Come on!
All right, in that case...
Hup... Hup...
Nothing to be scared of,
Hitokage!
I’m coming to get you now.
That was close.
Oh, that’s a nice smile!
So you could climb after all.
All right, I’ll join you!
Easy does it...
Shigeru!
Thank you for finding it.
I’m the one who
brought these three here.
You were, huh?
I’m glad you got out.
My, you were a great help, Satoshi!
I can finally get to their checkup.
Now then,
open your mouths and say “Ahh.”
Ooh, looking good!
You’re going already, Shigeru?
I may not look it,
but I’m quite busy.
Oh, right, Satoshi.
I still needed to say...
Congratulations on your victory.
Yeah... Thanks.
So now that you’re Champion,
how much closer are you
to being a Pokémon Master?
See you around.
It’s nothing.
Pikachu!
Let’s see who can get home first!
Wonder what’s for dinner today!
Welcome back, Kenji!
Table 20’s lunch is ready!
Bringing it straight out!
Orders here, orders there...
I’m swamped, meow...
Hey! Outta the way!
Right! Ready to take your order, meow!
Break’s over already.
Standing up all day is exhausting, meow.
Hup.
Where are you off to today?
Tokiwa Forest!
Make sure you’re back for dinner.
I know!
Barrierd! I’m heading out!
Man... Tokiwa Forest is
such a nice place.
This is the only path
left for me, meow.
I’m gonna cut them off, meow.
Ow!
That hard and cold feeling has to be...
That bristly sensation must be...
Nyarth?!
Shh!
Musashi... Kojiro...
We all came up with
the same idea, meow.
Naturally.
Cafeteria flowers never suit me
like the flowers of evil!
Once we’ve decided to catch Pikachu...
Our minds are united as one,
cruelest of the cruel!
Being out on the prowl
is the best, meow.
With that settled...
...time to attack!
Pumpjin! Seed Bomb!
Pikachu!
What are you doing?!
If you ask us
“What are you doing?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Haaaa...
Pikachu! Hold on!
Huh? Huh? Huh?
I left them all with the Professor!
How careless of you!
Pumpjin! Shadow Ball!
Wh-Wh-Wh-What?
Wh-Wh-What?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pikachu
Electric
Pidgeot! You came to help?
What’s that thing?
The brat boy’s Pidgeon
evolved, meow.
Huh?!
Now! 100,000 Volts!
What an awful feeling!
Even if it leaves me saying
“I’m going numb”...
...I just can’t give up
on that Pikachu!
The big dreamers...
...Team Rocket!
Together, our goal is...
...a great feeling!
You saved us, Pidgeot!
Thank you.
They’re all grown up, huh?
Wanna come with me again?
All right, Pidgeot!
Counting on you once again!
Where are you going today?
Hmm...
No idea!
Look, Pikachu!
A Nyoromo swimming on its back!
So now that you’re Champion,
how much closer are you
to being a Pokémon Master?
Hurry!
It’ll be over soon.
Pikachu.
Remember when
we saw Shigeru before?
Back then, he asked me how much closer I was
to being a Pokémon Master, but...
Being Champion’s not my goal.
I still consider myself a challenger.
I wanna have lots more adventures,
and meet more Pokémon.
All the things that happen each day...
Every one of them matters.
Like when I met that Latios.
I wanna make friends
with all the Pokémon in the world.
That’s gotta be what it means
to be a Pokémon Master.
Pikachu...
When I become
a Pokémon Master someday...
...you’ll be there, right?
All right!
Let’s go!
Oh, Satoshi.
He’s slept in again.
Huh?
Come back safe.
Which way should we go?
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind
No others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”