Huh? Where’s Satoshi?
Man, he’s so carefree.
Oh, don’t blame him.
Spending time relaxing with your Pokémon
is one of the great joys of being a trainer.
When I’m done tidying up,
I’m gonna follow suit and have a nap with Koduck!
Pikachu...
What?!
If you ask us “What?!”, “Pikachu?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Push.
What’s the matter with you?!
Nothing’s the matter
or the Matadogas or anything!
Until we catch that cool Pikachu...
...we’ll keep coming back, meow!
Satoshi!
I’ll be okay.
Tsutarja!
Leaf Storm!
Pikachu!
What an awful feeling!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
And,
We Gaze at the Same Moon!
It appears Pikachu was sent flying
along with Team Rocket.
Huh, meow?
Help, meow!
We’ve ended up
pretty far away, meow.
Hold on, meow!
Let’s have a truce until we meet up
with our friends again, meow!
I’m not lying, meow!
I’m being serious, meow...
I’ll use him as much as I can, then once I meet up
with Musashi and Kojiro, we’ll nab him, meow.
Huh, meow?
Hey, where are you going, meow?!
The brat boy’s headed this way, too?
You can’t know that, meow!
You can tell? How, meow?
You don’t know how,
you just can?
What does that mean, meow?!
Pikachu!
Hold on a sec.
Is this even the right way?
Yeah.
Pikachu’s headed this way, too.
How do you know that?
I don’t know how,
I just do!
Huh?
They can sense
each other’s thoughts.
What’s that supposed to mean?
I’m on my way, Pikachu!
H— Hey, wait, meow!
I can’t run any more, meow...
And I’m getting hungr—
Huh, meow? What’s that?!
Oran Berries, meow!
Time to dig inyarth!
Those are my berries, meow!
Take this!
Ow, ow, ow!
You take it from here, meow!
Run, meow!
They don’t give up, meow!
There’s a cave over there, meow?
Huh, meow?!
Wait for me, meow!
Oran Berries.
They’re charred.
It was Pikachu’s 100,000 Volts.
Which means
he went through here.
This feather...
Onisuzume.
I get it.
They had a battle here...
...and went in there.
Let’s go.
Okay.
Right.
I don’t have time
to battle you!
Please let me through!
Just give up on that hat, meow.
Reuniting with our friends
is more important, meow.
Pikachu!
This is all so we can catch Pikachu, meow.
Guess I’ve got no choice.
I’ll come with you, meow!
What? You saw it, meow?
It’s saying “Follow me!”, meow!
But you’re too slow, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Caterpie
Bug
Ow, ow...
Are you guys okay?
Yeah...
Yeah, somehow.
What’s that Onisuzume
doing here?!
Whoa...
You’re hurt...
Ah, ow, ow, ow!
Calm down!
Hey, you gotta stay still!
I agree.
But to calm a Pokémon down,
you have to calm yourself down, too.
Quietly... Calmly...
Rest up for a while, okay?
Hey, Koratta!
Is it hungry?
I was gonna share this
with Pikachu...
Oh, it’s fine.
What is it?
Of course. Koratta and Pikachu
are both Mouse Pokémon.
It’s reacting to
the scent of Pikachu on Satoshi.
That’s the spot
where Pikachu always sits.
Here, eat up.
I know!
Hey, Koratta...
Could you help me
look for my Pikachu?
Please!
Looks like it’ll do it.
Can you tell
where he is now?
Onisuzume...
Will you come, too?
Nyarth is probably
with Pikachu.
If we tail the brat boys
as they search for Pikachu...
...we can recover Nyarth and catch Pikachu,
two Poppo with one stone.
What a great feeling!
You’re ridiculously slow, meow!
I’ll carry you, meow.
“Grab on to me”?
You’re heavy, meow!
If you could do this all along,
you should’ve done it earlier, meow!
Fushide, meow.
Hup.
It’s getting pretty dark.
We gotta hurry.
Pikachu!
Up here? All right!
Fushide.
Onisuzume, stop!
That way?
Sorry for barging in.
Thank you!
After all this time,
now I’m feeling the Fushide’s poison, meow...
Here, Pikachu.
So, what should we do now?
We’ve split up with Koratta and Onisuzume.
It’d be dangerous to move around now.
Kasumi, Takeshi, you rest here.
I’ll keep looking a little longer.
Hold on!
We shouldn’t be wandering around in the dark.
Pikachu might be resting, too.
We should rest up here
and start looking early tomorrow.
A Momon Berry...
It couldn’t be...
This poison-curing berry...
You’re giving it to me, meow?
You’re so nice, meow...
Guess I’ll accept it, meow.
Can’t sleep, huh?
I feel like Pikachu is
gazing at the moon, too...
You’re right.
I had the same feeling.
It’s like you’re not yourself
without Pikachu.
Yeah. You’re two parts of the same whole.
Two hearts and bodies united as one.
Some nights, you can’t sleep
Come here, into my arms
We can talk, just you and me
What if we, what if we...
...had never met one another...?
I’d like to ask you...
Good night...
I’ll fall asleep soon, too
All better, meow!
But my stomach...
A Himeri Berry, meow!
Oh, what about some for you?
There’s no question...
I’m gonna find you, Pikachu.
Satoshi.
And Kasumi.
Thanks.
Pikachu!
Pikachu! Pikachu!
Ow...
Thanks for bringing my hat.
Satoshi?!
Anyway, I’m glad to
see you again, Pikachu!
Nyarth!
Get on!
Musashi... Kojiro...
What took you so long, meow?!
Team Rocket!
We’ll let you off for today.
But next time,
we’re catching that Pikachu!
Byesy-meow!
Satoshi!
Pikachu!
Thank you!
Satoshi and Pikachu...
They have always been, and will always remain,
the greatest of friends!
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
Look, look!
There’s so many Whaleko!
Now this is Whaleko watching!
Isn’t that...
the Laplace from the Orange Archipelago?
Ooh! Laplace!
Been doing good?
Happy to see you!
It seems like it’s saying
“come with me”...
Let’s check it out!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Riding on Laplace♪
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!