The sea!
Come on out, everyone!
Waninoko, Hahakomori, Mokuroh,
you okay?
Hey, Heigani!
Come back!
He must be happy to
be in the sea after so long.
Satoshi and Pikachu’s journey...
At a coast
with a salty sea breeze,
what Pokémon
will they meet today?
Pikachu?
It’s an Udeppou!
Udeppou. Water Gun Pokémon.
Water type.
By detonating gas
that accumulates in its right claw,
it launches water like a bullet
to defeat its enemies.
He’s strong...
I’ve decided!
I’m catching that Udeppou!
What?
Kasumi?!
It’s been so long, Satoshi!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Satoshi VS Kasumi!
A Seaside Showdown!!
I’m gonna catch that Udeppou!
Aww... Couldn’t catch him.
Pikachu!
It’s been so long!
They all look happy!
And so does Mokuroh!
I saw you on TV,
Champion!
Congrats!
Yeah! Thanks!
When I saw you battling,
I just couldn’t sit still!
So I left Hanada Gym to my sisters
and set out on a journey.
You did, huh?
What’s he doing?
Maybe he’s calling Udeppou.
I’m going to catch that Udeppou!
Why?
The two of us are linked together
by the red string of fate!
Fate...?
After all, I...
...fished him up with
my precious Kasumi Lure!
The moment our eyes met
through the Water Gun,
I felt a spark.
We met again and again...
Could this be chance?
No, it must be fate!
I can tell!
That’s how he shows his love!
You really think?
Can’t you just find another one?
No way! He’s the one!
Those eyes are so lovely...
So cool...
My heart throbs like it’s
Aqua Breaking!
But I decided
I’d catch that Udeppou, too.
You can’t!
I found him first!
My Heigani’s waiting!
I can tell!
The battle from before sparked
a deep friendship between Heigani and Udeppou!
Huh?
So I’ll catch him,
for Heigani!
In that case...
Let’s decide it by fishing!
Just what I wanted!
What’s that?
Huh? I got this from
a friend I traveled with.
I gave you one of mine,
didn’t I?
This one catches more fish.
It’s better than somebody’s lure.
Now you’ve done it!
Let’s have a fishing battle!
Hold it, Satoshi!
Whoever fishes him up first
has the right to catch him.
If they fail,
the other person gets a turn.
I get it!
Watch this, Heigani!
I’m definitely gonna
catch that Udeppou!
Ready? And...!
He’s not biting...
You’re so impatient.
He’s not gonna bite so easily.
You just have to wait.
Well, that may be hard
for a loudmouth like Satoshi.
You’re the bigger loudmouth.
Hmm? You just say something?
Wasn’t me!
Yes it was!
I could hear you perfectly!
Huh? It’s the brat boy.
And the original brat girl, meow.
Huh? So what?
I’m starving...
That’s it! Needs must
when the stomach drives.
We’ve gotta catch their food!
We’re the evils of justice, meow!
We’re supposed to catch Pikachu, meow!
I know that, but I can’t move...
You can’t catch
on an empty stomach...
Get it together, you gu—
Bleh... Hurry and bite.
Hurry and bite,
hurry and bite, hurry and bite...
Ugh, can’t you be a little quieter?
Aye, aye...
He’s here!
He’s here, he’s here!
This has to be Udeppou!
I knew he’d pick me!
I’ll do a way better job looking after you
than Satoshi the battle freak!
So come on out,
my beloved Udeppou!
Oh! She hooked something, meow!
Food?
An Udeppou.
Is that all...?
What an arm...
Oh, that looks tasty...
Huh?!
You noticed?
Even if you snap its claw off,
it grows right back.
The meat inside
is apparently a delicious delicacy.
So it really is?!
You’ve got guts, haven’t you?
Huh?! N-N-N-No, stop!
What?!
You tried to hook Udeppou
but he hooked you instead!
Gah!
Like you’ve even hooked anything!
This is it!
Come on, Udeppou!
I’ll fish you up!
All right!
I’m not giving up!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Heigani
Water
They’re talking about something.
He wants me to catch him!
Guess he didn’t agree.
Huh?
I’ve got it!
He’s telling us to battle!
We have a battle,
and whoever wins can catch him!
So that’s it.
Let’s battle, Kasumi!
I can’t say no
to a good battle!
Let’s do it!
What, what, what?!
If you ask us
“What, what, what?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world...
To protect the world from devastation...
To preserve world peace...
Championing the evils
of truth and love...
We’re the lovely, charming villains...
Musashi.
Kojiro.
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy...
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us...
Just kidding, meow...
Team Rocket!
I couldn’t hear any of that.
We’re starving...
You’ve been gone for a long time,
eh, original brat girl?
Forget that!
Let go of Udeppou!
It’s not like it’s
your Pokémon, is it?!
What we want is that Udeppou’s...
...huge claw, meow!
Claw?
You really don’t
know anything, do you?
Li’l Udeppou’s claw is a delicacy!
It’s supposed to be super tasty!
We’ve found
our dinner for tonight!
You’re gonna eat him?!
Well, you heard ‘em.
Once we’ve got the claw,
we’ll give the rest back, meow.
You can’t!
It’s fine.
It’ll grow straight back.
Don’t you worry,
don’t you worry.
Yeah, yeah!
Good job, Heigani!
Here they come!
We’ve gotta get outta—
Huh? What?
It’s hopeless...
I’m so hungry, I can’t move a muscle...
I can’t move, meow...
Come on!
Udeppou!
Amazing, Heigani, Udeppou!
When you’re together,
nothing can stop you!
Aww! I wanted to eat it!
The sea is vast.
Plenty more Udeppou in the sea.
I’ll take anything
as long as it fills me up, meow...
What an awful feeling!
The battle will be a 1v1.
Whoever wins catches Udeppou.
Watch this, Udeppou.
The skill of the world-class beauty:
the tomboyish mermaid!
Let’s go, my steady!
Nyorotono,
I’m counting on you.
Ooh! Nyorotono!
It looks happy!
Now, Satoshi!
Who are you picking?
Of course, Electric types are best
for dealing with Water types!
...is what I’d like to say, but...
Heigani, I choose you!
Hang in there, Heigani.
Hold it! Hold it! Why are you two
off in your own world?!
They’re men!
They have a friendship of the fists!
Hey, Udeppou!
We’ve felt fate
pulling us together too, right?!
Kyaah!
Those eyes, those eyes!
Let’s get going already!
We’re ready to go anytime!
My Nyorotono
is fully prepared, too!
Ooh, you’re gonna be the judge?
I appreciate it, Pikachu!
Let’s go!
Use Crabhammer!
Bounce!
What do you think?
These days, it’s the guardian deity of Hanada Gym!
You okay, Heigani?
Focus Blast!
Metal Claw!
All right, looking good!
Follow up with Aqua Jet!
Huh?! He’s so fast!
Nyorotono, keep your cool!
Dodge and use Hydro Pump!
Ach... So close!
Go up!
One more Aqua Jet!
Huh?!
Land the hit!
Hang in there, Nyorotono!
Let’s finish this!
Crabhammer!
Huh?!
Nyorotono, Megaton Punch!
We did it, we did it, we did it, we did it!
Good job, Nyorotono!
Heigani...
You fought well, Heigani.
There, there... I get it.
You’re frustrated.
Udeppou.
I won the battle.
I’m going to catch you.
So come on, Udeppou!
I caught Udeppou!
This really was fate...
Udeppou, I’ll treasure you...
H-Huh?! What’s going on?!
Awesome!
He’s giving him move training!
Lemme join in!
I’m the one who caught him!
Then why did we even
have a battle?
My head hurts.
I know you’re there.
Why’re you following me?
Huh? Um...
Udeppou and Heigani
seemed to get along well,
so I thought I’d let them
stay together for a bit longer.
J-Just for Heigani, okay?
Hmm...
Pikachu, let’s go.
Pikachu?
Guess I’ve got no choice.
Well then, here’s to good times ahead,
Satoshi, Pikachu!
Yup!
With new companions, Satoshi and Pikachu’s
journey grows even livelier.
And their journey
continues...
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
Huh?! We see Takeshi
for the first time in ages...
...and he’s heartbroken?!
Not to mention, he was taken away
by the witch of the woods!
What do we do?
Find yourself in a bind?
If there’s a riddle to solve, you can leave it
to yours truly; Sommelier Detective Dent!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Takeshi, Dent, and
the Forest Witch!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Here we go!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Championing the evils of truth and love!
Team Rocket Explorers!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Following an order
to catch new Pokémon...
...we made our first visit
to the Paldea Region.
Oh, meow?
There’s one, meow!
Hmm... It’s not in here.
Which means...
Look! There’s another one!
All right!
That’s it, meow!
The Legendary Pokémon,
Miraidon.
It says it’ll be an amazing Pokémon
forevermore!
All right, let’s catch it quick!
Yeah!
What an awful feeling!
Today’s roundup:
Miraidon is...
...futuristic!
Futuristic