I wasn’t expecting to find
an accessory shop there!
Who would’ve thought
she’d take an hour to pick something...
I fell asleep for a bit.
What do you think, Pikachu?
It looks good on me?
How about you two?
Accompanied by a merry Kasumi, Satoshi and friends
arrive at a town bathed in an evening glow.
It appears they’ll be staying here tonight.
Let’s see...
The Pokémon Center will be...
What was that scream?
Let’s check it out.
Yeah.
Over there!
Ms. Junsa!
It happened again?
Put your mind at ease!
You have nothing to fear
now that I’ve arrived.
I will exhaust every effort
to aid yo—Gah!
Okay, okay,
you’re getting us nowhere.
I shall be back...
Ms. Junsa, did something happen?
Well, there’s been a strange phenomenon
occurring in houses all over lately.
I believe a Pokémon’s behind it,
but don’t know who.
A strange phenomenon?
I have to investigate and stop it.
Let’s go, Guardie.
In that case...
Gänger!
We’ll help you!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Jupetta's Search!
Let’s split up and look around.
Right.
Guardie, smell something?
Ms. Junsa, behind you!
Gänger, use Shadow Ball!
Don’t let it get away, Pikachu!
Electroweb!
A Jupetta?!
I’ve figured it out!
It’s a Jupetta.
Jupetta?
But why would it do this...?
Over there!
Excuse us!
There it is!
H— Wait!
Over there!
Apparently Jupetta has been taking various items
from the houses it’s invaded.
Like what?
For example, a cushion.
A cushion?
Yes. A heart-shaped one.
Plus, a heart-shaped mirror,
heart-shaped sunglasses,
a heart balloon, heart chocolate,
and an ace of hearts.
Huh? They’re all hearts?
Right. The taken items have one thing in common;
they’re all heart-shaped.
Why hearts?
Hmm...
It looks great on you,
Gon-chan!
Jupetta. Plush Doll Pokémon.
Ghost type.
A doll given life as a Pokémon
by its grudge from being abandoned.
An abandoned doll...
Poor thing...
So is it harassing people
because of that grudge?
But why is it only taking
heart-shaped things?
I wanna know more
about that Jupetta!
All right!
Let’s go look for it again!
We’re all hungry...
We haven’t eaten anything
since midday.
Oh, is that so?
I’ll have to increase security...
Ms. Joy!
Your security is here.
Your heart’s worries are the key to unlock
my blazing flames of love—
I shall be back!
Let’s go to the cafeteria already.
All right!
I’m full of energy!
I’m gonna find Jupetta for sure!
There it is!
Hup.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Jupetta
Ghost
Huh?!
Hey— Why is it after me?!
Kasumi! It wants your hair tie!
Huh?!
Hey!
This girl...
For now, I gotta stop it.
Pikachu, use Electroweb!
Listen to me, Jupetta!
We might be able to help—
Wait! Gänger, follow it!
You okay, Kasumi?
Yeah...
I forgot it was after hearts.
Hey!
Takeshi!
I figured it out!
Huh?
Look at this.
What is it?
Jupetta dropped this earlier.
Hey, is it possible...
...that that’s Jupetta?!
Huh?
Oh, that’s right!
Plush dolls become Jupetta!
Look very closely at its head.
Oh! A heart!
It’s just like Kasumi’s!
Is it?
To sum it up, Jupetta is looking for
the hair tie it once wore as a plush doll.
So that’s why
it’s after heart-shaped things...
But why?
Maybe that girl, its owner,
is the one who gave it the hair tie.
It must be an important treasure
to Jupetta.
A treasure...
Gänger, where’s Jupetta?
I see...
Hmm, something’s bothering me...
What is it?
That’s what I can’t work out...
Hey, Kasumi... think you could maybe
give that hair tie to Jupetta?
Huh?
I wanna make it happy.
So, please!
Fine with me.
Actually, that was my plan, too.
Thanks!
Finished!
Wow! You’re so cute!
It looks great on you, Gon-chan.
I love you, Gon-chan!
See you at our new house.
Bye-bye, Gon-chan!
Hey, the truck’s leaving!
Hurry up!
It’s a ghost!
You lost track
around here, Gänger?
That place is suspicious.
A pile of hearts!
The things Jupetta took?!
Jupetta, are you here?
This photo’s yours, right?
We’re here to give it back!
There it is!
You want a heart-shaped
hair tie, right?
Here.
That should do it, right?
Hey, Jupetta...
The girl in that photo is your owner, right?
Don’t you wanna show her
your hair tie?
Let’s go see her right now!
Is that her?
Huh? What?
This is your plush doll.
It turned into a Jupetta.
Plush doll?
This is you, right?
No, that’s not me.
Huh? What?
Hey, Jupetta...
Are you sure it’s this—?
Huh?
Stop right there!
Sorry about that.
Jupetta... Don’t tell me
you can’t remember that girl’s face...
I knew it.
What do we do...?
The photo’s not exactly clear, either.
Huh? Hey, isn’t that green door
from that abandoned house?
Oh, you’re right.
Then this girl...
...must’ve grown up by now.
If we don’t know her age or her face,
we might not have any way to find her.
No, it’ll work out somehow!
If there’s no other choice,
we’ll just have to ask everyone!
Huh?!
I’m tired out...
Maybe she moved
somewhere far away.
Oh, I’m sorry, Jupetta.
See you tomorrow!
We’ll find her tomorrow.
Yeah!
Ah, Gänger!
He must be worried
about Jupetta.
What is it now, Takeshi?
I just feel like I’m overlooking
something important...
Welcome back!
It’s Ms. Joy!
Y-Yes?
Excuse you?
Learn when to give—
That’s right! It’s Ms. Joy!
The girl in the photo!
Huh?
Ahh!
Huh? What is it?
Ah, Gänger!
Where’s Jupetta?
We found the girl!
Huh? It didn’t go back
to the forest?
It went that way?
Kairyu!
Follow Gänger!
When I was young,
I lost my favorite plush doll during a move.
But I never imagined
it’d become a Jupetta...
Is that it, Gänger?
Kairyu!
So all this time,
you were waiting for me at that house...
Gon-chan...
Jupetta!
We found the girl!
Come on!
All right!
Let’s go, Kairyu!
Is that you, Gon-chan?
Gon-chan...
I’m sorry I left you all alone.
It looks good on you, Jupetta!
Now you’ll get to
be with Ms. Joy forever.
I’m so jealous!
Thank you so much.
The two of us working together
is like a dream come true.
Come back and see us anytime.
Right!
See ya!
Bye-bye!
One more bond has been formed
between people and Pokémon.
Okay, okay, let’s get going.
Ow, ow, ow!
Many more new encounters...
...still lie ahead for Satoshi
and friends.
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
Ooh! Aren’t these...?
Behold the Team Rocket...
...Revengers!
Amazing!
Simply amazing!
Let’s go, everyone!
Operation: Catch Pikachu!
Manene,
you’re the star this time!
The world is Team Rocket’s
for the taking, meow!
Yeah!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Team Rocket’s Counterattack!
Team Rocket's Counterattack!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon, meow!