On their carefree journey,
Satoshi and Pikachu reunited with Kasumi...
...and ended up traveling with her.
Ugh... I’m hungry...
Oh yeah, we should find some place
to have a nice lunch or...
Ooh!
Huh?
Perfect!
Thank you for waiting.
Here are your sandwiches
and special Pokémon food.
Time to eat!
Tasty!
This is the best!
But I feel like
I’ve tasted this flavor before...
I thought the same thing.
Oh! These are really tasty!
Thank you.
Manager!
They give their compliments!
Really? Thank you very much!
Huh?
Takeshi?!
Satoshi! Kasumi!
It’s been a while, Pikachu.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Just what it looks like.
I got hired as this café’s manager.
What about being
a Pokémon Doctor?!
I decided...
...that I intend to devote my life
to helping that lady.
Huh...?
Takeshi, good news!
My darling, who left to study cooking,
says he’s coming back to the café!
And he says,
“When I get back, let’s get married.”
Thank you for helping
support the café all this time!
Y—
You’re... welcome...
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Takeshi, Dent, and
the Forest Witch!
Cheer up, Takeshi!
I was burned...
Burned up...
Takeshi,
it’s like you used to say!
“Guys have to go for broke!”
No...
Not when you broke
without even going...
He’s hopeless.
What a mess...
Huh? Satoshi?
Dent!
It really was you, Satoshi!
It’s been so long!
Oh!
The guy who gave you that lure?
Yeah! I’ll introduce you.
This is my travel buddy.
Gym Leader of Hanada Gym,
world-class beauty, Kasumi!
I’ve heard of you!
The three beautiful sisters
of Hanada Gym are famous.
Oh...
Those are my sisters.
Huh?
Then, “the three beautiful sisters
and the spare” meant...
Spare?!
You looking for a fight?!
N-N-No,
I didn’t mean it like that...
He’s another friend
who traveled with me.
The Pokémon Sommelier, Dent.
Huh? What’s a Pokémon Sommelier?
I’m ever so glad you asked!
Would you send out
one of your Pokémon?
Ach! Popping out
without permission again...!
A Koduck...?
Interesting!
It’s tasting time!
Huh?
Yes, yes...
The glazed-over taste of Koduck and the spicy flavor
of the strong-willed Kasumi fit together perfectly!
Even if you become agitated, it can soothe your heart
like a forest silent save for a gentle rain...
The two of you truly are
a super mariage!
Okay, okay...
I think I get it now.
What a pity. My tasting was
just about to go into high gear...
I’ve got one more person
to introduce you to.
Another travel buddy, Takeshi.
Hey...
Takeshi?!
You know him?
We befriended one another
in the Johto Region.
We even watched your recent
finals match together.
Oh, of course!
Congratulations on your victory!
Oh, thanks!
So, what’s the matter with Takeshi?
He’s exuding a hefty
negative aura indeed...
Don’t even ask.
Ah...
Is it another heartbreak?
Can’t we do something
to cheer him up?
Hrm...
I’ve got it!
There’s a flower field nearby!
The fresh and cute flowers
are sure to perk him up!
That’s it!
Brat boy spotted, meow.
Brat boy #2,
original brat girl,
and even the sommelier boy
are with him, too...
Anyway, this time
we’re catching that Pikachu for sure!
Whoa! It’s so pretty!
Come on, Takeshi...
There’s lots of pretty flowers here!
Beautiful...
Beauty reminds me of... Ladies!
Ladies remind me of...
Pull it together, Takeshi!
Takeshi!
Takeshi,
I do love you after all!
Come over here!
Yes, right away!
Hey, Takeshi!
Where are you going?
Oh, Takeshi!
What’s that?
What is this?!
Suddenly, my head hurts...
What is that?!
Brimuon. Silent Pokémon.
Psychic/Fairy type.
It emits psycho-power
strong enough to cause headaches...
...as a deterrent
to the approach of others.
Ms. Kathy!
Takeshi! This way, this way!
Come quick!
Ms... Ka... thy!
Return, Koduck!
Takeshi!
Where could he have gone?
But... Why did Takeshi follow Brimuon
in the first place?
Yeah... It’s a riddle.
Did I hear you call for me?
Huh?
Sha-shing!
If there’s a riddle to solve, as a Mystery Sommelier-
crossed-Sommelier Detective, you may leave it to me!
Sommelier Detective?
This world has no riddle that cannot be solved
and no cork that cannot be popped!
It’s detective time!
He seems like a pain.
Brimuon can read the emotions
of creatures that are 50 kilometers away.
Which means that, naturally, she’s reading
the emotions of the presently heartbroken Takeshi.
Right, right...
The reason Takeshi
pursued Brimuon...
...is probably that Brimuon lured him in
with her strong psychic powers.
But why?
Our hints are Takeshi’s negative aura
and Brimuon’s alias.
Said alias being...
The Forest Witch!
The Forest Witch?!
The Forest Witch is said to love
negative auras...
...and trap those who have them
inside the forest!
Wha—?!
Also, the Index
contains this passage:
“If you’re too loud around it,
you risk being torn apart by the claws on its tentacle”!
What?!
That’s a pretty crazy Pokémon!
As things stand, Takeshi may...
We gotta save him quick!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Brimuon
Fairy
Psychic
Takeshi!
Where are you?
What is it, Pikachu?
What’s that?
Mibrim. Calm Pokémon.
Psychic type.
Via the protrusion on its head,
it senses other creatures’ emotions.
If you don’t have a calm disposition,
it will never warm up to you.
How cute!
She looks like a kind Pokémon!
“Via the protrusion on its head,
it senses other creatures’ emotions,” huh...?
Oh!
Mibrim might be able
to find Takeshi.
Huh?
If she can sense
the negative aura Takeshi is exuding,
she’ll know where he is!
That’s a good idea!
Hey, Mibrim...
Can you help
look for my friend?
Someone who’s important to us
could be in danger.
Please!
Was that an okay?
Thanks, Mibrim!
Then, Satoshi...
Think about Takeshi.
Got it.
Mibrim!
Can you sense anything?
I love you!
L-Likewise!
Hmph! I hate you after all.
N-No way...
I love you!
L-Likewise!
I hate you after all.
N-No way...
I love you!
Likewise!
I hate you!
No way...
Love!
Hate!
Hate...
Looks like she sensed him!
Right!
Another Pokémon.
Ooh! She looks like a stuffed toy!
She has quite a cute taste to her.
Tebrim. Silencing Pokémon.
Psychic type.
The evolved form of Mibrim.
So that’s why she looks like you.
It uses the braids on its head to pummel into silence
anyone with strong emotions, no matter who they are.
They are strong enough to
one-punch KO a pro boxer.
Huh?!
Did someone have
strong emotions?
I’ve been thinking super hard
that I wanna save Takeshi.
Which means...
That was a shock.
What a difference from Mibrim.
Mibrim, can you still sense
Takeshi’s aura?
You got it?
Okay, let’s hurry!
Yeah!
Sheesh...
You just ate earlier.
All this running
made me hungry again.
Uhh... Likewise.
As a Metro Sommelier-crossed-
Train Station Boxed Lunch Sommelier,
I’d love to eat one of the train station
boxed lunches exclusive to this region...
I wanna eat
my mom’s croquettes...
Hey, how can you two
act so nonchalant...?
Bugs bug me!
Kasumi loves Water types,
but can’t handle Bug types.
Huh... Then what about Shizukumo,
which has both the Water type and Bug type?
Hmm... That’s a tough one.
Satoshi!
Huh?
Mom!
Satoshi?
Here’s some freshly baked croquettes.
Eat up.
All right!
Time to dig in!
Huh?
Wait up! Mom!
Hey, Satoshi,
where are you going?
Wait for me!
What happened to Satoshi
and Kasumi all of a sudden?
Train station boxed lunches,
safety check complete!
Prospective customers, this way!
The Subway Masters,
Mr. Nobori and Mr. Kudari?!
I’ll have some!
Follow the schedule.
Everybody smile!
All aboard!
Oh! Wait!
Hey... We lost track
of the brat boys...
That’s weird.
I’m sure they went this way...
I’m not gonna get my wish for Sakaki
to reward me with cuddles like this, meow...
We’ll be promoted to admins!
Made branch managers!
Rise up the ranks
and celebrate with a party!
Until we’re full...
We wanna eat!
What’s that thing?
A Tebrim!
Run for it!
Mom! Wait up! What’s wrong?
Mom?
Here, eat up.
Huh?
Wait for me, Water types!
Mr. Nobori! Mr. Kudari!
Fueled up!
Full speed ahead!
One train station
boxed lunch, please!
I’m going numb...
Huh? Mom and the croquettes...
The Bug Pokémon...
And the subway train. To vanish like that...
Were we being deceived by illusions?
But Pikachu’s 100,000 Volts
opened our eyes!
Thank you, Pikachu.
But why show us illusions?
Brimuon likely hoped to
drive us out of the forest.
Huh?
This isn’t good.
She may truly plan on
trapping Takeshi in the forest...
Mibrim senses something!
Let’s check it out!
As I thought...
Takeshi!
Wait.
Let’s see what’s happening.
We may learn something.
Why don’t we have Mibrim help?
Right.
Mibrim will be able to sense what sort of
interaction Takeshi and Brimuon are having.
But how can she
communicate the information to us?
Pikachu might be able to help.
I see! Mibrim relays what she senses to Pikachu,
and Pikachu relays it to us.
I love you, Mr. Takeshi.
Ms. Joy!
I’ve fully recovered!
I lied! I hate you!
Did you get that?
More or less...
Pikachu, Mibrim, thank you!
Sha-shing!
Now, once again,
as a Sommelier Detective...
It’s detective time!
Judging by Takeshi’s
joys and depressions,
he’s being shown illusions
similar to the ones we saw.
In other words,
Brimuon’s goal is...
Indeed, to absorb the negative aura
Takeshi is exuding.
And to eke a richer and mellower
negative aura from him.
Her taste is to give him great joy,
then suddenly and coldly snatch it away.
No way...
If he keeps getting dumped,
he’ll never recover!
I’ve gotta save him!
Satoshi!
Takeshi!
Get away from Brimuon!
Get away from Kathy!
Takeshi, give me a hand!
Leave it to me!
I won’t let him get in the way of our love!
Huh?!
Let’s go! Haganail!
Wake up, Takeshi!
My vintage!
Yanape!
Seed Machine Gun!
Stone Edge!
Dodge it!
Mibrim!
Look out!
Take this!
I’ll protect Mibrim!
Satoshi!
Mibrim!
Satoshi, let me treat her.
Takeshi...
First, disinfectant.
Go for it!
Brimuon! Give it up!
Takeshi and Mibrim
are important friends of mine!
All right...
That’s a good girl...
I’ll be done soon.
Okay, all finished.
Brimuon has lost her angry taste!
I wonder if she’s saying
“Thank you.”
Thank you for your understanding.
Today’s events have shown
I still have much to learn.
I’ll travel with you
and give my heart some hard training!
Ooh! We’ve got another travel buddy!
We’re gonna get tasty meals!
The meals that Takeshi and Dent
make are the best!
While I am honored to
receive your compliment,
I’m afraid I must excuse myself.
Huh?
You’re not going with us?
I have to attend an event where Mr. Nobori
and Mr. Kudari are unveiling a new coach.
I’d like to try their boxed lunches, too.
Is that so...
Let’s meet again!
Best wishes! Safe travels!
Meeting and parting once again,
Satoshi and friends’ journey continues yet.
Delicious!
And no matter how much we eat,
there’s always more!
What a great feeling!
But how come we never feel full,
no matter how much we eat?
Infinite food,
but infinite hunger, meow...
Some kind of
infinite hell...
Lalala La-la-la - Oh, what a wonderful
Lalala La-la-la - string of letters!
Lalala - And I mean
...Lalala - And I mean...
“G”
“I”
“R”
“L”
!“S”!
I’m quick to fall in love
I know I am!
Hearts come tumbling
just pouring down
So many that I have
nowhere to step!
“Doesn’t he flirt too much?”
Let them think that
“What is he doing?”
Let them have their laughs
I have my very own
I have my very own dream!
Yeah! La-la-la - Oh, what a wonderful
Lalala La-la-la
paradise of mine!
Lalala - And I mean
...Lalala - And I mean...
“G”
“I”
“R”
“L”
!“S”!
No chance we’ll get lost now.
Yeah!
The rare spectacle of Koiking
climbing a waterfall!
I’ve always wanted to see it one day!
Come on out, Mijumaru!
Huh? It’s completely frozen!
Then we won’t see
any waterfall-climbing...
What?!
Oh! Look!
So that’s why!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Tunbear’s Sighs!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!
Tunbear's Sighs!