Then the Gyarados...
Mmhmm...
...suddenly attacked,
and I was in for a rough time!
This way, this way!
Satoshi and friends have come to a certain mountain
that receives perennial snow.
Their goal being...
No chance we’ll get lost now.
Yeah!
The rare spectacle of Koiking
climbing a waterfall!
I’ve always wanted to see it one day!
Mijumaru,
we’re gonna see Koiking!
So cute!
Huh?
It’s completely frozen!
Then we won’t see
any waterfall-climbing...
What?!
Bad luck, huh, Mijumaru?
We don’t get to see the Koiking...
Mijumaru?
Even Pikachu...
Well, if they’re having fun...
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Tunbear’s Sighs!
There they are—
Argh!
A Tunbear?!
Does that mean
Tunbear found the hotachi for you?
Thank you!
I’m gonna freeze!
Wait, Tunbear!
Fiarrow, melt the ice!
That’s its ability,
Flame Body, huh?
Thank you, Fiarrow.
Chase after Tunbear.
We’ll catch up to you soon.
Chase after it? Why?
Its eyes...
They looked really sad.
I see.
That is troubling.
Come on out,
Gaogaen, Kabigon!
Kabigon, use Megaton Punch!
Gaogaen, use DD Lariat!
That’s it!
Keep it up and carve out a path!
All right! Foretos,
you help, too!
Us, too! Starmie!
Pikachu! Mijumaru! Fiarrow!
What the...
What happened here?
Gaogaen! Great Blaze!
You okay?!
If Tunbear was behind this, too...
...it’s incredibly strong.
That waterfall must’ve been
its doing, too...
Hang in there!
Tunbear...
Where are you?
Kabigon, return!
Return, Starmie!
Return, Foretos!
Fiarrow, Gaogaen, help!
Nice and warm...
This Tunbear...
It can’t control its ice powers, can it?
You sure?
It made pillars of ice earlier.
Tunbear didn’t mean
to make those.
They’re just made by accident
when it gets scared or frightened.
You’re amazing, Tunbear!
You can freeze so much
with one breath...
...that you’d even surprise Kyurem!
You mean the Legendary Pokémon
of the Isshu Region?
Yeah, it has mighty
ice powers.
Your powers are really amazing!
I love them!
Don’t you wanna learn
how to use ‘em better?
Let’s train together!
Listen up, Tunbear.
Pretty much all Pokémon can
bring out their power using the same trick.
You picture it like
“mmmm...”,
you “fwoosh” it up
inside your body,
take aim, and “bam!”
Yeah, yeah...
See? Looks doable, right?
C’mon, try copying him.
Like this...
That part of Satoshi
hasn’t changed at all.
He still loves Pokémon,
and does everything he can for them.
Yeah. Hopefully Tunbear picks up on
Satoshi’s intentions.
That’s it. Fill your belly up with power,
like “mrrr,” then breathe it out.
You’re doing it,
you’re doing it! Keep it up!
That’s it! Take it slow!
Huh?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Tunbear
Ice
Thanks, Gaogaen.
This is a tough nut to crack.
I see why the mountain Pokémon
run from it.
Don’t let it get you down,
Tunbear.
So you failed once or twice,
so what?
I get it, Mijumaru!
You’re telling Tunbear to
make a hotachi with its ice, right?
I see! That’ll be good practice
for controlling its powers.
All right, now’s the real start.
Look closely at the hotachi
and concentrate!
Looking good, looking good!
Phew, that was a shock.
Thanks for the help.
You had the parts at the start down.
You’re amazing,
you know that?
So keep training
and don’t give up!
Go for it, Tunbear!
Believe in your power!
Keep it up!
It’s looking like a hotachi!
You did it, Tunbear!
You did it! You did it!
You’re amazing!
Fiarrow!
What power!
Gaogaen...
Tunbear, calm down!
You had it! You were so close!
Don’t worry!
You can do it!
Believe in yourself!
Tunbear!
Thanks, Tunbear. You saved me.
Ow!
Looks like I twisted it.
You can climb out of here.
With your big claws,
those ice walls’ll be a piece of cake!
Tunbear... I can’t move.
So take these guys up with you.
When you get out,
let Takeshi and Kasumi know.
You want me to get on?
Got it.
Thanks.
You gonna be okay, Tunbear?
Fiarrow! Satoshi...
Satoshi fell down here...
That’s how it’s done, Tunbear!
Wow! You just did it!
That’s what you wanted, right?
You controlled your powers!
You found a solution in a crisis!
Now there’s just one thing left to do.
Use your powers to get us out of here!
Don’t worry.
I know you can do it!
All right! Aim over there!
You’re doing it!
Go!
Next, the other side!
That’s it, that’s it! You’ve got it!
Keep climbing higher!
Hey! Kasumi! Takeshi!
Satoshi!
So you’re all okay!
Yeah!
Look!
Tunbear made these ice stairs!
You did it, Tunbear!
Yeah!
You were really cool!
Down I go.
Gah! Ow, ow...
Satoshi, your leg...?
I twisted it...
Let me see.
Thanks.
Give it a try.
You did it!
Did you all see that?!
Tunbear’s become an Ice Master!
They still look worried.
Isn’t that great, Tunbear?
A heart that doesn’t give up...
A heart that believes in oneself...
Tunbear has a bright tomorrow ahead.
And the journey
continues.
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
Come on!
The Zenigame Fire Squad Show is starting!
Step on up, come and see!
And why not buy some merch while you’re here?
The Zenigame have a show?
I hear it’s really popular these days.
Really?
Let’s go cheer them on
with Fushigidane and Lizardon!
Huh? Zenigame?
What’s wrong?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Burn!
The Zenigame Fire Squad!!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!