A crossroads...
Which way should we go?
All right.
We can use this!
We go whichever way the leaves point!
Left!
—is what I would say,
but this way’s better.
Just something about it
just feels right, y’know?
Now you’ve done it!
Oh? Gonna play dumb?
Then...
...maybe I should
leave you there!
Gah!
I’m going on ahead!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Kyaah!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
The Winds of Beginnings!
The Boundless Road!!
Following the wind,
following their whims...
...in a forest somewhere,
in a region somewhere...
...Satoshi and Pikachu’s
directionless journey continues.
Now then, what Pokémon
will they meet today?
Pi! Ka! Chu!
Pi!
Ooh, a Mukkuru!
Huh?! Koiking?!
Pikachu!
Don’t just laugh at me...
Thanks...
A Cocoon?
Oww...
Is it sleeping?
What?! Now?!
It evolved...
Poke.
That was scary...
But...
Did you see that, Pikachu?!
I...
...may have just
made friends with that Spear!
Ms. Mom!
Hello!
Professor Okido!
How are you doing?
Have you heard from Satoshi?
Nope, not a word since.
I don’t know where he is
or what he’s up to.
Well, it’s nice to wander around
without any particular goal every now and then.
I used to be just like that
when I was young.
Oh, he does have a goal of sorts.
He said he wanted
to make more friends.
Hmm, friends...
A poem just came to mind.
Pokémon Haiku
If it’s friends you seek
You should start with Pokémon
Hundred fifty one
Master of the craft!
Ooh, a Korobohshi!
A Minezumi?
Digda.
Nyarth...
Nyarth?!
Pikachu!
Byesy-meow!
What are you doing?!
If you ask us
“What are you doing?!”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
Whoosh! Shing!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
You again, Team Rocket?!
Wherever Pikachu may be,
Team Rocket is bound to follow, meow!
Then, Pikachu,
use 100,000 Volts!
What?!
This can absorb
all its electricity, meow!
Then... Iron Tail!
Escape is impossible!
We exhaustively researched Pikachu...
...and made an invention
that can withstand not just Iron Tail,
but any impact whatsoever;
the Super DX Capture Net!
So! With that outta the way...
We’ll be off!
You think I’ll let you?
Go, Onvern!
Blast Waves!
Sonansu, take care of it.
It’s up to you, Donphan!
Is that allowed?!
And that’s not all.
Go, Jukain!
Leaf Blade!
100,000 Volts!
Thanks, everyone!
You okay, Pikachu?
I don’t get it.
Our Pikachu countermeasures were perfect.
Alas, we didn’t prepare anything
for his other Pokémon...
Now we’ll know for next time, meow—
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Onvern
Dragon
Flying
What was that?
Let’s check it out.
Something’s there.
That’s...!
Latias, hold on!
Latias!
What’s wrong, Latias?
I’m sorry I scared you.
Buoysel, help us out!
Yeah! You’ve got it!
She’s wounded all over...
Thanks, Pikachu.
Just wait,
I’m gonna tend to you now.
I’m starving...
Everything hurts...
Hide!
Vwoosh!
The brat boy!
Hold it, what’s that?
Hey Rotom!
Who’s that Pokémon?
Huh?
Latias. Boundless Pokémon.
Dragon/Psychic type.
It communicates
using telepathy.
Its body is covered in down
that refracts light to make it invisible.
In short, it’s a Legendary Pokémon.
Get it now?
A Legendary Pokémon?!
That’s a huge find!
We’re gonna catch it, meow!
Oh, they got untied.
Thank you, Pikachu.
We should spray
some more medicine, too.
Thanks.
This’ll sting a bit...
Aww, sorry about that.
This time
I’ll tie them tighter...
...so they stay on.
That should do it.
I hope you get better soon, Latias.
Just rest up for now.
Latias! Good morning!
You can’t do that yet!
She’s scared...
I don’t know what happened,
but we’re helping you!
We’re all worried about you!
See? Come back down!
Can you understand me?
H-Hey, are you okay, Latias?!
Latias!
Open sesame!
Click, meow!
We caught Latias!
What?
I heard something, meow.
So cold!
Ack! The brat boy!
Oh, geez! It came with
some worthless freebie!
Hold on, meow.
If the brat boy’s up here,
those guys can’t attack us, meow.
Oh! Of course!
He can be our hostage!
Taking hostages
is elementary villainy!
Hey! Don’t you move, Pikachu!
Don’t you care
what could happen to the brat boy?
K-Kids don’t get cold!
I can deal with this just fine!
Latias, you okay?
Just hold on,
I’ll get you out somehow.
Escape is impossible!
This time,
we exhaustively researched Latias,
and now the Ice-hating Dragon type faces
Operation: Supercooled Capsule!
It’s super effective!
Operation successful!
What a great feeling!
Can’t I do anything...?
I know! Pikachu!
Send 100,000 Volts at me!
No way!
Latias!
Take my hands!
Onvern! Blast Waves!
We were so close, meow...
Whoops... This time we didn’t prepare
anything for Pikachu.
Just when we caught
a Legendary Pokémon!
What an awful feeling!
Thank you, Latias!
Latias...
I wonder if
I’ll see her again.
Meeting and parting with Pokémon
time and time again,
Satoshi and Pikachu’s journey
goes on somewhere, even today.
How many friends?
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
The more the merrier!
Specifically?
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
151 of them!
With a little courage
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
I get a new friend!
But yet sometimes
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
They get away instead!
I remember quite well
Meeting each and every one of you
Though we have hurt each other at times
Those were (er...) I forget
I know that there are
many more friends to meet
somewhere out there
151 joys...
151 dreams...
151 memories...
Let’s seek out every one!
We’re gonna have fun
by the sea today, Pikachu!
Ooh! An Udeppou!
All right, time to catch it!
Hold it right there!
Kasumi?!
The world-class beauty
Kasumi is here!
Satoshi! Let’s decide
who catches it with a battle!
All right! I’ll take you on!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi VS Kasumi!
A Seaside Showdown!!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Here we go!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Championing the evils of truth and love!
Team Rocket Explorers!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Following an order
to catch new Pokémon...
...we made our first visit
to the Paldea Region.
Oh, meow?
There’s one, meow!
Hmm... It’s not in here.
Huh? What’s that?
Let’s open it up!
Bingo, meow!
The Legendary Pokémon,
Koraidon.
It is said to have power
far surpassing that of other Pokémon,
but its biology
is shrouded in mystery.
All right, let’s catch it quick!
Yeah!
What an awful feeling!
Today’s roundup...
Koraidon is a...
Ko-fright-don!
Ko-fright-don