It’s like they’re balls!
When Whaleko
fill their bodies up with water,
they can bounce around like this.
Whaleoh watching may be
what’s famous,
but this is Whaleko watching.
Good going, Pikachu!
What’s that?
It’s a Laplace.
Don’t you think
it looks panicked?
Yeah, it does.
Pikachu...
No way... Are you the one
I met in the Orange Archipelago?!
I knew it!
Been doing good, Laplace?
Amazing! It is that Laplace!
So it was migrating
through this area, huh?
What’s wrong, Laplace?
Is it saying “Come with me”?
Right. Got it!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
PocketMonsters
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Eek!!)
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side,
we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
Will be one!
Riding on Laplace♪
The Laplace who once went on adventures around
the Orange Archipelago with Satoshi...
Where are our heroes now heading
as they ride on Laplace’s back?
Is that it, Laplace?
Wow...
What an interesting island.
It has holes and caves all over it.
They must be the result of many years
of erosion from the seawater.
Still...
What’s up with everyone?
Huh?! It’s a Whaleko!
A Whaleko inside a hole!
Huh?
Is that what you wanted
to tell us about?
It might have gotten itself stuck
from hopping around.
Laplace, thanks for telling me!
You can leave this to us!
People and Pokémon have to
work together at times like these!
Whaleko, I’m gonna get you
out of there for sure.
Oh-ho! Laplace, Whaleko,
so many Pokémon!
That’s perfect, meow.
Add in Pikachu...
...and let’s catch
every one of them.
But... What’s the brat boy doing?
Let’s try getting
a little closer, meow.
Go quietly...
Quietly, quietly...
No good.
We’ll just have to break the rock.
Don’t worry!
You can leave it to me!
Kingler, Negigaknight,
I choose you!
Pikachu, I need you too!
Okay, let’s do this in a single blow!
Kingler, use Crabhammer.
Negigaknight,
you use Brutal Swing.
Pikachu, you use Iron Tail!
Where’s Satoshi?
Ow, ow, ow...
Oh, I’m fine.
Heracross!
This rock is pretty tough.
Sorry I scared you like that.
You were a huge help,
Heracross.
Laplace!
We’re not gonna give up!
Satoshi, we should think of
another method.
Then...
This time, leave it to me!
That’s right! What do you do with
Water Pokémon but fish them up?
Okay, Kasumi.
Let’s fish it up together!
So help me out, Bayleaf!
Hey, it’s Bayleaf.
We can play together later.
Right now, I need your help.
Okay then,
use Vine Whip on Kasumi.
Huh?
Huh? Huh?!
Heracross,
you hold me in place.
I get it now.
Nice having you here, Bayleaf.
Whaleko!
This time, we’re getting you out!
Ready, and...
It’s hooked!
All right... Pull!
Keep going!
Whaleko!
Thanks, Negigaknight, Kingler!
Numacraw, support Kasumi!
Thanks, Numacraw.
Satoshi, let’s go on
three-two-one!
Yeah!
Three...
Two...
One!
We did it!
It’s out!
Success!
Whaleko?
Is it...
...evolving?
Wha...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Aim to be a Pokémon Master
Laplace
Ice
Water
Why evolve into a Whaleoh now?
It was so happy
it overflowed with evolving power... maybe?
What else can I say but...
what awful timing...
Uh... What do we do?
We fished up Whaleko,
but that won’t cut it for Whaleoh...
Yeah.
We’d need more manpower.
Anyway, let’s head
back down for now.
Yeah.
Looks like some kinda
commotion, meow.
That’s perfect. While they’re distracted,
we can snatch Pikachu quick—
Pikachu, you’re ours, meow!
Like a whatsit to a flame!
We’ll catch Pikachu,
and what a great feeling it’ll be!
Wha-Wha-What? “Lend us a hand”?
Wha-Wha-What did you say?!
Wha-Wha-What nerve!
There’s no way I’d take orders
from an enemy like yo—
Wh-Why is it I suddenly feel
in the mood to follow your orders?
Wh-What may we do to...
...b-be of help, meow?
Can we really trust them?
We’ve made a vow
with Mr. Pikachu, meow.
We don’t have a choice. Right now,
we can’t look a gift Nyarth in the mouth.
Yeah.
And that mecha will be a good
source of power to pull Whaleoh out.
“Power,” he says...
It’s human-powered...
The sin of ignorance, meow.
Great work, Pikachu!
Look at that,
after he threatened us...
What a schemer, meow...
He’s much more evil than us.
Oh, “Pikapika”...?
Yes, we would be happy
to help you.
We’ll do our best, meow!
Come on out, Dodaitoise!
Takeshi, you handle telling
Dodaitoise what to do.
Sure, but...
What are you going to do?
Okay, so, this is my plan.
First, me, Heracross, and Bayleaf
get close to Whaleoh from inside the cave.
Takeshi, you...
Dodaitoise, use Hard Plant!
...hold Whaleoh tight
with Dodaitoise’s Hard Plant.
Kasumi, you give orders
to everyone on land.
Gyarados!
Team Rocket,
you get the Mecha Koiking moving.
The Whaleko will
give Team Rocket support.
Then, Laplace and everyone in the water,
and Kasumi and everyone on land...
...can all pull Whaleoh out!
To rescue the trapped Whaleoh!
To live up to expectations!
Giving the full power
of truth and love!
We’re the lovely, charming help!
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
crosses the seas!
Like a whirlpool,
whirling waves await us!
Just kidding, meow!
Keep it up, everyone!
It started moving.
Time for us to start!
Bayleaf, use your Vine Whip!
Heracross, use your Megahorn!
Go all out...
Tickle, tickle, tickle,
tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle!
It’s working! It’s working!
Please work!
Looks like... it’s super effective!
All right! Full power!
Mecha Koiking turbo boost...
on, meow!
What’s that?
Heavy Bomber!
We did it!
Gyarados, guard us!
Dodaitoise, prepare to escape!
All right,
time to get out of here...
We’ll catch Pikachu
without expending any effort.
Meow... It couldn’t be...
The hatch!
Pikachu!
Good work.
Dodaitoise, time to escape!
What an awful feeling!
Kasumi!
Where’s Satoshi?
That’s the thing...
No good.
It’s completely blocked.
And the water’s rising...
Return, Bayleaf.
What other way out is there...?
The tide’s rising!
Huh?
Then, the water in there...
We have to save him, quick!
But... How?!
Laplace?
Ice Beam?!
It’s stopping the water
from flowing?
What’s that?!
Thanks, Heracross.
Was that Laplace?
Is this...?!
Weather Ball?!
Laplace!
You came for me!
All right! Thank you!
Yahoo!
Thank you so much, Laplace.
Sorry for worrying you,
Pikachu.
Satoshi, Whaleoh helped, too.
It made that tunnel in the ice.
You did? Thank you, Whaleoh!
Now, look after yourself.
Let’s meet again sometime!
Look!
The Laplace herd!
Are they here to pick it up?
That’s right.
You were their leader.
You keeping at it?
I bet it saw that Whaleko in trouble
and couldn’t abandon it.
Just like a certain someone.
Huh? Who?
He doesn’t even get it.
Conducting a rescue
and being rescued in turn,
their day with Laplace
came to an end.
What sort of encounters
and adventures await them next?
What is it?
Couldn’t we have just caught
Whaleko in a Monster Ball?
Eh, it’s fine. We had fun!
We don’t need any boat
We don’t need to swim
We just call for you, and a journey begins
We don’t need any road
We don’t need any goal
We have you, so the map unfurls before us
Let’s overtake the wind
We can go anywhere
If we whistle a tune, la-lalalala
The Earth sings with us, la-lalalala
Riding on Laplace
Let’s go seek out!
The next piece of the story that nobody knows
La-la-la-lala
A strange phenomenon
where things in the town disappear?
Yeah. And it’s apparently
the work of a Jupetta.
Jupetta’s an abandoned plush toy
that became a Pokémon, right?
Is it harassing people
because of that grudge?
I don’t know... but...
Ms. Joy is worried!
Ms. Joy!
With the power of my blazing flames of love,
your heart’s worries will—
Ack!
Numb...!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Jupetta’s Search!
Jupetta's Search!
Everyone, go and catch Pokémon!