Hey, Ricchan.
‘Sup.
Oh... It’s so hot...
Huh? What are you looking at?
I found something neat.
Check it out.
Oh? What is this?
Death Devil is formed
Your overlords
This was in a cardboard box
Mio found the other day.
Looks like an old
Light Music Club’s photo album.
Wow... They’re amazing!
Makes ya wonder
what century they’re from, yeah?
Huh?
Y-Yeah, I guess.
Here I was thinking
all bands look like this...
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
Maybe we should
tweak this part...
Ow!
What happened?
I cut my fingertip.
Ouch, that looks painful.
Budokan or bust!!
by: The Light Music Club!
You look too, Mio-chan!
Huh?
I saw nothing, I heard nothing...
Budokan or bust!!
I’ve been drumming so much
that the blisters on my hands burst!
Budokan or bust!!
See?
See ‘em?
Budokan or bust!!
Sear ‘em into your eyes!
The blisters! Look!
Ricchan, do we have
any bandages or something?
Behold! C’mon, take a look! See?!
Hey! Can you see it, Mio-chan?!
Excuse me...
I need to borrow these music stands.
Oh?
Here! Looky-look!
#5: Advisor!
Would you two mind
carrying the notebooks for me?
Thank you very much.
Ow!
Hmm?
The disinfectant stings!
I know, I know.
Keep your finger still.
Her desk is so nice and tidy...
There you go.
That should do the trick.
Thank you.
Now, if I may...
Um...
You’ve got a long way to go.
The way your skin is now,
it’s going to keep peeling.
What?
Your skin will get tougher every time,
and it’ll get easier to play.
It’s a rite of passage
for every guitarist.
Oh, it is?
Hey, hold on!
Did you use to play guitar, ma’am?
Nope. I had a friend who did.
Good work today.
Same to you.
See you later.
Ah... See ya.
Would you like some tea?
Yes, thanks.
She’s so nice.
Oh?
Mugi-chan!
Huh?!
Infirmary
Mugi-chan, is something wrong?
N-No, I was just thinking
about how pretty she is.
Oh, Ms. Sawako?
Oh yeah,
where were you earlier?
Ah, right. Mio-chan asked me to make reservations
to use the stage during the school festival.
But they turned me away,
saying we’re not recognized as a legitimate club yet.
Ah, okay!
Hmm?
Huh?
They don’t think we’re legit?!
No, apparently not.
Weren’t we good to go
just by having four members?
I thought we were.
Wait...
If they don’t see us as a club...
Is it okay that we’ve been
using the music room like it’s ours?
Nobody’s said anything so far,
so I’m sure it’s fine. Probably.
But forget all that.
I’d better go ask what the problem is.
Good idea.
Huh? Wait, where’s Mio?
Oh, Mio-chan?
She’s still in the corner, curled up in terror.
Come back to us!
Greetings!
I’m the club president!
Oh? Yui?
Nodoka-chan?
Ooh! Nodoka-chan,
why are you here?
What do you mean?
I’m on the student council.
Huh?!
That’s amazing!
That’s my Nodoka-chan!
Ya sure you’re childhood friends?
You don’t seem to be listed.
You’re kidding!
Don’t tell me...
Ricchan!
You know what’s going on?!
Yes... The only thing
it can possibly be...
...is an evil plot orchestrated by
the student council to crush the little clubs!
I just know your heart is pure, Nodoka-chan!
Come back to the light!
What are you talking about?
Actually, did you ever submit
your club application form?
Club application form?
I’ve never even heard of that!
Yes. You. Have!
Indeed...
It all started back in the spring...
I’m club president,
so I’ll fill it out!
Are you sure
you can handle this?
Um... I brought pound cake.
Would you like some?
You bet!
Hey, Ritsu!
Relax, I know!
Just lemme eat first and I’ll fill it out.
Just let me eat first and I’ll fill it out.
Budokan or bust!!
...I’ll fill it out.
...fill it out.
Of course...
It’s all your fault!
Oh, dear. Mio-chan,
Ricchan didn’t mean any harm.
You’re too soft on her, Mugi!
Now, now, now, now, now, now...
How do I put this...? I think you fit right in
with the Light Music Club, Yui.
Six times? Seriously? And anyway...
Ouch!
You’ve been spoiling her all this time!
Someone needs to teach her some discipline!
Huh?
Oh, fine...
I’ll see what I can do.
Huh?
You will?
Light Music Club...
Membership, four.
And then...
Who’s your advisor?
Advisor?
Are you being serious?
Yamanaka Sawako.
Our fair school’s music teacher.
Owing to her beautiful features
and gentle demeanor,
she is popular with the student body
and school staff alike.
As if that wasn’t enough,
she’s a talented singer and instrumentalist.
Um...
She is popular enough
to have her own fan club.
What are you talking about?
You girls...
Miss!
Yes?
Please be the Light Music Club’s
faculty advisor!
So you don’t have an advisor yet...
You’re the only one we can turn to.
We’re begging you.
I’m sorry.
I really wish I could say yes,
but I’m already advisor for the Wind Ensemble.
I shouldn’t make myself responsible for another club.
No way...
I’m really sorry.
Countless men have sought her hand.
Y-You can’t bribe me with flattery!
We won’t take up any of your time!
We can practice without supervision!
Just sign and stamp this paper!
Simple, huh?
S-Slow down...
Stare...
You used to study here,
didn’t you, ma’am?
Y-Yes, why?
We were looking at an old
Light Music Club photo album earlier.
Huh?!
Is something wrong?
Wh-Where is that album
right now?
It’s in our club room.
I see.
Ma’am?
It never crossed my mind that a final copy
would lie hidden here at school.
A chapter of my grisly past
that must never see the light of day.
A spawn of the devil
never to be awakened.
No
running
in the
halls
A sealed tome
never to be read.
A forbidden gateway
never to be unlocked.
It’s...
It’s...!
At long last...
Death Devil is formed
Your overlords
I knew it.
So that really was you, teach.
This girl. Look.
I can’t believe you found me out...
It’s true...
I was in the Light Music Club.
I... I never would have thought!
So, does that mean
this is your voice?
I’ve been waiting for
your arrival...
Now die!
Stop!
It’s too embarrassing!
I heard nothing...
Still on that shtick?
Wait... Were you the one
playing the guitar, too?
Oh, that’s right!
Play something! Play something!
Wha—?!
Come on! Don’t be shy!
No...
I can’t!
Oh... The unmistakable weight of
a Les Paul’s mahogany and maple...
This dulcet tone, full of sweetly distorted harmonics
from its humbucker pickup...
Huh...?
Ma’am?
Oh, screw it...
Her look changed!
She’s shredding!
She’s tapping!
She’s teeth picking!
My poor guitar!
You punks’ve been acting
like the music room’s your little playpen!
W-We’re sorry!
And don’t even get me
started on—
Did all of you just see that?
So much for promising myself
I’d act all ladylike as a teacher...
Teach...
It all began eight years ago...
She just started narrating!
I was...
I was... in love.
I love you.
I’m sorry.
I’m into girls
with more of a wild side.
And so I made up my mind...
...that I would become
his kind of woman.
I would be wilder.
Wilder! Wilder!
Ever wilder!
More! More! More!
Wilder! Wilder! Wilder!
I guess we can go out...
Sawako...
You took it too far.
That’s how it always ends, isn’t it?
Ma’am...
Please, spare me your
words of comfort...
Don’t be so down, teach.
Ricchan...
If you don’t want this getting out,
please be our advisor.
You’re stone cold, Ricchan!
Mugi-chan?
What’s up?
Something’s up with Mugi-chan...
Mugi!
Are you okay?
You were kinda spaced out there.
Do you feel sick?
I-It’s nothing...
And that’s an original piece
we’ve been working on.
As our advisor,
what do you think?
Well... I have some concerns with how
your rhythm section is all over the place,
not to mention
the off-beat playing.
But most importantly...
What about the vocals?
You’re not telling me
you don’t even have lyrics ready, are you?
Well, uh...
You’ve got guts if you think you can
perform at the school festival in this state...
We’re sorry.
What’ve you been doing
with this space all this time?
This isn’t some
cozy little tea parlor!
She yelled at us!
Don’t get me started!
Teacher!
What?
by: The Light Music Club!
W-Would you care
for some cake?
I would!
She would?!
Let’s see...
We should’ve written the lyrics
before the tune.
It’s Mugi?
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Tsumugi
No attachments
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
No attachments
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Mail
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
Good evening.
This is Tsumugi.
Now that Ms. Sawako
has become our advisor,
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck with the
songwriting.
my heart is thumping
for some reason.
Best of luck
with the songwriting.
“Thumping”...?
Nah, no way...
They’re done?
Y-Yeah.
Show us! Show us!
Huh? Now?
Yes, now!
I’d love to see them, too.
B-But it’s embarrassing...
Don’t worry.
We won’t laugh at you.
Yeah, yeah!
But... Hey, wait!
We can’t wait! If you brought them,
you’re ready to show them, right?
Please, Mio-chan!
You can give me a little peek!
No fair! If anyone’s getting a peek,
it’s gonna be me!
Huh? Why?
Because I’m club president,
that’s why!
Wha...?
Then I’m Mio-chan’s soulmate!
In that case,
I’m Mio-chan’s soulmate #2!
What gall! I’m the place
that Mio’s soul calls home!
Since when?
I wonder how my granny
out in the country is doing...
That’s got nothing to do with this.
Oh, did I remember to send mine
a New Year’s card last year?
Don’t change the subject!
Show me this shit already!
Lessee, what do we got?
When
I
look
at
you,
my
heart
goes
all
"thump -
thump"
My fidgety emotions are fluffy like a
Marshmallow
FLUFFY
I’m all itchy!
I want to rip this up!
P-Personally, I think
they turned out pretty well...
You really think they’re no good?
W-We didn’t say that...
Yeah, yeah!
They just kinda blindsided me...
C’mon, Yui!
You say something, too!
I think they’re amazing...
For real?
I love these lyrics!
Y-You mean it?
M-Mugi, what do you think?
She’s totally enchanted!
You’re not telling me
you’re cool with this, Mugi... R-Right?
I am.
Uh, you really think it works?
Mm-hmm.
You sure?
Yes.
Bein’ real with me?
Bring it on.
Sawa-chan!
“Sawa-chan”?
You agree
we can’t use these lyrics, right?
Y-Yes! I agree!
Right?
C’mon, you three.
Let’s take a step back and think.
Let’s calm down and...
Wait a sec...
Maybe I can give my image a boost
if I say I like this perky, cutesy crap.
You’re so young at heart, miss!
Ms. Sawako always knows best!
It’s Ms. Sawako or nobody!
Sawako! Sawako!
I-I think that maybe
I like this song, too!
Say what?
Well, then I guess we’re going
with these lyrics.
Yay!
Isn’t this great, Mio-chan?
Um... Yeah...
Okay, so that means Mio’s on vocals.
N-No, there’s no way!
Why not?
Well, I... because I...
Because I can’t sing something
so embarrassing, that’s why!
Hey, you wrote it, princess!
This is a problem...
Well, if Mio can’t sing,
that leaves us with...
Mugi, you wanna try?
Huh? But I already have
my hands full with the keyboard.
True. In that case...
Guess not...
Yui, wanna give it a shot?
Who, me?
But I’m not a very good singer,
so I’m not sure if I’d be the best...
‘Kay, moving on.
I’m sorry! I didn’t mean it!
I’ll sing! I wanna sing!
All right,
let’s hear you sing.
Roger!
When I look at you,
my heart...
Hold it! Hold it!
You’ll have to sing
while you’re playing guitar!
Oh, you’re right.
I forgot.
Really?
Let’s see...
Now you forgot to sing...
I can’t sing and play guitar
at the same time!
by: The Light Music Club!
I guess I have no choice.
I’ll give you some special training.
Ma’am!
We’ll start with
a lesson on teeth picking!
No, thank you.
Okay, try to keep up!
Roger!
Ritsu...
What?
You don’t think Mugi has a thing
for Ms. Sawako, do you?
Come again?
I mean... Do you think
she has a crush on her?
What, seriously?
Mugi!
Do you like Ms. Sawako?
Hey! Don’t say that...
Moron!
Budokan or bust!!
Oh, no. It’s just nice to get to see
some girl-on-girl bonding.
No way...
Oh, good for you.
Huh?
You’re going along with it?
I don’t think there’s anything wrong
as long as both parties consent...
Well, um...
What do you mean?
So... Yui will be providing vocals,
and you’ll be performing “Fluffy Time.”
Okay. I’ll get in touch with you again
once your time slot’s been assigned.
Thank goodness. I really appreciate
you coming to tell us in person.
All in a day’s work
for a member of the student council.
But are you really sure that
you want to go with Yui?
Ms. Sawako’s been giving her
some intense after-school lessons all week.
She should be ready in time.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
She’s perfect.
Now, Yui-chan,
show them what you’ve got!
Whoa!
She’s improved!
She’s so confident!
When I look at you,
my heart goes all “thump-thump”!
B
L
E
H
by: The Light Music Club!
Wha...?
I pushed her a little too hard.
I broke my voice!
Knock off the cutesy act!
You’re joking...
Then who will do the vocals?
You can’t make changes
after today.
What, really?
That means it’s gonna have to be...
Yeah, Mio-chan should
remember the lyrics.
Yeah, ‘cause she’s the one
who wrote ‘em.
You can do it, Mio-chan!
Do it for Husky Yui!
Hey!
Mio-chan!
Get a grip!
Three days left
‘til we go on!
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
Hey, Ritsu, want to get some practice in
before our show?
Sorry, not a good time right now!
That’s not for a while yet.
Don’t you want to practice?
She’s right! Let’s practice!
That didn’t happen.
Nothing just happened.
We’re performing today, remember?
Let’s practice while we can!
Let’s practice!
Practice, huh?
#6 School Festival!