A-Almost got it...
Just a little more...
S-Sis, are you sure
you can do this?
Yeah...
I can do it!
All done!
I wonder if Mr. Santa’s
gonna come this year...
I forgot my homework a lot...
Sometimes I didn’t eat my whole lunch...
I haven’t been very good,
so maybe he won’t come.
Please let me get presents!
It’ll be okay, Sis!
I’m sure Mr. Santa will
bring you presents.
You should make a wish, too, Ui!
Please let there be
a white Christmas this year.
White Christmas?
It’s when snow falls for Christmas
and everything turns pretty and white!
Ui! Ui!
Hurry, hurry!
Wait up, Big Sis!
Ta-daah!
It’s a white Christmas!
What is this, Big Sis?
It’s cushion stuffing!
Sis got a really harsh
telling-off that day.
Ui? What’s so funny?
Nothing.
I hope we’ll have another
fun Christmas this year.
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
It sure has gotten cold.
Huh?
You’re not wearing your scarf?
No. I think the wind blew it away
when I washed it and hung it out to dry last year.
Sis...
Nice and warm,
nice and warm...
Where’s your other mitten?
I guess I lost it.
Nice and warm,
nice and warm!
#7: Christmas!
Check it, you guys!
I made a flyer
for our Christmas party!
Christmas Party
Light Music Club
12/24
Place. Mugi's
.
Da   te.
Cover
charge.
.
1,000 yen
Huh? Did we decide
we were doing a Christmas party?
I didn’t tell anyone.
You should’ve.
“Date: December 24th.”
“Place: Mugi’s.”
“Cover charge: 1,000 yen.”
Um, I’m terribly sorry,
but the house is busy that day.
Ah, I was afraid of that.
The schedule at our house
is always packed.
You have to make arrangements
a month in advance.
I’m truly sorry!
Y-You don’t say...
What is her family?!
What about your house,
Ricchan?
No, forget it. Ritsu’s place is so messy
there’s nowhere to even stand.
Excuse me?!
You’re one to talk. You’ve got dirty clothes
dumped all over your room.
Like panties, for instance.
D-Don’t make stuff up
and say it with a straight face!
I have plenty of picture proof.
You big liar!
It’s the truth.
T-Two packs of bread...
futatsu
pan
Pantsu: Panties
“Pan”...
I have more...
S-Stop it! Please, stop!
H-How about your house,
Yui-chan?
Sure, why not?
Score!
But is it okay for you to have
a big group over on Christmas Eve?
Yeah. Mom and Dad
are both gonna be away that day.
Oh yeah, weren’t they away
last time we visited, too?
They travel a lot together.
They said they’re going to Germany this Christmas.
What a lovey-dovey couple!
Would you like us
to provide anything?
Leave the food to me!
Are you sure?
Yeah! No problem!
‘Cause Ui can make us stuff.
It’s a good thing she
has such a mature sister...
Oh, right!
You know what else we should do?
A gift exchange!
Yeah, great idea!
Don’t bring anything weird, Mio.
That’s your thing!
Like that time
in elementary school...
Awful cliché of ya.
You’re playing the straight man?!
Ms. Cliché.
I can’t wait!
A Christmas party!
Do you want to come to the
Light Music Club Christmas party, Nodoka-san?
Are you sure?
I’m not a club member.
It’s totally fine!
We’re all friends, after all.
The more people come,
the more money we’ll have for spending.
Money for spending
on what, exactly?
Can you come, Nodoka-chan?
Yup.
Yay!
And that’s the deal,
so I hope we can count on you for the food.
I’ll help out, of course.
I’d be delighted!
But...
I don't want Big Sis
to hurt herself!
I’d like you to handle
the decorations, if you could.
Roger that!
What do you plan to do at
the Christmas party, anyway?
Eat cake, exchange gifts,
that kind of stuff.
And we’re all gonna do
a party trick!
Party tricks, huh?
What can I do for that?
Huh? You’re actually
taking it seriously?
But don’t worry!
I’ll think of something!
I also have to get a present!
Oh, that’s right!
I need to go buy one, too!
What would be good?
Fancy Stationery
Nanohana
This is cute!
Nodoka-chan, I want this!
If you get your own gift,
you’re supposed to pass it along.
Then I guess I’ll go with this.
Hey...
Ritsu?
Have you made up your mind?
How’s this?
A-Absolutely not!
Then how about this?
Or how about this?
Preda                   ZomBaby
Ow!
Why do you always
go get stuff like that?
I finally decided on something!
Ah.
Ooh, you guys
shopping for gifts, too?
What did you buy?
If we told you,
it would spoil the fun.
Oh, right.
Oh, hey! Ta-daah!
We’re on our way over
to the raffle drawing!
So are we!
All right!
Another box of tissues?
We have a winner!
Top prize!
Here! Congratulations!
Mugi-chan?
All of you
are out shopping, too?
You won?
Yes. A trip to Hawaii,
it seems.
What is it with
her amazing luck?
But I turned it down.
How come?
SUPER
GAME OF
I wanted this instead,
so I asked them to exchange it.
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
Let’s all play it together
on Christmas!
Uh, sure.
Cook up a
F E A S T
What should I make?
Cook up a
F E A S T
And what trick should I do?
Anyone can do it!
Short Performance Primer!
Sis! What happened?
Oh, Ui...
I thought you were
cleaning the place.
Sorry.
Those look delicious!
Don’t eat those, Sis!
Don’t worry,
I won’t even have a nibble!
I said I wouldn’t!
I-Is she playing Statues?
Come on. Big Sis,
don’t fool around.
You haven’t put up any decorations yet either,
so you’d better hurry.
Hiyah! Snip, snip!
You’re just getting started?
Pardon the intrusion!
Come on in!
Hey-o!
Yui, we’re here!
Hey, everyone!
Come on in!
What’re you doing?
Once I started, I couldn’t stop.
What are you,
an elementary schooler?
Ah, I’ll take your coats.
Oh, thanks.
A hardworking little sister...
...and a goofy big sister...
Feels like the setup to
a tragic family drama.
Whoa!
This food looks awesome!
You made all this, Ui-chan?
Don’t be rude!
I made some, too!
Look at this cake!
Whoa, awesome!
I put the strawberries on top!
Consider that “awesome”
officially retracted!
Wasn’t that enough?
Oh, um... Big Sis worked really hard
on all sorts of things.
Like how she tried to clean the house
and tried to put up decorations...
And she also... Um...
She’s trying so hard
to stand up for her!
We understand.
We’re sorry.
Nodoka-chan says she’ll be late,
so let’s go ahead and have a toast.
Yup!
The carefree older sister
and the diligent little sister...
I guess they make
a pretty good team.
Cheers!
Can you believe it?
Another year drawing to a close.
Sheesh,
you sound like an old man.
Sawa-chan?
These are delicious.
Can I have another helping?
When did she get here?
Don’t tell me she scaled
the wall with a rope...
...and snuck in...
...through an open window?
Goodness,
who do you think I am?
Honestly, how could you forget
to include your faculty advisor?
Uh, well, “forget” isn’t exactly
the right word...
We didn’t invite you because we figured
you had plans with your boyfriend.
You’d better watch your mouth,
young lady!
Natural-born airheads are scary.
As punishment,
you’ll have to change into this!
Why in the world did you bring
something like that with you?
Ta-daah!
No good. You need to be
more embarrassed.
This calls for...
There’s no escape!
Come back here!
Hello?
Stop struggling!
I’m sorry.
I have the wrong house.
It’s the right house!
Help me!
No one will ever want to
marry me now...
High schoolers sure lead
amazing lives!
Let’s get this party back on track
and have our gift exchange!
Yeah!
High schoolers change moods
at the drop of a hat!
But what about you, miss?
Oh, I also brought something.
To be honest, it was meant as
a Christmas present for my boyfriend, but...
Heavy...
All right!
Let’s get started!
Sure...
The present in your hands
when the song ends is yours.
Here.
Jingle bells! Here!
Jingle bells! Yay!
Jingle all the way!
She’s trying way too hard.
Oh what fun it is to ride in a one-horse open sleigh!
Isn’t a Christmas gift exchange
supposed to be more fun than this?
No one will ever want to
marry me now...
Yay! Jingle bells, whee! Jingle bells, whoa!
Jingle all the way!
I’m getting dizzy...
This might be the most exciting
Christmas I’ve ever had!
And stop!
Oh, this is the one I bought.
All right, I guess
we’d better trade, then!
Ms. Sawako!
Something tells me
this is something truly wonderful!
Let’s see what we have!
This is the best Christmas ever!
Oh no, we broke her!
Stay calm, everyone.
Merry Christmas! Happy Christmas!
I’m sorry!
I’ll never do that again!
I’m sure something good
is just around the corner for you!
That’s the one I bought.
Grilled
Seaweed
That’s from me.
Nodoka-chan, we’re giving Christmas presents,
not year-end presents!
Lucky!
They look so yummy!
The ultimate album,
birthed from the depths of Hell
Yeah, yeah,
that one’s from me.
You were really planning to
give that to your boyfriend?
Yes, I was!
Got a problem with that?!
Natural-born airheads are scary...
Now the only ones yet to open their presents
are Yui-chan and Ui-chan.
Hurry up and open them!
Y-Yes, ma’am!
Because you said you lost your scarf!
Because you said you lost your mitten!
What would you have done if you
hadn’t ended up with each other’s presents?
Isn’t that wonderful?
Thanks, Ui!
Thank you, Sis.
I get the feeling this will make
the rest of winter feel that much warmer.
All right!
Next, let’s all do party tricks!
Way to ruin such a sweet moment...
Wanna go first, Mio?
She’s such an old geezer...
Yui, then!
Who, me?
All right! I’ll do it!
Ui?
Greetings!
Merry Christmas!
Is everyone having a good time?
I’m sorry.
This is all that I can do.
Did you practice?
Yes! Since Big Sis said
everyone had to do a trick.
Wait, you thought
that was serious?
It wasn’t?
I’m sorry, Ui...
That’s okay.
Don’t worry about it.
Now I’ll go!
Air guitar!
Then I’ll play air drums!
Mio-chan gave it
everything she had!
I’ll do an impression!
Wh-What’s that?
That was my impression
of a sunfish!
Okay, I’m going next!
Maple leaf!
What happened to the beautiful, sweet
Ms. Sawako we thought we knew?
Thank you for having us over!
It’s really cold, huh, Ui?
Snow!
Wow, you’re right!
It’s a white Christmas!
You know, you once gave me a white Christmas
as a present, didn’t you?
GO TO START
GOAL!
EL DORADO
WARP
SUPER
GAME OF
LIFE
Today sure was fun...
Ui, can I come in?
Big Sis?
Mind if I sleep with you?
Sure!
I’m gonna wear these to bed today!
They’re so nice and warm!
Then maybe I’ll wear my scarf to bed,
seeing as it’s so nice and warm.
Ah-choo!
Come on, Big Sis,
I’m freezing!
I’m gonna start dusting, Sis.
The New Year’s Countdown is about to start!
Sis, have your
New Year’s Eve noodles!
Yay!
Happy New Year!
You wanted two mochi
with your soup, right?
Yup.
We’re here in Yamanakako,
which overlooks Mt. Fuji...
What the heck?!
I peeled some tangerines.
And that’s how I spent my holiday.
Gimme Ui-chan!
You two are still quite close, I see...
Won’t you get fat doing nothing
but eating and sleeping?
I never gain weight,
no matter how much I eat.
That’s—
That can’t be true!
Even you, Mugi-chan?
On that subject, Mugi, how much
weight did you put on?
...kilograms.
I put on... kilograms.
You should apologize,
just to be safe.
I’m sorry!
Mio-chan, you went all out
with your outfit today, huh?
Well, Ritsu asked me yesterday
if I was going to...
I was just asking!
Wh-What?
Looks like Mio-chan’s gonna be playing
the same position this year, huh?
I’m going home to change!
You should keep it on!
It’s cute!
Y-You think so?
I sure do!
I got to see something lovely
this year, too!
You haven’t changed
a bit either, Mugi!
Tch!
Ms. Sawako?
Look at this!
She hasn’t changed, either.
What did you guys pray for?
For my family’s health and safety.
I asked to lose weight.
I asked to be able to eat
lots of yummy food!
Let’s all pray for
the Light Music Club, too.
May we all become
better performers.
May we all continue
to have fun together.
May we all be able to eat lots of the
great cakes that Mugi-chan brin—
Ow!
May I improve
at playing the guitar.
All right!
Want to grab something
to eat on the way home?
Please don’t mention food!
You really never
gain any weight, Yui?
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
We’re the Light Music Club.
If you get lonely,
you can come visit us whenever you want!
I’m not an elementary schooler!
Welcome to our club room!
Come in, come in!
It’s great to see you!
W-Wait, um... Before we do that,
could you explain what that was just now?
You two...
In any case, we’ll be performing
four songs tomorrow, so be sure to come.
#8 Student Orientation!
I am lonely...