Yui!
Oh, Nodoka-chan!
Let’s walk home together.
Sorry, but I have
club activities today.
Oh, is that so?
Another time, then.
Yui finally found something
she can pour her soul into...
It makes me happy,
but also a little sad.
What’s the matter?
Mugi-chan is bringing
some yummy treats today!
What happened to playing guitar?
Huh?
When I was in kindergarten...
In elementary school...
In middle school...
Your ice cream.
I’d just kinda drift around
and be all unfocused...
But now that I’m in high school,
I’ve joined my very first club!
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
Prep Room
Hello.
These three are
my Light Music Club buddies.
Yo!
Hello!
Akiyama Mio
This is our bassist,
Akiyama Mio-chan.
She’s really tall and has
a cool, grown-up lady vibe.
Hey, so, why did you choose to learn
bass instead of guitar, Mio-chan?
Because playing guitar is...
...e-embarrassing.
E-Embarrassing?
The guitar is like the core of the band,
and you have to perform front and center...
The audience’s eyes
are naturally drawn to you.
Just the thought of
being in that position...
Mio-chan!
Mio-chan is a little delicate.
Are you okay?
Kotobuki Tsumugi
On keyboard we have
Kotobuki Tsumugi-chan.
We call her Mugi-chan.
She’s calm, silly, and cute.
You’re great at
the keyboard, Mugi-chan.
Have you been playing it
for a long time?
I’ve taken piano lessons
since I was four years old.
I’ve even played at competitions
and won awards.
W-Wow!
That’s amazing!
What’s she doing
in the Light Music Club?
Now, then... It’s tea time!
By the way,
I’ve been wondering something...
This club room
has so many nice things.
Are all high schools
like this nowadays?
Oh, I brought it all from home.
It’s all yours?!
Yes.
It looks like Mugi-chan
is pretty rich.
Tainaka Ritsu
Our drummer is
Tainaka Ritsu-chan.
She’s a really cheerful girl
with tons of energy.
You were really born to
be a drummer, huh, Ricchan?
I chose drums for a noble reason!
One that’d move anyone to tears!
Really?
Tell me, tell me!
The reason is...
Um, well... You know...
...they’re cool.
That’s it?
L-Like, I mean...!
When I picture all the fancy stuff you gotta do
with your fingers to play guitars and keyboards...
It just makes me wanna scream!
I guess the instrument you pick
says a lot about you.
#2: Instrument!
Would you like more?
Ooh, thank you!
Come to think of it, you wanted to join
the Choir Club, right, Mugi-chan?
Yes.
But I’ve always wanted to befriend
fun and unusual people.
We’re like exotic animals to her?
By the way, Hirasawa-san,
did you buy a guitar yet?
Call me Yui!
I’m already calling you
Mio-chan, after all.
Y-Yui...
Sh-She’s cute.
So, Yui, what about the guitar?
The guitar...?
Oh, right!
I forgot all about it!
I’m supposed to play the guitar!
The Light Music Club isn’t a café.
How much do guitars cost? A lot?
Cheap ones start around 10,000 yen,
but they’re usually junk.
Something around
50,000 yen should do.
50,000?!
That’s ten months’ worth
of allowance...
The really expensive ones
can go for over 100,000 yen.
May we use club funds
to pay for it?
No, we may not!
Have one. It’s delicious.
Anyway, we won’t get anywhere
if you don’t have an instrument.
All right!
Then let’s go check out some guitars
on our next day off!
Yeah!
‘Tis most tragic...
Yes?
Big Sis, dinner’s ready.
Ui...
What’s wrong?
I joined the Light Music Club.
Really?
And I wanna buy a guitar.
Really?!
You can play guitar?
Nope! No idea how!
So, um...
Do you think you could
maybe lend me some money?
I’m sorry,
but I don’t have much either.
I was afraid of that...
Why don’t you ask Mom
for an advance on your allowance?
I’ll come along and back you up.
I knew I could count on you!
Yui!
Over here!
Hey, everyone!
Ow!
I’m sorry!
She only has a few meters to go...
Can she make it?
Who’s a good doggy?
Did you have enough?
I begged my mom and got her to give me
a 50,000 yen advance on my allowance.
So now I’ll have to be
really careful with...
...how I spend my money, but...
I can afford this now.
Whoa, there.
I’m just looking!
I’m so tired.
I’m all stocked up!
We had so much fun!
Where should we go next?
Wait...
Aren’t we forgetting something?
We still need your instrument!
Oh! Oops!
Amazing...
There’s so many guitars!
Yui!
See anything you like?
Is there anything
I should think about when choosing?
Of course there is.
You have tone quality, but you also have weight.
Not to mention the neck’s shape and size.
Being a girl, you should
pick one with a slender neck—
Ooh! This guitar is cute!
She’s not listening!
That guitar costs 250,000 yen.
Huh?
Oh, you’re right!
That’s way more than I can afford.
Is this the one you want?
There’s cheaper ones over there.
But I want this one...
That reminds me of how badly
I wanted the bass I have now.
I spent ages agonizing...
I-I’ll take this one!
And I haggled like crazy
for my used drum set.
Gimme a better offer!
You made the shopkeeper cry.
I really wanted that set.
Um... “Haggled”?
What does that mean?
It’s when you get ‘em to drop the price
on what you want using the power of your guts n’ grit!
Incredible!
How very admirable!
What’s so admirable about it?
Yui...
‘Kay, let’s all do
some part-time work!
Part-time work?
Yeah, so Yui can buy the guitar!
What?
I-I couldn’t ask you to...
Don’t sweat it.
I’ll count it as a Light Music Club activity!
Ricchan...
I’d love to give it a try!
Mugi-chan...
All right! Let’s do it!
Yeah!
Ye-heah!
Woo!
Woo-hoo!
What kind of job
are we going to do?
Part-time work?
Yup, so I can buy a guitar.
She’s already become self-sufficient!
It makes me happy,
but also a little sad...
Everyone from the Light Music Club
is helping me, too.
Huh? You’re getting
everyone involved?
Yup!
What kind of work
should we do...?
Maybe handing out tissue packs?
I-I can’t.
Perhaps a job
at a fast food restaurant?
W-Welcome!
That might... cause problems...
Yeah, honestly...
I think that’d push you too hard.
I couldn’t ring a doorbell if I thought
a scary person might come out.
I can’t take orders.
M-Mio-san!
I’m sorry! I don’t want you to
push yourself because of me.
I keep giving up or psyching myself out
before even trying.
We’re doing this
so Yui can buy a guitar!
Meaning it’s for the greater good
of the Light Music Club.
I have to overcome
my own limits.
I’ll do whatever it takes!
Just name it!
Wh-What?
How about this one?
Traffic survey...
You count the cars
and pedestrians on the road.
With a counter in your hand.
Like the Wild Bird Society of Japan!
This is a job even Mio can do!
Yes, you’re right!
I’m heading out!
Oh, Big Sis! Your lunch!
Why is there so much?
I made lunches for
the rest of the club, too.
They took this job
to help you, right?
Yay! Thank you!
Here.
We’ll pair up and switch every hour.
My, you’re so nimble.
Ki-yah!
Think you’re good, huh?
You’re so fast, Ricchan!
Ouch!
That’s what happens
when you get too heated.
We have a little bit of time
before we have to start.
Let’s have some tea in the meantime.
Yay! Picnic!
You guys worry me sometimes.
Traffic Survey
The weather’s so nice today,
isn’t it?
It certainly is.
She’s like a highlands princess!
Please give
me Prize A,
The Gibson
Les Paul!!!
Magazine sweepstakes?
It says one of the prizes
is a guitar!
Good idea. That could be faster
than saving to buy one.
Right?
Aren’t you tired, Mugi-chan?
I feel quite well.
Your finger still feels fine?
Yes.
Not sleepy?
I pressed the counter
instead of replying.
That’s a quarter note beat.
Now it’s an eighth note beat.
Do your freaking job!
Mugi-chan, all these treats
are really delicious,
but are you sure it’s okay for us to have
all these expensive-looking sweets every day?
It’s perfectly fine.
All manner of people
keep giving me these.
If I left them at home,
they would only go to waste.
People give your family enough sweets that
they go to waste? What kind of family do you have?
We’re counting the clouds
as they go by!
Is this an occupational illness?
That’s a wrap on day one!
I’ll leave for the train station, then.
Me and Mio are taking the bus.
You said you’re walking home, Yui?
Yeah.
Tomorrow, let’s—
Yup! Let’s eat more sweets!
I was going to say,
“Let’s give it our best”...
Hey, now.
But if they’re just
gonna go to waste...
Hey, hey, hey...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey...
It really is an occupational illness.
See ya!
Yeah!
Bye-bye!
See you tomorrow!
Everyone!
Thank you so much!
Once I have the guitar,
I’ll practice every day!
Thank you for these past two days.
The pleasure was all ours!
Here.
8,000 yen a day, huh...?
Even with the 50,000 yen advance
from your mother, this is far from enough.
Then let’s work a few more jobs.
Yes, let’s.
All right! Guess I’ll poke around
for ads again.
Yeah.
I can’t take this.
You should spend the money
on yourselves.
Yui-chan...
I’ll buy a guitar I can afford.
Yui...
I want to start practicing
as soon as possible so we can play together.
Would you come with me
to the music store again?
Thanks, you guys.
Well, I’d better get home.
Yeah.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Bye!
I need to get good as soon as I can,
for them and for me.
Well, I’d best be going as well.
Okay.
All of a sudden
I feel embarrassed to know her!
Looks like she wants it pretty bad.
Okay!
Back to work we go!
Wait here just a minute.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Would it be okay
if I were to haggle?
Huh?
Can you give us a discount
on a guitar?
Y-You’re...
...the company president’s daughter!
Does this...
seem good to you?
Gimme a better deal!
He will sell you this guitar
for 50,000 yen.
For real?!
What?
What did you do?!
The thing is, this store is part of
my family's business consortium.
R-Really...?
Thank you, Mugi-chan.
I promise I’ll pay back the rest!
It’s so cute!
I look like a real musician!
I need to practice autographs!
Big Sis, keep it down.
Big Sis!
You’ll be late
if you don’t get up soon!
Big Sis?
She slept with it...
Cool!
You really do look the part
with that guitar on you.
Play something!
You haven’t practiced at all yet?
Well... The guitar is all shiny and new,
so I’m kinda scared to touch it...
Oh, I totally get it!
I posed in front of the mirror with it,
took pictures of it, and slept with it, but...
Just play it.
I see you haven’t taken the film off
the guitar yet, either.
Couldn’t help myself.
Ritsu! Apologize to her!
I’m sorry!
I let my impulse take the wheel!
Forgive me, Yui-chan!
Yui-chan, have a treat.
As if that will cheer her—
It worked!
You’re right.
Guitars are for playing.
I’m being rude to it
if I just admire and never play it.
Thank you, Ricchan!
You gave me the kick I needed!
Yeah?
I was hoping it might get you
to start practicing...
I’m pretty awe—
Now, practice time?
How do I get it to sound
like they do in concerts?
You need to plug it into an amp.
It’s set!
Yay!
We got our club member!
Nice to meet you
Woosh
That’s so cool!
We’re finally taking off.
Our Light Music Club.
Indeed.
Our dream:
to play at the Budokan!
What?
Before we graduate!
What?!
Sorry.
That’s all I can play right now.
I should practice more
before I play with an amp.
W-Watch out!
That’s what happens when you pull the cord
before turning down the volume.
N-Now you tell me...
1065 days until a live show at the Budokan
?!
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
What?! Midterms?!
Is that another chord?
Why didn’t you study?
I was trying to...
But you know how when you have to study,
you tend to get distracted with other stuff?
Ooh! We’re having
sweet bean jelly today!
#3         Training!