Summer!
The sea!
It’s so pretty...
It’s sparkling!
All right! Let’s swim!
Yeah!
Hey! Don’t get carried away!
Yui, the water is salty!
It’s the salt!
It’s ‘cause of the salt, Ricchan!
Yui, there are waves!
There are waves, Ricchan!
They’re—
They’re not listening...
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
Light Music Club
“Light Music Club”?
Sakura High Festival
“Sakura High Festival”?
#4: Boot Camp!
Budokan or bust!!
So I do...
M-My finger!
You seriously forgot everything?
My grandma used
to compliment me all the time...
She’d say, “Yui, as soon as you learn one new thing,
everything else leaks out of your head.”
I don’t think that’s a compliment.
Mio-chan!
Where’ve you been?
We’re having a boot camp!
Boot camp?
That’s right. After all,
it’s almost summer vacation.
Wait, we’re going to the beach?
Or maybe the mountains?
We’re not going there to play around!
This will be a band boot camp!
From sunrise to sunset,
we’ll be practicing nonstop!
I’d better buy
something cute to wear!
Gonna need a swimsuit, too!
Listen!
After summer vacation,
the school festival will be around the corner.
The school festival...
Yes! The Light Music Club used to be
pretty famous for its live performances...
...at the Sakura High Festival.
But we’re...
Wow, the school festival!
High school festivals
are just awesome, aren’t they?
Concession stands!
Yakisoba!
Takoyaki!
All right!
I wanna have a maid café!
What?
A haunted house would be better!
Maid café!
Haunted house!
Please!
A maid café is so obviously—
Why just me?
We’re the Light Music Club, aren’t we?
We’re doing a live performance!
I’m very sorry.
I know I’m late.
Would you like to...
have some madeleines?
Oh, dear...
What do you think, Mugi?
I know we said not to rush it,
but come on.
It’s been three months now...
...and we haven’t even
played together once!
Now, now, now,
now, now, now...
Six times.
By all means, we should go!
I’ve always dreamed of
having a sleepover with my friends!
Wow! Really?
So, should we go to the beach?
Or how about...
I told you, this is going to be
a boot camp for the band!
How much will it cost?
Good question.
Aren’t we on a tight budget?
W-Well, um...
M-Mugi?
Yes?
Do you happen to have...
a summer home...?
I do.
She does?!
Big Sis?
Big Sis!
Shouldn’t you get up soon?
And wait,
are those my pajamas?
Just a little more...
Oh, fine...
U-Uh... Big Sis...?
What time is it?
Um...
Mio-chan
Hello.
Morning...
Good morning to you, too.
I’m so sorry!
I can’t believe I made it...
And after we warned you
not to oversleep, too.
Sorry, I was so excited
I could barely sleep.
What are you,
an elementary schooler?
Well... Maybe you’re being
a little too hard on her.
Mugi-chan...
Well, she did say
she’s dreamed of this.
I want it in gel form...
Gel?!
I wonder what
she’s dreaming about...
‘Kay, let’s get a picture!
You shouldn’t!
That’d be mean!
It’s for the memories!
Oh, I’m sorry.
See? You woke her up.
My bad!
Anyway, tell us already!
Where’s this summer house of yours?
Let me see...
We’re nearly there.
Whoa!
By the beach, huh?
Yes, on the beachside.
Yui!
A one, a two...!
Smell that salty air!
I’m so ready to take a swim!
I already said
we’re not here to play around!
It’s huge!
To be honest,
I hoped to secure a larger house,
but I could only borrow
our smallest.
This is your...
smallest house?
So much space!
This is amazing!
What’s this?
Oh, I’m sorry! I said that they didn’t
need to leave anything out for us.
What’s in here?
It’s a princess’s bed!
That looks great!
I’m so sorry!
I always tell them that I’d like
things to be as normal as possible.
They just don’t seem
to understand what that means.
Come in.
It hasn’t been used in some time,
so I hope everything still works properly.
Looks good to me!
Huh? Where are Yui and Ritsu?
They wandered off at some point.
Those two are impossible.
What’s that?
Oh, this?
It’s a school festival performance
by an older Light Music Club.
I found it in the club room
the other day.
They’re good.
Way better than we are.
Yeah.
When I heard this, I realized
I don’t want us to be in their shadow.
And that’s why you suggested
this boot camp.
Yeah. But...
We won’t be
stuck in their shadow.
I believe in us.
Mugi—
Awright! Time for some fun!
Oh, yeah!
That was fast!
What about practice?
We’re going ahead.
You two hurry up and get changed!
Still believe?
Y-Yes, I think.
Hey!
Hurry up!
We’ll be right there!
Shall we, Mio-chan?
Mugi, you’re gonna go?
We came all this way, so we may as well
enjoy ourselves a little. Right?
But I...
Mugi! We’re going!
Coming!
We’ll be waiting for you.
I’m going, too!
It’s been two weeks since we washed ashore
on this deserted island...
I was sure we were goners
when we got cast adrift at sea.
Still, this is fun in its own way.
What a grand find...
We’re saved...
Tonight we feas—
What crazy scenario
are you two acting out?
Mio-chan...
BUSTY
Eat this!
Yui! Let’s swim!
Yeah!
Ow.
That said...
This sure is a beautiful place.
C’mon, tell me,
what did you draw?
Before I knew it,
it was already this big...
Okay...
I’m not scared. I’m not scared.
When you go to the doctor,
they’ll find barnacles all over your kneecaps.
I swallowed seawater!
We’ve made it at last!
To the golden island of Zipangu!
The day’s not over yet.
When’d you get that?
We’re at the beach and all.
If we don’t live it up,
what was the point in coming...?
Practice!
You really forgot?
O-Oh for crying out loud...
This is all because you kept insisting on playing...
And which one of us
was having the most fun, huh?
Uh...
I’m stuffed!
The floor is so nice and cool...
When you close your eyes, doesn’t it feel like
the waves are carrying you away?
Hey, you’re right...
Good night.
Night.
We’re starting!
Get up, you two!
Mugi, stand back just a moment.
C’mon, let’s just call it a day.
We came here to practice,
so we’re practicing!
Yeah, but you know...
Say, Ritsu...
Have you gotten a little chubbier as of late?
Huh?!
Especially your belly.
I wonder if it’s because you haven’t
been playing the drums lately...
I just can’t carry
the guitar anymore.
Huh?!
This guitar weighs a lot, you know!
That’s why I told you
to get a lighter one!
Whose idea was it
to buy this, anyway?!
Yours!
The floor’s warmed up...
Yeah...
Roll... roll... roll...
Careful, you’ll get dirty.
This spot is nice and cool...
How do you expect us to play
at the school festival if we don’t practice?
Didn’t I tell you
we should do a maid café?
No, we should do
a haunted house!
Yui, you’re not
following me at all.
Take a good look at Mio.
Wh-What’s that
have to do with me?
There aren’t many people in this world
better suited for the maid look than Mio.
Black stockings!
A lily-white apron!
And a maid headband!
Moe moe...
...kyun!
Or something like that!
That sounds super cute!
Relax, Mio, I’m kidd—
S-Squad Member Ricchan...
Once we’re done with this,
we have to practice, got it?
We know, don’t worry!
One, two!
Time for our last number!
Let’s do it!
Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah!
Huh? It’s over already?
Budget ran out.
We’ll get to redo it someday.
You said it! They’ll go off like crazy
at our Budokan show!
Budokan?
Seriously? That’s what we agreed
we’d shoot for, remember?
Right?
Budokan or bust!!
Then I want
the fireworks to be pink!
You an elementary schooler?
What do you mean?
It’d be cute!
We’d look like a buncha kids!
I think pink would be
a bit much, too.
Aw, you really think so?
If we want to play at the Budokan,
we need to get at least this good.
Wow, they’re good.
Huh? I feel like
I could play this song...
I’ve been waiting for
your arrival...
Now die!
Huh? What was that?
The tape must have
switched to side B.
Oh, right...
I heard nothing. I heard nothing.
I heard nothing. I heard noth—
Barnacles on your kneecaps...
In a haunted house.
Stop it!
Stop it, please!
Ricchan.
I think you went too far.
Hey, I’m sorry.
I shouldn’t have done that, Mio.
Everything’s okay, Mio-chan.
There are no ghosts.
Really?
Sparkly!
Moe moe kyun?
I’m really sorry, Mio.
Yui-chan, what you said
about that song earlier...
Yeah, watch this!
Let’s see...
No way.
There! How was it?
Amazing, that was perfect!
I don’t know how to
make it go “myon,” though...
“Myon”?
I think what you’re talking about
is called choking.
This choking?
No.
Choking is when you
pull on the strings while a note is playing.
When you do that...
See?
Do this...
...and this?
Yeah, just like that!
That sounds funny!
Funny how?
That’s a real barnacle-burner.
Barnacles!
I can’t believe you even
have an outdoor bath.
Today was so much fun.
Yeah.
Maybe you were right, Mugi.
About me not having to worry so much.
So we could’ve had more fun?!
Who are you?
It’s me!
Wow, your bangs are long...
Got a problem with that?
They’re long,
but surprisingly cute.
Thanks! Wait, what do you mean
by “surprisingly”?
I’m sorry! I didn’t mean...
Um...
I think you’re trying for this.
You can tell? Amazing!
Now stick out
just your ring finger.
Oh, I get it!
A-Are you all right?
Music sure is great, isn’t it?
It was so much fun
finally getting to play together today!
Yui...
And it’s all thanks to you
for suggesting a boot camp!
Thank you!
Ah... You think so...?
Look at Mio
all embarrassed over there!
A-Am not!
I’m red from the heat, that’s all!
You’re not fooling anyone.
I’m telling you you’re wrong!
Uh-oh! Mio’s mad!
You little...!
Come back here right now!
Scary!
Anyone home?
Coming! I’ll be right there!
You said the photos from
the boot camp are ready?
Yep. Right here.
That one turned out great, huh?
Oh, and there’s one of Mugi, t—
Hand over the negatives.
I-It’s a digital camera,
so there’re no negatives...
Budokan or bust!!
Come on, Mio!
We’re starting!
Budokan or bust!!
Coming!
Give me just a minute!
Budokan or bust!!
by: The Light Music Club!
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
You don’t seem to be listed.
You’re kidding!
Don’t tell me...
Did you use to play guitar, ma’am?
Nope. I had a friend who did.
This was in a cardboard box
Mio found the other day.
Looks like an old
Light Music Club’s photo album.
That’s amazing!
That’s my Nodoka-chan!
#5       Advisor!
Who’s your advisor?
Advisor?