Hello. Hirasawa Ui here.
Today is going to be my first time
hanging out with Azusa-chan.
Hey!
Ah! Azusa-chan!
Sorry!
That outfit’s so cute!
Oh, you’re having a boot camp
with the Light Music Club soon, right?
Yeah. They said it’ll be
four days and three nights.
My sister told me she had
a ton of fun last year.
Fun?
Oh! Meaning they practiced a lot
and felt really fulfilled?
Huh? Uh... Yeah.
Probably.
Ui! Isn’t this cute?
Oh, I see.
They all play so well that surely,
at the very least...
...they get serious
during boot camp...
...right?
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
#10: Boot Camp Again!
What’s my sister like when
she’s at the Light Music Club?
W-Well...
She’s a little bit...
Tell me, tell me!
She doesn’t practice at all,
she gave me a weird nickname,
and she keeps getting
really touchy-feely all the time.
Azu-nyan! So squishy!
My sister’s warm
and sweet, isn’t she?
Um, that wasn’t really
what I meant.
What’s Yui-senpai up to today?
She’s at home.
BLEH…
Sis doesn’t handle heat very well.
She hates air conditioning, too.
I can picture her
sprawled out on the floor.
She’s been dead tired
all day lately.
What a slacker...
But she’s so cute
when she’s lying around!
Ui! Ui! Uiuiuiuiui!
Why do Ui and I view
her sister so differently?
I wish I had a big sister
like Mio-senpai.
Mio-san is so nice,
and on top of that she’s really cool.
What about Ritsu-san?
She’s irresponsible
and unfocused. I’ll pass.
Hey, now...
Who are you calling unfocused?
Hi, Ritsu-san.
Heyo! I came in when
I saw you two from outside.
I’m sorry, I’m sorry, I’m sorry...
You’re by yourself today?
Yeah, Mio’s taking
summer classes.
You don’t have to go,
Ritsu-senpai?
Who, me? To summer classes?
How come?
Of course...
Oh, that reminds me.
I’ve been meaning to ask you...
Mugi-senpai brings her own tea sets
and has vacation homes.
Does she come from
a really rich family?
You bet!
They even have a live-in butler,
and during long breaks,
they travel abroad!
Really?!
Sure would be cool if they did,
wouldn’t it?
Oh, so you don’t actually know.
Well, let’s give her a call
and go hang out at her place!
Are you sure?
That’s a little out of the blue.
Weird...
She’s not answering her cell.
Guess I’ll try her
home number.
Yes, hello?
Oh, somebody picked up.
Uh, is this Tsumugi-san’s father?
No, I am in the employ of
the Kotobuki family as their butler.
They really have a butler!
U-Um, would Tsumugi-san
happen to be home?
Senpai, calm down!
Lady Tsumugi is presently
summering in Finland.
Oh, she is?
Thank you very much!
I’m sorry to have
bothered you!
Wh-What did I tell you?
It’s exactly like I said!
I’m exhausted for some reason...
Want to come over?
We have watermelon.
I’m in!
I’m home!
Sis!
Watermelon...
Ritsu-san and Azusa-chan
are here!
Welcome home...
What a weirdly relaxing sight...
It’s just like she said...
Oh, you’re so cute...
Excuse us!
There she is!
Gotta be rough having to work
during summer vacation...
We have to go
to seminars and whatnot...
Are you guys practicing?
Yeah!
What brings you here?
The Light Music Club
is having a boot camp.
We were wondering
if you wanted to come.
A boot camp, huh?
Whoa... Her face has “what a pain”
written all over it.
Well, fine!
We’ll just go by ourselves.
She gets mad when we don’t ask her,
but when we do, this is what we get!
Too bad, she could’ve gone swimming
and had barbecue and stuff.
I can’t wait for the boot camp!
Who's on tea duty
Yui Yui Yui Yui Yui
BRIDGE
It's Yui
So about our
new song!!!
Dinnnng
Snacks I want to eat
Art by Mio
All right!
It’s been a while since
we were all gathered together,
so why don’t we go buy stuff
for the boot camp?
By the way, what are we
going to buy? New gear?
Well, uh...
Swimsuits!
She’s going just to play!
I figured as much...
Hey, we’re not playing around
the whole time.
I can’t trust your words!
Huh? How come?
Well, everyone needs a break
sometimes, you know?
True...
I hadn’t thought of that.
What’s this loneliness I’m feeling?
This one’s even more awesome
than the last one!
I bet this is the vacation home you said
you couldn’t borrow for us last year!
No, I’m sorry. That home wasn’t
available this year, either.
I find this one rather cramped,
so please try to make do.
You have an even bigger one?
Oh, yeah!
Let’s have some fun!
Hey!
No messing around until
after we practice!
Aw...
We wanna have fun!
Majority rules, then.
I vote for practicing first.
Playing!
I want to practice.
I vote for playing.
An unexpected betrayal!
Hurry up!
Wait for me!
I swear, they’ve got endless
energy for goofing off.
When Mugi-senpai says “playing,”
does she mean...?
I’m flying!
Yes, yes, yes!
No, that could never happen...
I said I didn’t want this stuff,
did I not?!
Get rid of everything on the beach this instant!
I don’t need the yacht, either!
Mugi...
Senpai...
Catch!
Back and forth, back and forth!
Will we ever get around
to practicing?
Azu-nyan!
Come play with us,
No, thanks.
Oh, you’re bad at sports, huh?
I am not! Bring it on!
Azusa-chan has really taken to
everyone in the club, wouldn’t you say?
Has she?
Dr. Ricchan, take a look at this!
Ooh! It’s a star-shaped alien!
Mio-senpai.
You know that story
about barnacles, right?
A long time ago, a boy cut his foot
on a barnacle, and he...
Uh, Mio-sen...
...pai?
Gotta move up some more!
Left! Left!
Gimme!
No!
Mio!
I don’t know
what got into me—
Where am I?
A deserted island?
Ricchan!
Yui...
Y-Yui!
Ricchan!
We... finally made it!
It’s the new world!
Zipangu!
The land of gold!
What are they doing?
We played ‘til we dropped...
Let’s eat and then call it a night.
What about practice?
I knew we should have practiced
before playing on the beach!
But you played
more than anybody, Azusa.
You’re all burnt.
I’m gonna practice, too!
All night long?
I will!
I’m beat...
I’m starving...
Suck it up.
Amazing!
Yeah, amazing is right...
I’ve never used
an amp like that before!
Mio, let’s hurry up and practice!
These snares are brand new!
Talk about self-serving.
Azu-nyan, what’s that?
What? Oh, this?
It’s just a tuner.
Whoa... It’s called a tuner...
You use it to tune your guitar.
You’ve never seen a tuner before?
Nope, this is the first time.
Then how do you
tune your guitar?
Huh?
I just do it by ear...
See?
Sh-She has perfect pitch?!
I can’t tell if she’s
amazing or appalling!
Here we go!
One, two, three, four!
Don’t you think
that sounded great?
We played perfectly together!
You were wonderful, Yui-chan!
When did they have time to practice?
What? Oh... no, no, no!
You kept perfect tempo too, Ritsu.
Have you done special training?
I’m so hungry
I can’t play right, got no strength...
You’re so hungry that you couldn’t
go berserk on the drums like you tend to, huh...?
C’mon, let’s eat! Feed me!
I’m hungry, too.
We’re back!
Welcome back!
Hello again.
Ricchan! We brought meat!
And veggies!
Just what I’ve been waiting for!
A whole head of cabbage!
I’m so hungry I’ll eat it raw!
Show a little patience, all right?
They goof off all the time,
but for some reason they play really well.
Let go! The cabbages!
The god of cabbages is enraged!
It’ll be ready in no time
if we work together.
I’ll light the grill.
See? Our underclassman is taking
initiative and working hard.
Yeah, all right...
My eyes are burning!
Yui, can you handle it?
Ricchan!
Yui!
When we die,
we die together!
Yes!
Ready! So, why don’t we make
some rice balls?
Sure!
They’re so different!
My, Mio-chan,
what giant hands those are.
Shut up!
That was so yummy!
It was delicious!
Awesome!
Now...
Shall we light
some fireworks?
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
FIRE      WORKS
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
FIRE      WORKS
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
FIRE      WORKS
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
FIRE      WORKS
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
Celeb
Fireworks
FIRE
Bargain
item
It burned out.
When it’s almost burnt out,
it makes you want to cheer it on, doesn’t it?
You can do it!
You can do it! You can do it!
Right, one more time!
You can do it!
It broke off again.
Ricchan, it’s going out!
All right! Now we just gotta
combine ‘em and make ‘em bigger!
Combine!
Form Sparklerman!
No fair!
Idiots.
It’s not too heavy?
I’m fine.
Let’s do a test of courage!
Yeah!
If it’s not one thing,
it’s another...
Why not?
When you’re on a summer boot camp,
you gotta have a test of courage!
I’m not doing it.
Oh, you won’t? Guess it’s true
you never could deal with scary stuff.
I can handle it just fine!
Bring it on!
You’re going to pay for
making me wait so long to eat!
S-Seriously, who still does
tests of courage in high school?
Um...
You’re hurting my hand.
Wh-What could that be?
I b-b-b-bet it’s R-R-Ritsu
messing with us!
Mio-chan...
Senpai! Senpai!
Pull yourself together!
M-Miss!
What are you doing here?
I... I finally found you...
Huh? Sawa-chan-sensei?
What’s wrong? Or wait...
Why are you here?
My plan was to catch up
and surprise you.
But I got lost.
Well, you definitely succeeded
in surprising us, at least...
Mio-chan! Everything’s okay!
Mio-chan!
I had no idea Mio-senpai
got scared so easily.
Nobody’s coming...
That was dreadful...
Now, now...
Mio! Mio!
Azusa, you can’t handle hot water?
No, that’s not it.
Azu-nyan, at a moment like this,
it’s best to grit your teeth and get it over with!
Ow!
Oh, was it because
you’re sunburned?
Yui-chan,
have you lost weight?
Huh? No.
Didn’t I say before?
I can eat all I want, and I never gain any weight.
I’m so jealous!
Huh?! You too, Sawa-chan-sensei?
You know, I can’t tell you two apart
without my glasses on.
I guess I’ll have to use bust size
to tell you apart!
Gel...
Gimme the cabbage...!
I’m sorry, I didn’t mean to
make you practice with me.
Don’t worry about it.
I was hoping to practice
with you some more anyway.
Thanks!
Let’s see...
You’re so good, Azu-nyan!
Huh?! Not at all!
Okay, now I’ll give it a try.
This part is really tough...
You should start by
playing it at a slower tempo.
Like this?
I did it!
I’m so glad I met you, Azu-nyan!
Azu-nyan!
Thank you, Azu-nyan!
Hello. Hirasawa Ui here.
Today I’ll be hanging out
with Azusa-chan again.
Hey!
Sorry I’m late!
What kept you?
Wait, who are you?
Oh, so you didn’t get
to practice much...
We did practice, but I was expecting it
to be a lot more focused.
We basically just goofed off and did stuff
like swim and have a test of courage.
I wanted to practice more!
I see.
Though... my sister wasn’t tan at all.
How did you get so sunburned?
U-Um...
Because I played around
more than anyone else.
Still, though...
I’m really glad I went.
I learned lots of things
about them.
Really? Like what?
Well, like how Mio-senpai is
more of a scaredy-cat than you’d expect.
Oh, she is?
What about Ritsu-san?
Well, she’s unfocused,
but her and Mio-senpai are great together.
And Tsumugi-san?
Well, Mugi-senpai is sweet
and always thinks about others,
but she has a childlike side
that’s really cute.
What about my sister?
Well, Yui-senpai...
She actually practiced
on her own!
Right?
Yeah, but...
She still jumps me
and gets all handsy.
She’s warm and sweet, isn’t she?
I suppose so.
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
The strings are rusty!
When was the last time
you changed them?
Huh? You’re supposed
to change them?
Wh-What?
Is this...
a vintage guitar?
We’re sorry.
It’s just dirty.
I only bought it last year!
But if she doesn’t come back...
What’ll happen to our show
at the festival?
#11                   Crisis!