Hello! I’m Hirasawa Ui!
My high school entrance exams are through,
and I’ll be joining my sister this spring at—
Successful applicants
Hada            Junko
Hayama              Sae
Hirasawa              Ui
Fukui               Satoko
Fukuyama            Mika
Ui!
W-W-Was y-y-your...?
Why are you so nervous, Big Sis?
Because!
I saw my name up there.
I passed!
Really?!
Yup!
B-Big Sis?
I can’t breathe...
You did good!
You did great!
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
Ui wouldn’t have passed without
the generous support from everyone here!
It seems like she passed.
Looks like Yui is
the happier of the two.
Doting parent much?
Or I guess more like doting sister.
I think we’re going to have
a very happy spring!
Congratulations, Ui-chan.
Way to go!
Thank you, everybody.
There’s my name.
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
We’re in the same class again!
Akai’s our homeroom teacher?
I wonder if I’ll be in the same class
as Yoshiko-chan...
Class 2
Akai
Iguchi
Uemura
Uto
Okada
Nakamoto      Yuuki
Hamagoto      Keiko
Hirasawa       Yui
Fukuoka     Morimi
Furuta          Nana
Narumi
Miko
Kazue
Oru
Takako
Um... There I am!
2nd Year, Class 2, huh?
I’m there, too.
Really? I’m also in Class 2!
No way! Does that mean...
Is Mio-chan with us, too?!
Class 1...
Wh-What’s with the looks?
If you get lonely,
you can come visit us whenever you want!
I’m not an elementary schooler!
Are you gonna be okay
away from me?
I won’t be there
to let you copy my homework.
Don’t you worry about me!
Mugi’s got my back!
Hello, everyone!
Good morning!
The uniform looks great on you!
You look so pure!
Y-You think so?
Sis, your collar.
You left the dry-cleaning tag on.
Wow, you’re right!
And...
Your hair’s sticking up here.
I didn’t have time to brush it!
Let’s try to get up a little earlier
starting tomorrow, all right?
Maybe you two should just
swap your “big” and “little” sister labels...
Well, I’ll see you later.
Guess we should take off, too.
Huh? Class 2 is on the second floor?
That’s right.
It’s like we really are
upperclassmen now, huh?
See ya around, Akiyama-san
of Floor 1, Year 2, Class 1!
Shut it!
We’ll see you at break!
Where on the second floor is it?
I am lonely...
I don’t know any of these people.
Mio!
Am I glad to see you!
When I saw I wasn’t in the same class as Yui,
I got worried I wouldn’t see any familiar faces.
Let’s have a great year togeth—
Yes, let’s!
#8: Student Orientation!
Want to join
the Basketball Club?
The Tea Ceremony Club
is lots of fun!
Please consider
the Occult Studies Club!
Are you interested in ping pong?
Wow, the halls are packed already!
Large clubs certainly know
how to recruit.
Don’t sell us short
just ‘cause we’re the Light Music Club!
Mio, did you make any flyers?
Want to join a band?
W-Well, I made this, but...
Pretty bland.
Want to join a band?
In short, it lacks appeal!
But what is
the Light Music Club’s appeal?
Want to join a band?
Well... I guess...
Something like...
“Have all the tea and snacks you want
and laze around at the Light Music Club!”
Ooh!
That sounds great!
No it doesn’t!
Got any better ideas?
‘Cause the way it is now, it’s got no impact!
If it needs impact,
we’ll just have to give it some!
We’re the Light Music Club...
We’re performing
at the reception tomorrow.
Please be sure to come, meow!
If you’re interested, come to the music room
after school! Woof, woof, woof, woof!
There’s also lots of
yummy snacks, cluck!
Say, Mio-chan...
Huh?! Wh-What is it?
I think we’re scaring people away.
That just crossed my mind, too.
Oh, really?
That's right. I just don’t know
what club to pick.
It’s a tough choice, isn’t it?
Yeah.
Ui!
Huh? Big S—
Ui...
What was that all about?
Beats me.
We’re the Light Music Club.
If you’re interested, feel free to come by the music
preparation room on the third floor after school.
Uh, sure...
What exactly...?
Want to join a band?
Taking up the whole music room! !
You know you shouldn’t
run at people like that!
I’m sorry...
Lemme just say,
these things are ovens...
You think so? I find this fun,
like we’re working a part-time job.
You sure like working, Mugi-chan.
Let’s go, Azusa.
Oh, sure.
Prep Room
We worked so hard,
and have nothing to show for it...
We just gotta make up for it
at tomorrow’s show!
I think you’re right.
Excuse me...
I made you these outfits, too.
Well ladies, let’s move!
Time for afternoon classes!
The Light Music Club?
Yeah, they seem pretty cool.
Wanna go check them out?
N-No thanks, I’ll pass.
See you.
What’s up with her?
You’ll come, won’t you, Ui?
Sure, I suppose.
Then let’s go!
Azusa, Jazz Club’s having an orientation meeting
in their club room on the second floor.
Let’s go.
Prep Room
Here it is.
Excuse us!
Welcome to our club room!
Sis?
Ui-chan!
Wish to join
the Light Music Club?
Ritsu-san and Tsumugi-san, too?
Help me!
‘Scuse me!
Come in, come in!
It’s great to see you!
W-Wait, um... Before we do that,
could you explain what that was just now?
Hmm... I think it was two doors down
from the Occult Studies Club.
What’s up there?
The music room, I think.
The music room...
Ever since Christmas,
it’s like Sawa-chan-sensei has gotten addicted
to putting us in costumes.
Ah, I see.
Oh, this is my big sister, Yui.
Hi, I’m Hirasawa Yui.
Wait just a minute, I’ll go get you some tea.
It’s okay to take this one, right?
It’s hot, so be careful.
Ow!
Are you all right?
B-Big Sis?
You have a seat, Big Sis.
I’ll take it from here.
A-Are you sure?
Um... Yui...
This is Ritsu-san.
Hi there. I’m club president,
Tainaka Ritsu.
Hey, Ritsu!
She seems really cool.
You still haven’t submitted your request form
to use the school auditorium!
If you don’t, you won’t get to
perform tomorrow.
Oh, you’re right...
I swear, how many times
am I going to have to tell you?
I’m so sorry, I’m so sorry!
And this is Kotobuki Tsumugi-san.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
Pleasure to meet you, too.
I’m so sorry for all the noise.
W-Wait, wait!
She seems really nice.
And what’s with
the getup, anyway?
Don’t ask me
like it was my idea!
Oh, Ricchan...
And lastly there’s... huh?
Her?
Yeah. Akiyama Mio-san.
She gets embarrassed
really easily.
What’s the deal, Mio?
Quit hiding out there and come on in.
No chance!
You’ll laugh at me!
We won’t laugh.
That outfit looks great on you.
Y-You really mean it?
She’s so cute!
Um... Who is this?
This is Ms. Sawako.
She’s the Light Music Club’s faculty advisor.
You two...
Ma’am?
Care to try one on?
No, thanks.
Please consider joining up.
Thank you, we will.
What did you think?
It didn’t quite feel
the same as real jazz.
It didn’t, huh?
What’s up?
That reminds me...
Want to join  a band?
Want to join a band?
We have snacks
too
(unofficially)
Taking up the whole music room!!
Ooh, they look kinda cool!
Now they finally look like
a proper Light Music Club.
Mio-chan, my strap is stuck
on my shoulder.
Yeah. Mine, too.
I can’t move in this hem...
And these sleeves are...
No, actually they’re fine.
I can’t play like this!
Whose bright idea was it
to wear maid outfits?
We decided to change
into track suits.
‘Kay! Here I come!
Ready!
You’re next, Mugi!
Right!
What do you think you’re doing?
Okay...
Let’s get started, yeah?
Get new members!!
So cool!
They’re cool!
Those track suits, though...
You’re really going?
They were the ones in those animal costumes.
I just want a quick peek.
Track suits?
Hey, isn’t that Hirasawa-san?
She’s in our class.
She looks pretty uncomfortable.
It doesn’t look like
a very serious club.
Sorry we didn’t give you
a real performance.
We’re usually a lot more serious.
Get new members!!
We are?
Yes, we are!
In any case, we’ll be performing
four songs tomorrow, so be sure to come.
For your consideration!
Oh... Sure.
W-Well, I think we should be going.
See you at home later, Big Sis.
Get new members!!
Yup.
Wh-What did you think?
Huh? Oh, um...
They sure were something else.
You think so?
That cake was really good!
It was, wasn’t it?
Listen, I—
S-Sorry, I need to go to the bathroom!
Go on without me. Bye.
Their prospects are looking grim.
What did she think?
W-Well... She said you were
something else!
We totally are!
She’ll come tomorrow, too, right?
Yeah, probably.
The Light Music Club
is so much fun!
Yeah.
Big Sis?
Yeah?
What’s the best thing about
the Light Music Club?
Lemme think...
I guess the best thing is how fun it is.
Fun in what way?
Like, fun fun.
Wanna join us too, Ui?
Our goal is to play at the Budokan!
I’ll consider it.
Now that I think about it,
she’s been really energetic
ever since she joined the club.
Until a little while ago, she...
Ui... Ice cream!
After you’ve had your dinner!
Ice cream!
But now she’s really
giving it her all!
Ui?
Yeah?
I wanna have ice cream!
After you’ve had your dinner!
Some parts of her
haven’t changed, though...
New
Student
Reception
It’s packed out there!
Well, it is the reception
for all the new students.
We just have to play like
we always do.
B-B-But we...
Still not over
your stage fright, huh?
Ricchan!
I just found a 100 yen coin!
You should be
a li’l more nervous.
Song list
Fluffy Time
Curry, Then Rice
My Love is a Stapler
Brush Pen ~Ballpoint Pen~
Fluffy Time.
Curry, Then Rice.
My Love ls A Stapler.
Brush Pen ~Ballpoint Pen~.
Your style’s as unique as ever.
Really?
So, you really want me
to do all the vocals?
Oh, yeah.
We never worked that out.
Well, I guess since we’ve got two singers,
you should do at least one song, Mio.
C’mon, high five!
No way! Forget it!
Mio-chan...
But everyone loved you
at our last live show.
Forget it!
C’mon, accidents like that
don’t happen twice.
No way!
But—
Forget it!
Mio-cha—
No!
Do you want just ramen?
Shall I leave out the gyoza?
No!
Shooting everything down
indiscriminately, eh?
I guess we don’t have a choice.
Just let Yui-chan
handle everything.
Next up is a club introduction and
performance by the Light Music Club.
We’re on!
Break a leg, everyone.
And one last thing before I go...
Sawa-chan...
School uniforms look
surprisingly good!
Please step down
from the stage.
Really? You’ve decided?
Yeah, there’s this really cool upperclassman
in the Jazz Club, so...
I’m sorry.
O-Oh, really?
Well, it is what it is.
I can’t tell you what club to join.
See you.
E-Excuse me!
I’m sorry to
drag you with me like this.
Wow, it’s so full!
My sister’s on vocals!
Hi! We’re the Light—
We’re the Light Music Club.
Um, to all you new students out there,
congratulations on getting in!
When I first heard about
the Light Music Club,
I thought it was about
light and easy music.
Yui’s emceeing is always
relaxing to listen to.
I signed up without
thinking too much about it,
thinking I could play
castanets or something.
So I hope all of you think about joining up
with the same carefree attitude!
But you know,
Sawa-chan-sensei told me that castanets
are actually really hard to play.
Anyway, here’s our next song.
About time...
Oh, Sawa-chan is our nickname
for the music teach—
What are we, a comedy band?
Oops, sorry.
Anyway, here’s our next song,
“My Love ls A Stapler!”
That opening riff is tough,
and she’s pulling it off perfectly.
But rather...
Yui, sing!
I forgot the lyrics!
Why is it that I,
naze nan darou
on nights of restlessness,
ki ni naru yoru kimi e no
try to write out my feelings for you on stationery?
kono omoi binsen ni ne kaite miru yo
Mio-chan...
Hurry up and sing!
It could just be my whims
moshikashite kimagure kamo shirenai
But fact is the number of sheets just grows and grows
sore nano ni maisuu dake fuete yuku yo
If only there was some formula to calculate
suki no kakuritsu waridasu keisanshiki
the odds of being loved back
areba ii no ni
Let’s take my shiny, sparkly wishes
kirakira hikaru negaigoto mo
and grimy, slimy worries
guchagucha hetaru nayamigoto mo
and bind them together with my stapler
sou da hocchikisu de tojichaou
The bond was light and thin at the start
Hajimari dake wa karui nori de
But before long, it became thick with passion
shiranai uchi ni atsuku natte
And now the staples won’t seem to go through
mou hari ga nandaka tooranai
La la, see you tomorrow
ra ra ☆ mata ashita
Staaaaaaare...
Um, girls?
If you keep staring like that,
you’ll scare off any potential members.
Aw, but the crowd
at our show was so fired up!
Get new members!!
How is it that nobody’s coming?!
You don’t think it’s because
I messed up, do you?
Maybe it’s because
we have so few members...
The tea is ready!
I guess we’ll just have to
go nab Ui-chan.
She’s not a bug.
Excuse me...
Yes?
I’m interested in
joining your club.
Um, could you repeat that?
I’d like to join the club.
We got one!
I’m so happy for you, Big Sis!
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
Um, what are those?
They’re cat ears, of course.
No, I can see that...
I mean...
What am I supposed to do with them?
Maybe they’re
testing my initiative.
Here. Now it’s your turn,
Azusa-chan.
Um... I’m Nakano Azusa,
year 1, class 2.
I look forward to playing with you.
#9  New Club Member!