Let’s see...
It’s really cold, huh, Ui?
Yeah.
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
Prep Room
So... cold...!
It’s so cold!
Ricchan, don’t you think so?
‘Tis most frigid indeed!
Truthfully!
Ricchan...
Whack!
Your cheeks are so warm,
Ricchan!
What’s the big idea?!
Ricchan Cold Hands Special!
Cold! Cold!
Bonus Episode: Winter Days !
It’s too cold for me
to play Geeta!
I just had a great idea!
I should play with my gloves on!
Dare you to try.
Ready!
And here we go...
Let’s see...
I can’t hold the pick!
Oh! They’re getting stuck
on the strings!
You are a disappointment!
What did you expect?
Right, Ritsu?
Ritsu?
Ritsu, is something wrong?
Ricchan?
What’s wrong?
Uh, it’s nothing!
Check it! Mustache!
Ricchan, that’s awesome!
Me, too! Mustache!
Wrong! That looks nothing
like a mustache!
Like so, Senpai?
Glovington!
I’m sorry I got mad at you!
You named your gloves, too?
This is all the winter’s fault.
Don’t blame the winter.
You’re right, Azu-nyan! There’s plenty of
fun things to do on winter days!
Hey, I know! Come over to my place on Sunday
for a hot pot party! Hot pot!
Huh?
I’m sorry, but I have plans.
Me, too.
I promised my kid brother
I’d take him to the movies.
For my part, I don’t think I’ll be able
to leave the house at all.
What about you, Mio-chan?
I can’t come, either.
I want to write some new lyrics.
Aw...
You and Ritsu are always bothering me,
so I can never concentrate.
See?
I may be
short-legged,
But I love you, Ritsu!!
I'm poop!!
So bright!!
These aren't pants, but drums.
These are
his platform
shoes
Hirasawa
SHIMMER
RICCHAN
We apologize profusely!
Oh, well. Guess it’ll just be
me, Ui, and Geeta at the hot pot party.
Don’t get your guitar dirty, okay?
You just had it worked on.
Don’t you worry!
I’ll be sure to put a bib on him!
That’s okay, then.
You gotta have a hot pot party
in the winter, right?
It’s full-on winter now,
huh, Ricchan?
I’m so glad Ui gave me Glovington!
My hands are so warm!
That kid’s really got her act together.
Wish I had a sister like her.
Darn you,
I’m green with envy!
Um...
What’s up, Mugi-chan?
I have to bow out here today.
Do you have plans?
Um, sort of... Bye!
I wonder what’s up with Mugi-chan...
Think she’s meeting someone?
Maybe with a boyfriend?
Wha...?! Oh, but thinking about it,
Mugi-chan does look like she’d be popular.
Yeah.
Later!
See you next week!
Goodbye.
Senpai?
Yeah?
I have some shopping to do
by the station before I go home.
Oh, whatcha buying?
Um... Some toys.
Oh, toys? Maybe I’ll come with...
No, it’s fine!
Goodbye!
Bye-bye!
Ritsu, what did you think about...?
Ritsu?
Huh? What?
Something wrong?
Nothing at all!
Gosh, it sure is cold, huh?
I’m starving, Mio!
Thank you, come again!
My piping hot meat bun!
It’s freezing!
So cold...
Please! Could you look after
my cat this weekend?
My aunt was supposed to,
but she came down with a cold.
She’s still little, so I’m worried
about leaving her alone.
But I’ve never taken care
of a cat before.
Oh... I should’ve
thought about that...
But if there’s no one else
that you can ask...
Really?!
W-Wanna play?
NAME: Hoshino Hitomi
Go ahead.
R-Right!
I did it!
Okay, let’s start off
with the cleaning.
Yes! I’m eager to learn!
Yui's room
Sis! C’mon, get out of bed!
Sis!
“Winter days,
I am happy no matter how cold it is.
“When I see you running towards me,
panting out white puffs of breath,
“your neatly trimmed hair
suits you so well.
“But I’d also like to see you
with your bangs down.”
Looks weird.
Sis, you ready yet?
I said I’ll be right there!
Nyan... you’re Azu-nyan #2.
TRAINEE
Allow me to confirm your order.
That was one cheeseburger
and two medium colas, sir?
Smile, smile!
Would you like fries with that?
Sure. Fries, too.
Thank you, sir!
You’re doing great!
Thank you!
All right... I think I’ll be able to
come up with some great lyrics here!
Oh, no one’s coming?
No.
That’s too bad.
Yeah. So let’s come up with
some all-new hot pot recipes today,
for the next time
everybody comes over!
Ever the optimist,
aren’t you, Big Sis?
How about a marshmallow soy milk hot pot
or a chocolate curry hot pot?
Maybe we shouldn’t try to
run before we walk, okay?
Wha...?! They might taste good!
Who knows?
Big Sis, why don’t we buy
some strawberry milk?
Ui, you’re so generous!
It’s cold!
Lyrics aren’t coming to me at all.
Maybe I should’ve just gone for hot pot at Yui’s.
But it sounded like everybody else
already had plans...
I wonder what everyone’s up to...
It’s freezing!
What happened to that
“global warming” thing?!
It’s supposed to be cold
in the winter, dummy.
What a wimp. I wish the girls
in your class could see you now.
Cut me some slack...
Oh, that reminds me...
What?
Whack!
So warm!
Hey, Tainaka!
Hi!
Hello.
Cold, isn’t it?
I’m going over to Suzuki’s house.
Wanna come?
Ooh, yeah! Can I, Sis?
Sure.
Don’t stay out too late.
We’re off!
What’ve you been up to?
Saw a movie.
How was it?
Pretty good.
Thank you for waiting!
I’m sorry, but I ordered coffee,
not a cola.
I’m sorry!
I’ll exchange it right away!
Sorry, my bad!
I’m sorry! I’m sorry!
It’s okay, don’t worry.
What drink did you need?
I’m sorry! I’m sorry!
Azu-nyan #2?
What’s the matter?
What’s the matter?!
Azu-nyan #2!
Was that a...?
Was that really...
...a love letter?
Maybe I should go home.
I messed up...
I really thought I could do it, but...
What should I do?
Which hot pot sounds better:
Marshmallow soy milk or chocolate curry?
Incoming mail
Yui-senpai
Hey, hey
Which hot pot sounds
better:
Marshmallow soy milk or
chocolate curry?
What kind of hot pot is that?
How odd!
That’s weird,
nobody’s answering...
It’s Azu-nyan!
Hello? Azu-nyan?
Don’t send out weird texts
at a time like this!
At a time like what?
It’s the cat! It’s this kitten that
a friend asked me to look after!
What’s wrong with it?
I don’t know, but she doesn’t
seem to be doing well...
But nobody’s at home right now...
and I don’t know what to do!
Got it! Stay calm, Azu-nyan,
we’ll be right there!
I’m sorry, I didn’t mean to
cause such a fuss.
I’m just glad that nothing’s wrong
with Azu-nyan #2.
I didn’t know that cats
threw up hairballs.
Say “Ahh”!
For you, Azu-nyan!
I guess they might taste better
when you eat them as-is.
Of course they do!
I’ve got texts from the others!
Huh?! Mugi-chan has a job?!
Mugi-chan
Re.   Hey, hey
I'm at work now.
Huh? Mio-chan went to the beach!
Ricchan wants to know
where we are.
“We’re at Azu-nyan’s place.”
How may I help you?
Can you believe Mugi-chan
started working part-time?
Our Mugi sure is growing up!
Yeah!
Azusa!
Did Jun-chan come over
to get her cat?
Yeah.
That’s good news!
Oh, you were cat-sitting, huh?
Mio-chan, welcome back!
Write anything good?
Looks like that’s a no.
That’s kinda cool, though!
Just casually going to the beach in the winter!
You guys are awesome!
Don’t grow up and leave me behind, okay?
You haven’t changed,
right, Ricchan?
I’ve changed, too! I...
Huh? What?
Did something happen?
Forget it. It’s nothing.
Oh, that reminds me, Ritsu...
What?
What did you think of those lyrics
I left in your mailbox the other day?
Huh? Lyrics?
Yeah. I tried writing them out
on my computer this time.
Then...
you were the one who...
Yeah.
You wrote that?!
That was you?!
I said I was leaving it
in your mailbox!
Don’t do something so old-fashioned
in this day and age!
Come on, Ricchan,
let’s eat our hamburgers.
‘Kay?
Thank you very much!
Eep!
What’s the matter,
Mio-chan?
My bass was really cold,
and when it touched my thigh, I...
That little “Eep!”...
Do it again!
Forget it.
You always seem fine
playing your keyboard, don’t you, Mugi?
Hmm?
Don’t your hands
ever get numb from the cold?
No, they’re fine.
They’re so warm!
Lemme see!
Wow, you’re right!
I have a high body temperature.
You’re so lucky! I wish we could
get a Mugi-chan installed at home!
Azu-nyan,
you have to feel this!
No thanks, I’ll pass.
She’s really warm!
Here!
I-If you insist...
You’re right, they’re warm!
Your hands are so
tiny and cute, Azu-nyan!
And I’m just a cold-hearted woman
with giant hands...
Oh! Dost that still trouble thee?!
People with cold hands
have warm hearts, Mio-chan.
Mugi, what are you doing?
Mugi-chan, both your hands
and heart are warm!
I’m so warm!
This is nice and warm...
Winter’s not so bad.
Mugi-senpai, are you going
to keep working for long?
Yes, at least through
the end of the year.
We’ll come to
your restaurant again, okay?
Mio, those lyrics you sent me
are absolutely a no-go, got it?
What?! Why?
Hey, does it cost a lot
to rent the Budokan?
You want to rent it?
If we don’t, we can’t play
a show there, right?
It’s best to dream big.
We’ll stand on that stage one day!
Prep Room
We’d better practice
some more, then.
Prep Room
That’s right!
We have to practice!
Prep Room
And anyway, we’ll never play there
if we don’t go pro.
Prep Room
Boy, you two are
hardcore realists, aren’t you?
Prep Room
I, for one, am gonna
work hard, Ricchan!
Prep Room
Let’s all work hard!
Yeah!
Prep Room
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
A live house?
Yeah! A friend of mine from middle school
is playing there and invited us to come play, too.
Wow...
But this says it’s on
New Year’s Eve.
That’s just ten days from now.
We don’t have anything ready.
Aw, but it sounds like fun!
I’d really love to give it a try!
Right?
Geeta, let’s do our best together
tomorrow, okay?
I just know this is gonna be
a ton of fun!
Bonus Episode        Live House!