I never would have guessed that
the Light Music Club...
...would face this terrible catastrophe
mere days before the school festival.
You look real cheery, Azusa.
I’m just happy thinking about
getting to perform at the school festival soon.
That’s so cute!
I wish I could’ve seen you play
at last year’s festival
Yeah... Mio really was
the star of the show last time around.
She tripped on stage and—
If you want to see their show from last year,
I got it all on video!
Sakura
Music
Club
Light
High
Festival
Sakura
Music
Club
Light
High
Festival
Sakura
Music
Club
Light
High
Festival
I wanna see! I wanna see!
No, Azusa!
Please think about this!
Yui-chan, Ricchan?
Let go of me!
Let’s just skip straight to
the good part.
Don’t look, Azusa! It’s too dangerous!
You’ll be cursed!
I... I saw it...
I was too late...
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
#11: Crisis!
It has to be said... You really only play well
during live performances.
You’ve gotten real comfy
speaking your mind, huh? Ya li’l...!
Head lock!
What is it?
This is bringing back
lots of memories.
Oh, as I recall, you had lost your voice
when we did this show.
Yeah! I just woke up one morning
and my voice was all raspy!
So Mio-chan took over vocals...
This is gonna be your first show
as a member of the Light Music Club.
But Mio-chan’s singing was super great!
Yup!
Yes, it really was wonderful!
I’m giving it all I’ve got!
Mio-chan was so cool!
I’m sorry to interrupt
your fun time.
Oh, Nodoka!
What’s wrong?
Don’t act like you don’t know.
Here.
Auditorium usage application...
Yes. You didn’t submit one
for the school festival, did you?
Oh, I forgot.
You say that so casually!
Well... Things have been
kinda hectic, y’know...?
Something like this
happened last year, too...
Oh... No, actually that was
the club application...
Ow!
Okay, Azusa, you be secretary.
Wait, me? Well, I guess I don’t mind.
Um... “Applicant” is Light Music Club...
Um... What do I put down for “Name”?
The band name, I guess.
Right.
Now that you mention it,
what is the band’s name?
Sweets Smile!
Girl Gang!
Chocolate Melody!
All over the place...
We never settled on one.
Guess we might as well
do that now!
How about “Hirasawa Yui
and the Bumbling Sisters”?
What are we,
your backup dancers?!
How about something like
“Pure Pure”?
Enough with the jokes,
let’s be serious about this.
But I was being serious...
You really meant that?!
Well, everyone has different tastes.
Okay, here’s what’s happening!
Huh?
I’ll choose it!
Let’s all give it
some more thought!
Perfectly synced...
Well... bring the paperwork to
the student council office when you’re done.
I’m so sorry to make you wait.
It’s all right.
Nodoka-chan, it’s been a while,
so let’s grab some tea on the way home!
Sure. I’ll message you later.
Okay, why don’t we sleep on the band name
tonight and get to practicing?
Good idea.
The school festival is right around the corner,
so we’d better stay focused!
Right!
Oh, I just remembered! My guitar hasn’t been
sounding right lately, for some reason.
Could I take a quick look at it?
The strings are rusty!
When was the last time
you changed them?
Huh? You’re supposed
to change them?
Wh-What?
Plus, the neck is warped, too!
That’ll completely
throw off the intonation!
I-Intona...? Neck?
Calm down, Azusa!
That stuff is still way beyond
Yui’s comprehension!
Basically,
you have to treat it well.
This is a really good guitar, so...
But I do treat it well!
I sleep with it every night,
and I even dress it up!
That’s not what I mean
by “treat it well”!
Wha...? Then...
Sawa-chan-sensei,
can you please do something?
Err... I think you’d be better off
taking it to a music store, don’t you?
Just say you can’t be bothered.
Let’s go to the music store, then.
What? It’s not that serious, is it?
Yes it is! The festival’s coming up,
and we can’t practice with your guitar like this!
Ricchan, you don’t tend to
your drums either, do you?
Yeah, I do!
Huh?
Don’t talk like it’s just a given
that I wouldn’t take care of them!
But it’s you.
Ow!
‘Kay, here we are.
I’ll wait for you out here.
Hmm?
Why aren’t you coming in?
I’m left-handed,
so looking at all the right-handed instruments
would only make me sad.
Ooh, check this out, Mio!
It says here
they’re having a Lefty Fair.
Huh?!
H-Have I died and
gone to heaven?
M-Mr. Clerk! Give me everything
that’s on display here!
Hey, settle down.
Mio-chan looks really happy.
It’s because there aren’t
many models made for lefties.
Want to go on without them?
Yeah!
Excuse us!
How can I help you?
We’d like to have some
maintenance done on a guitar.
Sure thing.
Which one will it be?
Ah, this one here.
Very well.
Let’s have a look at it, then.
Is this... a vintage guitar?
We’re sorry. It’s just dirty.
I only bought it last year!
R-Right...
W-Well, feel free to wait
in the store until I’m done.
Thank you.
Well, let’s go browse
until it’s ready.
What’s the matter?
Stare...
My poor guitar is being
stripped naked bit by bit!
What are you talking about?
Still, why did you buy that guitar
in the first place?
Huh?
I mean, look at it.
It’s heavy, and it has a thick neck.
It has all sorts of quirks.
Oh, I got it because it’s cute!
Cute?
Yeah, ‘cause it’s cute.
Huh? It’s cute! Don’t you think?
I don’t get Yui-senpai’s sensibilities.
Sorry we kept you waiting!
We dropped it off
for maintenance.
Nice.
Huh? Where’s Mio-senpai?
Oh, Mio-chan is still—
Lady Tsumugi!
It’s so good
to see you again, madam!
Oh, hello.
Oh! If it isn’t Lady Tsumugi!
It’s been too long!
Mugi says that this shop is part of
her family’s business consortium.
What?
It’s always a shock to hear
someone call her that, isn’t it?
Thank you for waiting.
Ooh! It’s all clean again!
Make sure you keep it well maintained
from now on, all right?
Geeta!
She named the thing...
Thank you so much!
D-Don’t mention it.
Oh, and that will be 5,000 yen.
Huh?
It costs money?
U-Um, yes.
Of course it costs money!
I don’t have money.
Huh?!
What am I gonna do?
What’s the matter?
Ah...
Well, it looks like Yui-senpai didn’t know
that they charged for maintenance work.
She didn’t? Oh, dear. Let’s see...
Did I bring any pocket money?
M-M-M-Madam!
Please, consider it on the house!
Huh?!
No, I couldn’t possibly!
Think nothing of it!
We’re constantly in your father’s debt!
B-But, I...
I insist!
Please, this is on the house!
Looks like you lucked out.
Well, that’s that!
How about we get going?
Okay!
Wait...
Hmm?
Where’s Mio-senpai?
I’ll go call her.
Mio!
C’mon, we’re leaving.
Don’t wanna.
You an elementary schooler?
Look, everybody’s waiting for you.
Don’t wanna.
Sheesh!
C’mon, Mio-chan!
Hey, wait! Ritsu!
C’mon, kiddo. We’re goin’ home.
I said I don’t wanna go!
I know someone who strings guitars
in reverse order.
Too bad, we’re going!
Wow...
Hey, wait! Watch it!
Whatcha doing down there, Mio?
Enough, already!
Stupid Ritsu.
Thank goodness!
Geeta is all pretty again!
You gave your guitar
a name, huh?
What do you
want to do now?
Hmm, good question...
All right!
How about we grab some tea?
Tea again?
Oh! Sorry, guys! I’m supposed
to meet Nodoka-chan now.
Huh? Nodoka’s coming, too?
Can I tag along?
Oh, right! You’re in the same class
as her, aren’t you?
Sure!
Really?
I’m gonna give her a call.
Great, thanks!
Today's menu
I’ve always wanted to
try this place!
Even though you don’t have
any money on you?
I’ll pay for Yui’s share.
When I get negh’d mond’th allowanthe,
negh’d time we go oud’th on me!
Thanks, I’ll hold you to that.
Is Yui really doing all right
in the Light Music Club?
As soon as she learns one thing,
she forgets something else.
I know how it is.
But when she’s focused on something,
she can do amazing things.
For sure!
She can be a real handful,
can’t she?
Huh? Whatcha talking about?
Tch. Those two sure seem
to be having a good time.
More to the point,
why are we sneaking around like this?
It’s like we’re detectives,
isn’t it?
Okay, I’m going in.
And then the teacher—
You two sure seem friendly!
Boom!
Ritsu?
What are you doing here?
Oh, I just happened to be here.
Are you by yourself, Ricchan?
Nope. Mugi and Azusa
are over there.
Ooh, they are!
Gosh, thanks for taking
such good care of our Mio!
Uh, Ritsu?
What? You got a problem
with me being here?
Well, no, but...
Then what’s the matter?
What’s that?!
Whatcha get?
Ricchan...
Your ice cream is melting...
Wow, that’s a gorgeous boxed lunch!
It’s nothing special. I just threw together
whatever I had lying around.
Huh?!
You make your own? That’s amazing!
Oh, no. As I said, it’s nothing special.
No, mine are...
Okay, lunchtime is over!
Ritsu?
Sorry, I just started eating.
We’re practicing through lunch break
from now until the festival!
Huh...?
Gee, I wonder what Mio’s gonna do
to liven things up at this year’s festival.
She gave the crowd that
panty shot last year,
so maybe she’ll show
her belly button this time?
Or maybe...
We’re here to practice!
We will!
Then why—?
Takoyaki!
Ponytail!
Hey!
Braids!
C’mon, cut it out!
Geez! What’s gotten into you?
Oh, right! I brought
a great horror movie! It’s so scary!
I-I’m going back
to my classroom!
Oh? Suit yourself, then.
I’m so sorry I interrupted
your pleasant lunchtime with Nodoka.
Who said anything about that?
What? Why are they fighting?
Wh-Why don’t we have some tea?
Let’s have tea! All right?
I brought some
lovely tarts today. Okay?
Wh-What should I do?
I have to do something!
Anything!
L-Let’s all be friends
and practice, everyone!
I-It didn’t work!
Yeah, I guess we should practice.
Yeah...
Let’s get started.
O-Okay!
One, two!
I'm Azu-nyan
Ho ha ha ha
Rustle rustle
EEEEEEEK
Nyaaaa
Huh?
Ritsu?
Look, I’m glad your drumming
isn’t as wild as usual,
but don’t you think
it’s a little weak?
Ritsu?
Hey! Ritsu!
Aw, sorry.
I’m just not feeling it.
Ho ha ha ha
Rustle rustle
Let’s try again after school.
R-Ricchan...!
Art by Mio
Let her go, Yui.
But she...
Stupid Ritsu.
Ritsu-senpai isn’t here...
She didn’t come
after school yesterday, either.
I wonder what’s wrong...
I’d say it’s because Mio-chan
has been so cold to her.
For the sake of the Light Music Club,
be Ricchan’s plaything for a day!
If you don’t,
then Ricchan’s heart...
...will harden.
Old man! Make it a jumbo!
And she’ll order a jumbo beef bowl
too big for her to finish...
What am I doing?
She’ll get desperate...
She’ll go so far down
the path of heavy metal...
...that she’ll never
find her way back!
That’s what happened to you
when you got dumped, isn’t it?
What was that?
But if she doesn’t come back...
What’ll happen to our show
at the festival?
Let’s practice.
What? Without Ricchan?
What else can we do?
Um... Shouldn’t we go ask her
to come first?
You could also start looking
for a replacement.
Now, I’m just saying that it’s always
a good idea to be prepared, that’s all.
But...
There’s no replacing Ricchan!
Mugi-chan...
Let’s wait.
Let’s wait for Ricchan to come.
I know she’ll come.
Mio-chan!
Ah! You’re right!
G-Good morning.
Hey, about Ricchan...
Look! I didn’t come here
to check up on Ritsu. l, uh...
She’s not here today.
Mio...
Do you have ESP now?
Oh, please.
I can recognize your footsteps.
How’s the cold?
I’m still a little feverish.
That explains why
your drumming sounded weak.
Heck of a time to get sick,
right before the festival...
Get better quickly, okay?
We’re all waiting for you.
They’re not mad?
Nope.
Are you?
I’m not mad.
How could I be mad at you?
It’s just...
Just what?
Without you there drumming,
I guess it’s kinda lonely.
Even though you’re pretty wild,
I like how your drumming is
so energetic and powerful.
Ritsu! Were you...?
Hooray, I’m cured!
You are not!
Come on, lie down.
You still have a fever.
I’m going home, okay?
C’mon, stay here ‘til
I fall asleep! Please, Mio!
Oh, good grief.
Excuse us.
Ricchan, how are—?
I just managed to
get her to go to sleep.
So...
Why did Yui fall asleep, too?
Oh, good grief...
I’m at 100%!
Now, let’s bust our butts to
get ready for the school festival!
Yeah!
Hey!
You didn’t submit
your auditorium use form?
Huh?
I’m sorry! I’m sorry!
A deadline is a deadline.
Could you bend the rules?
I’d like to appeal on their behalf.
They missed the submission deadline
because the club president was home sick.
Please!
Well, if you insist, Manabe-san...
You have until the end of the day.
Y-You...
Yer a good egg!
Look after Mio!
And while yer at it, look after me, too!
Hey!
What’s wrong with “Pure Pure”?
Rejected.
How about “Clenched Fist”?
Too enka-ish.
Then, maybe
“Gum On the Sole of My Shoe”?
You stepped in some today, huh?
Huh?! How did you know?
Mugi, don’t you have any good ones?
Something like “Recovery Time”?
Gah! Sounds like a jinx!
How about
“Popcorn Honeymoon”?
Come on, what’s with
all these cutesy names?
What do you think of
“Rocket Pencil”?
Hush, you!
Today, people!
I can’t even enjoy
my tea in peace!
You should just pick
something random here!
Done!
She decided it on her own!
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
Eh, I guess that’s fine.
Houkago: After School
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
Somehow we managed to
pick a band name!
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
All that’s left now is to practice hard
for the school festival.
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
HOUKAGO TEA TIME
BAND NAME!
Art by Mio
Or...?
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
So her fever
still hasn’t come down...
No. As it is, she’ll probably
have to stay home tomorrow, too.
Catching a cold at a time like this
just shows her lack of dedication!
You’re the one
who gave it to her!
Wha—? Li’l ol’ me?
Big Sis...
You may be able to fool them,
but you can’t fool me.
Finale       Light Music!