Guitar strings sure are scary!
They’re thin and tough,
so I’m scared of cutting my fingers.
Damn right!
If you’re not careful, you’ll slice your fingers clean off
and gush blood everywhere!
Did Mio-chan just scream?
I... I can’t even think about pain!
Don’t worry, I’m okay.
See? I’m not actually bleeding.
Well... Your fingertips will toughen up
as you practice,
so you won’t be shedding any blood.
See?
Wow, you’re right!
They’re all squishy!
Squishy, squishy...
Um... Are you done?
J-Just a little more!
Chatting now
Chatting Now
Super rowdy never-ending girl talk
gachi de kashimashi Never Ending Girls’ Talk
I just can’t wait ‘til the end of class
shuugyou chaimu made matenai
I might be tardy, but leaving early is a non, non, non!
chikoku wa shitemo soutai wa Non Non Non!
I’ll study hard after school
seiippai Study After School
There’s no brakes on the excitement, my head’s going full speed ahead
dokidoki ga tomannai furu surottoru na nounai
Hopes, desires, passions... wrap them up in a bow
kibou yokubou bonnou ribon kakete housou
neta dossari mochiyori New Type Version uchikomi
Got so many ideas, the Newtype version’s getting filled to the brim
A photo album free of boys, a diary bursting with love
danshi kinsei no purichou koi tsuzutta nikkichou
I’ll trim 2 cm off my skirt and take a mighty leap
sukaato take nisenchi tsumetara tobu yo
Going farther than yesterday, and an octave higher than the day before
kinou yori tooku ototoi yori okutaabu takaku
Jumping now
Jumping Now
Super lovely never-ending girls’ life
gachi de uruwashi Never Ending Girls’ Life
Can’t be still ‘cause every day is a brand new show
hibi maji raibu dashi matta nashi
I might rise and shine, but turning in early is a non, non, non!
hayaoki shitemo hayane wa Non Non Non!
I’ll shout as loud as I can, woo-hoo!
meippai Shouting wasshoi
Super wonderful never-ending girls’ song
gachi de subarashii Never Ending Girls’ Song
It goes pitch perfect with afternoon tea
gogo tiitaimu ni wa mottekoi
Even if this love isn’t meant to be, we’ll go for broke! Here we go!
kataomoi demo gyokusai de Here We Go!
We’ll be singing and shining after school
utaeba Shining After School
Budokan or bust!!
I know I have to practice,
but I have no idea where to start.
Here.
Budokan or bust!!
You should start off
by learning the chords.
Thanks!
Budokan or bust!!
C-Could you teach me
how to read music first?
You don’t even know that?!
#3: Training!
See you.
Bye!
See you tomorrow.
Let’s see...
“C” goes like this,
and this is a “D.”
Yui!
Nodoka-chan!
What’s that?
Some new kind of greeting?
It’s a guitar chord!
Today, I asked my clubmates to teach me them!
Ooh. Sounds like you’re working hard.
Oh yeah, you’re heading home
later than usual today.
Yeah. I was in the library
studying for midterms.
Wow...
What?! Midterms?!
Is that another chord?
I see...
So it’s time for midterms already?
And here I thought I had lots of time
to really practice with my guitar...
You’ve never studied for exams,
not even back in middle school.
Oh, right!
Then it’s all good!
Um, I wouldn’t exactly say that...
Prep Room
At last, we’re free from
the tyranny of tests!
They’ve become much harder in high school...
It was quite the struggle.
That’s for sure.
And...
Here we have someone who struggled
a lot more than we did.
Budokan or bust!!
Ah
Ah ha
Ah ha ha
Ah ha ha ha
Ah ha ha ha ha
Your tests went that badly?
Looks like I’m the only one in my class
who has to take a make-up test...
E-Everything will be fine!
Perhaps you just didn’t study properly this time.
Yup, yup! Just study real hard
and that make-up test’ll be a piece of cake!
I didn’t study at all, though.
I want my pep talk back,
damn you!
Why didn’t you study?
I was trying to...
But you know how when you have to study,
you tend to get distracted with other stuff?
Oh, I know what that’s like.
Like cleaning my room or whatever.
I practiced guitar
when I took a break from studying,
and I couldn’t put it down.
In the end...
I didn’t study at all.
But it’s not all bad,
‘cause I learned
a whole bunch of chords!
Might wanna try putting that focus
into studying sometime...
Well, how did you do, Ricchan?
Who, me?
Passed with flying colors,
thank you very much!
This isn’t in character for you...
When you’re as smart as me,
everything comes easy!
But I thought
you and I were the same...
Who was it that showed up at my doorstep in tears
the night before the test?
Hey! She doesn’t need to know that!
Now that’s the Ricchan I know!
I don’t wanna hear that
from someone who bombed!
How did you two
do on your tests?
Here you go.
O-Oh, you know how it is.
Always room for improvement...
Have a heart!
Please say something!
Another day...
Thank you for your time.
Ooh! We’re having
sweet bean jelly today!
Apparently, if you have to take a make-up test,
you can’t do club activities ‘til you pass.
Wow, that’s harsh.
Is it okay for you
to be here, then?
Sure, it’s fine.
I’m just here to eat sweets.
Oh, cool.
Nothing to worry about.
What the heck?!
If you’re banned from clubs,
we’ll be back down to three members.
Are you saying that we’ll...?
We’ll be short on members.
We’ll be... disbanded?
When is your make-up test?
A week from now.
A week from now, huh?
Since it’s so far,
it’s okay for me to come here every day, right?
That’s not far at all!
If you don’t pass your test,
we may have to say goodbye to the club.
Yeah, that’s true.
I want to keep doing stuff with you guys,
so I’ll work really hard!
Okay, time to study.
Let’s do this!
How’d it get so messy?
GUITAR CHORDS EVEN
A MONKEY CAN LEARN
The Monkey Series for beginners Vol. 18
GUITAR CHORDS EVEN
A MONKEY CAN LEARN
The Monkey Series for beginners Vol. 18
Climb
the ladder
like the
monkey!
Climb
the ladder
like the
monkey!
Climb
the ladder
like the
monkey!
GUITAR CHORDS EVEN
A MONKEY CAN LEARN
The Monkey Series for beginners Vol. 18
Climb
the ladder
like the
monkey!
Climb
the ladder
like the
monkey!
Wow, it’s already that late?
I have to take a bath
and get to bed!
6 days until the make-up test
Man, meetings feel kinda pointless
without Yui here.
That hasn’t affected
your appetite, though.
One matter has nothing to do
with the other, my dear!
I hope she’s studying hard...
I’m sure she’s fine.
Um...
x² - y² = (x - y)...
I can do this if I set my mind to it!
This is x²y - 4y,
so I start by factoring out the y,
leaving me with (x² - 4)...
3 days until the make-up test
Yui has to be making progress
with her studies, right?
I wonder...
Okay, now I’m worried.
What if we all send her
an encouraging text tonight?
Genius!
Yeah! I’ll send her one, too.
A text from Mio-chan!
Mio-chan
Are you studying
like you're supposed to?
Idleness is the devil's work.
Roger that.
It’s Mugi-chan!
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
I'll be waiting with delicious sweets.
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
I'll be waiting with delicious sweets.
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
I'll be waiting with delicious sweets.
Please pardon my messaging
you in the evening.
Please work hard at your own pace.
I'll be waiting with delicious sweets.
Thank you, Mugi-chan!
Ricchan!
Accept this message
of encouragement!!
2 days until the make-up test
I just don’t have the focus I need.
Hot-Blooded
Publications
Even a monkey
can do it!!
But with this, I’ll make it!
Concentration Training
in 5 Minutes
Hot-Blooded
Publications
Even a monkey
can do it!!
Concentration Training
in 5 Minutes
Hot-Blooded
Publications
Even a monkey
can do it!!
Concentration Training
in 5 Minutes
Hot-Blooded
Publications
Even a monkey
can do it!!
Concentration Training
in 5 Minutes
Hot-Blooded
Publications
Even a monkey
can do it!!
I’ll spend the first five minutes
reading this to get myself in the zone...
It’s no use!
I can’t read this book, either!
No, no, no! The problem is that
I always give up before I even start!
The day before
the make-up test
Prep Room
That’s why I need you
to help me, Mio-chan!
What? Weren’t you studying?
I couldn’t!
If you don’t get
a passing grade, we’ll...
That’s the last thing
I want to happen!
All right. We’ll have
a cram session tonight.
Really?
With Mio teaching you,
you’ll pass for sure!
Oh, stop...
She’s real good
at helping you cram info at the last minute!
Hey! I’ll teach her
so it sticks, darn it!
My dad’s away on business,
and my mom went with him,
so don’t worry about bothering anyone.
Huh? But didn’t you say
you had a little sister?
Yeah, I think she’ll be at home.
If she’s home,
won’t we be a bother?
Yui-chan’s little sister...?
Big Sis!
Little Sis!
I don’t think we’ll have to
worry about that!
Come on in, everyone.
Pardon the intrusion!
Welcome home, Big Sis.
Oh, are these your friends?
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
I’m Ui, Yui’s little sister.
Thank you for looking out for her.
Here are some slippers for you.
She’s so mature!
Yui's room
Wow.
It’s hard to imagine two sisters
being such total opposites.
What do you mean?
It’s like your little sister
stole all your best traits.
That’s mean!
I brought some tea,
if you’d like some.
I’m sorry that all we had were
these plain snacks, though.
She really is mature!
What year are you, Ui-chan?
Third year of middle school.
Just one year behind!
So you’re taking
entrance exams?
Yes.
Have you decided
where you want to go?
I’d like to go to Sakuragaoka
if I can make the cut.
But I’m not sure if
my grades are good enough...
Don’t worry!
Even your sister got in!
Join us, join us!
Just get Yui to help you study.
Well... I can do it myself.
She shot you down!
Huh? How come?
B-But Sis can do anything
once she sets her mind to it.
How is she this mature?!
All right, we’re short on time,
so we’re jumping right to the important stuff.
Page 20 in the textbook.
This expression here.
What do you get
when you expand it?
Whee, whee, whee!
Here.
Ooh, comics.
Oh, I get it.
For crying out loud!
My feet are falling asleep.
Poke.
Ritsu!
Yui's room
No good!
I can’t focus anymore!
Come on now.
it’s only been half an hour since we started.
Yui-chan, after we’re done,
we can all eat this cake I brought along.
So hang in there
a tad longer, okay?
Leave it to Mugi.
Hmm...
How can I make my way back in?
Hello! Hard at work, eh?
‘Kay, that didn’t work.
Yay! It’s me, everyone!
I need an entrance
with more impact.
Alley-oop... Greetings!
Pipe down!
This is great!
This is what life’s all about, y’know?
What kind of life do these two lead?
Coming!
Who could that be?
Nodoka-chan!
So, making any progress?
Yeah, thanks for asking.
Are you all from
the Light Music Club?
Let me introduce you.
This is Akiyama Mio-chan,
and here’s Tainaka Ritsu-chan,
and she’s Kotobuki Tsumugi-chan.
Nice to meet you.
I’m Manabe Nodoka. I live nearby,
so Yui and I have been friends forever.
We even ended up
in the same class in high school.
We’ve been together
pretty much since kindergarten.
We have this weird connection.
So anyway,
I made you some sandwiches.
Great timing!
I was just getting hungry!
You just had some cake.
No problem at all!
Give ‘em! Give ‘em!
Thanks for the eats!
When we were in middle school, I came down
with a bad fever and had to be absent for a while.
Class 3-D Field Trip
Yui came over every day
to bring me the printouts from school.
I’ve never caught a cold!
But one day, she accidentally
left her own test paper with the printouts.
You haven’t changed even a little!
But she was a huge help to me.
That reminds me,
one time Ritsu—
Gah! N-No, don’t tell them!
Tell us! Tell us!
You won’t believe this,
but Ritsu...
That can’t be true!
No way!
By the way,
how’s the studying coming along?
You got that?
Because it’ll all be on the test.
In the case of x² - xy - 6y² +...
...2x - y + 1,
first, try to factor out
the common factor of x.
When we do that,
we get x² - (y - 2)...
x - 6y² - y + 1...
Which equals x² - (y - 2)...
x -...
Wake up!
Please, get up!
Where am I?
Yui, stay awake!
You’ll die if you fall asleep!
I was this close to falling asleep!
What? Commander,
I don’t see Squad Member Ricchan!
She’s outside, and she’s... playing!
It pains me to admit it,
but there is nothing I can do for her.
Ma’am!
Hey, Yui.
Squad Member Ricchan!
We wish you... the best!
(x - 2y + 4)(x - y - 1)...
All done!
You’ve done enough
that I think you’ve got the hang of it.
You should be able to
pass the make-up test now.
Thanks, Mio-chan, Mugi-chan!
I think perhaps
we should call it a night.
Huh? Where’s Ritsu?
I lost again!
Don’t get too friendly.
Wait, “again”?
Now then, you may start!
I wonder if Yui is doing okay...
She’ll be just fine.
Be more worried!
Ah, Hirasawa-san.
Ma’am...
How did your make-up test go?
It went...
It certainly looks like
you studied hard for it.
A-As long as you don’t give up,
you’re sure to succeed eventually!
Prep Room
A Few Days Later
The test results are today, right?
I wonder if she passed...
After all that studying,
I’m sure she did fine.
H-How did you do?
What am I gonna do,
Mio-chan?
You failed again?
I-I got a hundred!
It’s all or nothing with you!
But that’s a real relief.
You’re home free for now.
She’s right!
I couldn’t have done it
without you guys! Thank you!
Aw, it was nothing!
You didn’t do jack!
Now, shall we get right down
to practicing?
You were practicing chords
while you were first studying, right?
Try playing something.
I have it down!
Ask me anything! X, Y, whatever!
All right, play a C, A minor 7,
D minor 7, and G7.
Sure thing!
What’s the matter?
I don’t remember how!
It’s ‘cause of all the
X and Y stuff I’ve been studying.
So you’re back to square one?
Um, was this an X?
Hold it, I’ve never heard of that chord.
Oh, no, wait! Like this, like this!
Mio-chan, this is an X!
I’m telling you that’s not a chord!
The Monkey Series for beginners
GUITAR CHORDS  EVEN A MONKEY CAN LEARN
You can still play that?!
The Monkey Series for beginners
GUITAR CHORDS  EVEN A MONKEY CAN LEARN
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the regal swan
hakuchoutachi wa sou
frantically waddles her feet out of view
mienai toko de bataashi surun desu
A servant to my instincts,
honnou ni juujun chuujitsu
knowing how they toy with me
honrou mo juujuu shouchi
The future’s bright anyway
zento youyou dashi
So yeah, I need to take a break sometimes
dakara tama ni kyuukei shichaun desu
If I see a shortcut, I’m taking it
chikamichi areba sore ga oudou
If I can tuck in my wings, all the better
hashoreru tsubasa mo areba joutou
Shoot, I broke my nail
yaba tsume wareta
I fixed it up with some glue
guruu de hoshuu shita
A little thing, but I’m still gonna feel proud
soredake de nanka tasseikan
The most important thing is you, treat yourself well
daiji na no wa jibun kawaigaru koto
You must love yourself, or you can’t love anyone
jibun o aisanakya hito mo aisenai
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
Please don’t say “you are lazy”
Because I’m really crazy
datte hontou wa crazy
Even the clever hawk
nou aru taka wa sou
knows when to hide her talons
mienai toko ni pikku kakusundesu
We try and try to dream
souzou ni isshoukenmei
because the world out there is hopeless
genjitsu wa zettaizetsumei
It’s a work-in-progress anyway
hatten tochuu dashi
So yeah, I mess up the pitch sometimes
dakara fui ni picchi hazurerundesu
Next episode
We’re having a boot camp!
Boot camp?
That’s right. After all,
it’s almost summer vacation.
Wait, we’re going to the beach?
Or maybe the mountains?
We’re not going there to play around!
This will be a band boot camp!
From sunrise to sunset,
we’ll be practicing nonstop!
By all means, we should go!
I’ve always dreamed of
having a sleepover with my friends!
#4    Boot Camp!