Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
We must defeat
Tenjou Utena at once...
...and engage the Rose Bride
to another.
Hmm?
Isn’t Tenjou Utena supposed to be
the golden goose?
The golden goose is valuable
because it lays golden eggs.
What a selfish man.
Then which piece
will you move?
Miki’s Birdhouse
(The Sunlit Garden - Arranged)
Kozue!
Oh, my goodness!
Just leave them!
Use both hands!
We’re being serious,
you’re gonna fall!
Kozue!
Miki...
Sheesh, what a troublemaker.
But why would she do
something like that?
Well, when she heard that tree
was being cut down after school today,
she went out the window and onto the ledge
to save the little birds’ nest in the branches.
Kozue’s usually pretty calm,
but she can get pretty weird sometimes.
Stop leaning on me.
It’s sweltering.
It’s more comfortable like this.
You should stop pulling
dangerous stunts like these.
Your brother worries a lot about you.
My, is that so?
Worried about little old me?
I said to stop leaning.
I left your bags here.
Sorry...
You even carried our bags...
What about these little ones?
It’s nice that we brought them home,
but now what do we do?
For now, why not give them
some ground millet?
Millet?
Feed for parakeets
and Java sparrows.
Oh, that stuff?
Soak it in lukewarm water
and then grind it up.
Okay.
Being chicks, they must be fed
every three hours during the day.
Right.
Wow, that’s a lot to manage.
Yes, quite a lot.
The conversation’s
flowing for once!
You must have raised chicks before,
right, Himemiya?
I have not.
Really? Well,
you know a lot about it.
You’re a true animal lover,
aren’t you?
In truth, it would be best
to return them to their parents, but...
Oh, are you able
to stand on your own?
Thank you.
But since you came all this way,
the sweet little sister
will politely excuse herself.
Stay as long as you like.
This letter...
Is it from her?
Yeah.
You read it, too.
It’s from our mother.
Ooh, a letter from your mom?
Sounds nice.
I lost both of my parents,
so I’m a little jealous.
We don’t need parents.
We’re wild animals, after all.
Don’t say things like that.
Father and Mother
always worry about us.
Oh, no.
Now he got all serious.
Hey, do you think
this is the garden?
Hmm?
What do you mean?
The sunlit garden.
You know, the title of
the song Mickey wrote.
I don’t know.
But it’s just an image, isn’t it?
Didn’t Mickey say he and Kozue used to
play piano in a garden when they were little?
He did, yes.
Could it have been this garden?
It’s pretty derelict.
It’s but a memory, after all.
I guess you’re right,
but I was expecting something more...
More what?
I don’t know.
What indeed?
I simply do not know.
What do you think of her?
What do I think of her?
Tell me.
The teacup broke.
Mr. Akio? Are you here?
Yes, over here!
What’s up?
Nothing really, I just...
Huh?
Am I butting in on sibling stuff?
Butting in?
Are the three of us
not practically family?
There’s no need
to be so reserved.
Practically family, huh?
I apologize.
My brother was being too pushy.
No, not at all.
I don’t have any family,
so it made me happy.
I mean it.
He’s just—how do you say it?—
broad-minded.
My brother is...
Well, let me think.
I guess he is very adult.
To me, he’s like a parent.
A parent...
Do you think fathers and mothers always
care about their children like Mickey said?
Could that be because
of their genes?
That’s a harsh way
of looking at it.
Forgive me.
You don’t have to apologize.
It seems The End of the World
started sending us letters again.
Saionji despised the duels,
yet he dueled again.
There could be some connection.
I’m worried about
what Touga’s up to.
What’s this about my brother?
“Defeat Tenjou Utena,
for your own good as Duelists”, right?
I don’t like this!
Most adults who tell you to do something
“for your own good” can’t be trusted!
Is that a motion of no-confidence
towards The End of the World?
Interpret it however you want.
If dueling means letting selfish adults
manipulate me, then this is where I stop.
It’s too soon to come to
a final decision.
The End of the World’s
true nature remains unknown.
Yeah. He might be a nice person like
Daddy-Long-Legs for all we know.
Nanami, hurry up
and let me use that thing.
No...
Yeah. It was in Mother’s letter.
No, Kozue and I aren’t against it.
That’s entirely up to you, Father.
I don’t think we’ll be able
to come to the wedding,
but we’ll at least send a telegram.
Huh? With who?
Don’t trouble yourself.
Our new mother—
Don’t worry about that.
Father?
It’s okay.
It would be impudent of me
to call myself “Mother” so quickly.
Hey.
Hey yourself.
What are you doing?
I heard you got hurt.
Wild animals recover fast.
Huh.
Well that’s good, but loitering is prohibited
for anybody not on the Student Council.
I’m meeting someone.
At this hour? Who?
Daddy-Long-Legs.
Want me to introduce you?
No, thanks.
It’s almost dawn.
How long do you intend
to stay here?
The school festival is coming up.
I’m getting my fingers in shape.
What’s got you so annoyed?
I’m not annoyed or anything.
I hear you plan to stop
being a Duelist.
I do.
Yet you’ve already chosen
the path of the Duelist.
I think you already know that some things
can only become yours if you seize them by force.
Is that as far as you go?
Juri said she suspects
you’ve been up to something lately.
A beautiful timbre.
But it can’t sustain that beauty
merely by being beautiful.
My.
It hit the wall already.
What are you trying to say?
There is someone
I want you to meet.
Someone you want me to meet?
There it is.
Can you not hear it?
Hear what?
So long as your soul
has not truly given up...
...you can hear
the sound that races...
...across the end of the world!
What are you talking about?
I hear it!
I really hear it!
What is this?!
Now, join us!
Follow us to the world
of your desires!
You’re the Board Chairman, right?
Yep.
Himemiya’s big brother.
What are you doing here?
I’m on a date
with Mr. Akio, obviously.
Well, do whatever you like.
More importantly, what do you want
with me, Mr. Board Chairman?
You love Himemiya, don’t you?
H-Hey...!
You don’t have to be so bashful.
If she’s so important to you,
then make her yours.
Mr. Akio said he’ll help you.
He’s awesome.
I thought you hated Himemiya.
I just want you to be happy.
What’s brought this on?
I’m always honest
with my feelings. That’s all.
I don’t lie.
Don’t you trust me?
It’s not that, but...
Mr. Akio said
it’s for your own good.
Typical thing for an adult to say...
So?
If everything around you is tainted,
you’ve got no choice but to become tainted too.
Only by becoming tainted
can you get what you want.
What I want...
You were the one who made
Saionji duel again, weren’t you?
You seduced Touga and interfered
with the Student Council’s affairs.
Who are you?!
I will now show
the end of the world...
...to you, as well.
So you’re...!
Whoa! Be more gentle, okay?
Sorry. Is it crooked?
Nope, it’s good.
Set it here.
Okay.
Hey, you two.
You setting up a birdhouse?
I wonder if their parents
will come back.
What’s wrong?
Today, after school,
at the dueling arena.
No way...
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Miss, isn’t it about time?
Darn it...
I’m betting my whole purse!
Everything on black!
Is that your final answer?
Oh, what a shame!
It was red!
Miss, didn’t you say you had
never once gambled before?
And that you hate it?
You’re the one who told me
to try it at least once!
Wait right here!
I’m withdrawing my life savings!
Heh, what a sucker.
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
Kozue...
Why are you dressed like...?
Miki.
Ready? Here we go.
Yeah.
Master Utena?
Right.
O Rose of Noble Emotion...
I beg of you, manifest...
Existence, a marvelous alchemy
Base metal to noble metal
From right to left, the beginning and the end
The power to revolutionize the world!
Destruction, a hunt, a wild dance, a feast
Nativity, an invisible alchemy
A man-made recombinator
From top to bottom, reshaped and misshaped
Books, anonymity, indulgence, disgrace
The world is unaltering
I— I am unaltering
unalter altering teringun ingunal unaltering
I thought we were friends!
Your sword can’t defeat mine!
Halt, fowl and fish that spin in circles
From today on,
the Rose Bride is mine!
Halt, egg and bed that seek to deceive
You’ve gotten even better.
However...!
Halt, ship and coach that dance in the ways of old
Halt, sea and falls that overtake me
Glimmering reverie
Wavering imagination
Clattering fantasy
Slithering expression
Rustling delusion
Himemiya!
Flickering creativity
Fluttering ideas
Quivering supposition
I’ve heard people engaged to you
get an amazing power.
Birth, an immortal alchemy
Time, space: the cosmic egg
What kind of “amazing power”?
Philosophy, crystals: Rosenkreuz
Kozue!
What are you doing?!
Purity, harmony: perspective
Show me that power.
I, the future, the past, the present
Kozue!
You’ll lose if your eyes
keep wandering.
I, the future, the past, the present
Glimmering origin
Wavering solitude
Clattering maze
Slithering space-time
Rustling reminiscence
Flickering memories
Fluttering evaporation
Quivering immortality
I, the future, the past, the present
A child’s sword...
What made Mickey
want to duel me so suddenly?
I don’t know.
I mean, Mickey is more...
More... what?
What’s with you?!
Pathetic.
Prehistory, perfection
Solitude in the desert
Air, atoms
Celestial body of causality
Yes, a child of the earth is conceived
An embryo of philosophy
And...
Sphere of the Moon
Sphere of Mercury, Sphere of Venus,
Sphere of the Sun, Sphere of Mars,
Sphere of Jupiter, Sphere of Saturn,
Sphere of Fixed Stars,
Sphere of Primum Mobile
Further beyond...
...the infinite, endless circle
A type of organic mechanism
A type of perpetual motion machine
Ah, motion from nothing
It is motion...
...from nothing
Nothing
Next Episode
Hey Himemiya, do you have worries
you can’t share with others?
Fried eggs, rolled omelets,
hot spring eggs...
I’m sure everyone has embarrassing stuff
they can’t talk about freely.
Scrambled eggs, omelets...
Wonder what Nanami’s
so freaked about.
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the omelet cannot be made.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Nanami’s Egg
“Nanami’s Egg”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.