isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
Once upon a time...
...there was a young princess grieving
the deaths of her mother and father.
Before the princess appeared a traveling prince
mounted upon a white horse.
His appearance gallant
and his smile gentle,
the prince enveloped the princess
in the scent of roses...
...and gently wiped the tears
from her eyes.
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
“As a token to remember this day,
please take this.”
“We shall meet again,
will we not?”
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
Could the ring the prince gave her
be anything other than an engagement ring?
This was all well and good,
but so impressed was she by him...
...that the princess vowed
to become a prince herself!
But is that really okay?
The Cowbell of Happiness
All right!
Thank you, everyone!
Now, Steve...
Next up we have...
...this pendant from renowned
designer brand Sebastian Dior!
Potato Chips
Beef Flavor
Whoa!
Did I just hear you right, Roger?!
Give it a good look! What do you think?
It’s got such an elegant shimmer!
Wow!
Himemiya,
you still watching that?
Yes.
I’ll go to sleep soon.
That’s amazing, Roger!
Then... good night...
Good night.
Now, orders are open for this
luxury designer brand Sebastian Dior pendant.
Cute!
Oh my, it’s beautiful,
Nanami-sama!
Such a gorgeous dress!
A present from my dear uncle.
It’s nothing special.
Oh my, it’s beautiful,
Nanami-sama!
Such a gorgeous ring!
Such gorgeous shoes!
Such gorgeous earrings!
Ever fabulous, Nanami-sama!
You’re always the best dresser!
It’s nothing special.
They haven’t seen anything yet.
The only reason I’m having this party
is to unveil the prize of my collection.
This special pendant
adorned with a twenty carat diamond...
Once everyone gets
so much as a glimpse at it...
Juri-san! That necklace...
Oh, one of Sorya Ricci’s designers
insisted I just had to have it.
Wow!
Sorya Ricci is an extremely
prestigious brand, right?
I just did a little
modeling for them.
It’s a little much.
So, do you think that necklace
is a complete one-of-a-kind?
Incredible!
Nanami.
Oh, it’s Juri-senpai!
Good evening!
Why did you decide
to throw a party out of the blue?
You can clue us in now that
the party is in full swing, can’t you?
W-Well...
Nanami-sama!
This just arrived.
Huh? What’s this?
What?!
Th-That emblem...!
It’s Sebastian Dior!
“Sebastian Dior”?
Sebastian Dior...
Purveyor of the British Royal Family,
and the most elite designer brand.
I’ve never seen
an item of theirs.
Most elite designer brand...
This is just what I need
to take the spotlight back from Juri.
That’s right!
Gather round, everyone!
You were all invited here today...
...for a first look at the newest
crowning piece of my fabulous collection.
Without further ado,
it’s time to open it!
Here, for your viewing pleasure!
A cowbell...
A Sebastian Dior cowbell...
They look speechless.
The radiance...
The grace...
All these luxurious brand-name
accessories are made for me.
Me, and only me.
Good morning!
G-Good morning...
It’s weird.
Indeed...
What happened?
Did she bang her head
or something?
No idea.
‘Cause, like, first of all,
a cowbell is...
Isn’t it?
Indeed...
If you know that,
why didn’t you tell her?
Do you seriously think
I could tell her at this point?
Good morning!
She’s clawing at her wound
and making it bigger...
It’s already pretty huge...
Nanami-san!
What is that thing
hanging around your neck?
It’s a cowbell!
A cowbell...?
Isn’t the weather lovely today?
A cowbell is...
Right?
Guess all we can do
is wait till she realizes.
Hey, hey... have you seen
Nanami-san’s cowbell?
Yeah, I did! I saw it! Y’know...
It’s a bit extreme, isn’t it?
Extreme’s one way to put it.
You have to hand it to Nanami-san!
No one else would go
all in the way she does.
Word is getting around.
Everyone is taking notice
of my immaculate fashion sense!
Um, Nanami-san...
Um...
Isn’t that heavy for your neck?
I’ve been thinking...
That cowbell looks weir—
Tsuwabuki...
Yes?
What exactly is “weird” about this cowbell
from Sebastian Dior, purveyor to royalty?
Looks like you’re still too young to understand
an adult’s fashion sense, Tsuwabuki.
An adult’s...
fashion sense?
It is weird!
That cowbell is weird!
I don’t know about brands
or anything,
but a cowbell
goes around a cow’s ne—
That he-she
is such a nuisance.
Poor thing doesn’t know
the first thing about fashion.
What’d you just say?!
Who’re you calling a “he-she”?!
I’ve been meaning to say this
for quite some time...
Your uniform is very weird.
D-Don’t compare my clothes
to your cowbell!
I wouldn’t dream of comparing it
to that tasteless uniform.
What was that?!
Say that again!
I’ll say it
as many times as I like!
Oh, dear...
To make matters worse,
your legs are fat!
Huh? Where am I?
aru hareta hirusagari
Late one sunny day,
Big Brother!
ichiba he tsudzuku michi
on the road to the marketplace,
Are you awake?
You’re feeling better,
Big Brother?!
nibasha ga gotogoto
a wagon rattles along,
You finally
came out of your room!
It’s all okay now, Nanami.
koushi wo nosete yuku
carrying a calf within
It’s all okay now.
Here you go, Nanami!
Your breakfast is served!
kawaii ni koushi urarete yuku yo
The adorable calf is to be sold
What’s going on,
Big Brother?
I can’t eat this!
All right...
Eat to your heart’s content.
After all,
this will be your last meal.
kanashisou na hitomi de mite iru yo
It looks on with mournful eyes
M-My last meal?
Farewell, Nanami.
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
Big Brother?
What’s going on,
Big Brother?!
koushi wo nosete
Carrying the calf within...
Farewell, Nanami!
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
Big Brother! Big Brother!
Farewell, Nanami.
nibasha ga yureru
...the wagon sways along
Big Brother!
Time to eat!
A dream...?
Hey, have you seen
Nanami-san’s cowbell?
Huh?! She’s still wearing it?!
Well, I guess you could say
she really stands out.
She sure has guts.
Seems more like stubbornness.
Dining
Hall
Yeah, yeah! And she’s never stood
in line behind other people before!
Dining
Hall
You’re right.
Rumination
Hygiene
Maybe she’s mellowed out.
She seems calmer.
Rumination
Hygiene
Nanami-san...
You’re eating again?
Didn’t you already
have your fill at the cafeteria?
Moo... Don’t stick your nose in
where it doesn’t bull-ong.
Class will be starting soon.
Yeah, yeah, I knoooow.
Cud you just be quiet?
Nanami-san...!
I’m about ready to hit the hay
after all that food.
Tsuwabuki,
answer for me when they take attendance.
Um...
But I’m in elementary school...
You’re really getting
udder my skin...
If you lie down right after eating,
you’ll become a cow!
Sheesh... Did I studder?
Hey, look, look!
Wow, Nanami-sama, that hair clip is...
Well? Does it look nice?
Y-Yes, very much so.
What a cow-incidence!
You think so too?
They really are fa-bull-ous!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Fight! Hoof! Fight! Hoof!
Hey, Kiryuu!
Pick up the pace!
Yeah, yeah, I herd you!
What’s the matter with her?
It’s like she’s running
in slow motion.
I can’t take this
bullying anymore.
You’re really getting
udder my skin...
I don’t knoooow
what’s going oooon...
Tenjou Utena
Himemiya Anthy
Tsuwabuki-kun?
It’s terrible!
Nanami-san...
Nanami-san is...!
She called and told me to bring her
something to eat because she was hungry.
But she didn’t even touch
what I brought, and she went to the park...
And then?
You lost sight of her here?
Exactly.
But no one’s around...
It’s so odd...
Moo... Honestly, moo...
Cut the bull, Tsuwabuki...
He doesn’t even knoooow what I like.
Udderly ridi-cow-lous.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
Squeak-squeak! It’s simple!
All we gotta do
is put a bell on the cat!
Squeak-squeak!
Oh, Nezutarou, you’re a genius!
But who’ll be the one to do it?
Squeak-squeak!
No need to decide!
Bell’s already on the cat!
You see, I just snuck off
and did the deed!
Squeak! Wonderful!
Nezutarou-san, you’re the best!
Squeak!
O Esteemed Mr. Cat!
I lied to ‘em like we agreed!
They feel so safe,
they’ll be sleeping soundly tonight.
You can catch and eat
as many as you want!
So, as promised,
please let me go.
Uh, Mr. Cat? Wait!
Munch!
Munch... munch... munch...
You reap what you sow.
Definitely.
Nanami!
Ditch the cowbell!
Ditch it!
Man-ure so annoying.
Do you know what that bell
around your neck is?
Bull-ease...
It’s a Sebastian Dior cowbell, moo!
A cowbell, as in a bell that
a cow wears around its neck!
What are myoo talking about?
Take a good, long
look around you!
Huh?
Y-You mean to say Sebastian Dior,
purveyor to royalty, actually...?!
It’s not Sebastian Dior...
It’s Calfstian Dior!
C-Calfstian...?
You don’t even know
what a cowbell is,
and yet you’ve been
parading around and showing it off.
And now you’re practically a cow.
A cow?!
Can’t do anything about that now.
What you can do is take that thing off
before you become a cow in body and soul!
Wh-What are myoo saying?!
How could it be possi-bull
for a human to turn into a cow?
I’m being serioooous,
stop trying to make me cower in fear!
You’re full of bull!
Utena-sama!
It’s finally finished!
What is it?
It’s a sweater!
Thanks, but it’s a little
out of season, isn’t it?
Moo... Just a little moooore time
and I would’ve been irresista-bull.
I’m mooooving in and out
of cow-nsciousness...
What are these horri-bull visions?
What does the appendix doooo?
Holy cow, hoof I been
poisoned by a snake?
Someone bring me
a comforta-bull blanket!
Nanami?
aru hareta hirusagari
Late one sunny day,
ichiba he tsudzuku michi
on the road to the marketplace,
nibasha ga gotogoto
a wagon rattles along,
Nanami, you’ve...!
How horrifying!
koushi wo nosete yuku
carrying a calf within
N-Nanami-san!
She’s charging at us!
kawaii ni koushi urarete yuku yo
The adorable calf is to be sold
Oh! I get it!
Seeing the red sweater
riled her up!
Oh, my!
Tenjou-san! The cowbell!
kanashisou na hitomi de mite iru yo
It looks on with mournful eyes
Gotcha!
Himemiya, run for it!
Right!
Take responsi-bull-ity!
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
koushi wo nosete
Carrying the calf within...
Olé!
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
nibasha ga yureru
...the wagon sways along
Utena-san!
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
koushi wo nosete
Carrying the calf within...
I’m udderly done for!
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
nibasha ga yureru
...the wagon sways along
Utena-sama!
aoi sora soyogu kaze
In the blue sky, gliding through the breeze...
How pitiable...
tsubame ga tobikau
...a swallow swiftly flutters by
The final days of someone
enslaved to brands.
nibasha ga ichiba he
A wagon bound for the market
That’s not very convincing
coming from you, Juri-san.
koushi wo nosete yuku
carries a calf within
Still, I wonder who sent Nanami-san
that cowbell in the first place.
moshimo tsubasa ga atta naraba
What a shame you don't have wings
Oh, I see!
That cowbell was for your pet!
Her name is Nanami.
tanoshii makiba ni kaereru mono wo
If you did, you could go home and graze peacefully
Nanami...?
Oh, so whoever delivered it
made a mistake.
Soon, she’ll be getting
a new nose ring, too.
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
Nose ring?
koushi wo nosete
Carrying the calf within...
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
nibasha ga yureru
...the wagon sways along
Good morning, all!
Dona, dona, dona
Dona
So? Do I look good?
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Arisugawa-senpai’s childhood friend
just transferred here!
Takatsuki Shiori-san,
correct?
But are they on
good terms or bad terms?
I don’t know
what happened,
but Arisugawa-senpai shouldn’t
keep holding a grudge for so long.
You’re rather naïve, aren’t you,
Utena-sama?
Huh? But Shiori-san just wants
to be friends with senpai, right?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Thorns of Death
“Thorns of Death”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.