Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Once upon a time...
...there was a young princess grieving
the deaths of her mother and father.
Before the princess appeared a traveling prince
mounted upon a white horse.
His appearance gallant
and his smile gentle,
the prince enveloped the princess
in the scent of roses...
...and gently wiped the tears
from her eyes.
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
“As a token to remember this day,
please take this.”
“We shall meet again,
will we not?”
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
Could the ring the prince gave her
be anything other than an engagement ring?
This was all well and good,
but so impressed was she by him...
...that the princess vowed
to become a prince herself!
But is that really okay?
Curry On Tripping
Nanami, class 2-A is having
cooking lessons, right on schedule.
So it appears...
And what we discussed earlier?
Yes. I made the switch.
Hundredfold Curry, an Indian specialty
hot enough to make you breathe fire.
Excellent.
Tenjou Utena and Himemiya Anthy...
Just you wait!
I’ll soon have you
begging for mercy.
Consider this your punishment
for trying to seduce my brother.
Nanami!
Be quiet.
We’re just getting to the good part.
I’m sorry, it’s just...
What?
We didn’t switch in
the Hundredfold Curry after all.
It seems we gave them
the Agonizing Blow Your Brains Out...
...Trippy Roaring Elephant Super Spicy
Nine Hundred Billionfold Curry.
“Trippy”?
“Blow Your Brains Out”?
No way...
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
My fellow councilors,
the Code of the Rose Seal faces its greatest crisis.
The Rose Bride
and her betrothed have both fallen.
This was an unforeseen turn of events,
even for The End of the World.
I was informed that
their lives are in danger.
This is my fault!
Miki?
I kept telling Himemiya that
I wanted to have some extremely spicy curry.
Himemiya risked her life
to make me that curry...
That doesn’t necessarily mean
you’re to blame, Miki.
But what’s our move now?
The fact remains that
a measly batch of curry ruined our plans.
It’s all my fault.
It’s me.
What?
They’ve been released?
Both of them?
Utena! Utena!
Utena, my love!
Oh, you had me so worried!
Are you all right now?
I heard there was a huge explosion,
and I was worried sick, and...
I’m so sorry!
I wasn’t thinking and just
hugged you like I always do...
I-I’d better call an ambulance!
Yeah. Um... Um... Err...
There is no need.
I’m unhurt.
I apologize for worrying you.
You’re acting weird.
You’ve been really
pleased with yourself lately!
Don’t flatter yourself just because
that she-he always hangs around you.
Some nights it gets
really dark, you know?
Hey... Don’t just stand there!
Say something!
What are you doing?
Oh, it’s just you, Miki.
Don’t sneak up on me like that.
Himemiya!
You... You hit me!
Not even my mom ever hit me!
Stop with your petty bullshit
unless you want something to really cry about.
It... It can’t be...
Pure, innocent Himemiya...
They swapped personalities?
Here are some candid photos of them
from the past few days.
Himemiya Anthy
and Tenjou Utena...
They completely switched
how they act.
You’re right. But why?
It all started after
that curry explosion.
Utena is Anthy
and Anthy is Utena?
All because of the
Nine Hundred Billionfold spice mix...
That’s inane!
Five, please.
That’ll be 2,000 yen.
Gallant Anthy
is cooler than I expected!
Calm Utena’s a keeper, too!
You’re selling them?
They have an unusual appeal, huh?
They’re popular with
boys and girls alike.
My goodness!
This...
This can’t be Himemiya!
But still...!
I bought some
and I hate myself for it.
Right, you wanted twenty, yes?
Thank you for your patronage!
Really... What’s so great
about a woman like her?
I see.
So that’s how it is.
Brother?!
I thought something
seemed strange,
but I didn’t think
you were involved in this.
O-Oh, no!
It’s just, well, you know...
Here are the negatives.
Thank you for your patronage!
Even you, Brother?!
I see. So that’s what happened.
Geh!
So you were
the masterminds...
You misunderstand.
Yeah, you don’t understand!
My brother would never
make passes at you two.
This was all my doing!
Nanami!
You’ve created
a real problem for me.
Please forgive me,
beloved brother!
I, being such a generous girl,
procured a mystical spice mix straight from India!
Just so that Anthy could make some
yummy curry for cooking class!
I never, ever expected such an incident
would happen! I don’t believe it!
I don’t believe you.
If I could just get
the mystical spice mix once more...
I’m sure Utena and Anthy
would turn back to normal!
So, please,
esteemed brother!
Very well.
I’m not letting you back in the house
until you have the mystical spice mix.
Okay!
Thank you, Big Brother!
That’s easy to say,
but where do we get it?
Well, it’s imported
from India, right...?
India?!
Wait for me, Dear Brother!
I shall return!
Why us, too?!
Love and youth: a course on idioms!
Today’s phrase is...
“Just deserts”
Just deserts?
It means that every wrongdoing of yours
will bring you an equal measure of misfortune.
Gimme yer money!
Bang! Bang! Bang! Bang!
Agh! What the...?!
If you do something bad,
expect to face consequences.
Wonderful jump,
Master Utena!
Man, it feels weird
to see me praising myself.
I’m not very good at sports,
so seeing myself being so athletic
really spices things up for me.
Still, we gotta find some way
to get back to normal.
Don’t worry.
Even at this very moment,
I’m sure Nanami is...
Anyway, it’ll be bad if we don’t
switch our bodies back soon.
I don’t wanna end up getting sacrificed
to the Rose Seal, or something.
I don’t mind being like this.
I don’t put any stock
in outward appearances.
Well, I do mind!
Saionji’s been hitting on me.
I’ve been waiting,
Himemiya Anthy.
See? Here he comes.
It’s that time again.
Will you come with me?
Could I come with?
You can stay here.
Come on, Anthy.
You were a massive help.
When those elephants were chasing us,
I thought we were finished.
By the way, would you know anything about
the mystical Nine Hundred Billionfold spice mix?
Mystical what?
I have longed for this day.
Oh, Himemiya...
What do you and Saionji
get up to in here?
Anthy.
I’ll get right to the point.
I need you to fulfill your promise.
Uh... What was it, again?
You’re quite the tease,
as ever.
Well, if that’s how you want to play,
I’ll just say it.
Today is our biweekly time...
...to prove our love
for each other.
“Prove”? “Love”?!
Now, time for
what we always do!
W-Wait!
Even if we defy fate itself,
our bond is genuine.
Though we must keep it
a secret for now.
No!
Don’t turn your eyes away!
Look at me!
Look at the real me!
No! No!
Here, you will find
nothing but the truth...
Here in our exchange diary.
Huh? Diary?
The mystical spice mix...
Nanami!
An elephant?!
I am content with merely
keeping this diary for the time being,
but someday, once I master the sword,
I’ll show everyone I can get you back.
Await that day, Anthy.
That Saionji...
He’s for real.
I guess, since she
knew about his feelings,
Himemiya just kept the diary
and hid it even from me.
But...
What do I do?
It’d be best to get her
to write a response herself...
...but if I do that, they’ll know
I found out about their secret.
It goes without saying
I can’t write in it myself.
Ah, it’s Saionji’s exchange diary!
Well, please be sure
to return it to him, Master Utena.
Wha—?!
You mean...
Are you telling me to write in it?
You are now
Himemiya Anthy, after all.
I can’t just butt in
on your privacy!
It’s just wrong.
Wrong?
Yeah, it’s wrong.
Well, then, I’ll stop.
Wait! What’s the big idea?
That’s a little extreme.
You can’t just throw it away!
I was only keeping the diary
because you never said to stop, Master Utena.
Now that you’ve declared
it’s wrong,
I can’t continue writing
in Saionji’s exchange diary.
All I’m trying to say is...
Yes?
...I think
I kinda pity him now.
Okay.
Nanami!
Not again!
Oh, well...
Guess I have to write something.
Let’s see now...
“Dear Anthy, even now I dream
of the time you and I were engaged.”
There, see?
He’s really serious about this, yeah?
Geez...
To my beloved Anthy,
I’m sorry for how long
you’ve had to wait.
I’m satisfied with this diary for now,
but you can count on me to overthrow
that impudent, ugly she-he Tenjou...
...and prove
that I can take you back.
By Saionji Kyouichi.
This ain’t funny at all.
Where’s the spice mix?
Where’s the mystical spice mix?
Nanami!
Not long now, Anthy...
...until the day I return
to a rose-colored life with you.
This is unusual for you, Saionji.
Showing your face
in the rose garden, that is.
Mark my words, Touga.
The Rose Bride
will soon return to me.
Oh? Anthy will?
No one can
tear our love apart...
Not even the Code of the Rose Seal.
Heh... Anthy, eh?
Saionji, darling!
Oh, Anthy!
I’ve been waiting!
Forgive me. I simply could not
stop laying all my thoughts bare!
Please, take it.
I see...
All this time, you...
I feel the same way!
So...
Hey, I was just told
Nanami has returned.
What?
PERV
Brother!
Nanami!
You seem more resolute
than before.
I finally found it!
This is the mystical spice mix!
Well done, Nanami!
All right!
Now we can return to normal!
Brother!
Nanami!
Is there any more?!
That was their last batch!
They said it will take two hundred years
to refine more Nine Hundred Billionfold spice mix!
Two hundred years?!
A textbook example of just deserts.
...or is it?
The spice mix... The mystical spice mix
I went through so much trouble to obtain...
We’re gonna be like this forever?
Now, now, everyone...
Don’t be so morose.
Please try to cheer up
and have some of my special curry.
But I don’t really
feel like having curry...
Nanami!
What is it?!
You’re annoying me!
Excuse us. It’s just...
Th-That’s...
The Nine Hundred Billionfold
spice mix!
What?!
It was in the cooking classroom.
Unopened.
It doesn’t look like
it was ever used in the curry.
So that means the explosion...
...wasn’t caused
by the spice mix!
It was caused
by Anthy’s cooking?!
That’s incredible,
Himemiya!
An explosive curry that causes
a personality switch when consumed...
It’s a new invention!
Oh, you’re embarrassing me.
Saionji!
Anthy,
what is the meaning of this?
When did you start writing
such shameless things?
I see it now...
It’s because you’re living
with that crude wretch, Tenjou Utena.
I get it, Anthy.
I’ll pretend I never read that,
so please rewrite it.
Use a new page
to express your love.
First, though,
tell me how you like this curry.
It’s a new invention,
you know.
Sure. I might as well.
Th-That curry is...!
A new invention!
So you were both your old selves when
you came to after the shock of the explosion?
That’s right.
Wow, that’s hard to believe.
The whole thing
was a huge pain!
No more curry for me!
I agree.
By the way...
Yes?
What’s with him?
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Himemiya’s been spirited away?!
No one is allowed to take me to the arena
without a duel declaration!
Please stop, Saionji!
Saionji! What are you
doing with Himemiya?!
Think about her feelings
for a change!
Someday, I want to go
to that castle floating in the sky.
Something eternal awaits within.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“The Castle Said to Hold Eternity”
The Castle Said to Hold Eternity
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.