Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
I’ve waited so long to meet you...
My whole life has led up...
...to this encounter with you.
Don’t you think, my prince?
Someone’s having fun!
Something good happen?
Yup!
Something good.
Ta-dah!
Wakaba is very happy to have made this pretty
little lunch for her dearest, most beloved Utena.
You’re a girl through and through.
You’re gonna make
such a good bride someday.
Right? You’ve said it!
These little octopus wieners
are a work of art!
Here! Say, “Ah”...
Um...
Um... How do you do?
I’m a second-year, class D.
My name is Kazami Tatsuya.
Tenjou...
Please read this.
LADY TENJOU UTENA
Second-year, class D,
Kazami Tatsuya, huh?
LADY TENJOU UTENA
Wakaba!
Sorry.
Don’t take it personally, okay?
Right...
Kazami Tatsuya?
But I’m... not really the type...
Kazami Tatsuya!
Yes?
I remember now!
You’re the Onion Prince,
aren’t you?
O-Onion Prince?
C’mon! It’s me!
We were in elementary school together!
I’m Shinohara Wakaba!
Um... Wakaba?
It’s been so long!
I had no idea
you went to this school, too.
I thought your name
sounded really familiar.
I was thinking, like,
“Is this deja vu?”
But no wonder
it seemed so familiar...
Song of the Fallen Kingdom
So? What’s an
“Onion Prince”?
Why are you being all gloomy?
I missed my chance
to return that letter!
I’ll give it back in your place.
I can’t let you do that.
It’d be poor etiquette, y’know?
I’ll return it.
Really, don’t worry!
He’s not the type of guy
you should be paying attention to.
But don’t let your guard down!
He’ll trick you
with his smooth talk!
That’s a pretty nasty thing to say.
He’s the same as he was back then.
He’s always chasing tail,
going around flirting with girls...
C’mon...
Guys like him
give men everywhere a bad name.
Don’t you think
that’s taking it a bit far?
He’s heartless.
Wakaba...?
He’s... just plain heartless.
Because...
...he transferred away
without telling me.
Wakaba...
He...
That guy used to be my prince.
Nyah! Nyah!
Onionhead!
Shut up!
You pumpkins and daikon radishes!
I have my Onion Prince
here with me!
Huh?
I have my Onion Prince
here with me!
Huh?
I have my Onion Prince
here with me!
Huh?
I have my Onion Prince
here with me!
Huh?
Well, it’s an old story, y’know?
Prince, huh?
Wh-What?
Fact is... You think this is destiny
or something, don’t you?
No way.
Wakaba!
She told me
to give this back to you.
In general the two of you
just aren’t a good match.
This is all because
you said weird things!
What?
You brought up this weird
Pumpkin Prince or whatever in front of her.
It’s Onion Prince.
It doesn’t matter
whichever it is.
It does matter!
It does matter.
It’s important to me...
It doesn’t matter to you, Tatsuya?
It’s an important memory for me, so...
Anyway...
Can you introduce me to her again?
All right.
If you really want it,
I’ll introduce you...
But that’s all.
Mickey, could you play the piano again
at tomorrow’s party?
Sure.
Speaking of that...
You always think about your one special person
when playing the piano, don’t you?
J-Juri...
Please don’t tease me.
Please. Move on and think about
something else when you play, already.
It must be nice to be you,
Nanami.
You can have all your desires satisfied
by an elementary schooler.
Shut up!
That’s just play! Play!
True love is something
you feel only once.
That’s why the shape of love
is eternal.
My beloved brother...
You mean anyone who isn’t
your literal brother is worthless small fry?
You only feel true love once?
If you could just change the one you love
as if flipping a switch...
...things would be much easier
for both of you.
Guess the same goes for me.
I’m still wondering if he’s the prince
Wakaba said she can’t stop thinking about.
What are you referring to?
Oh, I mean...
By chance, my friend reunited
with her childhood friend.
Problem is they’re not
talking things out with each other,
and I’m wondering if maybe
the prince she’s waiting for is actually him.
What a lovely story.
Oh, sorry.
I’m always the one talking here.
I don’t mind.
However, Ms. Tenjou...
The inside of a person’s heart
is akin to something veiled in silk.
It may feel like you can peer through,
but in reality you cannot.
The princes people hold
within their hearts...
...are surely beyond
others’ understanding.
Still, I envy young people in love.
I hope you, too,
find your own prince soon, Anthy.
Indeed, Big Brother.
Got it, Utena?
Sure, he’s not your cup of tea,
but just put up with him for a bit.
Put up with him, huh?
Yeah.
Even though
he’s not my cup of tea?
Yep!
Okay.
It’s not just for his sake
I’m doing this.
What do you mean?
Hello! Sorry for taking so long!
You’re late!
You think we’ve got all day?
Sorry, sorry.
Um... Who is this?
Oh, lemme introduce you.
This is Himemiya Anthy.
She’s my roommate.
Hello. How do you do?
I’m Kazami Tatsuya.
Hello. I’m Himemiya.
And this is Chu-Chu.
Hello.
I’m Kazami Tatsuya.
Pleased to meet you, Chu-Chu.
Why are you
hitting on a monkey?
What are you talking about?
That side of you hasn’t changed at all.
Stop talking like that
in front of everyone.
It’s the truth, no?
You’re always
buttering girls up.
That wasn’t what I was...
What’s your problem, Wakaba?
Why are you accusing me like this?
It’s strange.
I’m...
Forget it. It’s nothing.
What is it?
It’s nothing.
If you want to say something,
then say it!
I said it’s nothing!
Look, you have something
to say to Utena, right?
Right.
Um... Tenjou,
are you seeing anyone at present?
I’m not dating
anyone right now, but...
...a long time ago,
a prince gave me this ring.
I still think about him.
A prince, huh?
That sounds nice and dreamy.
Speaking of, looks like the princess next to you
has a prince she can’t keep off her mind.
Right, Wakaba?
Wh-What are you
talking about, Utena?!
The Onion Prince
is nice and dreamy, right?
You’ve got it wrong!
My prince is...
My... prince is...
My... prince...
Why not be more honest
with yourself, Wakaba?
I said you’ve got it wrong!
Oh...
Utena, you’re picking on me!
Wakaba!
Um... Tenjou?
What?
What you said about
Wakaba’s prince just now...
What did you mean?
She acts tough,
but she’s also a girl.
Maybe she just can’t forget
the prince she met so long ago.
I have my Onion Prince
here with me!
It’s an important memory for me, so...
Tenjou...
What?
To tell the truth,
when I transferred to this academy...
...I knew Wakaba was here.
She hasn’t changed
even a little since those days.
Whenever she looked happy...
...you were always
next to her, Tenjou.
If I could be with you...
Then you could be
with Wakaba, too?
So that’s why
you wrote me a love letter, eh?
I’m sorry.
That girl is just so shy.
I thought she only called me
Onion Prince to make fun of me...
...but I was wrong,
wasn’t I?
Well, I don’t know
anything beyond that.
The princes people hold
within their hearts...
...are surely beyond
others’ understanding.
But I think
it’s worth it to confess.
Thank you so much!
I wonder if I did the right thing.
With what?
With Tatsuya and Wakaba.
No need to worry.
When it comes to romance,
whatever happens, happens.
True, but...
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Oh, geez...
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Utena
you're a
meanie!!
Extra! Extra! Extra!
Come one, come all!
Fresh tires for sale!
The tire shop has a sale today!
I’ll take one!
But sir...
What’s a tire shop?
I’m glad you asked, ma’am!
Fish shops...
...sell fish.
Bread shops...
...sell bread.
And we’re a tire shop,
so we sell tires!
Wow!
Telling good tires from bad ones
takes lots of experience.
It’s very hard to tell if they taste
good or bad by looks alone.
Oop!
I’ll take a helping
of those tires, then.
Thanks, come again!
Feed your husband
something invigorating!
Oh, tire shop owner, please!
Now, how shall I cook
these tires up for dinner, I wonder?
Can you eat those?
Wakaba...
Can you spare a minute?
What is it?
You sound serious.
What’s wrong?
There’s somebody you like,
isn’t there?
What...?
You’re in love with your prince,
aren’t you?
Look...
You should be honest
when the chips are down.
I’m always honest.
Prince, huh?
What?
Well...
I was just thinking...
...that you might want to know
how your prince feels.
How my prince feels?
But just as you finally realized
your own feelings...
...maybe you’ve already realized
how your prince feels, too.
Childhood friends
are just that good, huh?
Of course.
You’re right.
I finally realize it.
I really do love that prince.
And maybe, if God’s on my side,
that prince will turn around
and look at me.
Maybe I...
Maybe I can finally
become happy, too...
Well, then...
You understand already.
You can become happy.
Tatsuya...
Wakaba...
But... Will you promise
to keep this a secret from everyone?
Sure!
If it makes you embarrassed,
we can make it our secret.
I still can’t really believe it,
but I’ve finally found happiness,
haven’t I?
Yeah...
I hope you hurry and
find happiness with someone, too!
Yeah, I’ll find happiness
with someone—
Huh?
Well, that settles that.
I gotta go!
Can’t make him wait forever!
Who?
Who do you think?
My prince!
See ya!
“My prince”...?
Huh?
Um... Excuse me?
Is anybody here?
Reception Booth
Excuse me?
Anyone at all?
Um...
I don’t have an appointment, but...
...would it still be okay?
In use
Sorry for barging in like this.
Middle school second-year, class D.
Kazami Tatsuya.
Now then, please begin.
Well, I’ve heard the rumors.
How you can come here for a consultation
when you have problems.
There’s this girl I’ve thought about
for a long time.
She was my princess,
and mine alone.
But...
She left me...
...to see another man.
I’m sure she’s being tricked.
She’s such innocent girl, and...
I’m sure he’ll do all sorts of
horrible things to her, like... or... or even...
But it doesn’t matter...
No matter how much she’s tarnished,
she’ll come back to me...
Because of my love for her!
Yes...
Because love always wins
in the end!
I would make you happy.
I would sacrifice anything
for your sake.
I would... I would...
Why can’t it be me?!
You really are a good person,
aren’t you?
Therefore,
there is no path for you to take here.
Go home.
This is no place
for someone like you.
I’m home.
Welcome home.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
I don’t get it.
How come Wakaba’s been
in such a good mood lately?
Something special must have
happened to her.
I don’t get it.
How come Wakaba’s been running
home as soon as class ends lately?
Something fun must be
waiting at home for her.
Hmm...
There’s so much I don’t understand!
But I do know this:
Wakaba is my dear friend.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Wakaba Can Flourish
“Wakaba Can Flourish”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.