isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
C’mere, c’mere!
Look! So cool!
What is it?
Look!
It’s Captain Juri and Mickey!
Awesome for sure!
Right?
Just too cool!
Well, what do you expect?
They both fence
at national level.
Wow!
That figures!
Hey, hey, by the way...
We saw it! So cool!
Amazing!
You finally defeated me.
You’ve improved.
No, I still have
a long way to go.
A long way to perfection.
Well, your strength
lies in that imperfection.
The power of purity.
Your sword always carries
the force of your sincerity.
Today, it seemed
stronger than ever.
Could it be owed to the girl
whose test you were correcting?
Wh—?
Wh-What are you
talking about?
But... I don’t think your sword
is meant for fighting.
The Sunlit Garden - Finale
Here you are.
Thank you.
This is just like that garden...
Darn it, Chu-Chu! Wait up!
Oops. Seems I got in the way
of something.
That’s... That’s the timbre
I’ve been seeking.
This?
This is the song she played
last night, isn’t it?
Yes.
“The Sunlit Garden”.
My sister and I wrote it
when we were little.
You wrote it?
But it’s a famous song, right?
As far back as I can remember,
me and my twin sister...
...would play with the piano,
as if it were our toy.
In that garden...
Our playing would astound
the adults in our community.
Wow...
So you were both
child prodigies.
I now realize that all my happiness
rested in that garden.
But then...
But then?
But then I ruined everything.
I ruined everything
with my own two hands.
A concert?
Yup! Next Thursday!
Everyone will be
coming to see us!
But, I...
Performing in front of
all those strangers...
All those strangers
scare me.
It’ll be okay!
Everything will be okay.
I’ll be with you.
I’ll be by your side the entire time,
and we’ll play, just like we always have!
There’s nothing to be afraid of!
He has measles.
Well, he should be fine
after a week of bed rest.
Come, sweetie.
Time to go to the concert hall.
Everyone’s waiting!
Your brother wants you
to do your best, okay?
Big Bro! Big Bro!
She just up
and ran off the stage.
She was hiding somewhere
until sunset.
For a while after being found,
she wouldn’t so much as say a word.
After that,
she stopped playing the piano.
Only after that did I realize
how much I loved her playing.
And how much
I loved that garden...
No matter how much
my technique improved,
I could never capture
the timbre of her playing.
Even though that very timbre
is the sole reason I continue to play...
But as for her...
She can bring it out
in her performance.
Is this what they mean
when they say love is blind?
I’ve finally found
that radiant thing!
Is this a confession?
How about it, Himemiya?
Hmm?
How do you feel
about younger guys?
I am your bride,
Utena-sama.
Look, Himemiya, I’ve told you
I don’t want you going around saying that.
But the fact of the matter is
I’m engaged to you, Utena-sama.
Listen here!
It’s not like I agreed to
you being my bride!
Not to mention, it’s insane to
make you someone’s bride because of a duel!
I won’t accept a system that
deprives someone of their freedom!
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
Why are we convening today?
We haven’t received yet another letter
from The End of the World, have we?
True, normally we meet to discuss
and act upon the contents of those letters.
But today, an urgent motion
has been proposed.
The urgent motion is as follows:
I propose the dissolution of the Student Council.
This is sudden.
The notion of winning
Himemiya-san by duel is insane!
I strongly believe such a thing
should never be accepted!
No matter how great
this power we’re supposed to attain is,
we can’t abide a system that
deprives Himemiya Anthy of her freedom!
Love certainly changes a person.
I see.
So it was her test
you were correcting...
Sometimes, youth can blind you
to your true desires.
After all, aren’t our activities trampling upon
an unalienable human right?
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world.
Oh!
That wasn’t very friendly.
Get out of my way.
You dropped your
sheet music.
So, are we giving it
another try?
I don’t expect anything
of someone like you.
As if you had the will to play.
What are you even doing here?
Nothing special.
I’m free to come here if I feel like it.
The music room isn’t just
for playing the piano.
Good morning.
How are you?
Morning. Just fine.
Good morning, Kaoru Miki-kun.
Your sister is as cute as you.
And just as earnest.
Good morning.
You have to seize and protect the things
most precious to you with your own hands.
People are not above stealing, Mickey.
Even if the Student Council
dissolves now,
the Rose Bride
will still be pursued.
Only the one to whom the Bride
is engaged may command her.
Command her...
Tell me, when did you
start learning to play the piano?
I’m not sure.
I was pretty young
so I no longer remember clearly.
I see...
You must have been as cute as an angel
when you were little.
My sister’s playing
was so wonderful...
I refuse to lose it this time!
I swear it!
Do you like playing?
Yes.
Would you play for me again?
If Utena-sama permits me.
How about tomorrow?
Must you get her permission
for everything?
Yes, since I am the Rose Bride.
So if she told you to
quit the piano, would you?
Of course.
I must obey the wishes
of my betrothed.
Only the one to whom the Bride
is engaged may command her.
You have to seize and protect the things
most precious to you with your own hands.
People are not above stealing, Mickey.
The Rose Bride
will still be pursued.
Don’t worry!
I’ll protect the timbre
of your playing!
Thank you, thank you.
So, when’s your make-up test?
Next week.
Well, I’ll manage
thanks to my overpowered tutor.
Oh? Who’s been tutoring you?
It’s Mickey, it’s Mickey!
It’s really him!
Why’s he here? What does he want?
Oh, isn’t he adorable?
Oh, he stopped.
Hey! If you’re looking for Himemiya,
I’d bet she’s in the greenhouse.
No, my business today
is with you, Tenjou-senpai.
I can do it now.
Linear expressions,
simultaneous equations, all that stuff.
Wait, you mean your tutor is...
Yep.
I’ll be waiting for you in the arena
today after school.
I’ll be waiting for you.
Behold! The vast ocean!
Today, I once again sail upon the seven seas
with a hundred lackeys in tow!
I am a pirate!
All the world’s riches
are now in these hands!
Cap’n, Cap’n,
won’tcha tell me, Cap’n?
Why’s whatcha really be covetin’
missin’ from yer plunder?
What I really covet?
I feel that’s why ye can’t quit
the piratin’ life, eh?
What I truly covet...
Whatcha really be covetin’, Cap’n...
What I truly covet is—
Uh, Cap’n,
we’ve sprung a leak.
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyakumawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
zettai unmei mokushiyami
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
In the end, it still
came down to this, Mickey.
I have to recapture that music at all costs.
And so, I need the Bride
no matter what!
Sitting at a piano
suits you better.
I quite agree.
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
I will make the Rose Bride mine.
Even if it means hurting you!
gekijou
Theater
tokubetsu seishin
Exceptional minds
shuugou genshou
Collective phenomenon
Do you like playing?
Yes.
gekijou
Theater
I’ll make you mine
no matter the cost!
tokubetsu jinbutsu
Exceptional people
kuusou genjitsu
Illusion, reality
shujutsudai nanpasen
An operating table, a wrecked ship
junsui yuugeki supira mirabirisu
A genuine play, the spira mirabilis
uzumaki rasen
Whirlpools, spirals
henka shitsuzukeru supira mirabirisu
Forever changing, the spira mirabilis
He’s good!
sukipio no yume
The Dream of Scipio...
Not bad. If nothing else,
I can see how she could beat Saionji-san twice.
gekijou
Theater
gensou seishin
Illusory minds
fushi no undou
Perpetual motion
gekijou
Theater
You’re good.
gensou jinbutsu
Illusory people
Gee, thanks.
But I’ll be the one
to have the Bride’s playing.
fushi no kozou
Perpetual structure
Like this?
anmongai renkinjutsu
Ammonite shell, alchemy
shinsei kouchuu supira mirabirisu
Scarab, the spira mirabilis
I must obey the wishes
of my betrothed.
futatabi ikiru tameni shinu supira mirabirisu
Ever dying, just to live again, the spira mirabilis
I can see it in her eyes.
kyoui no uzumaki
The wondrous whirlpool
She really wants to be set free!
I’ll protect you...
maimai maimai
Snail, snail...
I’ll protect your beautiful timbre,
Himemiya!
maimai maimai
Snail, snail...
En garde!
owarinaki gekijou
Never-ending theater
kikagaku butai
On the geometric stage
I won’t lose!
She believes in me!
seimei shi no shinpi
of the mystery of life and death
That’s it, Utena-sama!
Get him!
sariyuku issai
Exeunt, all!
shi saisei shi saisei shi saisei shi
Death, rebirth, death, rebirth, death, rebirth, death
I hope you’re satisfied now.
Why can’t I find someone
to be my radiant thing?
No one...
Thank you for everything.
Teach me again next time?
Did you really play
back in the day?
Even I can do
better than that.
Well, I never had the talent.
Not even the interest.
Then why’d you play?
When I was really young, a boy who lived
next door used to write me love letters.
They’d always say something like,
“I love your playing.”
He had the wrong idea
thinking I was good at the piano.
Since I always played
with my brother,
people often mistakenly thought
that I was as good as him.
Since he’s a genius, he could make up
for my playing no matter how bad it was.
But one time when we had
a concert coming up,
he got sick
and everything fell apart.
Everyone found out
I couldn’t do any of it by myself.
Your brother’s really cool, huh?
I guess.
But what happened next—?
Tenjou-senpai.
Mickey...
I let my guard down
yesterday.
But I won’t lose next time!
Come on...
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Recently, someone’s apparently
been trying to kill Nanami!
Oh, my goodness!
Don’t just go all
“Oh, my goodness!” here.
They say animals were involved,
so you’re being suspected.
But, Utena-sama, Nanami-san seems to
enjoy playing with the wild horse.
She’s not playing!
She’s running away!
Oh, my goodness!
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Look Out, Nanami-sama!”
Look Out, Nanami-sama!
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.