Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
H-Huh?
What’s this?
What’s the matter, Nanami?
Uh... N-Nothing!
Was I dreaming?
An egg...
Did... Did I...?
N-No... That’s not...
No!
Nanami’s Egg
Let’s see...
Looks like today’s third period phys ed class
got replaced with girls-only health ed.
As for today’s lunch,
what would you like to have?
The same old at
the cafeteria seemed boring,
so I was thinking maybe
a sandwich in the courtyard...
Stay calm.
Stay calm, Nanami.
You’ve never heard anything
about people laying eggs.
That’s right!
This must be someone’s
scheme to ruin me!
Goodness!
Nanami laid an egg?
I can’t believe it!
You can say that again!
She’s like an alien or something!
No!
What’s wrong, Madam Nanami?
O-Oh, uh... It’s nothing.
My bad, Nanami!
I didn’t think
it’d fly this far!
Oh, good morning,
Ms. Tenjou.
Morning.
Hey! Be more careful!
You could’ve broken it!
Broken it! Ugh!
That was such a close call!
Sheesh!
“Broken it”? Broken what?
Hey, what could’ve broken?
N-No way. Could she...?
My egg... My egg!
What’s this?
How come you’re carrying
that egg around, Nanami?
Oh no, Madam Nanami...
How could you carry around an egg like that?
You didn’t lay it, did you?
Oh no, Madam Nanami!
You really laid an egg!
That’s gotta mean you’re an alien!
Oh no, Madam Nanami!
That means you’re an alien!
No!
Is she sick or something?
No, but she’s been
like this all morning.
Madam Nanami,
are you really okay?
You’ve been acting odd today.
Hmm... Doesn’t feel like
she has a fever.
Oh! Her temperature’s going up!
Shut up!
A stupid she-he like you
couldn’t possibly understand!
Wait, Madam Nanami!
“She-he”...?
It certainly is a strange egg.
It doesn’t seem to be
from a bird or a reptile.
Not only that... It’s a still-steaming,
freshly laid egg from today.
Still-steaming, freshly laid?
Where did you get this egg?
W-Well...
What?! You laid this egg?!
No way...
It’s impossible...
A human can’t possibly—
Of course!
You must be an alien!
Of course! Of course!
Stop it!
I can’t tell him...
Not even Mickey can know...
Not this...
What’s wrong?
Hey, Mickey...
What if, just hypothetically...
What if the egg
was laid by a girl?
A girl?
Yes, a girl.
Hmm...
Interesting thing to suggest.
There are, after all,
mammals that lay eggs.
Huh?! There are?
Yeah.
Still, I’ve never heard of
a human girl laying eggs.
Huh?
Nanami?
I had no idea...
There are other people who lay eggs!
How marvelous!
Oh? Nanami.
What’re you doing here?
You look kinda pale.
Oh, don’t even get me started!
I woke up this morning and—
Wait...
What if I’m the only one
who didn’t know about this until now?
Y-You see, I...
...laid an egg this morning.
Huh?! Your first egg?!
You’re kidding!
It took you this long?!
I didn’t think you’d be
such a late bloomer!
A late bloomer, rain or shine!
Nanami the sunshine doll!
Nanami the alien!
My God!
Even if they come for me,
I won’t let them take me again.
Nanami?
D-Don’t mind me!
Everything’s just fine!
I won’t have it!
I simply won’t have it!
To think I was the only one
who didn’t know...
Watch out!
You could’ve broken my egg!
Great... I just had to
bump into Juri of all people!
Ugh... I just know
she’s going to belittle me.
All because I haven’t
laid any eggs until now...
Nanami.
Be careful!
You almost scratched my ball!
tama: ball, tamago: egg
Ball...?
Yes, this ball.
My ball.
Ball...
Ball.
I-It’s so big...
Want to hold it?
I-It’s so heavy!
Why is it like this?
Do they all get this big?!
I used to have smaller ones,
but that’s the size I get now.
U-Used to...?
When I was seven.
Th-That long ago?
I’ve got lots more of them at home.
L-Lots more?!
It’s just something fun to do.
Fun?!
You should try it sometime.
See ya.
Juri is so mature!
Strike.
Little egg, little egg,
my dear little egg.
Hurry now, hurry and grow big.
I had nothing to worry about.
Everyone is laying eggs these days.
Hurry and grow big for me.
For your mommy.
Hello to you, little babe,
and to your smile
and to your cries
What little hands you have
What round eyes you have
How very nice to meet you
I'm your mommy
Little egg, little egg,
my dear little egg.
Hurry now, hurry and grow big.
Madam Nanami?
Little egg, littl—
Madam Nanami!
Hmm? What is it?
Are you okay?
Of course I am!
I’m taking such good care of it!
Huh?
Madam Nanami, please tell me
if something is troubling you.
I’d do anything for you!
Oh, really? Anything?
Ah, I see!
So if I said to run at
300 kilometers an hour, you’d do it?
If I said to fly at Mach 5,
you’d do it?
If I said to dive 10,000 meters
underwater, you’d do it?!
Um, well... That would...
You can’t do it! You can’t do it!
You can’t do any of it!
Don’t say you’ll do anything
when you can’t!
Madam... Nanami...
Something’s wrong with Nanami?
Yes. How do I put it...?
Lately, it feels like
she’s been really irritable...
And she’s kind of pale...
I’m worried about her.
Maybe she’s got maternity blues.
It sounds as if she laid an egg.
Huh? An egg?
My pet Nanami gets like that
after she lays eggs, too.
No way.
Yeah!
No one wants to be compared
to a chicken, Nanami included.
Really?
Still, I wonder who the father is.
Seriously?
Little egg, little egg,
my dear little egg.
Hurry now, hurry and grow big!
Little egg, little egg,
my dear little egg.
Hurry now, hurry and grow big!
Nanami.
Big Brother!
You’re in very good spirits
this morning.
It’s because I’m doing everything I can.
For the sake of our bright,
shining future.
For our future?
Big Brother...
Boys or girls?
Which do you prefer?
Is it not obvious?
Girls, of course.
Oh, good! So do I.
You... prefer girls?
Yes.
Listen, Nanami...
God created men and women...
...because they form
the best possible combination.
No matter how psychologically fulfilled
you may feel, going against God’s design is—
What are you talking about,
Big Brother?!
You’re the only one for me!
But you just said you prefer girls.
That’s not what I meant!
Then what...?
Well...
What would you think
of a girl who lays eggs?
Nanami.
Do you know why we have
been able to share a happy life?
Huh?
It’s because you are not
the type of girl who lays eggs.
I truly pity the family of a girl
who would betray them so.
Stir, stir, stir, stir, stir...
How cruel, Big Brother!
You didn’t have to
say it like that!
Stir, stir, stir, stir, stir...
Juri and Keiko
and the others lay eggs,
so why shouldn’t I?!
Stir, stir, stir, stir, stir...
Wait a minute.
What are Keiko and the others
doing with the eggs they lay?!
They wouldn’t...!
Stir, stir, stir, stir, stir!
Slurp, slurp, slurp, slurp!
Burp!
No!
Now, everyone...
Things are only impossible
when you think they’re impossible.
Take this egg, for instance.
An egg can’t possibly
stand upright, you say?
However! If we prop it up with
disposable chopsticks like so...
U-Uh...
‘Scuse me!
Wouldn’t it be faster
to just crack the bottom?
No! That’s not the right answer!
If we prop it up with
disposable chopsticks like so...
Looks like that wasn’t an egg.
I’m so sorry.
I just don’t have the courage
to eat my own egg.
I hope you can be happy here.
It’s been quite some time
since we last ate together!
I’m just so delighted!
Nanami.
Do you know why we have
been able to share enjoyable moments?
Huh?
It’s because you are not
the type of girl who lays eggs.
O-Of course, Big Brother.
Naturally!
You did the right thing, Nanami.
You did the right thing.
I just can’t do it.
I just can’t!
It’s gone!
No... Wh-Where did it go?!
What’s that smell?
Wh-What have you done?!
What? The moon looks lovely tonight,
so I decided to camp out.
How could you?!
What are you doing?!
How could you eat an egg?!
It’s an egg! An egg!
Eggs are normally
a thing people eat.
You monster!
You monster! You monster! You monster!
You monster! You monster!
You monster!
Hey! Cut it out!
Give me back my egg...
Give it back!
There are limits to gluttony.
If you want to have some eggs,
you should just ask.
I have plenty here.
Thank goodness!
You’re safe!
Let me warn you...
Being acquainted with someone
who’d throw a fit over one egg...
...would be painfully embarrassing.
I don’t want you ever doing—
Just as boorish as her brother.
It burned!
Little egg, little egg,
my dear little egg!
Hurry now, hurry and grow big!
When you’re in love,
Please forgive me!
I’ll never let you go again!
time comes to a halt
Master Utena,
do you believe in reincarnation?
Hmm... I dunno.
Near the end of their lifespans,
elephants part from the herd
to die in solitude, or so they say.
To a world without time...
Maybe they don’t want to
make their children sad,
so they face death alone
without even telling anyone.
...the two of us shall go
From parent to child...
Souls being passed on eternally.
I see...
I guess passing your soul down to your offspring
could be considered reincarnation of a sort.
The night does not pass, nor do the stars fade
Why’d you bring this up?
Only our love song shall resound
The two of us love each other...
What?!
DANGER!!
Is this...?
Is this... my egg?
...and so our clocks come to a halt
I’m sorry!
I swear, I’ll never abandon you again!
I won’t ever abandon you again!
My... egg...
A dream...?
No!
Come to think of it,
I haven’t seen him lately.
He should be back soon.
If you say so.
Yeah?
Oh, Chu-Chu! Welcome back!
Prehistory, perfection
Solitude in the desert
Air, atoms
Celestial body of causality
Yes, a child of the earth is conceived
An embryo of philosophy
And...
Sphere of the Moon,
Sphere of Mercury, Sphere of Venus,
Sphere of the Sun, Sphere of Mars,
Sphere of Jupiter, Sphere of Saturn,
Sphere of Fixed Stars,
Sphere of Primum Mobile
Further beyond...
...the infinite, endless circle
A type of organic mechanism
A type of perpetual motion machine
Ah, motion from nothing
It is motion...
...from nothing
Nothing
Next Episode
Tsuchiya Ruka... He’s even more skilled
with the sword than Arisugawa.
A legend’s returned
to the Fencing Club...
You sound worried, Master Utena.
Just getting kind of a bad feeling.
Getting close to Shiori,
toying around with Arisugawa...
He is no ordinary person.
So it turned out
he was a Duelist, too?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Whispering in the Dark
“Whispering in the Dark”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.