isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
Good morning!
Um... This morning
your classes are as usual.
Music class at third period
will be on music appreciation.
The topic is Orff’s Carmina Burana.
The report you’ll hand in
is already written.
Before you go to the music room,
just check your locker.
At sixth period, English,
you have a vocabulary test.
Here is your cheat sheet.
Okay.
I’ll tell you about
your after-school plans at lunch.
After that—
Tsuwabuki...
Yes?
Thank you.
Not a problem!
Runaway horse!
A horse is on the loose!
Look out!
I am Tsuwabuki Mitsuru.
An elementary schooler
devoted to Nanami-san.
And I have a secret
that absolutely no one must know.
The Secret Nanami-sama Diary
Tsuwabuki-kun got hurt?
Yes...
While protecting me...
Did he die?
Of course not!
The only wounds seem to be a bruise
and a broken nail, but he’s still unconscious.
Right now, I’m having
a hospital room arranged for him.
Oh? What is this?
A schedule book?
Oh, that’s Tsuwabuki’s.
So he’s got addresses
and stuff in there?
Some of the writing
resembles diary entries.
What? Read it.
“I am Tsuwabuki Mitsuru.”
“An elementary schooler
devoted to Nanami-san.”
For a long time,
I have had eyes for Nanami-san.
Nanami-san
and no one else.
It’s all your fault!
You snared our Saionji-san
and ruined him!
He won’t come to Kendo Club!
Creepy bitch.
Give us back our Saionji-san!
C’mon, say something!
What’s going on here?
Nanami-sama!
Pray tell,
what is this commotion?
It appears I might have to report this
to the Student Council.
Um, well...
I-It’s not what it seems!
E-Excuse us!
Are you okay?
Yes, thank you.
You’re Nanami-san, correct?
You tend to make others jealous,
what with being so popular with the boys.
Nanami-san inspires awe.
With purity, nobility,
and great beauty...
...she protects the weak and detests all evil,
all to uphold justice in the academy.
But I know...
...about Nanami-san’s
authentic, true face.
Nanami’s true face?
Why are you
looking at me like that?
Looks like he knows all about you;
the good and the bad.
“The bad”?
What ever do you mean?
She’s wearing the dress we sent,
isn’t she, Nanami-sama?
It suits her so well.
Oh... Oh, my!
My apologies, miss!
Oh... No, I...
Without ever
getting her own hands dirty...
Merely watching stoically
from the sidelines as her target suffers...
Truly, the way she acts befits
the one ruling the academy from the shadows.
Oh yeah,
I remember when that happened.
Then, that was your doing,
Nanami-san?
Th-That’s clearly all
some delusion of his!
I can’t even imagine
doing something so outlandish!
He sure is a weird kid, huh?
Her malice wouldn’t stop there.
Indeed,
like that other time...
Nanami-sama, class 2-A is having
cooking lessons, right on schedule.
So it appears...
And what we discussed earlier?
Yes. I made the switch.
Hundredfold Curry, an Indian specialty
hot enough to make you breathe fire.
Excellent.
Tenjou Utena and Himemiya Anthy...
Just you wait!
I’ll soon have you
begging for mercy.
Curry!
It’s ready!
Nanami-sama!
Be quiet.
We’re just getting to the good part.
I’m sorry, it’s just...
What?
We didn’t switch in
the Hundredfold Curry after all.
It seems we gave them
the Agonizing Blow Your Brains Out...
...Trippy Roaring Elephant Super Spicy
Nine Hundred Billionfold Curry.
“Trippy”?
“Blow Your Brains Out”?
No way...
Tenjou-san and Himemiya-san...
Indeed, Nanami-sama’s curry powder
caused them to switch personalities.
Wonderful jump,
Utena-sama!
It feels weird
to see me praising myself.
I’m not very good at sports,
so seeing myself being so athletic
really spices things up for me.
Still, we gotta find some way
to get back to normal.
Don’t worry.
Even at this very moment,
I’m sure Nanami-san is...
Indeed, Nanami-san
put her best foot forward...
...to atone for her sin
without losing her cheerful smile.
Nanami-sama!
An elephant?!
Not again!
Nanami-sama!
A present for you.
And then, a more resolute
Nanami-san returned!
Nanami!
Brother!
Is there any more?!
That was their last batch!
They said it will take two hundred years
to refine more Nine Hundred Billionfold spice mix!
Two hundred years?!
Curry...
I was certain
it was just deserts.
Curry!
Now that you mention it,
that did happen.
You’re really freakin’ evil,
aren’t you?
What are you
talking about?!
It wasn’t my curry powder
that switched your personalities!
It was all because of
your cooking skills, wasn’t it?!
Was it?
You...!
Wonder what other crimes
he wrote about.
Wait a minute!
Forget that, is there anything
about Tsuwabuki in there?
Everything he wrote
seems to be about you.
Nanami-san seized every opportunity
she got to wrong Himemiya-san.
Indeed,
like that other time...
Wow!
They say this dorm is like a haunted house,
but it’s actually quite nice inside.
Such a lovely room.
Yeah. That’s thanks to
Himemiya’s daily cleaning.
So you enjoy keeping things neat,
Himemiya-san?
Wow! I’m really impressed!
Humph! Just you watch. Your days of thinking
Himemiya Anthy is cute are soon to be over.
I envy you, Tenjou-senpai...
getting to live with such a feminine girl.
Is that sarcasm?
Himemiya-senpai?
May I borrow an eraser?
A snail!
A garter snake!
There’s a live octopus in there!
Himemiya Anthy’s
true colors exposed!
That’s what’s going to happen!
But Nanami-san
has it tough, too.
Sometimes, the one trying to hurt another
ends up getting more hurt themselves.
Himemiya-senpai?
May I borrow an eraser?
Himemiya Anthy...
Prepare yourself!
No!
It’s dangerous to just go
and open that closet up.
This can’t be real!
This has to be a nightmare!
This massive live octopus...
And its octopus tentacles...
Hmm...
You really are evil, huh?
Evil? Me?
Gah! You’ve gotta be
kidding me!
That time,
I was the victim, wasn’t I?!
“And so, Nanami-san has treated
Himemiya-san as her enemy, but...”
No!
ya
No-No-No-No-No way!
I don’t treat you like you’re my enemy!
ya-ya-ya-ya-ya nee
After all this,
even if you play dumb...
“...there is a reason for that. A profound reason,
which I must never speak of to anyone...”
“Reason”?
Stop it already!
And give that back!
It’s not yours!
If you keep pulling, it’s going to tear.
You animal!
Fiend! Thug!
Look who’s talking!
Shh!
What is it?
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
That soft teeth grinding...
Like a rope bridge
swaying in the wind...
No... It’s the creak
of a swing set by the sea...
The man who was once ruler
of the Student Council, Touga-senpai...
Guess who?
Quit it, Nanami.
Isn’t it such a lovely night,
my dear brother?
How did I get
such an adoring little sister?
Touga-senpai is
Nanami-san’s entire world.
You two...!
“Touga-senpai is the one and only who can
live up to Nanami-san’s standards.”
Though I’m still inexperienced,
someday I want to be
a big brother like Touga-senpai!
We should stop.
Huh?
This isn’t right.
You can sense
the weight of his feelings in this.
And here we are
just peeking at it.
You’ve read almost everything
and only now think about his feelings?
What about the weight of
my feelings?
About 49 kilos?
Wh— It went up?!
Oh, my.
What is this page, I wonder?
“First Strategy...”
Did you say “strategy”?
Where am I?
Who am I?
It’s no use...
I can’t remember anything.
Nanami?
Who’s there?
Have you forgotten?
It’s me, your older brother!
My brother?!
Come to me, Nanami!
Big Brother!
H-Hold it!
What is this?!
Beats me.
“Second Strategy...”
No! Wait!
Tsuwabuki!
P-Please don’t read any more!
How dare you ask that?!
I’m gonna expose all your evil plans!
They’re not evil plans!
All I wanted was to become
a man worthy of you, Nanami-san!
You horrible little...!
Calm down, Nanami!
If you get too worked up,
you’ll turn into a cow again!
“Second Strategy...”
“The next time Nanami-san
becomes a cow,”
“I think I can handle it
like this:”
Nanami!
Ditch the cowbell!
Ditch it!
Man-ure so annoying.
Do you know what that bell
around your neck is?
Bull-ease...
It’s a Sebastian Dior cowbell, moo!
A cowbell, as in a bell that
a cow wears around its neck!
What’re myoo talking about?
Take a good, long
look around you!
Hmm?
Y-You mean to say Sebastian Dior,
purveyor to royalty, actually...?!
It’s not Sebastian Dior...
It’s Calfstian Dior!
C-Calfstian...?
You don’t even know
what a cowbell is,
and yet you’ve been
parading around and showing it off.
And now you’re practically a cow.
A cow?!
Can’t do anything about that now.
What you can do is take that thing off
before you become a cow in body and soul!
Wh-What are myoo saying?
How could it be possi-bull
for a human to turn into a cow?
Stop trying to make me cower in fear!
You’re full of bull!
Utena-sama!
It’s finally finished!
What is it?
It’s a sweater!
Thanks, but it’s a little
out of season, isn’t it?
Moo... Just a little moooore time
and I would’ve been irresista-bull.
I’m mooooving in and out
of cow-nsciousness...
What are these horri-bull visions?
What does the appendix doooo?
Holy cow, hoof I been
poisoned by a snake?
Someone bring me
a comforta-bull blanket!
Nanami?
Nanami, you’ve...!
aru hareta hirusagari
Late one sunny day,
How horrifying!
ichiba he tsudzuku michi
on the road to the marketplace,
N-Nanami-san!
nibasha ga gotogoto
a wagon rattles along,
She’s charging at us!
Oh! I get it!
Seeing the red sweater
riled her up!
koushi wo nosete yuku
carrying a calf within
Oh, my!
Himemiya, run for it!
Right!
kawaii ni koushi urarete yuku yo
The adorable calf is to be sold
kanashisou na hitomi de mite iru yo
It looks on with mournful eyes
It’s all okay now.
It’s all okay now,
Nanami-san...
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
Even if you become a cow,
I’ll always take care of you.
Dona, dona, dona, do...
I’ll stay right here with you,
Nanami-san.
Dona, dona, dona, dona...
Dona, dona, dona, do...
Stop it!
Please, stop!
Don’t be such a sore loser,
Tsuwabuki!
Don’t look!
Where am I?
Ah, you’re conscious.
How do you feel?
What were you writing?
You fell behind, yes?
On your schedule.
I’ve been adjusting it.
Really? How is it looking?
I want to see.
I’ll fill you in later.
No need to worry.
I’m helping myself to that!
Oh, no!
So, you do have
nasty things written here, hmm?
Restrain him!
ya
St-St-St-St-St-Stop!
ya-ya-ya-ya-ya-yamero
Let me go! Let me go!
What’s this here?
“Twenty-fourth Strategy...”
No! I’m done for!
If she reads that page,
I’m done for!
Extra! Extra!
Oh, I’m utterly done for!
Why?
I have a secret I can’t keep hidden anymore,
and it’s that the king has donkey ears!
“Donkey”, you say?
Sorry, not donkey.
The truth is...
I am...
...a monkey hiding behind
a girl’s face!
Oh, how shameful!
Now she’ll never be married!
Ooh-ooh-aah!
Aah-ooh-ooh!
Monkey captured!
Curry...
Curry!
Ooh-aah!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Starting today, we’ll be living
with my brother.
This is our new room.
Akio-san really brings with him
an air of nostalgia, doesn’t he?
Hey, Himemiya...
If you’re ever going through something
and you need help, come to me first.
Let’s always help each other out.
I want us to have
that kind of friendship.
Utena-sama...
In truth, I...
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Their Eternal Apocalypse
“Their Eternal Apocalypse”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.