isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
Are you okay?
Hello?
Are you all right?!
Weird girl...
Don’t know why I bothered worrying.
Look Out, Nanami-sama!
Someone is after your life?
This isn’t the first time.
A flowerpot nearly fell on me,
then a pile of logs...
I think someone even
tried to push me down a staircase!
What terrible luck...
Help me, Big Brother!
This just has to be the work of someone who’s
jealous of how cute, popular, and refined I am!
I’m so frightened...
And here I was worried...
Don’t you think you’ve been reading
too many mystery novels, Nanami?
No, that’s not...!
Sorry, but I have
Student Council business to deal with.
Excuse me.
Brother!
Gosh, my brother is so cruel.
Sibling relationships are complex...
What’s that supposed to mean?
Do you not have any ideas?
Have you done anything
to anyone worthy of a grudge?
How rude!
That’s right,
Nanami-sama knows what she’s doing!
She never gets her own hands dirty.
I see.
Don’t listen to them!
Sorry.
It’s no big deal for you,
but someone may be gunning for my life
at this very moment!
Nanami-sama!
Sorry about that!
Didn’t think it’d go that far!
Okay, so, where’s the ball?
Any of you seen the ball?
So it was you...
Dropping that flowerpot, rolling those logs,
trying to push me down those stairs...
That was your doing,
wasn’t it?!
What’re you ranting about?
This is so infuriating!
Are you really
gonna keep playing dumb?!
Nanami-sama, calm down!
We don’t know
for sure that it’s her!
Look, whatever.
Just gimme the ball back.
It couldn’t possibly be me.
For starters,
I don’t have a motive to kill you.
If you’re sure.
I happen to know
you’re trying to seduce my brother.
He’s the one
making passes at me!
My, how self-conscious!
Hmm? There’s someone
in the greenhouse.
Huh?
But there’s a
“keep out” sign on the door.
KEEP
OUT
Big Brother...
Why haven’t you done the deed?
Such refuse has no right to live.
But I can’t do it.
Do you have cold feet?
It’s far too late
to have a change of heart.
I want the killing done at once!
Did you hear that?
Yeah. Something about killing...
Now, do it.
Snuffing out such a puny life
will not get you in trouble.
That’s not right.
No matter how much everyone
despises you, a life is still a life.
Maybe the problem will resolve itself
if we simply bide our time.
You’re being too optimistic.
This... This can’t be!
The one trying to murder me
is my own brother?
Did he put up the “keep out” sign
so they could have a secret meeting?
Once this is done,
no one will stand in our way.
At long last,
we will be together.
Now, then...
Here we go.
Yes, Touga-sama!
Nanami?
You’re so cruel,
Big Brother!
I’ve sensed disaffection
from you lately,
but do you really see me
as such a big nuisance?
What is this about?
You’re such a meanie!
Nanami-kun!
I’m disappointed in you!
Even if you’re Student Council President,
you can’t just kill your own sister!
What are you talking about?
You were going on about,
like, killing someone.
You mean this?
Tick Killer
Wait, so you’re telling me...
How cruel!
It’s far too cruel!
The one trying to take my life turned out to be
none other than my beloved brother!
This is such a betrayal...
I might as well just drop dead!
Runaway horse!
A horse is on the loose!
Milady...
Are you hurt, milady?
Wh-Who are...?
What?! A prince showed up?
Yes. I was told that he rescued her
from a dangerous incident.
So awesome!
That’s the kind of thing I aspire to!
Good morning!
Tsuwabuki Mitsuru
And so, the values we get
from the measured lengths or weights...
Tsuwabuki Mitsuru
Tsuwabuki Mitsuru...
...or from rounding pi
are called approximations.
But the prince’s identity
is a mystery.
A mystery?
Oh, no... You’re bleeding.
Perchance, may I take a look?
Finished.
This should do it.
Thank you so much!
U-Um... Would you at least
tell me your name?
I do not deserve the honor
of relaying my name.
I hope to meet with you
again someday.
Goodbye, milady.
He left without even saying his name?
That’s so freaking cool!
<---Elementary School
<---Registrar’s Office
Dining Hall--->
Middle School--->
<-
->
In any case, I wouldn’t have guessed
there was a prince in this school...
...who could curry favor
with Nanami-kun.
She does seem to have
super high standards.
Is that her prince?
So she likes older men...
Doesn’t seem he’s it.
She has quite an odd taste!
That’s a no, then.
Tsuwabuki Mitsuru-kun?
Yes?
That little kid saved her life?
Here you go.
Thank you.
Tsuwabuki-kun, please...
Be my boyfriend!
Huh?
Huh?!
We’re camping!
We’re camping! We’re camping!
We’re having so much fun!
The best part of camping
is making curry and rice over an open fire!
Chow time!
The rice is pretty hard
and undercooked!
The bottom’s all burnt, too.
Also, the curry is way too runny
and doesn’t have enough powder.
Do you really like this?
You know what they say;
fresh air is the best seasoning!
All done!
It’s rather good.
I was talking about Nanami,
not the cafeteria food!
Dating an elementary schooler...
There’s no way she’s serious.
The target of her affections
will always be Touga-senpai.
The Council Prez?
Was that tasteless?
It’s got plenty of taste!
No, I don’t mean
the cafeteria food.
They’re siblings, right?
Nanami and Prez?
She has a brother worship thing going on.
Touga-senpai is the only man
she will accept.
Having the best guy
in the world by her side...
...makes everyone else
look like dregs.
Dregs?
Dregs. Leftovers.
Parsley.
But it seems this incident
was a real shock to her.
She said she was betrayed
by her only brother.
She’s got quite the imagination.
Tenjou-senpai, look!
Th-They’re actually going out.
They look more like siblings
than a couple.
Is she serious about this?
Hey, apparently we have tennis
for phys ed today.
Huh? I didn’t bring
my tennis wear!
Tsuwabuki.
Your tennis wear, madam.
Pop quizzes are so unfair.
You’ve said it.
It’s like they have no rules.
Tsuwabuki.
The solutions manual, madam.
So, apparently art is gonna be
outdoor sketching today.
Huh? I didn’t bring my easel!
Tsuwabuki.
Put some meatballs
in tomorrow’s lunch, would you?
Gladly, madam.
Can he even be called
a boyfriend?
I have no idea.
No matter how much
she may abuse him,
he is simply happy
to be near his beloved.
That is one form of love.
Love can manifest
in many different forms.
I would classify the love
between Anthy and I as a furtive love.
Exchange Diary
Furtive love...
No one asked.
Hey, Suzuki-kun asked me
to give you this.
Hey, Yamada-kun wants you
to read this.
Hey, Tanaka-kun said...
Oh, throw those away, please.
I am Suzuki!
I am Yamada!
I am Tanaka!
What is the meaning of this,
Nanami-kun?
You turn us all down
and then go out with a child?
Are you trying to make fools of us
middle school guys?
You people are... who?
We write you love letters
every day!
Do you mean to say...
...you don’t remember us?
Tsuwabuki.
There you are!
It’s inconceivable for a young child
like you to date Nanami-kun!
Why don’t we settle this
once and for all?
I made a vow...
For as long as I date Nanami-san,
I will protect her!
Tsuwabuki,
take care of them.
My pleasure, madam!
My, the weather
is just perfect today.
So blue...
What a beautifully blue sky!
Well done, Tsuwabuki.
Yes... I protected you,
Nanami-san... Right?
Now I see
your true colors, Nanami.
Tenjou Utena?
He desperately fought
to protect you,
and you just sat back
and watched!
This isn’t a relationship!
You’re just using him
as your bodyguard!
I was almost murdered!
By my brother!
Who I’ve dearly loved all my life!
How could you possibly understand?
Nanami-kun, you’re mistaken—
That’s right, I am Miss Taken!
I’m dating Tsuwabuki.
So I’m free to treat him
however I like!
Wouldn’t that make him
more of an underling than a boyfriend?
It’s okay.
This is what I wanted.
Tsuwabuki-kun, why...?
Why are you so in love with her?
It was a fateful encounter.
Fateful?
Nanami-san
doesn’t seem to remember,
but we met a long time ago.
Runaway bull!
A bull’s gotten loose!
Watch out!
Are you all right, Nanami?
Big Brother!
Come on, let’s go home.
C-Cool!
Since then, I’ve trained to become
a heroic big brother like that gentleman.
And at long last,
the stage was set!
You wanted to be her big brother,
not boyfriend?
But Nanami-san
didn’t remember me...
...even though I staged everything
in a way that should’ve brought that day to mind.
Staged?
Now I have no other choice.
I’ll have to
put her in danger again.
W-Wait a minute!
Yes?
You weren’t the one behind the flowerpot,
logs, and stairs incidents, were you?
I was. So I could save her
in the nick of time.
That’s how a big brother
is supposed to act.
Of course, I can’t let
Nanami-san find out.
So it was all a hoax
laid out by a little kid.
I heard everything.
Don’t be mad at him!
It’s just something
a kid would do!
Right! Nothing but youthful indiscretion.
He was at a loss!
I don’t want to hear
some lame excuse!
Because of you...
Because of you,
I called my big brother a meanie!
Runaway kangaroo!
A kangaroo’s going
on a rampage!
Tsuwabuki!
Tsuwabuki-kun!
H-Have to protect...
I have to protect
Nanami-san...
Eat this!
Tenjou-senpai!
Don’t attack anyone else!
Tsuwabuki-kun!
Come on!
I am your opponent!
I’m going to be
Nanami-san’s big brother!
I will be her big brother!
Nanami-san?
Run, stupid!
But...
My brother is my brother,
and you’re you!
I won’t cry for you
if you die doing something like this.
Why? Because, Tsuwabuki...
...you’re my valued servant.
I can’t just let you break here.
Big Brother! You’re here!
Your pranks are getting
out of hand, Nanami.
Utena-sama!
We’ve finished exterminating
the pests in the rose garden!
The reason they closed the greenhouse
and mentioned killing...
...was because of
a bug infestation.
Beloved brother of mine...
Tsuwabuki.
Yes?
Let’s break up.
Sure!
Now that we’ve broken up,
I want to be adopted into your family.
If I can’t be your big brother,
maybe I can be your little brother.
You really are the only man for me,
Big Brother!
Kiryuu Touga...
Like I thought, he’s no ordinary guy.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Those who’ve see her hidden face
won’t come within ten meters of her.
Who are you talking about?
Arisugawa Juri,
a member of the Student Council.
What?! She wants me
to throw away my Rose Seal?!
I can’t! It’s my only connection
to someone I cherish!
Arisugawa-senpai,
why do you want to duel me?
Do you believe in miracles?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Juri’s Impossible Dream
“Juri’s Impossible Dream”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.