isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
In the end, it still
came down to this, Mickey.
Yes. I have to recapture that music.
And so, I need the Bride
no matter what!
Sitting at a piano
suits you better.
I quite agree.
I will make the Rose Bride mine.
Even if it means hurting you!
You play the piano
so wonderfully, Miki.
You’re the pride of the academy.
Your performance at the party really made
all of the flower arrangements shine.
But why did you decline
entering the competition?
The teachers were so disappointed.
This piano seems to be
slightly off key.
Really? It was tuned
just last week.
Then maybe I’m the one
in need of tuning.
You always play this piece
when you’re alone, right?
To tell the truth,
I only play because of this song.
I keep playing in hopes
a certain someone will hear this music.
“A certain someone”?
But I can’t play it
quite the way I’d like.
No matter what,
I can’t get the sound I seek.
Far from it!
Sounds just fine to me!
It broadcasts your feelings
loud and clear!
You can’t play this piece, not unless you
possess eternal beauty within yourself.
And what’s the song’s name?
“The Sunlit Garden”.
The Sunlit Garden - Prelude
Aw, crap...
This is the worst grade I’ve ever gotten!
Hmm... That’s a shame.
Honestly, I think I know all the math I’ll ever need
with just the basic multiplication tables.
Pretty sure it’s to cultivate
our ability to think logically.
But as my mom
always told me:
“A truly fine woman foists all of
the logical thinking onto men.”
Oh, really?
I’m sure you did well
since you’re good at math.
No way!
You’re not usually
this bad at math, right?
I was a little distracted.
That’s no good. Gotta keep
cultivating that logical reasoning.
Hey...
Anyway, I can’t act bubbly
after getting a grade like this.
What a shame.
You do know
how much we love Mickey, right?
We heard all about it! Because of you,
our Mickey said no to entering the competition!
I... I had no idea.
Liar. You had to have said something
that made him lose his confidence!
That’s right.
I never said anything like that!
You there!
What are you doing?!
Seems like you were wrongfully
blamed about something on my account.
I’m truly sorry about this.
Thank you.
It’s nothing...
Hmm?
What?
Who’s that boy with Himemiya?
Oh, that’s Mickey!
“Mickey”?
Don’t you know about him?
He’s Kaoru Miki-kun, a middle school first-year.
Not only is he a pretty boy
who’s nationally ranked at piano and fencing,
he’s also a genius taking college classes
even though he’s only a first-year.
Wow...
Plus, he’s really popular
with older girls.
Mitsuko and her friends
never stop talking about him.
But...
Why’s he with Himemiya Anthy?
Hi.
Juri-senpai.
I thought I’d find you
in the club room or the Council office,
but here you are
studying in the library.
Are you correcting
someone’s test?
Yes, sort of.
Hmm...
That’s a change.
You usually keep your distance.
Say, Juri-senpai...
Happiness can sometimes
be surprisingly near, can’t it?
Hmm?
Anyway, this test
is really something.
Whose is it?
I looked over it.
That teacher always gives
tricky problems like these.
Try to keep that in mind
for next time.
Must be nice,
getting your test corrected.
Guess I need to get myself
a logical boyfriend.
Tenjou-senpai.
I’m Kaoru Miki.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
You know me?
Of course.
You’re the center of our
attention as of late, after all.
“Our”?
Referring to this.
You’re one of them?
You’re in the Student Council?
Then you must be
after the Rose Bride, too.
No! Please,
don’t get the wrong idea.
I may be a member of the Council,
but I don’t want to duel
to make Himemiya-san my bride.
I mean it!
Here are a few problems
I expect will be on the make-up test.
If you just memorize
the formulas in this notebook,
you should pass
without any trouble.
Thank you.
Not at all...
Well, it looks like
you’re awfully interested in her.
She— Himemiya-san
reminds me of a girl I know.
That’s all there is to it.
I don’t intend on challenging you
to a duel, Tenjou-senpai.
Oh good, you’re not crazy.
Do you guys in the Student Council
know how much of a pain you’ve been to us?!
I don’t even know what’s going on,
but we get roped into those stupid duels,
and now thanks to that,
we’re stuck studying for a make-up test.
“We”?
You’re retaking the test, too?
Um... Well... Yes.
It’s sounding very nice today.
You’re not beating the piece into submission.
Without that usual forcefulness...
...it sounds more graceful,
somehow.
Could you have found that radiant thing
you talked about once?
Yes. I might just have.
I may finally be able to recapture
something I lost long ago.
I envy you.
If you do regain
that radiant thing...
...be sure to tell me
what it is.
What is this
“radiant thing”?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
In elementary school, my first boyfriend
was the best at math in the whole class.
Oh? That’s news to me.
You had a boyfriend
back then already?
But... When he found out
about my love of pro wrestling...
...and super-sized bowls
of garlic ramen, well...
“Now I know what kind of girl
you truly are...”
...he said, and that was that!
O Lover!
O Youth of Dreaming Love...
Of your girlfriend’s identity...
...have you heard the truth?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the truth?
Coming!
Sorry I’m late.
Hey, we’ve been
waiting for you. Come in.
Well, actually...
Would you mind if I join?
Oh, you must be...
I’m Nanami!
Miki-kun’s girlfriend?
A-Absolutely not!
Well, come on in.
Himemiya’s waiting inside.
Thank you for having us.
Thank you for hosting us!
Wow!
They say this dorm is like a haunted house,
but it’s actually quite nice inside.
Such a lovely room.
Yeah. That’s thanks to
Himemiya’s daily cleaning.
You enjoy keeping things neat,
then, Himemiya-san?
Wow! I’m really impressed!
Humph! Just you watch. Your days of thinking
Himemiya Anthy is cute are soon to be over.
I envy you, Tenjou-senpai...
getting to live with such a feminine girl.
Is that sarcasm?
Himemiya-senpai?
May I borrow an eraser?
A snail!
There’s a snail in there!
She has a snail
in her pencil case!
Himemiya!
I’ve misjudged you!
I’m so disillusioned!
This is the end for you,
Himemiya Anthy!
That’s what’s going to happen!
I call it “Operation: Oh, My Gosh! Himemiya Anthy
Is a Weirdo Who Keeps a Snail in Her Pencil Case!”
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
Then let’s begin with
monomial expressions.
Don’t worry.
If you memorize the process,
it’s like solving a puzzle.
Himemiya-senpai?
May I borrow an eraser?
Himemiya Anthy...
Prepare yourself!
S-S-S-S-S-S-S-S-Snails!
There’s s-snails in here!
Oh, that’s my snail friends’ home.
I always tell her
not to keep them there.
But it’s so cute!
It’s very much like
Himemiya-san to do that.
They’re s-snails!
What’s cute about s-snails?!
I’ll see you later,
Catherine, Juliet, Marcelina.
I see the issue, Tenjou-senpai.
Here’s where you
made a mistake.
Oh, where?
In this case...
Well, then,
you leave me no choice.
My, what a pretty desk!
I wish I had one like it!
A garter snake!
There’s a garter snake in there!
She has a garter snake
in her desk!
Himemiya!
I’ve misjudged you!
I’m so disillusioned!
At last! This is the end for you,
Himemiya Anthy!
That’s what’s going to happen!
I call it “Operation: Oh, My Gosh! Himemiya Anthy
Is a Weirdo Who Has a Garter Snake in Her Desk.”
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
For triangle ACP, line BX
is parallel to line CP, so...
My, what a pretty desk!
I wish I had one like it!
My garter snake...
The snake I spent all night catching...
Oh, that’s Mr. Mongoose’s home.
I said not to keep him there.
But it’s so cute!
It’s very much like
Himemiya-san to do that.
It’s a mongoose!
A mongoose!
Don’t you think that’s weird?!
We’re studying now,
so I’ll have to see you later, okay?
Did Mr. Snake taste yummy?
How nice!
Hmm... So what do I do here?
Ah, you do this.
Oh...
Okay...
If that’s how it is...
I didn’t want to do this,
but you leave me no choice!
A live octopus!
There’s a live octopus in there!
She keeps a live octopus
in her closet!
Himemiya!
I’ve misjudged you!
I’m so disillusioned!
This really is the end for you,
Himemiya Anthy!
That’s what’s guaranteed to happen!
I call it “Operation: Himemiya Anthy Is a Total
Weirdo Who Keeps a Live Octopus in Her Closet!”
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
This time for sure,
with this live octopus...
...I’ll have you begging for mercy!
Himemiya Anthy...
You’ll be crying for mercy...
...because of this real,
living octopus!
Now!
Live octopus! Live octopus!
Live octopus! Live octopus! Live octopus!
It’s dangerous to just go
and open that closet up.
This can’t be real!
This has to be a nightmare!
This massive live octopus...
And its octopus tentacles...
Isn’t that the inflatable they used
for last year’s school festival?
I felt so sorry about it
getting thrown away that I hid it here.
Won’t you please talk her into
getting rid of it?
But it’s so cute!
It’s very much like
Himemiya-san to do that.
So, now x equals three.
And if you substitute it here,
you can solve this linear equation.
Oh, now I see!
Three plus y is...
Um...
And so... Got it!
How’s this look?
Correct.
Now I see!
You don’t disappoint, Mr. Genius!
That was way easier than class.
Oh, hardly.
Let’s take this seriously.
The test is next week.
Yes, Utena-sama.
Wow, it’s already this late?
Hey, Miki-kun!
Yes?
Wanna get a bite to eat?
And you, Nanami-kun?
Nanami-kun?
Um... Oh, yes. Supper.
Actually, I packed
a little something for us.
I hope you all enjoy it.
Another animal...
I suppose this is another one of
Himemiya-senpai’s friends, huh?
Chu-Chu! You can’t just...!
These animals...
I’m sorry! I’ll go make
something to eat!
Lemon and strawberry
taste nice together!
Oh, really?
She’s right! This is delicious!
This is my special recipe.
You don’t say!
I should write it down.
Can I get a little more
syrup on mine?
Nanami-san, you should have some
before it melts.
You’ve got to be kidding...
You should be more polite
to an upperclassman.
Snails in her pencil case...
A mongoose in her desk...
A giant octopus balloon
in her closet...
And to top it all off,
shaved ice for supper?
I’ll get a stomach ache!
I have a very delicate stomach!
I, for one, like shaved ice.
Don’t blame her
for your weak stomach.
This isn’t about the ice
or my stomach!
Why are you two
so interested in her?
Didn’t you say you wanted to be
Himemiya-san’s friend?
What’s that you say?
You’re the one
who likes her, Miki!
Confess!
Well...
Huh? Himemiya’s gone!
You’re right!
Maybe I shouldn’t have pushed her
to be in a study group.
Maybe takoyaki would have been
a better choice...
I’m gonna go look for her.
I’ll come with.
A piano...
That’s the song you always play.
Wow. I didn’t know
she could play the piano.
She plays with the same
timbre as my sister...
That sunlit garden...
I’ve found it...
My radiant thing!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Himemiya! You have to
play the piano for Mickey!
He seems really fixated
on your playing.
If you insist, Utena-sama.
No, don’t do it because I say so.
Do it for Mickey’s sake.
I am the Rose Bride.
I will do whatever
my fiancé requests.
Wake up, Mickey! This isn’t the way
to get Himemiya to play for you!
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“The Sunlit Garden - Finale”
The Sunlit Garden - Finale
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.