Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
I... lost...
Despite your princely
grandstanding,
at the end of the day,
you’re just a girl.
Whatever you may have hoped for...
...remains an unfulfilled fantasy.
Well, I think this presents a good chance for you to
return to being a normal girl, wouldn’t you agree?
Have a wonderful day,
Tenjou.
Tenjou?
Tenjou Utena?
Tenjou!
Tenjou Utena!
Looks like
she’s absent today.
Perhaps for Friendship’s Sake
Tenjou Utena
Utena?
It’s open.
Hey, hey,
why were you absent today?
Got a cold?
Lemme see!
Hmm... No fever.
No swollen tonsils.
Normal pulse.
My diagnosis:
you’re playing hooky.
Oh yeah,
where’s Himemiya?
Well...
Did you fight or something?
Kind of...
So, ‘fess up.
What’s wrong?
Nothing.
If it’s nothing,
why’d you skip?
Utena?
What’s this?!
How awful!
Oh, it just got caught
on something.
Want me to fix it for you?
Yeah...
Actually, don’t worry about it.
I have another uniform.
Hey, look!
Isn’t that Tenjou?
That look really suits her!
I like this look better!
Popular, aren’t we?
Yeah...
Looks like you’ve
taken to the uniform, too.
Yeah... It’s normal.
I’m just gonna wear this
from now on.
Huh?
Good morning.
Mornin’!
Morning, Himemiya.
Good morning, Tenjou.
Huh? Um...
I have to be normal...
Normal...
I knew it!
You did fight!
Who cares
what she thinks anyway?
Don’t sweat it!
Being a worrywart doesn’t suit you at all.
Hey! Utena, wait up!
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
As you can see,
the Rose Bride and I are engaged.
Any questions?
None.
How did you win?
“With skill and grace”...
...is what
I had hoped you’d think.
I’m just curious
about the details.
I rescued this lonely princess here
as the noble prince I am. That’s all.
Prince, huh?
A play is hardly a play if the prince and
princess don’t get together in the final act.
Bold of you to presume
that was the final act.
Indeed.
Um...
If we are a bother,
we can wait outside.
There is no need
for you to wait outside.
I want you here.
Very well.
I want you by my side
at all times,
seeing as
you are my bride.
If you don’t wanna say anything,
you don’t have to say anything,
but you know
you’re being weird, right?
It’s weird for you
to just ignore that!
You’re not acting like yourself!
You’re really
starting to make me mad!
If you think
I’ll just drop it—
Excuse me.
I heard the rumors, but this transformation
really is quite something.
That uniform
looks splendid on you.
Say, would you let me
take you out to dinner this Sunday?
Without the Bride.
H-Hold it!
Sound good?
C’mon, Utena!
Tell him to get lost!
Why won’t you
give me an answer?
Keep your hands off her...
Keep your hands off
my beloved Utena!
Hey, you!
If you don’t like it, tell him!
I-I’m sorry...
But it’s your fault, too...
...just standing there
and spacing out.
She’s like this because of
your fight or whatever, right?!
That’s right!
It’s your faul—
Would you look at that?
So you can act for yourself!
Your friend is quite perky.
Let’s talk alone next time.
Himemiya!
Here...
Thank you very much,
Tenjou.
Look... Stay out of
my business, okay?
No way!
I’m not stopping!
You...
You don’t get it at all...
I do get it!
I... I’m not giving up!
Ah, I see.
What are you saying?
Not at all!
I’m always thinking about you.
I’ve heard that story.
No, I hadn’t heard that.
Yes. Yes.
Well... I’m not particularly busy
at the moment.
I’m not lying! Got it.
Nothing for it.
I’ll be there immediately.
I’m sorry, Anthy.
Wait here for a moment.
Very well.
Wakaba... Um...
Hold it right there!
Don’t think you can just say sorry
and that’ll be that!
It was the Prez,
wasn’t it?
Right? It’s his fault
you’re not your usual self.
It’s the Prez’s fault, right?
I see that.
To be honest,
I don’t really get it.
Like, why are you even
wearing that uniform?
But... This is normal,
isn’t it?
No, it’s not normal!
I mean, not being normal
is normal for you,
so this kind of normal
isn’t your Normal!
Oh, this is so complicated!
My Normal...
This kind of normal...
You’re shutting down again, aren’t you?!
This Utena’s so uncool!
It’s like you had
something stolen!
I don’t know what it was, but if someone
took something from you, go take it back!
Take it back!
Your Normal
is way cooler!
And... And...
That uniform’s
just not right for you!
I’m sorry, Wakaba.
It had to have hurt...
...when I slapped you
at the table.
My bad.
I get it.
It’s just like you said.
This really isn’t
my Normal, is it?
I’m gonna go
take back my Normal.
You finally decided
to come talk to me alone.
So, would you like to
go out for dinner on Sunday?
Now.
Don’t want to wait?
Dueling arena forest, now!
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Go to a normal school,
find a normal job,
have a normal romance,
enter a normal marriage,
raise a normal family...
That kind of normal’s
got nothing to do with us!
We’ve done plenty,
and we’ve grown weary.
So, then,
it’s time to return to our Normal.
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Use this.
An indispensable prop
for any final act.
Why have you decided
to challenge me?
I decided there’s something
more important than you.
I see.
So you’ve
come to your senses?
But I don’t think
I will lose to you.
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
I think you understand
this is no ordinary sword,
but did you know
it can be used like this?
Rose Bride!
Cast off your body
and protect the sword!
Yes.
Himemiya...
What do you think?
Is it not beautiful?
This is the power of
the Rose Bride of Dios!
Can you win
against this power?
I will!
I’ll win no matter what!
Really?
Go ahead and try!
She can’t possibly
defeat Master Touga.
Poor thing.
I hope it’s over soon.
No human has any words to speak
Do you see the power
this sword possesses?
This is the power hidden
within the Rose Bride!
You posed as her prince
without even knowing.
No thing has any words to speak, either
Only within the unchangeable darkness known as yesterday
And you still
don’t understand.
So what?
Only within the ungraspable glint known as now
There’s something off
about Tenjou.
She could die.
Why is she fighting this duel?
Only within the still unilluminated darkness known as tomorrow
Maybe I don’t know anything
about Himemiya,
but I wanna get
my Normal back!
within the play...
Pitiful.
A human can become whoever
It’s over for you, Tenjou.
A thing can become whatever, too
But...
I’ve seen this before...
I know I have...
Only within the unchangeable darkness known as memory
This is... This...
I remember!
It’s like what happened back then...
Only within the ungraspable glint known as creation
Only within the still unilluminated darkness known as tomorrow
Wh-What...?!
within the play...
O actors, wearing the masks of time,
dance in the play of the ancient continent
O you, passengers of the galactic railway,
dance for the three of seven wonders you yearn for
Like a star, like a firefly
And with this...
I take back my Normal.
Born with a glimmer, vanish with a glimmer
We, too, are born only to vanish
Born with a glimmer, now vanish with a glimmer
Be born only to vanish, o soul of mine
Born with a glimmer, it vanished with a glimmer
Himemiya...
Born and vanished, o star of mine
I’ve been waiting for you,
Master Utena.
I am the Rose Bride.
The first star, o star of mine
From this day forward, I...
Everything’s okay now,
Himemiya.
Hey, let’s go home.
Glimmer and then vanish, o firefly star
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
If I may, Master Utena...
I’d like to note that we have
been engaged for quite a while now.
How many times do I have to say
we’re not “engaged”, or whatever?
The fact remains you have crossed swords
in duel seven times over our engagement.
Seven times, huh?
Friendship, choice, reason, love,
adoration, conviction, and self.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Tracing a Path”
Tracing a Path
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.