isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
You’re flying down the road.
Exquisite vibrations, no?
Care to take the wheel?
Huh? But I’m still not...
Well, aren’t you stiff?
That was rather inappropriate,
Board Chairman.
My Ohtori Academy values
the independence of its students,
Student Council President.
Their Eternal Apocalypse
Yes?
Um... I’m friends with
Tenjou Utena, and...
Ah, yes.
Just a moment.
Come in.
Th-Th-Thank you.
Hmm?
Welcome!
Oh, Wakaba!
Ta-dah!
I came over to help!
Thanks!
Ooh, cool!
It’s way nicer than
the room you had in the haunted house.
Just a little too big, though.
It’s beautiful no matter what you say.
You should be going
“Jackpot!”, y’know.
Yeah, I guess.
It is a nice room.
I don’t mean the room!
So wonderful...
What is?
The Board Chairman, duh!
That smile...
Is that what they mean by
an angelic smile?
Living under the same roof
as a guy like that,
a lovey-wovey-dovey
romance in the air!
I’m jealous.
Look, Wakaba...
Akio-san’s already got a fiancée.
He does?!
Yep.
Why is it that every hot guy
in the whole world’s already taken?
There, there...
What’s taken?
Won’t you have some tea?
Okay!
Since we have no other family,
I naturally wanted
my little sister near.
Still, she finally made a friend
and I hated the thought of separating them,
so I imposed on Utena-san
and asked her to move in as well.
Such an affectionate brother!
Oh, I-I’m a good friend
of Anthy-san’s, too!
I hope you continue
being there for her.
Yeah!
Oh, here you go, Himemiya-san!
More tea?
Thank you.
Hey, now...
What is it?
Is there a problem?
Not really, nope.
What?!
I’m just being my usual self!
Where were you until
you were admitted back, Saionji?
That’s not important.
In any case,
I’m through with dueling.
Lead, lead, lead!
Meaning what?
Meaning that what these letters say
is not to be trusted.
Strike!
Being tricked
by that fake letter...
...seems to have
taught you a lesson.
I already verified
the contents of the letter.
All right, all right!
Indeed... When I passed
through the Rose Gate...
Strike!
...at the center of the stairway
to the dueling arena...
Strike!
...a gondola appeared.
Strike! Batter out!
What do you mean,
“a gondola”?
Allegedly, it will advance us
to a new stage.
Whether the contents of the letter
are true or false doesn’t matter.
I don’t believe I signed up for being
End of the World’s lackey.
You’re out! Game set!
I will not fight
because of someone’s orders.
Kyouichi!
Don’t try to stop me.
Ugh! It’s not like I want this, either.
And that aside...
Who exactly is
The End of the World?
It’s that star.
It looks more vivid than usual today.
Uh... Which one is it?
Look. Right there.
Hmm?
Is this better?
Look at where
my hand is pointing.
That star up there
shining particularly bright is Venus.
Oh...
The Morning Star.
ake no myoujou
My name, Akio, comes from
this star’s name.
Wow...
Kind of romantic...
The Morning Star
is also known as...
...Lucifer.
Lucifer?
The star that was once an angel,
yet chose to become the Prince of Darkness.
Looking up at it from our planet,
it is always near the Sun.
Unless the Sun sets,
it can never shine.
What must it think
as it shines?
Himemiya!
Dinner looks to be just about ready,
Utena-sama.
R-Really?
I’m starving!
Well, Akio-san,
if you’ll excuse me...
Akio-san is really nice,
isn’t he?
Yes.
Though...
Though?
Whenever he talks
about the stars,
there’s a lonely look
in his eyes.
Like he’s someone who’s lost
something precious.
Still, something about him
gives me this nostalgic feeling.
There are times you give me
a nostalgic feeling yourself, Utena-sama.
Me?
Yes.
It’s rare for you to say
something like that.
Pardon me.
No, no...
It makes me happy.
Hey...
If you’re ever going through something
and you need help, come to me first.
Let’s always help each other out.
I want us to have
that kind of friendship.
I understand.
From now on, I’ll live with you
so that we can help each other.
Utena-sama...
In truth, I...
What is it?
Never mind.
Scrubbing the floor
at this hour?
Still as conscientious as ever.
You’ll be the champion
of the local tournament again this year.
That right there is
one of the reasons I hate you.
That conceit of yours.
Oh?
You’re right.
I am going to be
the champion again this year.
But you think of that as
meaningless child’s play,
and in your heart
you laugh at me.
That’s not the case.
Yet in the end, the truly strong win out.
That’s how the world works.
Even if you’re proud
of your petty tricks,
don’t forget that you lost
to Tenjou Utena.
As did you.
Moreover, I hear a certain someone said
he’s now through with the duels.
However...
I have not yet given up.
There is someone
I want you to meet.
“Someone”?
You haven’t really given up,
have you?
There it is.
Can you not hear it?
Hear what?
So long as your soul
has not truly given up...
...you should be able to
hear the sound...
...that races across
the end of the world!
What nonsense are you spewing?
What...?
What is that?!
Now, join us!
Let us go forth
to the world you desire!
He’s the one who’s engaged
to Ohtori’s daughter...
The Board Chairman...
Yes.
He is also Himemiya Anthy’s
older brother.
Do you want the Rose Bride?
What do you mean?
Exactly what I said.
What do you want?
What do you aspire to?
What do you wish to be?
What’s the point of asking
things like that?
I don’t trust you to begin with.
My, my. I thought you were
my one and only friend.
There is no such thing as friendship
in this world.
Is that what you think?
It’s what I know.
I wonder...
I wonder if you truly believe that.
Where are you going with this?
Well, why do you strive for
that castle said to hold eternity?
Do you believe you will find
something eternal if you get to enter?
Such as, for instance,
eternal friendship?
Do you remember the girl who was
in that coffin all that time ago?
Something like that
might have happened.
There was a girl who said
she wanted to see something eternal, yes?
I don’t know.
I barely remember it.
That night...
...the one who saved that girl
from the coffin was Akio-san here.
What?
Akio-san showed the girl
something eternal and saved her.
He what?
Who the hell are you?!
Exquisite vibrations, no?
What are you talking about?!
I will now show
the end of the world...
...to you, as well.
You can’t be...
How would I know?
I don’t get letters from The End of the World.
As I thought,
you don’t know.
So, what were you saying about
the stairway to the dueling arena?
You know how the stairway
spirals around the central pillar?
Yeah.
There’s some sort of gondola
inside the pillar.
A gondola?
Correct.
That gondola is a pair of wings
flying toward the end of the world.
It will carry me and the Rose Bride
to the castle that is said to hold eternity.
Saionji!
Are you not through with dueling?
Unfortunately, I’m not
the same person I was yesterday.
How are you any different?
Can’t you see?
No.
I have no idea
what you’re talking about.
I see. You don’t get it.
Not that you would get it
even if I explained it.
What are you scheming?
Mickey!
Are you okay?
The Rose Bride belongs to me!
Let Himemiya go, Saionji!
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
There’ll be another duel today
in the forest behind the school!
It’s been so long
since I last heard those words!
Naturally,
it’s better with two...
...rather than one.
Half the suffering...
...and double the joy!
Hey! Wait just a minute!
You used my shampoo last night
without asking me!
And you finished
the pudding I was having!
Though it was two weeks old.
Seriously?
Well now, O Brave Hero...
It’s hard to work as a pair.
I wonder, have you heard of that?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Ugh. It’s coming!
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyakumawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
zettai unmei mokushiyami
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
You need to learn
when to quit, senpai.
If you really love Himemiya,
try putting yourself in her shoes!
I have.
Long ago, I did think about
the Rose Bride’s feelings.
That’s what made me so heated.
But now I understand...
The Rose Bride
has no will of her own!
Guess you’re not gonna get it
unless I knock you down a peg.
Himemiya! The sword!
I’m no longer the same
as when I lost to you!
And that is because...
...I saw it!
“Saw it”?
That’s right!
What did you see?!
The world.
It vanished!
The Sword of Dios has vanished!
taiko kanzen
Prehistory, perfection
sabaku ni kodoku
Solitude in the desert
Hey...
If you’re ever going through something
and you need help, come to me first.
kuuki genshi
Air, atoms
ingaritsuboshi
Celestial body of causality
Let’s always help each other out.
I want us to have
that kind of friendship.
sou tochi no ko jutai
Yes, a child of the earth is conceived
I want us to have that...
tetsugaku no taiji
An embryo of philosophy
Utena-sama...!
I have you now!
What?
Himemiya...
tamago kanzen
An egg, perfection
Utena-sama, together!
ireko ni kigen
Origin in that which is nested
Huh?
oshibe meshibe
Stamen, pistil
hitotsubu no shushi
A single seed
sou tochi no ko seichou
Yes, a child of the earth grows
O Rose of Noble Emotion...
I beg of you, manifest...
tetsugaku no kodomo
A child of philosophy
soshite tsuki ten
And... Heaven of the Moon,
What?!
suisei ten kinsei ten
Heaven of Mercury, Heaven of Venus,
taiyou ten kasei ten
Heaven of the Sun, Heaven of Mars,
mokusei ten dosei ten
Heaven of Jupiter, Heaven of Saturn,
The power to revolutionize the world!
kousei ten gendou ten
Heaven of Fixed Stars, Heaven of Primum Mobile
saranaru
Further beyond...
enkan mugen ni hatenaki
...the infinite, endless circle
hitotsu no yuuki teki na kikan
A type of organic mechanism
hitotsu no eikyuu undou souchi
A type of perpetual motion machine
aa kuudou nari
Ah, motion from nothing
so wa kuudou
It is motion...
nari
...from nothing
Nothing
That Saionji... and after I went
to such lengths to be friendly with him.
Are you enjoying this game?
Of course.
Then there is no problem,
is there?
Play nice with your friend.
You are quite the evil man.
The Sword of Dios
did not take form.
did not take form...
...and yet she won the duel.
Oh, what a sight it was...
Come to me, Anthy.
Get over here.
What’s keeping you,
Himemiya?
taiko kanzen
Prehistory, perfection
sabaku ni kodoku
Solitude in the desert
kuuki genshi
Air, atoms
ingaritsuboshi
Celestial body of causality
sou tochi no ko jutai
Yes, a child of the earth is conceived
tetsugaku no taiji
An embryo of philosophy
soshite
And...
tsuki ten
Heaven of the Moon,
suisei ten kinsei ten
Heaven of Mercury, Heaven of Venus,
taiyou ten kasei ten
Heaven of the Sun, Heaven of Mars,
mokusei ten dosei ten
Heaven of Jupiter, Heaven of Saturn,
kousei ten
Heaven of Fixed Stars,
gendou ten
Heaven of Primum Mobile
saranaru
Further beyond...
enkan mugen ni hatenaki
...the infinite, endless circle
hitotsu no yuuki teki na kikan
A type of organic mechanism
hitotsu no eikyuu undou souchi
A type of perpetual motion machine
aa kuudou nari
Ah, motion from nothing
so wa kuudou
It is motion...
nari
...from nothing
Nothing
Next Episode
Kozue-chan fell off the second floor
of a school building!
Oh, my goodness!
Though thankfully she’s okay.
Don’t do anything like that again.
You’ll worry your brother, y’know?
They truly are very close siblings.
Mickey! I thought
we were friends now!
You want to duel me again?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Miki’s Birdhouse
(The Sunlit Garden - Arranged)”
Miki’s Birdhouse
(The Sunlit Garden - Arranged)
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.