isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
I heard there’s gonna be a duel
at the Kendo dojo!
Are Touga-senpai
and Saionji-senpai at it again?
A duel?
Touga-sama!
Look over here!
You’re so awesome and cool!
Get him, Saionji-senpai!
Senpai, I love you!
Fight! Fight!
Touga-sama!
Get him! Get him!
Saionji!
Stab him now, Touga-sama!
What are you even saying?!
Beat him at his own game, Saionji-senpai!
Shh! They’re starting!
Hmm, he’s not bad.
Guess he’s not just a playboy.
Looks like Prez won this one.
Saionji-senpai!
kend0
Club
Touga-senpai,
you’re the best!
kend0
Club
That’s my prince!
Prince?
So cool!
Oh, my!
There’s no need to look at me
with such hostility...
...my dear friend.
I’m not your friend.
How heartless.
I thought you were
my one and only friend.
Enough!
I will not accept defeat
from the likes of you!
The Castle Said to Hold Eternity
You’re such a pain in the ass,
always being around Anthy!
Look who’s talking!
Stubbornness
is not a good look, senpai.
So it’s you,
Tenjou Utena.
Don’t get carried away.
I will defeat you
in our next duel...
...and take Anthy back.
You stupid...
Shut up!
You really sure
you can beat me?
I thought you just got your ass
handed to you by Kiryuu Touga.
You were watching?
We’ve sparred hundreds of times
over the past ten years.
He was just lucky today.
Wow...
You’ve known each other
that long?
I will not lose to him!
I will win the Rose Bride.
Do you really love Himemiya?
If you do, why are you
trying to win her in a duel?
I need to win her by duel
so I can triumph over him.
Him?
You mean Touga, right?
Are you doing this
just to compete with him?
Are you using Himemiya
to get at him?
You wouldn’t understand
even if I told you.
With Anthy by my side,
I will attain something eternal.
Eternal?
Correct.
She told me that she, too,
desired eternity.
I knew it was gonna rain!
That’s why I said
to quit at the tenth match!
Can you blame me?
You’re the only one
good enough for sparring practice.
W-Well, I guess...
What’s the matter, Touga?
It’s a funeral...
I wonder who died.
You, there!
You two haven’t seen a girl
about your age anywhere nearby, have you?
What happened?
A girl lost her parents
in an accident today.
We took our eyes off her
for only a second and she was gone.
No, we haven’t seen her.
I see.
Thank you nonetheless.
You don’t suppose
she may have been spirited away, do you?
Don’t be stupid.
Let’s keep looking around here
some more.
So superstitious
even in this day and age...
Touga?
Hey!
Are we allowed
in here?
Hey, wait!
I was right.
There were three coffins.
I saw them through
a crack in the door earlier.
Huh?
What are you doing?
Touga!
Hey, stop it!
Don’t do that!
Stop it!
Don’t open it.
Please, don’t open it.
She was hiding
here of all places?
They’ve all been
looking for you.
Are you telling anyone
I’m in here?
No, I won’t tell anyone.
Hey...
I always side with girls,
‘cause I’m a gentleman.
But why are you hiding
in a place like this?
Because I belong here.
What do you mean?
There’s coffins
next to mine, right?
My father and mother
died today.
And there was an extra coffin.
It had to be meant for me.
Being alive makes me feel sick.
It does?
Yes... Awfully sick...
Why do we keep on living
when we’re all gonna die someday anyway?
Why did I never
notice that before today?
There’s no such thing
as something eternal, is there?
Something eternal?
So don’t bother.
I’ll never leave this coffin.
But someone will find you
at some point!
If that happens,
I’ll find another coffin to hide in.
I’ll stay by myself forever.
All alone in the dark.
Wait! Aren’t you worried she’ll
do something stupid if we let her be?
If you’re worried,
find something eternal and show her.
The next day,
she had left the coffin.
The look in her eyes
somehow made me feel uneasy.
Did you... do something
after we saw her yesterday?
No, nothing at all.
But I was sure of it...
He had to have shown her
something eternal.
Kiryuu Touga...
He’s always ahead of me.
Stepping into a world
beyond me.
Someday, I want to go
to that castle floating in the sky.
Something eternal awaits within.
You’ve also seen
that floating castle.
It holds eternity.
I’ll go there with her.
I won’t lose to Touga!
On that note, Tenjou Utena told me
she met a prince when she was little.
A prince?
Yeah.
She said
she came to this academy...
...to see a prince
she met as a child.
That girl is quite the romantic.
A prince, hmm?
I see.
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
It was undeniably
the princess’s first love.
Not to mention, could the ring the prince gave her
be anything other than an engagement ring?
We’ll meet again, won’t we?
That’s freezing!
What’s your problem?!
You looked awfully lonely
hunched over like that.
Mind your own business!
What could you be
doing up here, hmm?
You know something,
don’t you?
About that castle?
Castle?
The floating castle
you can see in the dueling arena.
I wonder what it actually is.
That castle is where you will
meet your prince someday.
Someone talked too much, huh?
That prince was
a guy like me, was he not?
Stop it!
Stop screwing with me!
Don’t make me laugh.
From The End of the World?
Ooh! A UFO!
Where, where, where?
Where is it?
Oh, that?
That’s just a shooting star.
No way!
It’s a UFO!
It was all wobbly...
and, I mean, it was zig-zagging!
Then it was a zig-zagging
shooting star.
There’s no way UFOs exist!
Oh, no!
It happened when I was
in kindergarten...
What happened?
I found out that Santa Claus
doesn’t exist!
Sheesh...
But it’s all right.
I get it now.
Get what?
That wizards...
...and fairies...
...and princes on white horses...
...and kind-hearted...
...friends...!
All of them
are only found in fantasy.
But it’s all right.
We get it now!
And so I’ll at least
let myself keep believing in UFOs.
This’s pretty tricky, eh?
Whoops...
We broke them.
Hey, Himemiya!
It’s dinnertime!
Chu-Chu!
Where’s your owner?
She’s not back yet?
That’s not like her...
Is that her?
Okay, okay.
Hi. East dorm, second floor.
Himemiya Anthy will be
spirited away tonight.
What?
Go to the dueling arena.
Who is this?
Hey!
Please stop, Saionji-senpai!
You’re hurting me!
I have to return home,
or Utena-sama will be worried!
I don’t care about
your Utena-sama!
I’m keeping
the promise I made you!
Promise?!
Yes...
Tonight, we’ll finally be able
to enter the castle said to hold eternity.
You mustn’t!
No one but my betrothed is allowed to take me
to the arena... Not without a duel declaration!
The End of the World told me
the castle will come down tonight.
I won’t let anyone else have you!
The one to attain eternity
with you...
...will be me!
Ow, ow, ow...!
Geez, what’s with...?
S-Saionji?!
Saionji! Wake up!
Tenjou...
What happened to Himemiya?!
Anthy?
What are you playing at?!
Rules are you can’t take her back
without beating me in a duel, right?!
What the hell
are you doing here?
Someone said to come here or
Himemiya would get spirited away!
Spirited away?!
Spirited away...
Anthy!
Where’s Anthy?!
That’s what I’m asking you!
Look!
Did you open it?
No, wasn’t me.
Impossible!
H-Hey! Wait!
What the...?
That’s...
Don’t open it.
There’s no such thing
as something eternal, is there?
Himemiya...
Anthy!
What?!
What is this?!
Himemiya!
Tenjou!
What’s going on here?
Doesn’t matter...
Gotta save Himemiya!
The castle...
The castle is coming down.
End of the World!
Here I am!
Now, fulfill your promise to me!
Grant me eternity!
Himemiya!
What...?
What is happening?
What the hell was that?
Himemiya! Himemiya!
Himemiya!
Hey! Snap out of it,
No... I was supposed to be the one
to save her from the coffin this time.
The castle said to hold eternity...
The power to revolutionize the world...
All of it will be mine!
The one who will go
to that castle with Anthy is me!
Himemiya! Himemiya!
Himemiya...
Utena-sama...
Thank goodness.
But what exactly happened?
Truthfully,
I’m not quite sure...
Utena-sama!
Touga! Why?
Your prince was...
...a guy like me, was he not?
Why do you always...?
Because I’m a gentleman...
It’s me.
Yes.
The letter Saionji received tonight
was from me.
Right, in your name.
No, it was just
a shallow wound.
Well, let’s just say it was
something of a performance.
Yes, Saionji is facing expulsion.
Nonsense.
Only a fool
believes in friendship.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Touga got hurt
trying to protect me.
It wasn’t your fault,
Utena-sama.
But his little sister
seems to think it is.
Kiryuu Nanami-san, you mean?
I guess I can’t really duck out of
Touga’s birthday party, can I?
Huh?! Nanami-kun’s a Duelist, too?!
I wish you a most
happy birthday, Kiryuu-senpai.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Nanami’s Precious Thing
“Nanami’s Precious Thing”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.