Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Once upon a time...
...there was a young princess grieving
the deaths of her mother and father.
Before the princess appeared a traveling prince
mounted upon a white horse.
His appearance gallant
and his smile gentle,
the prince enveloped the princess
in the scent of roses...
...and gently wiped the tears
from her eyes.
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
“As a token to remember this day,
please take this.”
“We shall meet again,
will we not?”
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
Could the ring the prince gave her
be anything other than an engagement ring?
This was all well and good,
but so impressed was she by him...
...that the princess vowed
to become a prince herself!
But is that really okay?
The Rose Bride
She’s late...
Sheesh... How long is she
gonna make me wait?!
I’m gonna be late
on the first day of term!
Wakaba!
What are you doing over there?
Waiting to see my boyfriend.
Boyfriend?
You got dumped.
Your boyfriend left the dorm
in the morning, ages ago!
Oh, that little...
She’s so gonna pay!
Ohtori
Academy
Ms. Tenjou Utena...
Do you intend to wear
that strange attire for this term as well?
“Strange attire”?
Strange attire.
All the boys here
wear something similar.
Except you’re a girl!
So why are you
wearing a boy’s uniform?!
There’s no rule against
girls wearing boys’ uniforms.
Looks like there’s no problem.
Well, that’s just how it is.
Why, that... Is she going to make
a fool out of me for another term?!
Great. Annihilated again.
Utena! Please use my towel!
Sure, sure. Line up.
How about it, Tenjou?
If you join our basketball team,
winning the regionals
would be a piece of cake!
Excuse me,
I happen to be a girl!
As if I’d want to play basketball
surrounded by sweaty boys.
Oh, come on!
You’re pretty much a guy
anyway, Tenjou!
How about not being rude?
Then why do you wear that uniform?
To be a prince.
Huh?
I want to be a cool prince,
not a princess who needs protecting.
What’s that even mean?
This smell...
The scent of roses...
I wonder... When did the scent of roses
become nostalgic to me?
Hmm? What’s going on?
A lovers’ quarrel?
They should work things out in private!
Whoa, hold on.
He went too far.
Thank goodness.
Utena!
Wakaba! You’re heavy!
This is for ditching me
this morning!
Deal with it!
Yeah, yeah...
Oh, it’s Saionji!
Saionji?
Don’t you know about Saionji?
Oh? He’s famous, huh?
I recognize the guy in front of him.
That’s Kiryuu Touga,
the Student Council President, isn’t it?
Yup! And the guy with him
is the vice president, Saionji Kyouichi!
And the girl?
Oh, that’s Himemiya Anthy.
Himemiya Anthy...
No one asked her to,
but all that weirdo does
is take care of the roses.
She’s in our class starting today.
Hmm...
So, is Saionji going out
with Himemiya or what?
No way!
Someone as cool as Saionji
would never fall for a girl like that!
They’re only together ‘cause
they’re both on the Student Council!
So is he your type, Wakaba?
Oh, wow!
Are you jealous?
Don’t worry!
You’re always gonna be
my true love, Utena!
You’re way cooler
than any of those guys could ever be!
You’ve called me out here on short notice,
my fellow Council members.
Saionji, we who wear the Rose Seal
are all chosen members.
Did you forget that adhering to the Code
is the one and only mandate we must follow?
Saionji, your recent treatment of the Bride
is somewhat problematic—
Oh? Is that so?
True, you are currently
engaged to her.
But that doesn’t mean you’re free
to treat her however you please.
However he pleases...
However he pleases.
Don’t be rough
with the Bride, Saionji.
The Student Council’s existence
is the will of The End of the World.
The End of the World would not take kindly
to learning about this.
Mind your own business.
The Bride and I are just
a happy pair of lovebirds.
We don’t want you
meddling in our affairs.
Lovebirds...
For now, I am...
Master Saionji’s Bride.
I will do whatever
Master Saionji commands.
This is just how we are,
you see?
And if you’re so concerned
about the Code of the Rose Seal...
...then you’re free to follow the Code
and duel with me for the Bride,
my fellow Council members.
Don’t forget that
the next duel will soon—
I look forward to seeing
who will challenge me.
Oh, it’s so pretty!
A rose crest.
So, is that our school’s crest?
Sure looks like it.
Who gave it to you?
A prince on a white horse.
Huh?
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
What?
I think someone
told me that when I got it.
I was so young
I can barely remember it.
Oh, I get what you mean.
When I was little,
I used to believe my mom when she said
I was a princess from the Onion Kingdom.
Well, you’ve always
had a big forehead, I guess.
Hey, come here
and get a load of this!
Hmm? What’s going on?
What’s that?
Someone’s love letter
got put up on the notice board!
Love letter?
Okay, what’ve we got here?
“And so, I dance with you
in my dreams, dear Saionji.”
“You smile at me, gently.”
“I guess I’m a fool...”
Oh, man!
You’re the fools!
This is in bad taste.
Stop it at once!
I see it, I read it.
Isn’t that normal?
A good man wouldn’t read
something like this!
Wakaba...
Wakaba!
You wrote this to Saionji,
didn’t you?
That Saionji guy’s
gonna pay for this!
I don’t know.
I throw away a lot of letters.
Anyone could have found it
and put it up.
Why did you do that
where people could find it?!
I can do whatever I want
with my letters.
Oh, I remember.
That incredibly stupid...
I mean, that delightful letter
was ideal for giving everyone a nice laugh.
Is that all you wanted to say?
No.
You’re captain of the Kendo Club,
aren’t you?
We’re gonna duel today
after school!
Who do you think you are?
I see... You must be
the next challenger.
The what?
Very well! I’ll meet you behind the school
after classes today, in the dueling arena forest.
The forest? You mean
the one nobody’s allowed to enter?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
There’ll be another duel today
in the forest behind the school.
O Brave Hero!
O Brave Hero who fights
for her friend’s sake...
But, be careful,
O Brave Hero.
They follow a Code in the forest.
I wonder, have you heard of it?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard of it?
Oh, great!
How am I supposed to go in?
I knew it.
It’s locked.
That’s cold!
What’s with this entrance?
Well, I guess
I’m good to go in!
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
How can a castle float in mid-air...?
That’s right...
You’ve never seen
the castle before, have you?
What is that thing?
I couldn’t see it
from outside the forest.
A kind of mirage.
Think of it as a trick of the light.
A mirage?
Never mind that.
I’m surprised that someone from outside
the Student Council wears the Rose Seal.
Rose Seal?
One of these.
That ring...!
Anthy! Prepare us!
Himemiya Anthy...
Himemiya,
what are you doing here?
The Bride is, of course, the witness.
Those are the rules.
Bride?
This scent...
It’s the same.
The same rose scent that he had...
The one whose rose is stricken
from their chest loses.
Good luck.
What are you doing?!
How dare you, Anthy?!
You are the Rose Bride!
In other words,
you’re a flower just for me!
What’s the meaning of you
wishing another good luck?
Forgive me, Master Saionji.
Are you an idiot?!
How can you obey someone who treats you like this?!
Master Saionji
is the current champion Duelist.
I have to do
whatever he desires of me.
What do you mean?
You’re not his girlfriend?
Come. Let’s begin.
I don’t know what’s going on,
but I just have to beat him, right?
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
Now what?
Another “trick of the light”?
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
When? Where? Who? Which?
You’re pretty good...
...for a girl!
So, trying to be a prince
who saves damsels in distress?
A bloodstream held by the cage of memory,
Well...
cradled in a thousand years of bliss
Wait a minute...
I am an actor, eternal metaphors
That trick sword...
Is it real?!
I’m shocked.
You challenge the Sword of Dios
with a useless wooden practice sword?
A desert’s wintry Sphinx, Phinx
The Sword of Dios?
You don’t know
about the Sword of Dios?
Who are you?
Now you’ve piqued my interest.
This duel isn’t finished!
Of the flesh that is born and dies,
Quite right. If you wish,
I’ll turn that rose red with but a single strike.
the sad winds tell you
If you have the courage to face me
and stake your life, that is!
A prince on a white horse,
here to save the princess!
The holy actor, eternal metaphors
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
Margineaux of light and dark, fallen down to hell
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
Brightly burn!
What?!
Awaken and sing!
Fool!
Born into the world, born into an instant
An endless cycle!
Impossible!
I... lost...?
Anthy!
Have a wonderful day...
...Saionji.
Well, an unexpected development.
I think she’s in the academy’s
middle school.
Oh, yes, baby...
You’ve lit a fire in my heart.
Man, this has been
one really weird day.
What was all that about?
Better to just forget about it.
You...
I’ve been waiting for you,
Master Utena.
I am the Rose Bride.
From this day forward,
I am your flower.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
What? I need to have a rematch
in the dueling arena tomorrow?
Is it true no one who defies
the Student Council’s rules stays for long?
Are you sure about this,
Master Utena?
You said you weren’t
fighting any more duels.
I’ll just lose on purpose.
There shouldn’t be a problem with that.
Yes...
Do as you please.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“For Whom the Rose Smiles”
For Whom the Rose Smiles
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.