Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Somewhere unknown to us,
new Duelists are making their move against us.
Have we been abandoned?
The End of the World
may be exploring other avenues.
What are you talking about?!
We, the Student Council,
make the rules of this academy!
All we need to do is stop these newcomers
dead in their tracks!
It isn’t that simple.
He’s right.
What is it with you two?
Why are you so gloomy?
Don’t tell me
they got you too, Juri!
Oh, no! Really?
Wh-What was it like?
Did it hurt?
Madam Nanami!
Physical education will be in the gym today
because of the rain.
I think it’ll be basketball,
so I brought your basketball shoes.
Um...
This place is off limits
to anyone who isn’t involved.
Oh, but don’t I happen to be
Student Council President now?
In any case,
you’d better be cautious.
We’re at a disadvantage
as long as our opponents remain hidden.
What’s with those two?!
Madam Nanami!
What were you talking about?
Nothing to do with you.
It’s grown-up talk.
Mitsuru’s Impatience
Wow, it’s really
coming down out there.
Bet the roses wish
it was nice and sunny out.
Indeed.
Roses are sensitive
to seasonal changes.
Nanami and Tsuwabuki?
Tsuwabuki sure is dedicated.
I wouldn’t last three days
living like that.
I’m sure he endures it
because he loves her.
Is that how it is?
Well, I guess I just hope
he gets something out of it.
There’s no way you’re getting
anything outta this!
This is not okay!
Oh, it’s just you, Mari.
You carry her things,
arrange her schedule, run her errands...
You’re not her secretary
or whatever!
You think a girl’s gonna give you attention
just ‘cause you’ve been nice to her?
As if that would be enough.
Then what’s the point?
I’m happy just being able
to be near Madam Nanami.
That’s messed up.
Get yourself a better crush.
Don’t get a big head!
You’re only a year older than me!
Doesn’t matter if it’s just one year.
Older is older!
You’re no different from me!
What did you say?
Your body sure doesn’t look mature.
Stupid!
What’s her problem?
Tsuwabuki?
Who was that?
N-Nobody important!
Nobody at all!
Tsuwabuki, I’m curious...
Don’t you have any friends?
Friends?
It’s just that you always
accompany me to the middle school.
Does it bother you?
That’s not
what I’m trying to say.
For being a kid,
you’re not very childish.
I-I have the most fun
when I’m with you, Madam Nanami...
That girl was kinda cute,
though, huh?
N-No way!
Someone like her?!
Your girlfriend?
Just someone I’ve known a long time,
nothing else!
Ohtori Private Academy
Elementary Student Housing
What’s this for?
You gonna have a party or something?
Don’t touch those!
They’re for Madam Nanami’s
lunch tomorrow!
All this?!
Got a problem?
You don’t get it, huh?
Hey!
You shouldn’t eat something
if it’s not yours!
No matter how hard you work,
she’s gonna have her lunch and eat it, too.
What’s that mean?
Woman’s intuition.
Like a black widow, she surrounds her prey
and takes it in bit by bit, all nasty.
You don’t even understand
how amazing she is.
Oh, I understand her.
It’s a woman’s intuition!
She’s like a black widow.
If I can get her to even just
eat my banana, I’ll be satisfied.
Nasty!
How is that nasty?!
You’ll get it
when you’re an adult!
Hey, take this!
I don’t want it now.
You eat it.
Do adults
even eat chocolate?!
Would this be
an indirect kiss?
Where are we having lunch?
Well, it’s still raining...
Madam Nanami!
I have your favorite today!
Fried chicken with asparagus and bacon!
What is it, Tsuwabuki?
Um... Your lunch...
I won’t need it today.
This is someone
from the Mikage seminar.
Hello.
I’m thrilled to be
invited to the seminar.
I am thrilled.
Sometimes being forceful has its benefits.
If you think someone like me
can help you in any way...
Then why don’t we go get a light lunch
and discuss everything in more detail?
Sure.
If you wish,
you can also stop by the seminar.
No need for that.
Tsuwabuki’s still a child,
after all.
Let’s be on our way!
Huh?
What’s wrong, Tsuwabuki?
You have some
heavy reading there.
Ms. Utena...
What does it mean
to become an adult?
Huh?
What does it mean...?
W-Well, I think can mean
a buncha different things.
I think to become an adult
you need many colorful experiences.
“Colorful?”
So I’ll become an adult
once I’ve experienced more things?
Probably...
Are you very experienced,
Ms. Utena?
Uh... Well...
Once he’s more like us, he’ll have
plenty of adult experiences. Right, Master Utena?
Er... Y-You think so?
Yes.
Is it weird to dream
about my prince?
What?
I mean...
A younger student asked me about
what it means to be an adult and not a kid,
and I started wondering
which one I am.
What are your feelings
on the matter?
I don’t really know.
For starters, I don’t think I even know
what the differences are.
As time passes,
a star’s brilliance gradually fades.
You might say
the same applies to people.
You’re at your brightest
right now, aren’t you?
Getting a pretty bride and all.
I suppose so.
Mamiya... Why do you not
come out once in a while?
The rain depresses me.
I feel safer like this.
You don’t have to see unpleasant things
in this darkness, is that it?
Anyway,
has the next Duelist been selected?
If I said it’s an incorrigibly
jealous queen and her retainer...
A child...
Until last night,
he was a rather tough flower bud,
but with a little encouragement,
he will burst open easily.
You’re a bad person.
Beauty isn’t enough
to capture the Rose Bride.
I know.
If I experience more things...
I’ll become an adult...
What’re you doing?
You again?
What are you doing?
Watching many things
so I can become an adult.
will make you an adult?
Yeah.
You’ve been seriously
annoying me lately!
Why are you
following me around?
trying to pretend to be an adult?
Obviously, someone
who’s had one real kiss...
...is more adult than someone
who’s seen a million fake ones.
One real kiss?
Sheesh...
This is turning into a real problem.
You’re not dumb,
but the way you think is really weird.
There’s this thing
called practice.
Did you really never even
think about it?
You’re so stupid!
Could you be more tactless?!
I knew you were
just a kid!
What is he up to?
Ohtori Private Academy
Elementary Student Housing
No need for that.
Tsuwabuki’s still a child,
after all.
I think to become an adult
you need many colorful experiences.
Once he’s more like us, he’ll have
plenty of adult experiences. Right, Master Utena?
Coming.
Madam Nanami!
Why were you
in the screening room?
Huh? Why are you asking?
I saw you and that girl
in there together.
Mari was being—
I knew it.
What were you doing
with “just someone”?
You like that girl,
don’t you, Tsuwabuki?
So what if I do?
I’m short...
I don’t like bitter food,
or difficult seminar talk...
...and Mari’s been
making a fool of me lately,
saying a kid like me
wouldn’t understand.
Why couldn’t I have been born
the same year as you?
I want to become an adult
as soon as I can.
I want to have many colorful experiences as an adult.
Dummy.
You don’t have to be a grown-up.
You’re more than good enough
just the way you are.
Reception Booth
In use
Elementary school fourth-year, class A.
Tsuwabuki Mitsuru.
Now then, please begin.
Actually...
This is about Madam Nanami.
She’s really pretty and reliable.
I’ve admired her
for a very long time.
Even if she works me hard,
just being with her
makes me happy.
But... But...
Deeper... Go deeper...
It’s just that...
Somehow, it’s not enough...
Just being near her...
Even Mari.
She’s started butting in recently
because she’s my childhood friend.
They’re both making fun of me.
They laugh at me
for being a kid!
I want to be an adult!
I want to be an adult
and wreck the world!
I want to...
I want to wreck the world!
I understand.
A path you should follow has been prepared.
Where are...?
Tsuwabuki?
What are you up to,
calling me here?
Why are you so quiet,
Tsuwabuki?
Say something!
Now, now...
Please sit down.
What is it? Geez.
H-Hold it!
You’re overstepping,
Tsuwabuki!
Tsu... Tsuwabuki...?
With this,
I will become an adult...
Where’s the rain?
It always stops when
I actually bring my umbrella!
Why don’t you watch
the weather report?
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
Today... Today...
Was my first time!
What?! And you didn’t tell
your own father?!
Where did it happen?
In a car, apparently.
What?! You little...
Now, now, dear...
My heart was pounding like crazy,
but I don’t regret it at all!
My—
You seem awfully determined
for being a first-timer.
It took a lot of courage, but I could do it
because I knew it was my proof of adulthood.
Plus they give you
juice and stuff when it’s over!
Huh?
What are we talking about?
Isn’t it obvious?
I donated blood!
You can donate blood
when you’re sixteen.
Proof of a-dult-hood!
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
Upon this black rose,
I swear...
...I’ll win this duel and grant death
to the Rose Bride!
Tsuwabu—?
No way...
You’re the one who challenged me?
Have you forgotten
that this is a dueling arena?
Our fight has already begun.
Those eyes...
As I thought,
they look just like all the others’.
Then Tsuwabuki is also...
...not his normal self.
Himemiya!
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
Philosophical existence
From the realm of Grand Guignol’s populist stage tricks
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
Exhaling and sighing and gasping and wheezing and snorting
Gathering breath... Storing breath...
Magnifying glass
The power to revolutionize the world!
Sighing and exhaling and gasping and wheezing
and snorting and sighing and exhaling and gasping
and wheezing and snorting and sighing and exhaling
and gasping and wheezing and snorting and sighing
Ha-ha-hah!
Not one speck of energy used!
Tsuwabuki!
Snap out of it!
We don’t have any reason to fight!
Not one speck of energy wasted!
I will become an adult!
What?
Perfected man! A breathing machine
It’s not enough
to just experience things...
Only once a child defeats an experienced adult
will they become one themselves!
Perfected man! A mannequin of flesh and bone
Who put that idea
in your head?!
Perfected man! Peeling back the layers
Perfected man! Whole greater than sum
Ah-hah! Revolutions of heavenly bodies
Ah-hah! Synthesis of existence
The birth of a new species?
Or the ruin of humanity?
Either way, tick-tock
And my heart too, thump-thump
The hammer strikes the hour! Peck, peck, peck, peck!
As the time-telling cuckoo, I open the door!
Good morning, Nanami!
Oh... Morning.
Something wrong?
N-No. Nothing.
Tsuwabuki!
You’re gonna be late
if you don’t hurry up!
She’s so...
I have to run.
Why am I sweating?
Must be the weather...
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Huh?!
A boy sent me a love letter?!
He is an old friend
of Wakaba’s, Master Utena.
Then, if she’s the Princess of the
Onion Kingdom, he must be the Onion Prince!
With two onions, I could make
a really delicious curry tonight!
Wha...? Curry again?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Song of the Fallen Kingdom”
Song of the Fallen Kingdom
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.