Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Hey, look.
Yes.
We’re down to
the last black rose.
Yes.
Tokiko...
Your brother is sinful.
However, upon the sacrifice of those
one hundred Duelist boys lies true eternity.
Is it true?!
Did you do this?!
Were you behind this?
Yes.
Why?
How could you do this?
Tenjou Utena is strong.
Yes.
I sense immeasurable
strength in her.
Yes.
Hey, look.
We’re down to
the last black rose.
Yes.
For the life of me, I simply can’t
construct a scenario of assured victory.
Is there no other way
but to make her an ally?
Get Tenjou Utena
to be our ally?
Yes, seeing as some shadowy group
is making a move against us.
Right now, we should have
the betrothed cooperate with us.
But don’t you hate her,
Nanami?
I don’t like her,
but this is a crisis we’re facing.
Considering the situation,
I think we should have her as an ally.
I’m so admirable!
Big Brother... I, Nanami, will protect
the Student Council no matter what!
You say
“ally this, ally that”, but...
It’s not as if
we are even allies.
Then what are we?
We are...
...Duelists.
The Qualifications of a Duelist
Not here.
She’s not here, either!
Where’d Himemiya go?
Now that I’ve looked here,
I’m out of places I can think to check.
Maybe I shouldn’t have
gotten mad at her the other day.
I swear, it’s always one thing after another
when you’re friends with the likes of the Rose Bride.
Nice fragrance, is it not?
Oh, Mikage...
The modest scent of a single blossom
is nothing to scoff at,
but I am also compelled
by the fragrance of a bushel of roses.
They create a tense aura
of competition, you see.
Have you seen
Himemiya anywhere?
I wouldn’t know.
Who is that?
My classmate.
She’s been missing since this morning.
You’re very mindful
of your friends.
It’s not really that, but...
Did you more carefully consider
my offer from before?
Your offer from before...?
About joining the Mikage Seminar.
But I mean...
Why do you want someone like me?
You have a mysterious charm.
To be completely honest,
I find myself drawn to you.
If possible,
I wish to be with you.
Oh, so that’s what it is?
Pretty bold way of saying it...
You’re quite welcome
to just visit, too.
And, if you become our ally,
we will do everything we can
about whatever troubles you.
I don’t mind visiting,
but... Um...
I don’t really feel troubled,
so I’m not looking for help.
For one thing,
if I brought Chu-Chu with me,
he’d get cookie crumbs
everywhere.
Cleaning up after him
is really hard.
Huh?
It doesn’t need to be
you specifically.
Do you not have
any troubled friends?
Troubled friends?
Troubled friends, hmm...?
Please, don’t open it.
This coffin was meant for me.
Being alive makes me feel sick.
Why do we keep on living
when we’re all gonna die someday anyway?
Why did I never
notice that before today?
There’s no such thing
as eternity, is there?
Himemiya...
You’re back.
Hey, Himemiya...
Is there really no way you can just
up and stop being the Rose Bride?
A trouble friend, huh?
Excuse me!
Anybody here?
Hello?
Oh, I’m so sleepy...
Why have I been
so sleepy as of late?
There is a visitor
in the entrance hall.
Thank you.
I will be there shortly.
Well, I have a car waiting for me,
so I’ll be going now.
I see.
Thank you for your work.
Telling me to get out so abruptly
was so like you, to the last.
That’s exactly how it was
when we met...
Completely out of the blue,
you said, “Be my secretary”.
But it’s fine.
I can let my hair down
now that I’m free from your chains.
I wonder what you even
thought of me.
You are who you are.
You really are
some kind of special person.
Maybe one of the chosen.
But... the one I fell in love with
wasn’t a boy younger than me, like you.
I am who I am.
Well then, goodbye.
Huh?
Ms. Kanae...
Kozue, too...
What is this...?
The path to the dueling arena
is now open.
At last, it is about to begin.
With this, Professor Nemuro’s
job is finished.
From now on,
carrying on without him...
...is probably what
you-know-who is planning.
Surely even he
will lose to someone.
We can just leave him
by the wayside.
Now then,
let’s open the champagne.
How selfish they are.
It’s because of you that the castle appeared
and the path to the arena opened, is it not?
They are all afraid you.
They think you may be able
to attain eternity.
I will not duel
or anything of the sort.
Why not?
Do you not want to take into those hands
the power to revolutionize the world?
Even though eternity exists
in that castle?
Eternity means
to last forever, correct?
For years... Decades...
Centuries... Millennia...
Tens of thousands, hundreds of millions,
billions of cycles of billions of years...
My life may be
nothing but an instant, but...
...eternity means this moment lasts
billions of cycles of billions of years...
...and even then it does not end.
I... I...
I want eternity!
What are you talking about?
This is the first step
in what you are advancing...
In soon opening the path to eternity
from this academy.
Mr. Nemuro!
Mamiya did
as he was supposed to.
Now I, too,
wish to attain eternity.
You finally returned.
I knew you would come back to me
sooner or later.
Ms. Tokiko...
You don’t have to regret abandoning me.
Mikage... You...
Mikage... Are you the one
who was pulling the strings?
Strings?
By no means.
They were all
part of the Mikage Seminar.
Each one of these girls had their own
unforgettable memories.
Very, very precious memories.
They sallied forth and fought
to protect those memories.
They are, in a sense, people who tried to
change their lives using their memories.
Memories?
What about you?
We’ll meet again, won’t we,
my prince?
We’ll meet again...
Until then, I won’t cry...
I’ll be patient, no matter what.
Knowing your potential, you are able to
make that memory eternal, as I did.
The world requires it.
A path has been prepared for y—
You bastard!
Who the hell is “the world”?!
Don’t even pretend I’m anything like you,
you manipulative little...!
No need to get worked up.
You seem to be yelling out,
“Don’t touch my precious memory!”
What?! Don’t act like
you understand me!
My memory is...
I see.
That memory was the sole thing
sustaining you all this time.
There is no need to be ashamed,
for the memory you possess
is a worthy one.
Only those who hold
beautiful memories are allowed to wish...
...for those days to last forever,
to be just as you were back then.
I know full well...
...that you and I are the same.
You have the same eyes as
someone who will not stop wishing to...
...turn memories
into something eternal.
Reception Booth
I challenge you to a duel!
Come to the dueling arena tonight!
I’ll beat you to a pulp!
I’ll prove I’m nothing like you!
In use
Why did you call her here?
Why are you silent?
What’s so funny?
Here, look at this.
A tear.
A tear?
It seems the pain
forcibly brought out a tear.
If she hadn’t seen
my Rose Seal,
she might have killed me
right then and there.
You sound like
you’re enjoying this.
Truly, she always keeps
hurting and surprising me.
As I thought,
Tokiko has returned...
...to settle the score with me
once and for all.
You intend to duel her?
After all, we haven’t
made any progress in all this time.
But she is closer to
the power of Dios than either of us.
We need to defeat her
if we are to proceed.
A rose in majestic full bloom
at the end of the world...
...is bestowed to me!
Your eyes are the same as the eyes of
someone who will not stop wishing to...
...turn memories
into something eternal.
Utena!
C’mon now, haven’t you been forgetting
your best friend Lady Wakaba these days?
I haven’t.
No matter what happens,
I’m always on your side!
Extra! Extra! Extra!
At your age,
your pa was class rep!
Wow! That’s awesome, Pa!
Hey, you! What’s with
this paperwork? It’s all wrong!
Dammit...
I used to be class rep!
Dear, you can’t just throw your socks here
when you take them off. That’s just wrong!
Dammit...
I used to be class rep!
Well, Pa, I’m off to school!
Wait!
Gimme that school bag!
Your pa’s goin’ to school!
Take care!
The power to revolutionize the world!
Darkness, incandescence,
creation, puppets;
theocentrism is the name
I’ll start us off.
Nice block.
A single being pulls all the strings
Yet...!
I’m not yet back to normal.
Everyone else is merely illusory puppetry
You got my shoulder quite well.
But... I don’t feel as though
I’ll lose to you.
Darkness, frigidity,
Quit bullshitting!
I’m not losing to some bastard
pulling strings from the shadows!
creation, organisms;
That isn’t accurate.
theocentrism is the link
Upon nature’s stage, the original agent
Those who received my black roses
approached me of their own free will.
is the illusory art of life creation
Then they stood here
of their own free will.
All who stand here
are the same as me.
Words, births - encounters and meanderings
They come here
drawn by eternity!
Shut up! Don’t put the blame on them
for what you did!
Wisdom, births - encounters and voids
I knew since I first saw you...
Oh, where and when am I?
You met someone
important to you long ago, right?
And then that person
changed your life, right?
Incantations, charms, mysteries, prayers, me
You stand here because of
the strength of that illusion.
It’s why you could enter
the dueling arena.
Stage, destiny, magic, mirror
Am I wrong?
After all,
you and I are the same!
Right here, right now...
...I will win...
Full moon! Mysterious transformations
...and you will lose, Tokiko!
Don’t kid yourself.
I’m not losing to you!
I am an illusory lifeform coming to my end
You’re such an obstinate girl, Tokiko.
Full moon! Mysterious transformations
Seems you won’t see
till I strike that rose from your chest.
I am an illusory fateform coming to my end
Wishing for time and never resting,
I knew you would jump!
Crap!
living on as a hollowform
Master Utena!
Himemiya!
Wishing for soil armless, legless
Master Utena!
I continue to exist, transparent, intangible,
You’re about to lose.
nothing but a faint sigh
Mamiya!
She is going to strike the rose
from your chest.
What?!
Where are you?! Mamiya!
Mamiya!
Who...
...is this?!
You can’t defeat her.
You’ll never defeat the sister of mine
within your memory. Not for all eternity.
Tokiko!
Eternity is right before my eyes!
I will defeat you and grasp
the power to change the world!
With my own hands!
Why don’t you understand me?!
I took it all as my burden!
Even your brother’s sin!
Now, watch carefully.
At that time, at that place,
who was truly there?
Who wasn’t there?
Who truly set fire
to that building?
Mamiya...
It’s been such a long time...
How many decades has it been
since I last saw you?
Ah, Nemuro, my friend...
I was just thinking
a call from you was due.
Yes.
The boy called Mamiya you kept by your side
owing to your regrets over Tokiko...
...died a long time ago.
I exploited the illusory memories which
you held so dear as to halt your own time.
The time you spent restraining your own potential,
never quite reaching adulthood, was useful.
But that has run its course.
From this point forward,
no path has been prepared for you.
I’d like it very much
for you to graduate.
Man...
Looking for Himemiya
took us to a real weird place.
There was a very big fire here
a long time ago.
Damn. Something like that
happened here?
There appeared to be no casualties,
but since it was before the Student Council
was established, no records remain.
Hmm, what was the building called?
Kushiro Memorial Hall...?
No, sounds wrong.
Himemiya? Where are you?
Noboribetsu Memorial Hall...?
Argh! I hate it when
I can’t remember something!
What’s the matter?
Are you sympathizing with him?
But already, he no longer exists
in this academy.
No. He never did
in the first place.
Quite the same as you.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Tsuwabuki got run over
by a runaway horse!
Oh, my goodness!
Huh? What’s this notebook?
No, this isn’t right. You shouldn’t look
in others’ notebooks without asking.
Goodness! There are all these
awful secrets written in here!
Like I said,
we shouldn’t look!
Oh, my! Even this?!
Huh? Where? Where?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
The Secret Nanami Diary
“The Secret Nanami Diary”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.