Tenjou Utena-kun!
So? How are you liking your first day?
Well, with a cute girl like you around
I can’t really complain.
Oh, my!
Think we’ll get along?
I’ll show you around the academy!
What’s your name?
Shinohara Wakaba!
Hi, everyone!
If our voices reach you,
please lend us your ears!
We’re the dynamic duo of
the Ohtori Academy Broadcast Club, E-ko and...
...F-ko!
Bringing you
the Midday School Radio Show!
Today has turned out to be
a beautiful day blessed with a refreshing wind!
If you packed a lunch,
this is the perfect time to enjoy it outside!
You shouldn’t try that.
You’ll just invite
a capricious passing shower.
Wait a minute...
The forecast said nothing about that.
The rain in my heart
will surely cloud the skies above.
Did you get dumped again?
What’s so wrong with me anyway?!
So, everyone...
If you plan on scribbling
on your boyfriend’s back while he’s napping,
make sure he doesn’t have
to swim in phys ed the next day!
Hey, Wakaba...
What?
The high school building...
What’s that?
The Fencing Club.
It’s super popular with girls!
Look, it’s the prince!
The prince?
Impressive as always.
But I’m not giving up.
You’re better suited
to playing the piano.
They’re so popular.
Of course!
They’re Juri-senpai and Mickey, after all.
The lady with the curls
is Arisugawa Juri-senpai.
She’s captain of the Fencing Club
and a capable member of the Student Council.
Next!
All the girls call her a prince.
Maybe she’ll be your rival.
Huh?
Oh, and... the boy is Kaoru Miki-kun,
or “Mickey” as we call him.
He’s only a first-year middle school student,
but he’s a super genius who’s already in a few college classes.
He’s cute and popular...
...but they say that his twin sister gets in the way,
so he can’t get a girlfriend because of her.
Huh? Utena?
Where did...?
It started raining.
It’ll stop soon.
I hear it’s a capricious passing rain.
How many years has it been...
...since we last met like this?
Remember our promise
to go to the planetarium?
We never got around to it.
Don’t get the wrong idea!
The wrong idea?
I’m not... who I used to be.
I didn’t come here chasing after you.
But I’m surprised.
I never imagined you’d be
here in this academy.
Those clothes you’re wearing...
It’s because of the prince.
After we separated, I decided...
...that I’d aspire to higher principles.
For one who aspires
to higher principles.
That ring...
I see. You’re engaged to someone.
It is what led me to this academy.
The Rose Seal.
Roses...
A white rose.
This is...
What... is that?
Are you not afraid?
Are you not afraid,
standing in a place like that?
There’s so many roses.
This is my rose garden.
Yours?
I’m the Board Chairman’s sister,
so I get special treatment.
But...
But truthfully,
I’m the one captive to the roses.
What did you come to this academy for?
I...
H-Hey!
It’s mine!
It’s my Rose Seal!
How do you know that name?
What are you doing?
What are you doing
to the Rose Bride?
The Rose...
...Bride?
Only those authorized
may step foot in here.
I see. You are also a Duelist.
Duelist?
Pardon me.
I’ve never seen you before,
but it appears you do possess the right to be here.
The right?
What do you mean?
Don’t feign ignorance.
The Rose Seal...
Wait!
Do you know what this is?
“What this is”?
It is this Rose Seal that marks us as Duelists;
those who may duel to obtain the Rose Bride.
Duelists?
To obtain you?
Oh, my...
You possess the Rose Seal...
...and yet, you didn’t even know that?
Perhaps you weren’t meant
to be my opponent in a duel after all.
It is what led me to this academy.
The Rose Seal.
Anthy...
Prepare us.
The one whose rose is stricken
from their chest loses.
Where’s your sword?
Sword?
Do you really understand
what having that ring entails?
If you want to remove it,
do it now.
Well, this puts us in a bind.
A duel against one
with no sword is not valid.
If it’s a sword I need, I’ve got one.
Wait...
Any objections?
Fine by me!
Saionji-sama, she might—
When the bells toll, the duel begins.
Don’t interfere, Anthy!
Don’t hit your girlfriend!
My girlfriend?
She is the Rose Bride.
In other words, since I’m
the current champion of the duels...
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
...she’s my possession!
“Possession”?!
sukora chuushou
Scholastic abstraction
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
Are you really using this girl
as a prize for winning duels?
mahi suru shisou
Thought petrification
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
Without caring about how she feels?
Answer me!
fukitsu yogensho
Ominous prophecies
Does everyone who has
one of these rings duel to win her?
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
seishin mahoujin
Spiritual magic circles
“How she feels”?
What are you on about?!
sonzai souzou
Creating existence
fushigina kairaku
Peculiar pleasures
haguruma souchi
Gear mechanisms
seinaru dekadan
Holy decadence
You understand nothing!
mikan no rekishi
Incomplete history
She is the Rose Bride!
shoubin souchi
Glassware apparatus
You’re the one
who doesn’t understand!
eien naru kiseki no sore wo shinji
I believed in that eternal miracle
What?!
No girl could ever be happy
being used as a dueling prize!
eikyuu naru kami wo kokoro mita
I put the immortal god to the test
Is that right?!
aa mukyuu no rekishi chuusei yo
Oh, the timeless era of the Middle Ages...
You’re... a girl?
ware ni yomigaere
...reawaken within me!
I never said I was a boy!
And I’ll never lose
to anyone who hits girls!
zou shoku rekishi
Offal-eating history
aa yomigaere
Oh, reawaken...
Let’s end this.
You really understand nothing!
mukyuu no rekishi chuusei yo
...the timeless era of the Middle Ages!
This is the end!
Anthy!
waga gankyuu ni
“In my eyes!”
One may not duel without a sword.
waga ryou no te ni
“In my two hands!”
waga chi to iki ni
“In my blood and breath!”
Hey!
yomigaere yomigaere
Reawaken! Reawaken!
rekishi naru yomigaere yomigaere
I become history! Reawaken! Reawaken!
chuusei sono subete no toki yo
The Middle Ages, all of its years!
heya yo irui yo
Its rooms! Its garb!
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
A sword?
kyouki to gumai
Insanity and ignorance
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
sensei igaku
Medical astrology
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
uwagoto shijutsu
Incoherent arts of death
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
kougaku gedokuzai
Optical antidote
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
sukora chuushou
Scholastic abstraction
watashi no subete chuusei ni shite
Make me the Middle Ages incarnate!
Who is it?
It’s me, Himemiya Anthy.
Good evening.
You just moved in
and it’s already so tidy.
I was about to go to sleep,
and I don’t invite people
into my room.
Then I should leave for tonight.
Dummy...
I’m not letting you go home.
Of course not.
What is this?
It’s the Rose Seal.
You know about it, no?
Those who possess it
have the right to duel.
That Saionji guy...
He said he duels against everyone
because he wants you.
What does everyone do
when they win you?
Such an amusing girl...
Tenjou Utena-san.
Just Utena is fine.
Well, then...
I’m pleased to meet you, Utena.
We’ll get along... won’t we?
Do you always do this
with the winner of the duel?
I’m the Rose Bride.
I act in however my betrothed
wishes for me to act.
You’re so thin.
Cut it out!
Playtime’s over.
Go back to your room, now.
Oh, my...
You have so many cute outfits.
So what?
Is there a problem with that?
Not at all.
Knock it off!
What are you thinking?
You’re weird...
She’s weird, isn’t she?
What?
Talking about the prince again?
Yes, the girl who still wears
the prince’s clothes.
Yet she probably still dreams
of the prince’s castle.
That reminds me,
I used to have a prince myself.
But that prince is dead.
A childhood friend of mine killed him.
The prince liked her,
so one time, when she fell off a boat,
he dove in and was swept away trying to save her.
So stupid.
We were just about to be alone.
But the prince died instead.
So I will never forgive her.
I’ll make her play the prince
for the rest of her life.
H-Hey! Wakaba, cut it out!
Ow!
To think that you’d be
chosen as a Duelist...
You said this ring is what
led you to this academy.
Then are you also... after her?
You could say that.
Why?
Why? Because she’s attractive, of course.
Do you know the kind of girl she is?
What kind of girl is she?
She’s weird!
Really?
Because... with anyone who
wins the duel, she’ll...
What?
She is the Rose Bride.
Naturally, she’ll spend the night
with her betrothed
Have you ever won a duel yourself?
And been “betrothed” to Himemiya—?
That shouldn’t concern you, should it?
Himemiya Anthy.
Let’s go!
One, two! One, two!
What shall we do tonight?
I told you yesterday,
I have no need for any “Rose Bride”!
Really?
Even though this prince
has just won you... So unfriendly.
Indeed.
Goodness, goodness.
Look, we’re all soaked now.
Well, if you’re at the pool,
you’re bound to get wet.
Oh, Touga-senpai.
Hmm...
Why did my little sister
imprison the Rose Prince?
In any case,
then the masses stormed in.
It was an ordeal.
Open the door!
Give us back the prince!
Open up, you witch!
Witch! Witch!
Yes, yes, yes,
my sister really was a witch.
She had magical powers.
But there was another secret.
What was that?
The Rose Prince was actually...
...the Lord of the Flies.
My sister, the witch, used her magic
to change him into a prince.
So when my sister’s magic faded,
the prince returned to his true self.
So to regain that lost magical power,
you devised this game.
But I’ll be the one
to gain it in the end.
What are you trying to gain?
What do you mean?
Don’t try to hide it.
I know you’re doing things
behind my back.
Don’t move.
We can’t return to the garden
where we were together.
But you’ll always be precious to me.
You traitor!
Where is she going at this hour?
The Rose Bride, huh?
When I was a child, I grew out my hair,
as instructed by my father.
That was what the customer wanted.
Customer?
My new father. I was sold.
I lost many things.
But thanks to that, I became able to
partake in this academy’s dueling game.
I know you’ll win.
You won’t lose to someone like Juri.
Someone like Juri?
Because... she’s gross.
She doesn’t think anyone knows,
but I saw it.
Saw what?
She always wears a pendant,
doesn’t she?
She has my photo in the locket...
...and stares at it
when she’s by herself.
Honestly, it makes me sick.
Word got out about it,
and it’s been such a hassle.
I wonder who was spreading the rumor.
Win the duel and punish Juri, please.
I don’t know.
I intend to win the duel,
but I can’t be cruel to Juri.
Why?
Duelists aspire to higher principles.
This darkness leads
to the end of the world.
That’s kind of scary.
I feel like it might pull me in.
It will soon begin...
The revolution.
Why are you a Duelist?
Because I was chosen, of course.
But you could have refused.
I always wish to obtain more power.
How boyish of you.
And you, Juri-san?
You despise the Rose Bride.
Why do you participate in this game?
I want power so I can
be free of everything.
What is “everything”?
Everything that chains me down.
We’re finally alone together and here we are
discussing such unromantic things.
Shiori!
This place is off-limits
to regular students.
I’m sorry. I’m intruding, aren’t I?
What’s the matter, at this hour?
I felt so lonely.
I wanted to see your face, Juri-san.
Did something happen?
You’re a Duelist, aren’t you, Juri-san?
How do you know that?
I know other things, too.
Other things?
For example,
about that Tenjou Utena girl.
What do you know of her?
She likes Touga-senpai.
That’s why she’s so insistent on crossdressing.
So she could become a Duelist.
Playing prince because of some guy?
It’s wrong for someone like that to get
the power to revolutionize the world, isn’t it?
True, she’s not even
amusing enough to be a joke.
You’ll win, right?
You’ll be the one to win,
won’t you, Juri-san?
Yes... I’ll be sure to give her
a beating in the next duel.
That which chains Juri-san down, huh?
Utena.
Why are you here this late?
“This late”, yet you’re
tending to your roses?
Because I’m the Rose Bride.
I must have said something
to offend you again.
Do you really do things like that...
...with anyone who wins the duel?
Things like what?
Are you, perhaps,
curious to know about Kiryuu-senpai?
Is he your—?
Shut up!
What do you know?!
It was you, wasn’t it?! Touga...
Touga started acting strange
because of you!
It was you, wasn’t it?!
It was you... wasn’t it...?
I thought he’d be
right there, beside me...
He was there when
my mother and father went away...
I thought he’d always be by my side,
and no one else’s...
We said we’d always...
...gaze at the stars, together...
Stars?
There is no prince...
Himemiya...
This rose is our destiny
michibikare
Guide us
futari wa ima
Right now, the two of us...
mou ichido deau
...meet once more
donna toki mo
No matter what’s going on,
ano yakusoku wasurenaide
don’t forget that promise
yatto koko made kita yo
At long last, we’ve finally made it here
toki ni ai wa tsuyoku hito no kokoro wo kizutsuke mo suru keredo
Even though at times, love is so strong it wounds our hearts,
yume wo atae yuuki no naka ni itsumo hikari kagayaite
it grants us dreams, and always shines when there is courage
ai wa tsuyoku hito no kokoro wo ugokashite yuku
Love is so strong that it moves our hearts
dakara futari de iru kitto sekai wo kaeru tame ni
I just know the two of us came together to change the world
soshite subete wa hitotsu no chikara ni naru
And everything, all our power, will join into one
Okay, listen up! Listen up!
Now, pair up and sketch each other.
Don’t get bogged down in the details.
It’s important to
capture your partner’s essence.
It’s a nice day, so you have
permission to work outside.
Himemiya...
Wait up, Himemiya!
Hey! I said wait!
Hey! Himemiya! Hime—
Himemiya!
There’s an observation room up here.
Is it fine for us to be
all the way up here?
It’s all right.
No one comes here.
What a great view!
I’m sorry about last night.
And thank you.
For what?
Don’t tease me like that.
I was kinda one-sidedly
tossing all of my feelings at you.
But what you did for me—
Think nothing of it.
You are my betrothed.
Um, can you stop saying that?
Anyway, I’m not going to duel anymore.
You don’t like me after all, do you?
It’s not that.
It’s more like...
If we’re going to be close,
we should do it properly, right?
Last night, after I got back
to my room, while I was alone...
I realized that I felt better.
It was kinda unexpected.
I wondered if talking about our problems,
or helping each other when we’re in trouble...
Maybe something that simple
is exactly what I needed.
I had honestly wondered about that.
If you don’t mind,
would you open up to me a little more?
I want to be your friend.
We shouldn’t keep secrets from each other,
like this Rose Bride stuff.
But you don’t tell me anything
about yourself—
Shall we switch now?
H-Hey...
What is it?
I changed my mind,
let’s not do this.
Why?
Do you have to ask why?
It’s important to
capture your partner’s essence.
Shouldn’t we not keep secrets?
Fine... This is what you want, right?
H-Hey...
If... If I’m the only one...
...modeling... it’s not fair...
That’s true.
You don’t have to do that.
Hey, Himemiya...
These paintings...
The model in them...
Is it you?
I’ll show you the reason...
...why everyone wants...
...the Rose Bride.
Wh-What is that?
I’ve got a big scoop!
There’s a really scandalous painting
in the back of the Board Chairman’s room.
This is so, so outrageous!
Oh, but I’ve gotten my hands on
an even more outrageous videotape!
Now this is a crazy scandalous tape!
Start!
Is this really your scandalous tape?
My bad.
And now, for the real
scandalous tape!
Start!
Oh!
It’s the Acting Board Chairman, Mr. Akio-san!
This must be back when he had just
gotten engaged to the Board Chairman’s daughter.
A picture-perfect prince!
So young, yet competent, with a great
personality... and a real looker to boot!
Thank you, but you flatter me.
Is... Is this really a videotape?
A nice car complements
a good-looking guy!
Oh, but this car isn’t going anywhere.
I lost the key.
Welcome back, Big Brother.
I’m home.
That’s right!
I heard Mr. Akio-san takes care of his sister.
They’re quite the tightly-knit
pair of siblings.
But the scandal starts...
Starts...
Starts here!
The shocking secret
of the Rose Bride is...
Is...
Is...!
Himemiya... What is this?
This is the secret of the Rose Bride.
shura ima moen
Asura, now, blazing out!
te no ashi no kodou ni
Hands and feet, throbbing
shura ima atsuku
Asura, now, burning hot!
owari shiranu mama ni
Ignorant yet of its demise
kuraki saraba
A dark “farewell”
utsushimi nugi
Shedding its transient body
kouyami ni fuki
blown away into wild darkness
Juri-san is on the defensive.
That’s no easy feat.
kokuu no kagiri
to the reach of endless void
shura ima chinmoku
Asura, now, silent!
chidou ten jindou mitsumetsutsu
Gazing at the orbits of stars, planets, humans
shura ima arishi
Asura, now, present!
You’re not bad at all.
You’d hold your own
against my club members.
ten no hate arishi nara
For if there is an edge to space...
minikusa saraba
Bid foul bindings farewell
chishio ni toke
Melting into the blood
But you don’t seem to realize how much
it’ll cost you to play prince so halfheartedly.
jouki no gotoku
like vapors
mata tsumetaku
only to cool, again
The Rose Seal doesn’t suit you.
shura wa hitori nari
Asura is solitude
I...
hitori to wa orishi kyomu
Solitude is anon emptiness!
I can’t afford to lose!
shura hotaru no you ni aojiroku sukete
Asura, like a firefly, pale and translucent!
Do you love Touga so much?
What is Juri-san talking about?
imawa no kiwa ni tatsu
Facing its final moments
Who is...
...Touga?
shura ima seijaku
Asura, now, motionless!
See that?
That...
That is the castle said to hold eternity.
kouei kenryoku mina hoshi nari
Glory and power, from stardust to stardust
Castle?
I haven’t been inside myself,
shura ima henshin su
Asura, now, transforms!
but I hear you can have anything there.
Eternity, miracles, everything radiant.
raimei inazuma daiankoku
Thunder and uncanny lightning, pitch darkness
It’s a place where
all your secret wishes can come true.
kanashiki saraba
A tragic “farewell”
That’s what it means to win me.
eien wo mo
Even the wandering stars of eternity
Even so, you’ll still...
tsureai ni shite
it takes as companions,
...throw away your Rose Seal?
tera wo shinzou ni
and Terra, into its heart
Was that really all you had, O Prince?
shura wa hoshi nari
Asura is a star-man
hoshi to wa minamoto nari
A star-man is the spring of life
shura maboroshi atete ikuseiki wo tsutsumi
Asura, chasing phantom stars, cradling eons
That’s...
chikara no koa korona
The core of fearsome power, the corona!
My, my... Are we still
playing prince, Tenjou-kun?
So brave, Tenjou-kun. You think you can
fight with a stance like that?
Your appearance...
Just now, you...
Extra!
No!
Akio-san...
Akio-san!
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Is that the Board Chairman?
Yup, it’s the Board Chairman.
Yes, it’s the Board Chairman.
We were wondering where you were.
And it turns out
you’ve been in the cold earth.
I wonder, did someone murder you?
Someone buried you, after all.
So then, who’s the culprit?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
It’s the owner of the flowerbed.
What?!
The reason she was growing roses...
...was to hide her brother’s corpse.
If you need to see proof,
then feast your eyes on this video!
Feast your eyes on this video!
Hey, it’s...!
The scandalous video I found!
When did she get it?!
Himemiya did this?
Himemiya?!
Himemiya!
The prince...
You... weren’t asleep?
Himemiya!
How long?
How long have you been awake?
Were you never asleep to begin with?
Did you always
only pretend to be asleep?
Hey...
Don’t worry.
You are my prince, Big Brother.
You can do with me as you please—
Don’t say that!
I’m not like that!
Himemiya!
Reception Booth
Himemiya?
The key! The key!
The key! The key! I can’t find the key!
Key? What are you talking about?
A car without its key
can’t move, it’s doomed to rust!
Where’s the key?
The key...!
The key...
Where the hell is the key?!
Calm down, Big Brother!
You’re the prince,
you can do whatever you wish.
You don’t understand!
All those engaged, please wait in the back.
Utena...
Touga... Where is Himemiya?
Why do you want to see her?
Have you started wanting the power
to make miracles happen after all?
Does such power truly exist?
Utena, what do you think is the meaning
of the game we play at this academy?
Everything here revolves
around the prince.
Yet, an actual flesh-and-blood prince
is nowhere to be found.
That’s why this game is necessary;
it’s to fill that void.
When she became the Rose Bride,
the castle said to hold eternity appeared.
Yes... When she killed
her brother, the prince.
That’s not true.
The prince was already dead
from the start.
I’m finally starting to remember.
Remember what?
About when we separated.
The time you disappeared.
I somehow forgot about it
when I arrived here.
Don’t you remember?
Back then, a boy drowned
in the river by our school.
Perhaps that happened.
It did.
There was a girl on a boat
who fell in the river.
A boy jumped into the river
to save her...
...and he drowned instead.
Why had I forgotten that until now?
Help! Help!
Help!
Someone help! Someone!
Utena...
Won’t you come with me?
I’m right here now.
I’m always thinking of you.
I promise to love you
until the end of the world.
Isn’t that enough?
Let’s be happy here.
You said that back then, too.
Someone, quick! Anyone!
That night, when I was
crying alone in the chapel,
you told me how
you’d been thinking of me...
...and gently embraced me.
Wait!
Thank you.
You really were my prince...
What’s the matter, Utena?!
Oh, no! A girl is drowning!
Wait! Don’t go!
Don’t go, Touga!
No, I have to go or she’ll drown!
But Touga! You’ll die!
Touga! Touga!
Touga!
Utena.
I finally found you, Utena.
You were my true prince.
You are now the prince of the academy.
Any miracle and all of eternity are yours...
...as long as you remain in this world.
No.
Let’s go... to the outside world.
Come on.
Himemiya, let’s leave!
Leave for the place outside this world!
No, I can’t!
Himemiya!
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
Utena!
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyaku mawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
Utena, is that you?
The key! I can’t find the key!
Key?
A car without its key
can’t move, it’s doomed to rust.
Where’s the key?! The key...! The key...!
Where the hell is the key?!
Let’s go, Utena...
To the outside world!
STOP
DANGER
YOU WILL DIE
Hi, everyone!
Are you all cruising?
This is E-ko’s and...
...F-ko’s...
...live radio coverage!
Engage racing mode.
Engaged.
Today’s main event
is just about to start!
Currently, Himemiya Anthy
has a large lead.
Of course, there’s only one car,
so it can only be in the lead.
You don’t have to say it like that!
Extra! Extra!
A black vehicle is gaining from behind!
It’s fast!
Are you surprised?
If you thought you were the only one
who turned into a car, you’re sorely mistaken.
That’s right. I turned into a car, too.
She’s a rough one!
I won’t let you be the only one to pull off
a dashing stunt like escaping this world!
The one who’s really dashing
and beautiful is none other than myse—
Myse— Myse—
My— My— My— My— My— My— My—!
My! The black vehicle just crashed!
Himemiya Anthy
leads all by herself again!
What’s going on?
The black vehicles are multiplying!
Misfortunes never come alone...
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
Celery
Green Pepper
Carrot
They really are multiplying!
They’re like demons!
I’ve never seen a swarm this massive!
Where did they come from?!
Hey— Hello—? Did you enter— tunnel?
Extra!
They went into a tunnel,
so our signal won’t reach them for a while!
Well, excuse me!
Are you breaking down?
I can’t get any speed.
It’s no use... Help!
Utena!
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
Be quiet
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
CAUTION
TRAFFIC AHEAD
SLOW DOWN
We have a signal again!
We can finally resume our broadcast.
Well, well... Looks like the problem
was dealt with while we were out.
It seems friendship saved the day.
You can get onto
the left bypass up ahead.
Why did you...?
You’re heading
for the outside, aren’t you?
Higher principles attract good company.
Don’t worry, I just know
you can make it and find the outside.
We plan on following you eventually.
When you make it to the outside,
I’ll be there to seduce you.
Good work!
You should reach the exit soon!
The exit? To the outside world?
Yes! Not that we’ve seen it ourselves...
But it should be close!
Wait. We have a visual of something.
What is this? A castle?
Is it signposting the exit?
It’s a trap!
That’s not the exit! Run!
You’ll see a bypass
to the left in a kilometer.
Get off there and run away
back to our world!
I’m not running anymore.
Huh?!
The exit is probably right there.
What makes you think that?
Let’s go... to the outside world!
isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Extra!
Now scanning the inside
of the obstacle ahead!
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
They’re gliding through the many
enormous tires on the inside.
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
It seems the tires are there
to crush any external intruders.
There’s no way to get through there!
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
Well, they’re doing a pretty good job.
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida
Even in my dreams, even with my tears
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
Extra! Extra! The exit is near!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart
Commencing countdown!
19... 18... 17... 16...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
15... 14... 13... 12... 11...
10... 9... 8... 7...
6... 5... 4... 3...
2... 1...!
They made it!
Big Brother...
Indeed... It is I, your prince.
You have nothing to fear anymore.
Now, come back with me...
...to that closed world where
you can be dead even as you live.
How pitiable.
You can only be a prince in that world.
But I... and Utena, too...
...are leaving for the outside world.
Don’t.
You’ll only end up at the end of the world.
That may be.
But we will have gone there
of our own free will.
Goodbye, my prince.
I see. That’s too bad.
But I think I will have both of you
remain princesses back in that world after all.
It’s easy. All you need to do
is die even as you live.
The power...
...to revolutionize the world!
Himemiya Anthy
Tenjou Utena
So, now we’re headed into
a world without roads.
Over there,
we might not make it after all.
Utena, I see it now.
We were born in
the outside world to begin with.
Then we’re returning
to the place we came from.
I understand now, too...
Why you sought me
and why I didn’t reject you.
We were both responsible
for killing the prince.
That’s right.
The outside world has no roads.
But you can always build new roads!
That’s why we have to go.
As we travel, the world will grow and grow...
I’m sure of it.
kotoba yori mo tashika na mono
It’s something more certain than words
karada yori mo aimai na mono
It’s something more vague than flesh
mitsukaranakute futari
Without ever finding it, the two of us
kasurikizu fuyashite
will only get more scratched up
omoide ga kyuukutsu ni naridashite konogoro no bokura wa
Our memories have grown uncomfortably dull to recall as of late
niramiau you na me de
With glaring eyes,
kokoro no kyori hakatteru
we measure the distance between our hearts
wakareru ki nante nai kuse ni
Even if we we have no intention to break up,
itsumo fuan dake atsumete
all that we feel is constant anxiety,
itazura ni butsukeau
as we butt heads for a laugh
dame na koibito sa
We’re such worthless lovers
soba ni ite motto chikaku ni
Stay with me, come closer...
sono hitokoto ga detekonai
I can’t say something like that
akireru hodo wagamama ni
It’s super selfish to say
naretara ii no ni
If only I could get used to it
kotoba yori mo tashika na mono
It’s something more certain than words
karada yori mo aimai na mono
It’s something more vague than flesh
mitsukaranakute futari
Without ever finding it, the two of us
kasurikizu fuyashite
will only get more scratched up
mou hashaganai de kore ijou
Don’t play around any more than this
boku yori tanoshisou na kimi wo
When I see you having more fun than me,
miru no ga kurushii no wa naze darou
it hurts so much and I don’t even know why
isso no koto
Well you know what?
fiance ni naritai
I want to marry you
tomodachi ni nanka modorekkonai
I can’t just go back to being friends
kimi dake no tame ni ikirarenai
and I can’t live just for you
tomadoinagara futari
While we hesitate and ponder,
kiss wo kurikaeshite
let’s just keep kissing nonstop
mou nayamanaide kore ijou
Don’t worry me any more than this
itoshiku omoeba omou hodo
The more lovely I find you
kodoku wo kanjiru no wa naze darou
the lonelier I feel and I don’t even know why
isso no koto
Well you know what?
fiance ni naritai
I want to marry you