Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
It’s nice to have lunch outside
once in a while.
Right? You’ve said it!
Don’t I have the smartest ideas?
Here, here, here...
I obviously made some
for you, too!
But I have...
No, no, no! Doesn’t it stink
to have to eat something bland?
Instead, have this lunch I stuffed
with my adoration for you, my beloved Utena!
Look! Look! Look!
Okay...
Yay!
Quit it already...!
Graceful and Ruthless:
The One Who Picks the Flower
Come one, come all,
and feast your eyes on this!
Ta-dah!
It’s just pre-made food,
but I made it look super pretty, right?
Well, love and admiration aside,
it sure looks tasty.
Thanks, Wakaba.
Woo-hoo!
All my hard work paid off!
I am pretty amazing,
after all!
Master Utena?
Would you appraise
my lunch, as well?
Long as it isn’t
shaved ice again...
Here.
Wow, that’s a whole lot.
Sure has impact.
Please, open it up.
Right, first up we have...
Takoyaki...?
Is that it?
Yes.
Next...
Yakisoba...?
Yeah, I think so...
Looks scrumptious, yes?
And third...
Oh, my.
Didn’t think it’d actually be pretty normal.
Feels like stuff you’d find at a festival, though.
“Pretty normal”?
What did you think it was gonna be?
Well... I’ll tell you later.
Let’s eat now.
What are you observing?
Oh, it’s you.
I was watching a lonely princess.
Tenjou...
And Himemiya, too.
They seem to be
enjoying themselves.
But what did you mean
by “lonely princess”?
You can’t see.
No one can, but me.
You mean to say
you’re referring to an illusion?
It’s quite concrete.
Quite visible and tangible.
Whoa, so cool!
Utena?
What’re you looking at?
Um... Nothing...
Oh... Eyeing the prince
of the Student Council, huh?
Prince?
That time, he said...
Was your prince not...
...a guy like me?
If that’s true...
...could he be my prince
from back then?
Astounding!
Is it okay to eat like that?
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
As you may already know,
Nanami lost the duel
against Tenjou Utena.
I’m ashamed to admit
the gap in their capabilities was laid bare.
As it was from the start.
Nanami fought
only so that she could lose...
...all in line with Student Council President
Kiryuu Touga’s setup, hmm?
It’s quite upsetting
that you see it that way.
I only ever wish to
dote upon Nanami.
Like you would
with a pet cat?
6.12 seconds...
It was her own fault
that she lost the duel.
Whether or not someone
plotted it,
her involvement
was her own responsibility.
How cold.
Sometimes,
the depth of your feelings...
...can weigh so heavily upon you
as to hold you back.
And the stronger the feelings,
the stronger the effect.
Was your prince not
a guy like me?
Incredible, all of them!
And they say
this variety is quite difficult to grow.
My sincere thanks.
Incidentally, you and the others
had lunch outside today, correct?
Yes. You saw us, then?
Master Utena,
Wakaba, Chu-Chu...
It was incredibly fun!
That’s lovely.
Wakaba’s lunch
was so delicious...
I’d love to make food like hers.
The Rose Bride? Cooking?
You shouldn’t
stoop to things like cooking.
Your only concern
should be tending to the roses.
This birdcage
is where you belong.
And you are
its beautiful little bird.
I wish to possess this cage,
and everything in it.
I would never
let you leave. Ever.
Get away from her!
Hello.
Happy to see you here.
You really only see Himemiya
as the Rose Bride?
Is that wrong?
Very wrong!
Cut the “Rose Bride”
and “possess” bullshit!
She’s just a normal girl
called Himemiya Anthy!
Really? Is it true
you’re just a normal girl?
You don’t like having to be
the Rose Bride, right?
I...
Give him a piece of your mind!
My mind...
Yeah!
You hate being treated
as the Rose Bride, right?
Be clear and tell him that!
Yes. I hate being treated
as the Rose Bride.
What’s so funny?!
Nothing, pardon me.
She sure is your bride, hmm?
Go on.
What do you want
with Himemiya?
Nothing at all.
I came here hoping to see you.
I’ve been waiting.
What do you want from me?
I have something important
to tell you, as your prince.
Prince?
You really...
You really were my prince.
You were crying
when we met...
You shed so many
glittering tears.
He’s right.
I was crying.
Was it really you?
Were you really
the one who saved me?
Do you wish for proof?
Proof?
Tell me,
was it not something like this?
He’s going to kiss me...
But... it was...
just like this...
Forgive me.
I was imprudent.
For two Duelists to act this way
before the Rose Bride...
Well, that important thing
I had to tell you...
Tenjou Utena.
I challenge you to a duel.
I...
...completely forgot
Kiryuu Touga is a Duelist.
But...
The prince who saved me
when I was little...
I came to this academy
so I could see him again.
And now my one and only link to the prince
forces me to fight him.
If only I didn’t have this ring...
Master Utena!
The tea is ready.
How did you like the lunch I made,
Master Utena?
Um, it was delicious.
Thank you.
Wakaba said
she liked it, too.
I’m delighted to hear!
Wakaba is very fun
to be around, isn’t she?
Yeah.
She always cheers me up
when we’re together. She’s a good friend.
Why not try and
make friends with her, too?
Oh, right.
You’ve got Chu-Chu.
He’s more fun
than a friend, or ten!
I...
I, too, wish I could
befriend her...
You can!
I know you can!
If you approach ‘em with an open heart,
I’m sure anyone would accept you.
Open heart?
Yeah. You’ll be okay.
I’ll help you out.
All right.
That’s right...
I have to protect Himemiya.
Only I can make her
back into a normal girl.
I can’t let anyone else have her.
Not even my prince.
Now, my son, stand over there
with this apple on your head.
Yes, Daddy! But...
Astounding, Daddy!
But that was shot number 37,919.
How long must we do this for?
Until a doctor’s stoppage is called.
Enough complaining, my son.
Stand over there
with this apple on your head!
Yes, Daddy!
But why hasn’t the nobleman
forgiven us after the first shot?
Don’t make me
think for myself!
Misery! O Misery! What fate awaits
the Tells, reduced to a target practice machine?
Do you know, do you know?
Oh, do you know their fate?
Aim a little higher, Daddy.
Uh, oh.
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
You’re here.
Do we really
have to fight each other?
Well, then...
Excuse my cutting into
your busy schedule.
Shall we begin, Tenjou?
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
Don’t hold back.
Underestimating your opponent
in a duel could prove fatal.
Take that to heart,
and advance!
A binding spell, sealed without a mark
An iron mask of misfortune
Tenjou Utena is nothing but
an amateur sword fighter.
But the Power of Dios
poses quite a problem.
Blue skies, seas, and the blowing wind
It is time, Tenjou Utena!
I can’t lose...
Grass, rabbits, and the flowing river
Show me the Power of Dios!
Time is—the ages are—unchanging
Time is—the ages are—existent and not
We say that our blood is what makes us humans
Humans, drowning in our own teachings
We say nothing deeper than “humans are humans”
Always the same
Seeing it by day
Was your prince not...
Missing it by night
Seeing it by night
...like me?
Missing it by day
Anagram
My prince...
A riddle of words, a mask of words
And they come from...
Dich!
This is fortunate,
is it not?
Your wish came true.
You no longer need to take part
in these meaningless duels.
Shall we go, Anthy?
Wait.
Don’t take Himemiya.
She wants to
go back to being a normal girl.
If I don’t stay by her side...
I don’t need the power to revolutionize
the world, but Himemiya needs me!
You don’t understand anything.
It’s true!
She told me
she wants friends!
Without me,
she’ll be all on her own again!
Anthy...
Yes?
You’re happy
as the Rose Bride, are you not?
I...
...am happy
as the Rose Bride.
You don’t want friends.
You like being alone, correct?
Yes, I like being alone.
This is how it works, Tenjou.
Himemiya Anthy is betrothed
to the victor of the duel.
While she was engaged to you,
the Code required her to obey you.
It’s not true...
The Rose Bride answers
her master’s wishes.
Making her a normal girl
was merely your own wish.
You’re lying to me...
Now that you have lost the duel,
the connection between you has been severed.
Forget everything.
Forget her, and forget this duel.
You’re lying!
Tell me he’s lying,
Himemiya!
Tell me the truth!
Didn’t you say
you hate being the Rose Bride?
That you want to make friends?
Didn’t you tell me all that?
Anthy, bid her farewell.
Have a wonderful day,
Tenjou.
No way.
No way...
No!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
I... lost...
Good morning, Tenjou.
Himemiya...
Is something the matter,
Tenjou?
Himemiya, how can you...?
I am the Rose Bride.
This is normal for me.
Just you wait, Himemiya!
I’m on my way to win back
the real you, and the real me!
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
For the Sake of Friendship, Probably
“Perhaps for Friendship’s Sake”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse