Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
How is it that this rose can bloom in the depths
of the Earth, so far outside the sun’s reach?
My black rose
absorbs the darkness.
You know...
I’ve heard Council President Kiryuu
has been missing school as of late.
That’s why the academy’s
been so quiet recently.
That’s a good thing.
A proper academy should be
a peaceful place of study.
The Boys of the Black Rose
Well then, I shall be going.
I’m back, Chu-Chu!
It’s Saturday, so me and
the rest of the class had some fun.
Your owner should’ve
been there with us.
She’s no fun.
Himemiya, I’m home.
Huh?
She’s not home?
Those are leftovers
from the party.
Man, I’m beat.
Now that I think about it, I barely ever
see Himemiya around on Saturday nights.
Chu-Chu, do you know
what the deal is with that?
Oh, Master Utena!
Welcome back!
Where’ve you been?
I was at school.
Ah, okay.
Y’know, it feels like you disappear most
weekend nights. You got something going on?
Yes. I was asked
to go visit at least once a week.
Visit who?
My older brother.
Hmm.
Huh?! You have a brother?!
Excuse us!
Oops. Wrong floor.
No, this is the right floor.
Oh?
So, is this
the Board Chairman’s office?
Looks super hard to keep clean!
It’s huge!
This your brother?
No, this is a planetarium projector.
Whoa...
Huh?
Master Utena?
Shh! W-We came at a bad time,
Himemiya!
They’re kinda busy right now.
Let’s scram
before we get in the way!
How do you do?
I’m Ohtori Akio.
Sorry.
I’m Tenjou Utena.
Sorry for...
Not at all.
I’m very glad you’ve come.
My sister has never introduced me
to one of her friends before, so I’m very happy.
No way... Your brother’s
the Board Chairman...?
Oh, no!
I’m only Acting Board Chairman.
The actual Board Chairman
is Kanae’s father.
Father is quite fond of Akio...
...and plans to let me marry him
as soon as I graduate from high school.
Well... Congratulations.
Oh, no, I keep telling her
it’s too soon, but...
I never thought the Board Chairman’s
office would look like this.
The truth is
my passion lies in stargazing.
You like stars, huh?
So much that
it’s almost abnormal.
Some people think he got himself
adopted into my family...
...just for access to this equipment.
I hear he stayed here
again last night.
I find the stars lovely!
When I use the telescope to observe the stars I’ve
come to know, they show me their hidden selves.
Spare a thought for me
once in a while, would you?
If I discover a comet,
I’ll name it after you.
Honestly!
Such a hopeless man...
I haven’t been here long,
but there is one thing I know for sure.
The students of this academy
are all free spirits, have a love for learning...
...and above all,
they never fight.
Correct?
Hope it always stays that way.
Nothing bad ever happens
at Ohtori Academy.
Well, see you soon,
Ms. Kanae.
Listen...
You can call me “sister”.
After all, I will formally become
your big sister very soon. Right?
Sure.
Thank you, Mikage!
Thanks to your paper...
...our research lab got picked
for the advisory board.
That was not my paper.
It was your work, professor.
Hey! Hurry up
and give him the gift!
My wife went to
a hot spring resort the other day...
...and she said
you simply must try these.
Hot Spring Resort Manjū
Come on!
Forgive me for
beating around the bush.
Toi Bank
This is only a pittance,
but please accept it.
Toi Bank
No need for such concern.
Instead, I may call upon you
for help someday soon.
Toi Bank
I’ll count on you then.
Of course! Consider anything
within our power already done.
Toi Bank
So that was the charismatic high schooler
who hosts the Mikage Seminar.
What an overpowering aura!
I lost my nerve!
The Mikage Seminar, also known as
the Black Rose Society...
It’s rumored that they even have a minister
among their ranks, and odds are it’s true.
That shouldn’t be surprising
to any of us. After all...
...the entire faculty reaps
plenty of benefits by associating with him.
The genius high schooler,
Mikage Souji...
Do tell...
Have you thought about
what we discussed?
I-I have...
I’ve been on the edge
of my seat. Well?
I very much appreciate
your kind offer, but...
...I simply think I’m not qualified
to be part of your seminar.
Steel
I see.
A mind like yours
is just what I was looking for.
Steel
But it is what it is.
If that is how you feel,
all I can do is accept it.
Let me know if you change your mind.
I’ll make it worth your while.
I’m very grateful.
I will be off.
Thank you kindly,
Master Utena.
Huh? For what?
For not telling my brother
about my secrets.
Oh, that.
I don’t want him to know anything
that might upset him.
Me being the Rose Bride,
or the Duelist’s Code...
I getcha.
It’s best we keep that stuff
from your brother.
Kanae seems nice, too.
I’d hate it if they got mixed up in all this.
C’mon, let’s go home.
Oh? Tenjou!
Himemiya!
Mickey!
Hello, hello.
Aren’t you supposed
to be free today?
We went to visit
Himemiya’s big brother.
Is that so?
The Board Chairman, yes?
What are you up to, Mickey?
Well, I had to look some things up
in the archives here.
Wow...
You sure like studying,
even on your days off.
I didn’t even know
this place existed.
You don’t know about
Nemuro Memorial Hall?
This building has
a rather unfortunate history.
“Unfortunate history”?
It’s said that, a long time ago,
one hundred boys were buried alive here.
You know, Mamiya...
It seems you are eligible
to be the Rose Bride.
Don’t you mean “groom”?
I am a boy, after all.
“Bride” suits you better.
I will make you into
a true Rose Bride.
I will attain
the Power of Dios...
...and make
the secret of eternity ours.
If you say so.
I know what I’m doing.
The End of the World
has acknowledged us.
But to do all of this...
...we must defeat Tenjou Utena,
obtain Himemiya Anthy...
...and then kill her.
Yes...
To that end,
we’ll need a strong Duelist.
Excuse me.
I have an appointment
for an interview today.
Interviewees, please fill out a form and await your turn.
- Nemuro Memorial Hall
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Sex
Address
Ohtori Kanae
18 yrs.
Female
Kanagawa Prefecture
Reception Booth
In use
High school third-year, class A.
Ohtori Kanae.
Now then, please begin.
Next spring,
as soon as I graduate...
...I will be getting married.
I will marry someone my father,
the Board Chairman, selected for me.
He... He’s very gentle...
He can be
a little childish, but...
Actually, he’s much more
mature than I am,
and he watches over me
so very warmly.
I would do anything for him.
I feel this way
from the bottom of my heart.
Except... Except...
Deeper... Go deeper...
Except...
he has a younger sister,
and no matter how hard I try,
I just can’t bring myself to like her.
There was this
thing that happened...
I gave her my beloved scarf
and said to use it...
...and she said “thank you”
and wiped her glasses with it!
I was completely taken aback...
And when I told her
it wasn’t a lens cloth,
she just stared at me
without saying a word and smiled!
Looking at her eyes
made my skin crawl...
...because she looked like
something not of this world!
And my father...
I can’t help but think his falling ill coincides
with when that pest started coming to our home.
I... don’t think I can keep smiling
around her any longer.
I’ve done all I can
to like her...
But I just can’t!
No matter what...
...I can’t!
I understand.
Your only choice
is to revolutionize the world.
A path has been prepared for you.
Where am I?
Hallowed ground.
A sacred place where
one hundred Duelists sleep.
This room leads to
the end of the world.
School ID: D-13.
Please look.
This Rose Seal...
You see? It’s black.
When its bearer dies,
its color changes like so.
Personally,
I find the black much more beautiful.
You can’t run now.
You’ve been chosen...
...by my black rose.
This is your new heart...
...and your rebirth.
This rose which reaches full bloom
only at the end of the world...
I bestow it upon you!
A Black Rose Seal...
Isn’t there anything fun
we can do?
We had a party
just this Saturday.
I don’t mean
something like that.
Something more exciting!
Our school’s too freakin’ quiet!
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
I wish something
really shocking would happen.
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
At last! At last! At last!
At last, what I feared
has come to pass!
Ain’t it too early for her?
My big sis is always
ahead of the curve!
Right, say “ahh”.
Ahh!
What shall we do
about this wisdom tooth?
Ahh!
Oh, what should I do?
...get it pulled?
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
What’s this...?
What the...?
Who are you?
Upon this black rose,
I swear...
...I’ll win this duel,
and once I emerge victorious...
...I’ll grant death
to the Rose Bride!
Kana— Kanae...?
Why...?
That is not Ms. Kanae’s normal self.
This is my true self.
The other self
which slept within.
So long as I have
this black rose,
I don’t have to play
my false self anymore.
That black rose is doing it?
Now, Tenjou Utena...
Draw your sword!
If you don’t,
the Rose Bride will be mine!
Be thou a spirit of health or goblin damn’d
Whether thou bringst with thee airs from heaven
Be the intents of hell’s heart wicked or charitable
The power to revolutionize the world!
Whether thou bringst with thee blasts from hell
Thou com’st in such a questionable shape, I bid thee
Speak to me!
This is nowhere near enough...
Put some effort in!
Kanae, the thing you said...
Swearing on the black rose
to win the duel...
Further, upon this night with a horrible moon,
...to grant death
to the Rose Bride!
thine soul revisit’st us so
Fine...
I see how it is.
So I’m not gonna hold back!
This mystery beyond human knowledge...
What?!
...makes us humans, dwarfed by nature,
tremble in fear at thy image
So that’s the Duelist
Tenjou Utena, hmm?
I see. No wonder The End of the World
has such high expectations.
A mere facsimile of a duelist
created when their heart is frozen...
...has no hope of defeating her.
Well, Master Utena...
Master Utena?
Huh?
I’m heading out now.
Oh right, today’s the day
you go see your brother.
See ya later.
Uh, Himemiya?
How’s Kanae been
after what happened?
Oh, she’s all better now.
Glad to hear.
But she really doesn’t
remember anything?
Correct.
Nothing that led up to the duel.
I see... Then I guess
she can’t tell us what happened.
Anyway, I’m really sorry for hurting
your future sister-in-law.
Don’t let it trouble you.
You weren’t at fault,
Master Utena.
Thanks.
Sorry for keeping you.
Well, say hi
to your brother for me.
I will.
Huh?
Chu-Chu,
you’re still here.
Aren’t you going with her?
Come here, Anthy...
Did you feel
lonely this week?
Yes, Big Brother.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Mickey’s sister, Kaoru Kozue...
Wow, they really are twins!
Wish I had a sibling.
I’m an only child,
so I’m jealous.
Yes, having a big brother is nice.
But I’m worried about these
Duelists with the black roses.
It seems like someone is
controlling their hearts.
Kozue! Why are you
in that outfit?
No way...
Not you, too!
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“The Landscape Framed by Kozue”
The Landscape Framed by Kozue
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.