isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
Utena-sama!
Good morning!
Morning!
So cool!
Ohtori
Academy
For Whom the Rose Smiles
Morning!
Good morning!
Someone’s love letter
got put up on the notice board!
Okay, what’ve we got here?
“And so, I dance with you
in my dreams, Saionji-san.”
Morning, Wakaba!
Pretty rare to see ya
with a book.
Whatcha readin’? Hey!
The whole way through...
The whole way through,
there was a guy she liked.
But she ended up
with a broken heart.
The next day, a different guy
conveniently appeared and got with the heroine.
When I read this a while back,
I was all like, “No way! This is boring!”
Now that I’ve read it again,
I think it’s pretty awesome!
I’ll just be yours instead, Utena!
Utena! Utena!
Utena-sama!
You’re all mine!
Um, Wakaba, can you cut it out
with saying I’m yours?
Why?
Good morning.
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
Have you received your new letters
from The End of the World?
Yes.
I received mine.
We all receive his letters...
...and carry out
the instructions within.
As it is written in this letter, Saionji faced defeat yesterday...
...and the Rose Bride became engaged
to the girl who won the duel.
Was someone outside the Student Council
receiving letters from The End of the World?
Who’s to say?
However, she wears the Rose Seal.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Who is this girl?
Tenjou Utena.
She’s rather well known among
the middle school students. Quite popular.
Very gallant and lovely...
This isn’t funny! Another participant
just gets added without us knowing?
If this happens again...
If it happens, what will you do?
Drop out of the game?
The letters are only ever one-sided
messages from The End of the World.
Whether or not we obey them
is our decision.
When we opened the door
to the arena with these Rose Seals,
the illusory castle appeared,
just as the letters said it would.
I know.
I couldn’t drop out
after seeing that.
Indeed. As the letters
from The End of the World say:
“The one to win the duels
and become engaged to the Rose Bride...”
“...shall eventually reach the castle and
receive the power to revolutionize the world.”
And that is why
we must continue to fight.
To think that best friends like us
got assigned separate rooms...
God can be so cruel!
What can you do?
It’s what the Student Council decided.
Anyway, I heard I got a room to myself,
which suits my cool self just fine.
But since no one’s used the east dorm
in more than ten years,
cleaning it up
will be tough for sure.
Ten years?
Well, I’ll bet cleaning it on your own
will suit your cool self just fine.
Anyway, my room’s on the
third floor of the south dorm.
Drop by when you get sick
of the haunted house.
Fare thee well!
Huh? Haunted house?
What’s the big deal?
It’s a nice building.
Sheesh.
Wakaba must’ve just been
trying to scare me.
Hello!
Tenjou Utena here!
Nobody home?
Don’t tell me
I’m the only one living in this dorm!
Let’s see, the farthest room
on the second floor...
Ten years, huh?
It’s possible.
All right!
Pardon me, Utena-sama.
I’ll be finished shortly.
What are you doing here?
I request that you allow me
to live by your side from now on.
I am in your care.
Same.
But this is a one-person room, isn’t it?
Tenjou Utena
Himemiya Anthy
Guess not...
Tenjou Utena
Himemiya Anthy
Suddenly sharing a room with you
is a strange twist of fate, huh?
It looks pretty well cleaned.
Sorry you did all the work.
I cleaned most of it last night.
But they only just announced
the dorm assignments, right?
Us sharing a room
is no coincidence.
It’s the Code of the Rose Seal.
I am the Rose Bride,
and as such...
Bride?
...I am to be engaged
to the winner of the duel.
Are you okay with that?
Let me ask one thing...
What in the world are
the mirage castle and that trick sword?
Quite mysterious, aren’t they?
“Aren’t they?” You mean
you don’t know what they are, either?
Why would you do all this
if you don’t even know anything?
Why do you always
dress like a boy, Utena-sama?
This...? I just kinda like it.
It’s the same for me.
Does having us here
bother you?
I wouldn’t really
say that, but...
Huh? Who’s us?
Allow me to introduce you.
This is my friend, Chu-Chu.
Your pet?
My friend.
Oh, my goodness!
Here ya go.
Nice to meet you, Chu-Chu!
I’m Tenjou Utena.
Will you be my friend, too?
This is the first time Chu-Chu has taken
a liking to another person, Utena-sama.
Look, can you please cool it
with the “Utena-sama”?
But I’m engaged to you,
Utena-sama.
That again...
That Saionji guy was
wearing a ring just like mine.
Do you know what this is?
All the members of the
Student Council wear them.
It’s a Rose Seal.
Anyone who has that ring
is entitled to participate in the duels.
So, since you are
the current champion,
one by one, the other bearers
of the Rose Seal will challenge you to duels.
You’ve gotta be kidding!
No way I’m gonna keep fighting
those pointless duels!
Oh, it’s you, Mr. President.
Am I disturbing you,
Mr. Vice President?
No. You are technically
a member of our club.
Is the captain of the Kendo Club
going to fight the middle schooler again?
Of course.
The power to revolutionize
the world is mine.
It’s wrong that the Bride
should be engaged to a mere girl like her.
That’s just how it is.
No matter what you say, she...
Himemiya Anthy...
...will be engaged
to the victor of the duel.
No!
She belongs to me!
She said she would
obey me forever.
I even have it written down
in our exchange diary.
You kept an exchange diary?
Great... Are me and that girl
really the only ones in this dorm?
Is this also part of that
Code of the Rose Seal?
Chu-Chu,
go get her quickly!
If she doesn’t show soon,
I’ll have to eat all alone in this great big hall.
Why, Anthy?!
Why won’t you obey me?!
I’m sorry, Saionji-senpai.
I’m engaged to
Utena-sama now, you see?
But when we were engaged, didn’t you
swear to devote yourself to me completely?
Yes, but that is all in the past.
My engagement to you is over.
Please give up on me.
Do you know no shame?!
Could you be
more shameless?
You’re the shameless one!
You again...
Just as well.
I let my guard down
during our duel.
Why don’t we settle
once and for all...
...who shall
possess the Rose Bride?
We’ll have a rematch in the arena
tomorrow after school.
Ridiculous.
I’m not about to fight a duel
for no reason!
I fought you yesterday
for Wakaba!
For my friend!
I don’t care about this
Rose Bride stuff!
Even if you don’t, I do.
If you intend to remain engaged
to the Rose Bride as a Duelist...
...then you cannot refuse!
Those who disobey the rules of the
Student Council cannot remain at the academy.
Those are the school’s regulations.
Fine, I accept!
I’ll meet you in the arena
after class tomorrow!
I thought you weren’t
fighting any more duels.
No choice. Apparently, if I don’t fight him,
I won’t be able to stay at the academy.
I’ll just lose on purpose.
There shouldn’t be a problem with that.
Yes... Do as you please.
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
There’s gonna be another duel
in the forest behind the school today!
It’s time we settled this.
Bang!
I’m done for...
But it’s okay,
‘cause I lost on purpose.
But, but, O Brave Hero...
Of how hard it is
to lose on purpose...
...have you heard them speak?
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard them speak?
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyakumawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
zettai unmei mokushiyami
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
You know the rules.
The one whose rose is stricken
from their chest loses, right?
Do be careful.
Sure.
It’d be stupid to get hurt
in a duel I’m losing on purpose.
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
tentai jidai genshi no kaiyou
A celestial age, the primordial sea
shin shoku taiseki
Erosion, sediment
sanjuu oku nen seimei tanjou chi shitsu jidai
3 billion years, the genesis of life: a geological age
kanburia orudobisu shiruru debon
Cambrian, Ordovician, Silurian, Devonian
I have you now!
sutorosu toraito bakuteria korenia
Stromatolite, bacteria, collenia
Some guts you’ve got...
Valuing that rose
more than your own life.
sanjou juraki hakuaki
Triassic, Jurassic, Cretaceous
You understand, yes?
Alive or dead,
it doesn’t matter.
hikage no kazura iwa hiba
Lycopodium clavatum, Selaginella tamariscina
The one to lose their rose
loses the duel.
pureuromeia
Pleuromeia
kaitonia bennechitesu
Caytonia, Bennettitales
anmonaito
Ammonite
umi no bara umi no yuri
Marine Rose, Marine Lily
We call it the Sword of Dios,
but it does not have any special powers of its own.
umi ringo umi tsubomi
Marine Apple, Marine Flower Bud
It’s a champion’s sword,
to be wielded by the best!
umi tenshi umi kagami
Marine Angel, Marine Mirror
I let my guard down yesterday,
but we clearly have a vast gap in skill!
umi tobira umi kagerou
Marine Doorway, Marine Haze
sekitan nijouki koseidai
Carboniferous, Permian, Paleozoic
umi no anata umi no watashi
Marine You, Marine Me
Both the sword
and Anthy belong to me.
They are flowers blooming just for my sake.
Just for Saionji Kyouichi.
nikutai no naka no koseidai
The Paleozoic within the flesh
iki tsuzukeru
Continuing to live,
Prepare yourself!
shini tsuzukeru
continuing to die
katarikakeru koseidai
The Paleozoic tells a story
kujira no youni
Just like a whale...
iruka no youni
Just like a dolphin...
azarashi no youni
Just like a seal...
umi no soko he umiwatashi
...the Marine Me, to the bottom of the ocean
umi no soko no dai rekishi
The grand history at the bottom of the ocean
boku ga boku suru umi no soko
The bottom of the ocean, which makes me myself
anmonaito
Ammonite!
What was that just now?
Was that the power
to revolutionize the world?
The Power of Dios?
Weren’t you going to
lose on purpose?
I didn’t do it for you.
I did it for Chu-Chu.
If you ended up with Saionji,
he’d probably pick on Chu-Chu, right?
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
That’s great, Himemiya!
You got nominated
Queen of the Dance?
But I’m not going.
I won’t know anyone there.
All the more reason to go!
You’ll get to make lots of friends!
If you insist, Utena-sama.
But behind this party
lies a trap.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“On the Night of the Ball”
On the Night of the Ball
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.