isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
Hey! Did you hear
about Saionji?
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
The following student has been
punished with expulsion for flagrant
violation of the academy’s code of conduct:
High School 2nd Year, Class A
Saionji Kyouichi
Provost, Ohtori Academy
Yeah, I heard!
The heck did he do?
He got expelled?
That fool...
Starting a personal duel to take the Rose Bride
without permission from The End of the World...
Does he have no shame?
I thought
he might do it eventually,
but now that he has,
can I really say that it was in character?
Ultimately, he turned out to be
the clown of the Student Council.
I’ll do everything I can as fast as I can
to get your expulsion overturned.
Sorry to add
to your troubles, but...
Your exchange diary
with Himemiya?
Say no more.
I’ll make sure to get it to her.
I’m sorry to keep
being a nuisance until the very end.
Don’t worry about it.
We’re best friends,
after all.
Nanami’s Precious Thing
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
We are the chick.
The egg is our world.
If we do not break the world’s shell,
we will die without being born.
Break the world’s shell.
To revolutionize the world!
We’ve received a new letter
from The End of the World.
Another duel approaches.
Following turn order,
Touga would be next, but...
Touga-senpai’s wound
isn’t healed yet.
I’ll fight in his stead.
You’re no match for Utena.
I’ll go.
This time,
I’ll crush her for sure!
I’m going.
Please stay out of this,
Juri-san.
What?
Don’t be hasty, you two.
There is another Duelist.
That’s unthinkable!
You mean to say that, in addition to ourselves
and Utena, there was another with the right to duel?
Chosen by
The End of the World?
My brother got hurt
because of you!
All because of you!
Why aren’t you
saying anything?!
Why did my brother have to get hurt
saving someone like you?!
I’m sorry.
If I was more alert,
none of this would’ve happened.
I’m sorry.
Don’t give me that!
My brother won’t get better
just from you saying you’re sorry!
Nanami!
Nanami.
Brother...
My injury isn’t worth
this much fuss.
Besides, rescuing imperiled ladies
is the duty of a knight.
Prez...
As long as you’re safe,
I’m satisfied.
I won’t forgive you.
I will never, ever forgive you!
Don’t worry.
Nanami is just upset.
Deep down,
she knows you weren’t at fault.
Is it really true
that a girl can’t be a prince?
What’s wrong?
You seem depressed.
Not like it’s for no reason.
The Student Council President
got hurt protecting me, after all.
I wonder if
everything is all right.
That’s what I’m worried about.
Guess I should go
give him a visit, yeah?
I haven’t even thanked him
for saving me.
Oh, of course!
Are you hungry by any chance?
Thanks, but I don’t really want
shaved ice right now.
What are you doing?
Tell me,
what do you think we should...
...call this little one?
So you were talking to...
If I may, Utena-sama...
There are a lot of roses
blooming now.
You are visiting him, right?
Himemiya...
Surely, no one would ever be
displeased to receive flowers.
Thanks.
Happy birthday,
Touga-sama.
Happy birthday.
Big Brother...
Nanami, what happened?!
Just look at you!
This is for my big brother.
Ugh, it’s so filthy!
Get it out of here!
But, Mommy...!
Give it to Daddy.
No!
Wait a minute!
Thank you, Nanami.
This is the best present ever.
My brother was always
so nice and protective...
His smile was for me alone.
Big Brother, you shouldn’t!
You’ll reopen your wound!
I’m all right.
I’ll be out of shape
if I don’t exercise.
If you push yourself,
you’ll only get hurt!
Please, stop!
Hey, you don’t have to
get so worked up.
Please stop...
If anything ever
happened to you, I would...
Nothing is going to happen
to your big brother.
Right?
A kiss...
Aren’t you going to
give me a kiss?
I couldn’t possibly.
We’re no longer children,
you know.
You look surprised.
Well, I’m heading off to sleep.
Good night, Nanami.
Huh? The Prez isn’t here?
Apparently he said
he’d be absent today.
I see...
But you can always
see him at the party.
Party?
Tonight, at his house.
Even if he’s skipping class,
he has to be there.
Happy birthday, Touga-sama!
Here, a gift from both of us.
It’s a birthday party...
Weren’t you aware?
Were you?
Yes.
You can tell us already,
can’t you?
Who’s this other Duelist?
Come, now.
This is my birthday party, you know.
No need to spoil the festivities
by talking about The End of the World.
The duel is scheduled
for tomorrow night.
Relax. The stage is already set.
Hello! Glad you could join us.
What’s that?
Don’t get the wrong idea.
I’m just here
to wish you well.
Plus I never said thanks
for saving me.
What’s so funny?
Forgive me. I was just thinking that
it’s so typical of you to give an excuse like that.
You making fun of me?
No, I’m just very happy
to have you here.
What’s that supposed to mean?
What a shameful woman!
Is this your way of
trying to seduce my brother?
Nanami!
Give it a rest already!
You give it a rest,
Big Brother!
She is the one that hurt you!
That’s not true!
It was...
Please don’t be upset at
Utena-sama.
It was all Saionji-senpai’s—
Quiet!
You’re the root
of all of this, anyway!
Stop!
What are you doing?
I’ll never let you have him.
I’ll never let someone like you
have my brother!
Is that true?
Touga and Utena?
Well, that’s surprising...
No!
There’s nothing between us!
Is it because
I always spoil her?
It’s a bit weird
for me to be saying this,
but Nanami seems to have never
grown out of her brother worship phase.
Having the best
older brother in the world...
...makes everyone else
look like small fry.
Miki’s words?
Who knows?
He talks too much.
This reminds me
of another birthday.
Nanami didn’t have a present lined up for me,
so she went and found me a kitten.
A kitten?
Although the kitten
disappeared soon after,
no other present I received
made me happier.
Um...
I missed my cue
to give you this.
Hey! Cut it out, you!
Do you not like cats?
On the contrary! Thank you.
What a lovely present.
Go away!
Big Brother!
Come help me pick some apples!
Later.
But I can’t reach them.
Please, Big Brother?
You’re so annoying.
I’m playing with this little guy now.
Bad cat!
Leave him alone!
He was only playing.
But...
Go away!
This is your fault.
You came between me
and my big brother.
My brother belongs to me
and only me.
Stop right there,
Nanami-kun!
Do you know
what you’re doing?
You won’t run from this,
will you, Tenjou-san?
If you stir up trouble,
even you’ll wind up
getting expelled just like Saionji.
I don’t care.
We have to follow
the academy’s rules.
Nanami, your left hand.
Brother...
Have you forgotten,
Nanami?
The only ones authorized to duel at this academy
are those who wear the Rose Seal.
Now show me your power
as The End of the World’s chosen.
You mean...
Nanami-kun is also a Duelist?
Tomorrow night,
at the arena,
you will have a duel.
Look, look!
I found a kitten.
I wonder what I should name it.
How does “Mittens” sound?
That’s far too ordinary.
Surely, there must be something
more unusual.
“Unusual Mittens”!
No, not like that.
Something
with a bit more flair...
“Unusual Mittens With Flair”!
I said, not like that!
Isn’t there anything cute, yet classy,
but also memorable?
“Cute ‘n’ Classy Memorable
Unusual Mittens With Flair”!
Oh, fine!
If you think “Mittens” is so good,
then “Mittens” it is!
Come here, Juliano.
Ugh, I said it’s fine
if it’s not cute!
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyakumawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
zettai unmei mokushiyami
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
Do we have to do this?
The two of you are eyesores...
always hanging around my brother!
I challenge you,
Tenjou Utena!
O Rose of the Noble Castle...
O Power of Dios
sleeping within me...
Heed your master;
now is the time to manifest...
The power to revolutionize the world!
She’s quick!
Don’t underestimate me.
For the past 13 years,
I’ve been watching my brother.
chikyuu no hajimari butai souchi
Genesis of the Earth, stage props
rapurasu seiun kankyakuron
Laplace’s nebula, spectatorship theory
fuhen no gensou nazotoki dokei
An immutable illusion, a riddle-solving clock
I know everything
there is to know about him.
fumetsu no hate no ubaguruma
The baby carriage at immortality’s edge
Meaning I know
his sword techniques, too.
eien no watashi
My eternal self
You can say our fighting styles
are one and the same!
I even received this ring
from my prince!
eien no tanin
The eternal stranger
My prince will lead me
to victory!
That’s not gonna happen!
futatsu no kankei futatsu no tanjou
Two relations, two births
shinpi no tenbin jintai seiza
A mysterious scale, a constellation of the human body
Fight’s over.
The fight has only just begun.
You can’t do that,
Nanami-san!
Per the rules, you’ve lost
once the rose is stricken from your chest!
toki wa kasetsu gensou no
Time is a hypothetical illusion...
I don’t give a damn!
umare hajime no butai souchi
...of the newborn stage prop
unmei sentaku gubbairon
Destiny, choices, the theory of goodbyes
watashi to anata wa amanogawa
You and I are the Milky Way
kakonashi tada genzai mirai nashi
No past, no future, we live solely for today
teatoru uchuu ni tada hitori
All alone in the theater of the cosmos
Quit it, Nanami!
There’s no point fighting like this!
That’s me! Wait!
My last evolution, revolution, everlution!
That’s enough!
This is your fault.
You came between me
and my big brother.
Nanami...
I can still win!
I haven’t lost yet!
Silly girl...
Nanami... There’s no need
for you to fight any longer.
I will protect you.
Brother!
Forgive me...
Forgive me, Big Brother!
It’s okay. It’s okay now.
So you can
act like a good brother sometimes.
I can’t ignore
a damsel in distress.
toki wa kasetsu gensou no
Time is a hypothetical illusion...
It’s just the prince in me.
umare hajime no butai souchi
...of the newborn stage prop
unmei sentaku gubbairon
Destiny, choices, the theory of goodbyes
I’ve gathered
all the data I need.
watashi to anata wa amanogawa
You and I are the Milky Way
The Power of Dios
will be mine.
kakonashi tada genzai mirai nashi
No past, no future, we live solely for today
teatoru uchuu ni tada hitori
All alone in the theater of the cosmos
That’s me! Wait!
My last evolution, revolution, everlution!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Can it be that Kiryuu Touga
really is my prince?
I...
Stop it! She’s just a normal girl
called Himemiya Anthy!
I am...
I forgot he’s even
a Duelist. But...
I am the Rose Bride.
Are you aware of everything
that entails, Utena-sama?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Graceful and Ruthless -
The One Who Picks the Flower”
Graceful and Ruthless -
The One Who Picks the Flower
“Graceful and Ruthless -
The One Who Picks the Flower”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.