Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
And so, even the black roses
are down to the last flower.
But I wonder,
will he step in and fight?
Nemuro Memorial Hall
We must find out
who they are at once!
They aren’t trying to take
the Rose Bride.
They’re trying to kill her!
Needless to say, it is our duty
to maintain order in the academy,
as representatives of the student body
and executives of the Student Council.
Seriously...
Who are these people?
Manipulating ordinary students and making them
duel Tenjou Utena one after another...!
You sound irritated.
Is it because your friends,
and even Touga, have been targeted?
Always keeping yourself
in the know, aren’t you?
But if your network of information
is that good,
then I want you to find out
who these people are, and now!
We have one clue.
Only someone chosen by The End of the World
is supposed to have a Rose Seal.
So our lurker in the shadows
could in fact be The End of the World, right?
Who knows?
But if you think about
all the evidence,
it’s obviously someone
who has backing from The End of the World.
In any case, that someone
must be within the academy!
Sorry,
I couldn’t hear you very well.
Chu-Chu!
Here, Chu-Chu!
Man...
Where could he be?
Is this little one yours?
Oh, Chu-Chu!
You...
Thank you so much.
Did he cause you any trouble?
No.
I found him caught
in a mousetrap in the kitchen.
He was crying.
A mousetrap?
Could you behave
once in a while?
Ms. Tenjou Utena...
How do you know
my name?
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
I have been interested in you
for quite some time.
I’m Mikage Souji,
from the high school.
Mikage?
So you’re the genius high schooler
who runs the Mikage Seminar?
What do you say,
Ms. Tenjou Utena?
Wouldn’t you like to
join my seminar?
Huh? Me?
I— See, last test I took
was a make-up test.
This has nothing to do
with academic skills.
My seminar always seeks out...
...those with unique personalities.
You’re more than welcome
to come and look around.
This building is where
you hold your seminar, right?
Correct.
Nemuro Memorial Hall.
I imagine you’ve heard the tales
they tell about this building, yes?
Yeah...
If you’re thinking of the story about
one hundred boys dying here, that one is true.
Long ago, there was a man
called Professor Nemuro.
There was a fire here.
His students were trapped inside
and burned to death.
The building was later renovated
into the Nemuro Memorial Hall we have now.
Still...
...that happened long ago.
Excuse me!
Mr. Akio? Are you here?
He’s not here...
That’s weird.
It’s you...
All I did was
make a deal with you.
I have no obligation
to obey your orders.
True.
That is our contract.
Ever since that time...
It seems to be sticking around,
doesn’t it, Professor Nemuro?
Hmm? What does?
I was talking about the snow,
professor.
Stop calling me “professor”.
We’re not apart in age, you know.
Distinctions are important.
With a genius like you here,
this has really gotten off the ground.
Really, now...
You give me too much credit.
In any case, I didn’t think they would be
this extreme with the secrecy.
They treat us like
parts in a machine.
Didn’t you agree to that
in the contract with the academy?
But we don’t even know
what the section next to us is researching.
Rumors say it’s about
“the power to revolutionize the world”,
or some research on
“attaining eternity”.
Can’t you even give us a hint?
Even I know nothing
beyond the rumors.
And I care not to know more.
Incidentally, there’s something
I’ve been meaning to ask.
What is it?
What are those rings
you all wear on your left ring fingers?
They don’t have
a particular meaning.
They’re just the latest fashion.
So that’s the genius
Professor Nemuro?
And he really doesn’t know
about what we’re doing?
So it seems.
And yet... you-know-who
vouches for his intelligence.
His thesis is interesting,
but the man himself is pretty dry.
People who pretend to not care
about anything lack experience.
Let him put on airs
as much as he wants.
The man’s practically a computer.
We should get as much use
as we can out of him.
At the time,
I certainly was more computer than man.
Computers are peerless machines,
but machines on their own lack purpose.
The dry days of a dry man.
And it is also true that I was not very
interested in the research at that time.
The fact that what I was tasked with
wasn’t progressing...
...also made no difference to me.
You’re the research coordinator,
Professor Nemuro, right?
The Board of Directors sent me.
I’ve been assigned as the new inspector.
I’m Chida Tokiko. Pleased to meet you.
The streets around here are awful.
The slush must make things difficult.
Yes, well...
So, what did you need
that required me to come to your house?
Too strong...
The tea seems a little too strong... even though
I let it steep the same amount of time I usually do.
I wonder, is it possible
for an hourglass to run slow?
The job assigned to me
is proceeding as planned.
However, I can’t guarantee
that it will be completed.
I know you’re not the type of person
to take orders from others.
Genius is something divine.
Its essence can’t be tied down
to this world.
I’m not a genius.
Why are you working
on this assignment?
Purely for business reasons.
As it is, I think I’m doing more
than my contract calls for.
We have one hundred extraordinary boys
assembled at Ohtori Academy,
all pursuing this.
They say the research is a path to
the power to revolutionize the world,
or to attain eternity,
or something of the such.
To even think of
attaining eternity...
Makes it sound like they’re building
a perpetual motion machine.
People should be humbly grateful
for what God grants them.
But if it’s you, surely...
Excuse me just a moment.
Mamiya!
What are you doing?!
Weren’t you told
to rest in bed for the day?
Yes... But I got a little worried
about the roses.
Go back to bed right now!
Yes... In a moment.
There’s nothing I hate more than someone
who neglects their own well-being!
Sorry you had to see this.
Hurry up and go to bed.
Professor Nemuro?
You are...?
I’m Chida Tokiko’s
little brother, Mamiya.
For the longest time
I’ve really wanted to meet you.
Because of the interesting
and odd rumors?
They say I’m more computer than man.
I’ve read your thesis.
You’re the first person
I’ve ever looked up to aside from my sister.
My sister came to Ohtori Academy
to meet you.
I have to do this since
you won’t sleep like you’re told to.
I like it when you
give me injections.
Don’t say such silly things,
little troublemaker.
It’s for his sake...
that I involved myself in this.
There’s nothing left
but to accept there is no hope,
or so the doctors tell me.
But if that proves successful...
That has nothing to do
with medicine.
Even if it proves successful,
it’s not like it will cure your brother’s illness.
But...
Maybe I could
attain eternity for him.
I’m sorry
for crying like this.
No...
It feels like this is the first time
I’ve ever seen someone shed tears.
Is there someone in your life
who’s important to you?
Or is it perhaps impossible for someone
lauded as a genius to love another?
Indeed.
Up until today,
that had been the case.
Professor Nemuro has been
very eager about the project lately, huh?
The Board of Directors
sent an inspector, right?
She certainly seems to be
the right one for the job.
Well, you-know-who
never makes a pointless move.
Then, does the professor
still not know what this is all about?
Is it fine that
you’re not resting right now?
Yes. I feel a little better today.
I see.
The snow in this garden
seems to be sticking around, doesn’t it?
My sister was called away
by the Board of Directors,
so she’ll likely
be gone until evening.
That’s just as well.
Today, I’m here to see you.
Here. Do you like them?
They’re sugar-preserved roses.
My sister makes them.
These dried flowers
are like them, too.
She doesn’t like to see
the flowers stricken with age.
Like this, even short-lived flowers
can be made to last a little longer.
But...
I wonder if the flowers are happy
being forced to go on.
Eternity does not exist
in this world.
And yet...
...people find
the pursuit of eternity beautiful.
You don’t expect what your sister
and I are doing to succeed?
I look up to both of you,
and I’m grateful, too.
I should be going.
I’ll be back sometime.
Professor Nemuro...
I’ll be sure to tell my sister
that you’re worried about me.
You still can’t solve that equation?
Outsiders aren’t allowed in here!
There are no outsiders here.
That is, aside from you.
Huh?
That is the first step towards
the power to revolutionize the world.
That will set everything in motion.
Ridiculous...
How can you expect anyone
to do this?!
Isn’t that...
the ring everyone wears?
The Rose Seal.
The proof of a contract
made with me.
Contract?
Yes.
All one hundred boys who work here
are contracted to me.
That’s insane...
What is this contract?
Those boys bound by contract...
Why are you subjecting them to this?!
Besides that... Even if I do attain eternity
doing this, it won’t make her happy.
“Her”, hmm?
I leave you this Rose Seal.
Should you desire eternity,
put it on your finger.
Your one choice
is to revolutionize the world.
A path has been made ready for you.
Is it true?!
Did you do this?!
Were you... behind this?!
Yes.
Why?
How could you do this?
They had a contract.
Ancient creatures died and became fossil fuels,
like coal and petroleum.
Without that sacrifice, our present
civilization of energy would not exist.
Such sacrifices are always called for.
What are you talking about?
This is the first step
in the job you are advancing...
In soon opening the path to eternity
from this academy.
Mr. Nemuro...
Mamiya did
as he was supposed to.
Now I, too,
wish to attempt to attain eternity.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
It’s finished! An all-purpose robot
built from the very essence of science!
Robot does not age.
Robot does not tire;
catches monkeys.
You are superior to humans!
Robot is superior;
catches many monkeys.
You will never become worried!
Robot does not worry.
When a monkey is spotted,
it is caught promptly.
Robot does not feel lonely...
...because robot has
all the captured monkeys.
Robot can work indefinitely;
can catch many monkeys.
But looking at you
makes us feel lonely...
Robot has monkeys.
It’s you.
It’s been a long time.
The academy has changed a lot.
Just now, I saw
Professor Nemuro over there.
Look, you don’t have to do
what these mysterious people tell you to do!
But it isn’t up to me.
I am the Rose Bride,
after all.
Dummy!
There’s nothing I hate more than people
who don’t care about their own well-being!
Tokiko...
Just like you, he hasn’t
aged a day since then, has he?
Those who stay in this garden
we call our academy...
...will never become adults.
Whatever this is...
is wrong.
Are you leading a normal life?
I am.
My husband is a kind person.
He’s good to me.
What brought you here today?
I came to visit my little brother—
Mamiya’s— grave.
Say... Surely you know that to bear fruit,
flowers have their petals stricken from them.
Indeed.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Ms. Kanae, Kozue, Wakaba...
Who could be the puppet master
pulling their strings and making them fight?
I’m afraid I myself
don’t know.
Oh, yeah...
That genius high schooler from Nemuro
Memorial Hall said he’d help me with anything.
Mikage Souji... Guess I’ll try to
work up courage to ask him.
Sure. Whatever you wish, Master Utena.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“The Qualifications of a Duelist”
The Qualifications of a Duelist
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.