isagiyoku kakkoyoku ikite yukou
Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
hikari sasu gaaden te wo toriai
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
chikaiatta nagusameatta
consoling each other, we swore:
mou koi wa nido to shinai yo tte
“Never again will we fall in love”
hoho wo yoseatte utsuru shashin no
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
egao ni sukoshi no sabishisa tsumekonde
smiles touched with a little loneliness
yume wo mite namida shite
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
kizutsuite mo
even enduring this pain,
genjitsu wa gamushara ni kuru shi
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
jibun no ibasho sonzai kachi wo mitsuketai
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
kyou made no jibun wo
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
isagiyoku nugisuteru hadaka ni naru
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
jiyuu wo mau bara no you ni
Like a rose spinning free!
tatoe futari hanarebanare ni natte mo
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
watashi wa sekai wo kaeru
I will change the world
Looking pretty as always,
Nanami-sama!
Nobody in this academy
can compare with you, Nanami-sama!
We’re so happy to have the privilege
of being in your company, Nanami-sama!
Pesky Insects
Ohtori Academy Middle School Entrance Ceremony
Hey!
You’re in the same class as us,
aren’t you?
If you’d like,
why don’t you join our group?
Let’s be friends.
What a wonderful
entrance ceremony, Nanami.
Big Brother!
That’s Kiryuu Touga-sama!
That’s right! It’s Touga-sama,
the president of the Student Council!
Then that girl is...
Touga-sama’s... little... sister?
So dreamy...
Oh, what a wonderful encounter!
I feel like meeting Nanami-hama
changed my life!
We’re lucky we were
the first to talk to Nanami-sama.
We have to be grateful.
Nanami-sama had so many to pick from
and she chose us.
Yeah!
We were chosen
to serve Nanami-sama!
You’re right, Aiko!
Keiko! Yuuko!
From now on,
let’s work together and try our best!
Let’s!
We’re the chosen ones!
Let’s do it!
That’s it! A party!
Why didn’t I think of it sooner?
I’ll throw an extravagant party
to cheer my brother up!
And it must be extravagant!
Given the circumstances,
I won’t be selective.
Every big name in the entire academy
will be graciously invited!
Oh, Kiryuu-san?
You’re on day duty today, yes?
That will certainly
cheer my brother up!
Could you wipe the blackboard?
What a wonderful idea,
Nanami-sama!
Touga-sama has looked
so gloomy lately.
It’s so touching how much you worry
about your big brother!
K-Kiryuu-san?
The blackboard... Um...
Won’t you help me, girls?
Of course!
With pleasure!
A party?
If you would be so kind,
please do attend.
The Student Council is in crisis
and she’s doing this? Seriously...
Please come!
Nanami-sama is really worried
about Touga-sama.
Please come!
I’ll get to see Touga-sama
for the first time in so long.
Even though I know he won’t
take notice of a girl like me...
Touga-sama...
No matter what, I...
Aiko! Yuuko!
For Nanami-sama
and Touga-sama’s sakes,
we have to work ourselves to the bone
to get everything ready.
Right...
You’re really energetic today,
huh, Keiko?
Oh? I am?
That’s a new dress, isn’t it?
It looks good on you.
Really?
Yeah, really!
Don’t you agree it looks good, Aiko?
Yep! It’s super pretty!
Thank you, Yuuko, Aiko!
Well?
All preparations ready?
Y-Yes, ma’am.
Not sure how,
but we managed.
Oh, yes, Keiko-san.
I have a teensy favor to ask.
What is it?
It’s a bit silly of me,
but I completely forgot...
...that I have some Student Council
paperwork to put together tonight.
I’m sorry, Keiko-san,
but would you go do it for me?
But the party...
Everything is ready, right?
Yea— Yes...
Then I don’t see a problem.
The paperwork is at school.
Well, go get to it right away.
Um... Nanami-sama?
Is something wrong?
No...
Then, if you’d be so good.
Yes, ma’am.
I have...
...always...
...watched Touga-sama
from the sidelines.
Always...
The only one who can get near the prince
is a fairy tale princess.
Touga-sama...
He lives in a different world from mine.
That’s right.
A girl like me...
Touga looked better
than we thought, didn’t he?
But he still doesn’t show up
at the academy.
The way he is, I bet you guys
in the Council aren’t doing great...
My, are you so worried
about my brother...
...that you sneak around
and spy on him?
Disgusting!
Don’t be stupid!
Who’s sneaking around?
My, playing dumb, are we?
You were just talking about him!
You’ve got some nerve!
Meow, meow, meow!
Meow!
I went to the party
‘cause I was invited!
Goodness!
That’s no reason to gloat.
Haven’t you heard of the ugly friend effect?
Some people have such nerve!
Now, look...
Remember your place
in the pecking order, why don’t you?
You’ve said it!
I can’t stand the thought of someone
like you hanging around my brother.
That’s right!
Any and all insects swarming around
my brother will face my wrath!
Shall we go, girls?
I apologize, Tenjou-senpai.
No need to be sorry, Mickey.
Happens all the time.
I’m so sorry!
Um, was I asleep? Was I?!
Chu-Chu was crying all night, huh?
You see, in Japan,
the Pleiades open star cluster...
...is known as “Subaru”, and even gets mentioned
in “The Pillow Book” by Sei Shounagon.
You know so much about it,
Utena-sama.
Nah, I was just repeating
what Akio-san said.
He’s been teaching me
a whole lot lately.
Has he?
Quite lovely,
those winter constellations.
Big Brother.
Friendship is beautiful.
The Gemini, Castor and Pollux, are said to be
faithful companions to one another, but...
...the way you watch the stars together,
you look even more beautiful than the Gemini.
Oh, you’re kidding...
Well, I’m going.
Very well, Utena-sama.
Is that clear, Anthy?
You are to continue
being close to Utena-san.
Like the Gemini,
Castor and Pollux...
Very well, Big Brother.
What should I do?
Touga-sama’s getting drenched.
I could share my umbrella...
But a girl like me with him?
I’ll never...
have a chance like this again.
Um... Touga-sama?
If you please,
would take shelter with me?
It’s bad for you
to be out in the rain.
Nanami-sama?
Nanami-sama, it’s me.
Where are you?
Nanami-sama?
I’m here, Keiko-san.
Nanami-sama...
You said
you wanted to see me?
Sonoda Keiko-san, you are
hereby dismissed from all clubs,
your dorm’s self-government association,
culture circles, and any other groups you belong to.
Why is this happening,
Nanami-sama?
“Why”?!
Don’t play dumb!
I was so careless.
The real pesky insect
was right at my feet this whole time!
To think that I didn’t realize
until today...
Nanami-sama...
I’ve told you!
Any and all insects swarming around
my brother will face my wrath!
Any wicked insects like you...
...I will completely destroy.
No...
Do prepare yourself, Keiko-san.
Nanami-sama’s about to leave.
We should be leaving, too.
Yuuko! Aiko!
Please...
I need you two to get Nanami-sama
to change her mind!
You’re the only ones
I can rely on!
Please!
Did you hear something?
Not a thing.
I admired Nanami-sama
from the bottom of my heart.
That’s what I believed
as I served her...
But the truth is
that was dead wrong.
I was only with Nanami-sama so I could
get close to Touga-sama, even just the tiniest bit.
If not for that,
who’d deal with such a...?
Deeper... Go deeper...
Such a selfish little...!
I’m just one girl.
So what if I fall in love
with someone?
Why does a woman like her
have to hold me back?!
Just because she’s Touga-sama’s little sister,
she gets to be spoiled rotten by him!
Right to my face, too!
She has no idea
how I’ve felt all this time!
She doesn’t get it!
She doesn’t even try to get it!
I understand.
Your only choice
is to revolutionize the world.
A path has been prepared for you.
Where...?
Touga-sama...
Look at me.
From now on,
please have eyes only for me.
Tenjou Utena
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
There any pesky insects ‘round?
Eek! It’s a Namahage!
Nope! I’m a mantis!
Snip, snip, snip!
Everyone hurry up and run!
Run away, run away!
Snip, snip, snip, snip!
Run, run, run, run!
Snip, snip, shik, shik,
rip-rip-rip, shik, shik!
Run, run, r-run!
Run, run, ruuun!
Damn, we just can’t outrun it!
Take this insecticide!
The pain, snip!
That’s gonna kill us, too!
Thud!
That was air freshener.
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
shussei touroku senrei meibo
Birth records, baptismal registry,
shibou touroku
records of death
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
watashi no tanjou zettai tanjou
My own birth, absolute birth
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
yami no sabaku ni sanba uba
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
kin no mekki no tougenkyou
A gilded Shangri-La
hiru to yoru to ga gyakumawari
Day and night invert
toki no mekki no shitsurakuen
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
sodomu no yami hikari no yami
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
kanata no yami hatenaki yami
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
zettai unmei mokushiroku
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
zettai unmei mokushiyami
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
mokushiroku
Apocalypse
mokushi kushimo shimoku kumoshi moshiku shikumo
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
You’re...
Upon this black rose,
I swear...
...I’ll win this duel and grant death
to the Rose Bride!
You’re...
With Touga-sama’s sword
I will defeat you!
Touga’s sword?
For my future with Touga-sama,
I will fight!
Now!
Draw your sword!
Vanish! Fade away! Melt away!
kieusero
Get the hell away!
ari to arayuru monotachi yo
Every last one of you
The power to revolutionize the world!
Vanish! Fade away! Melt away!
kieusero
Get the hell away!
insutanto no nisemonotachi yo
Cookie-cutter fakers, all of you
Why are you...?!
By now you’ve gotta know all about
the kind of woman Nanami is.
nozomi ni uragirirare
Betrayed by desires
She doesn’t even see
someone like me as a person!
I served her
even though I knew that!
kibou ni fukushuu sareru
Avenged by hopes
But I don’t get it.
Why Touga’s sword?
konna jidai wa mou unzari da
I’m fed up with this day and age
It doesn’t matter
if you get it or not!
boku wa nigeru
I’ll run away
minna kiero
Everyone, get lost!
Can you beat this sword,
Tenjou Utena?
boku wa mou nanimo hoshikunai
I don’t want anything anymore
Touga-sama’s sword...
The noblest sword in the world!
With this sword,
I’ll attain great power...
...and then I’ll kill that bitch!
The one standing between
Touga-sama and me; that Nanami!
mujin no saidokaa ni matagatte
Aboard a sidecar with no driver,
kuusou ryokou sanzenri
imagining a long journey of three thousand li
That’s right...
The real pesky insect...
is Nanami...
chikatetsu kousoku hikoujou
Subway, highway, runway
I see it now...
That bitch is the pesky insect.
yukuzo jisoku hyakkiro no
Here I go, at a hundred kilometers an hour
kaiketsu hayate toubousha
Hotshot, gale, fugitive
I don’t even know her name.
I thought
she was Nanami’s friend.
It’s scary...
...how the roots of hatred spread
under the surface, completely hidden.
Another failure...
Still, it was amusing
that she called her master an insect.
I’m happy just being around you,
Nanami-sama!
There’s no way someone like me could
consider falling in love with Touga-sama, right?
That’s right.
It’s unthinkable, given your place
in the pecking order.
You’ll be my follower forever,
won’t you, Keiko-san?
Yes, of course.
And we’ll always
be friends, Keiko.
Yup!
No matter what, right?
I just don’t get it...
The one with the tied hair
and curly bangs is Keiko-san.
The one with shoulder-length hair
that curls outward is Aiko-san.
The one whose hair curls in
around her cheeks is Yuuko-san.
That’s not
what I’m talking about.
How can she still be
Nanami’s friend?
Even though she’s carrying
those kinds of feelings...
That’s simple.
Huh?
If it’s for someone you love, you can quell
any feelings you have towards anyone else.
You can deceive yourself
as much as you need.
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
dakishimete honto no te de
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
ashita wo hiraku kagi wa reality
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
uso wo kowashi tsuzuketai
I want to keep on dispelling lies
kore ijou hanashi wo shitemo
Even if we keep talking,
anata ni wa mienai
there’s no way you’ll ever see
mukashi no hanashi ni sugaru
Adults who reminisce too much
otona ni wa iiwake ga niau
and excuses go well together
erabarenai tenshitachi ni
The rejected angels...
hane sae mo iranai
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
ashita no jibun ga suki to
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
shinjiteiru no shinjitai kara
and because I want to believe so,
uso ni kirawareteitai
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Hey, Himemiya...
You know that rumor about the hall where
a hundred boys went missing a long time ago?
Yes.
Apparently that rumor’s
actually true.
I heard there was a Professor Nemuro
here at Ohtori Academy,
and there was a fire
and all his students disappeared.
But that was
a very, very long time ago.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
Nemuro Memorial Hall
“Nemuro Memorial Hall”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.