Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Believe in miracles...
...so that your wish may come true.
You’re so cruel.
There are no such things
as miracles, and yet...
You must hate me
for being this kind of person.
Yes. I hate you.
Thorns of Death
Next!
Wow!
The captain’s so good!
She moves so gracefully
when she goes for a touché!
Next!
Those moves...
Her swordplay’s reached a new level.
She keeps getting
more skilled.
Next!
You were wide open!
That’s not like you.
Yes, I’m sorry...
I’ll drop it now.
Are you ready?
Ready!
There.
Thanks!
Follow your individual plans
for the rest of today’s practice.
Yes, ma’am!
Ooh!
You’re friends with Arisugawa?
Yes.
My name’s Takatsuki Shiori.
I went to this academy
until middle school,
but as life would have it,
I had to move away.
I just transferred back in
and I’ll be living in the dorms starting today.
I’m a returning student,
but I hope you will look after me anyway.
Count on it.
He’ll be happy to help, too.
How do you do?
Have you known
Arisugawa for a long time?
You could say that...
We’re not just old friends.
We practically grew up together.
Juri has always been
so wonderful...
So strong... So cool...
I can totally see that.
She always protected me.
Juri was my only friend...
She was the only one
I could trust wholeheartedly.
But... I don’t have the right
to expect that anymore...
Shiori...?
I’m so embarrassed!
I didn’t mean
to drone on like that.
Visit me whenever. I don’t have
a roommate, so I could use the company.
I thought I said to be careful.
The more beautiful the rose...
...the more dangerous its thorns.
Uh...
You did it on purpose, yes?
We need this rose’s thorns,
do we not?
Indeed.
With thorns from the most beautiful
and most dangerous rose,
we can defeat Tenjou Utena.
But how to go about
removing the thorns?
A careless touch,
and this is what you get.
That’s simple.
Even roses have
natural enemies: pests.
An insect’s venom?
I have to wonder
if it’ll work on this rose.
The trap has already been set.
So your sister drew a sword
from within you. Do I have that right?
That is correct.
And when she did it,
she was wearing a Black Rose Seal.
I see.
What I’m getting from your report is that
someone aside from us is after the Rose Bride.
Yes, that is correct.
I find that hard to believe.
Yet this is our reality. And it’s a powerful enemy
that won’t be easily vanquished!
Anyway, for a member of the Student Council
to let their guard down like that...
That’s because...
It was unexpected.
Hey, this thing
you’re always doing...
What does it mean?
Is this interrogation finished?
Hey, hey,
while we’re on the topic...
How did it feel?
What do you mean?
You know what I’m talking about!
Did it hurt?
P-Putting that aside...
We now have to decide what to do about this.
Any thoughts, Juri?
Juri?
Right...
Sorry.
I need to excuse myself for today.
Ever since then,
you’re first in his thoughts.
However, I have absolutely no regrets
about stealing him from you...
You must hate me
for being this kind of person.
Juri!
There’s something
I want to tell you.
Wait! Please, Juri!
Please wait!
I eventually
broke up with him, but...
...that doesn’t change the fact
that I stole him from you.
I don’t imagine
you’ll ever forgive me.
Still, I wish we could
return to those days.
As soon as I got back,
I felt nostalgic.
I realized every last corner of the school
is so full of memories.
Those times
were so much fun.
Me, you, and him...
The three of us...
Is that everything
you wanted to say?
If so, then I’ll be off.
I’ll just say this one thing...
I never had feelings for him.
Not now, and not then.
What do you mean...?
I mean what I said.
I was never in love with him.
So there is nothing for you
to concern yourself with here.
But, then...
Whose picture do you have
in that pendant?
You still keep it hidden
under your clothes!
It’s you.
You were talking to Shiori
up there, weren’t you?
What if I was?
I don’t know the story,
but why not just forgive her?
She’s a nice girl,
isn’t she?
You used to be close, right?
Plus, I think
she really trusts you.
You’re just like Shiori...
Cruelly innocent...
Meaning...?
Look.
This is none of your business.
What’s with her?
I had no idea Arisugawa
was that petty.
She didn’t have to
say it like that, for one.
You’re just like Ganymede,
the boy of the constellation Aquarius.
Innocent and pure.
But such innocence
can hurt others.
You should be careful.
She said something
kinda like that.
Everyone has something
they want no one to pry into.
Is that the way it works?
Believe in miracles...
Believe...
The insect’s venom has begun
to course through the noble rose.
Soon, the rose
will offer us its thorns.
I couldn’t discard your picture
because I was weak.
But I don’t
believe in miracles.
Takatsuki
You kidding me?
Is that so?
I know, right?
Wow!
That’s strange...
Was anyone in here?
Really...
This is Juri’s!
Interviewees, please fill out a form and await your turn.
- Nemuro Memorial Hall
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Takatsuki Shiori
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
Nemuro Memorial Hall
Interview Reception
Please fill out the following details:
Name
Age
Takatsuki Shiori
15 yrs
I’ve hated Juri
since we were children...
She’s talented, beautiful,
popular with everyone...
I was jealous
of what she had.
That’s right...
I loved him because I wanted to take
something she treasured.
That was all I was after.
So I... So I...
Deeper... Go deeper...
That’s not right!
Juri was so kind to me.
But I thought that was
her way of making fun of me...
I thought she was kind because
she pitied me for being plain and worthless.
It made me feel pathetic!
That’s why I wanted
my relationship with her to change.
But what I did with him made me
even more miserable than before.
I thought that that was
what I wanted!
But now...
Now, she and I are even!
No, I’ve won!
I always had a place
in her heart.
I’m the winner!
Oh, what to do?
Knowing my friend’s secret makes me
so happy that I can barely contain myself!
She suffered all alone,
ogling at my picture in secret.
Juri reduced to that?
Poor little thing.
No! This is just wrong!
How could you
look at me like that?!
Why did things
turn out this way?!
I understand.
Your only choice
is to revolutionize the world.
A path has been prepared for you.
What is this place?
Shiori?
Hey...
What is it now?
This.
Yours, isn’t it?
How did you...?
Did you look... inside?
If you simply asked,
I’d have given you a nicer picture.
So pretty...
I loved the look in your eyes
when I hurt you...
Shiori...
Don’t play games with me...
You’re supposed to be stronger than
everyone else, but now you’re like this...
Tenjou Utena
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
Tenjou Utena
To the betrothed: I shall await you
at the dueling arena this evening.
Extra! Extra! Extra!
I’m doomed!
I was keeping it a secret
but they all found out!
You have nothing to worry about!
I can’t take this.
No one would ever
call it embarrassing.
Really?
Of course!
People wear much odder things
than woolen underwear.
But most don’t wear
three pairs at once!
So I really am doomed!
Despite being known as a fashion icon,
I wear woolen underwear!
Three pairs at once, even!
No one will ever
want to marry me now!
What should I do?
Take ‘em off?
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
Birth records, baptismal registry,
records of death
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
I’ll win this duel and grant death
to the Rose Bride!
This I swear
upon this black rose.
Why are you...?
This is me.
The real me!
Not the loser living a life of misery
in the shadow of the blindingly radiant Juri!
The real me,
transcending that light...
Yes...
The me who controls Juri!
Two opposites infinitely reflect one another
in the space between two mirrors
Revealing their desires,
The power to revolutionize the world!
their fickle cruelty, their lies
Oh, there is not a soul...
Oh, in the darkness...
Why are you doing this?!
I thought you really admired her...
Oh, the sound of the waves...
Because I know!
Know what?!
I know Juri isn’t what
everyone thinks she is!
Just as shadows exist only through light,
I only exist in opposition to myself
And that
I’m stronger than her!
The reason for the onset of my loneliness is that
What does that mean?!
I only exist in opposition to myself
Twins
Sworn twins
That move...
It’s like her swordplay...
Mechanical twins
Nonexistent twins
Looks like
you finally get it.
To make the invisible visible,
But this next move...
will finish you off!
a mechanical world comes into view
With instruments of wonder and optical illusions,
The Earth is a museum of personas
The Earth is a display cabinet of personas
The Earth is a...
Another failure.
Nevertheless,
the insect’s venom is effective.
There will surely be
another chance to use it.
Really, Shiori, come on!
I don’t get it.
Why’d you break up with your ex?
You want me to tell you?
We do! We do!
I wonder if I should...
Shiori looks like
a whole different person.
Do you really think so?
Huh? I mean...
She’s no different.
Not even a little bit.
That’s just cold!
That’s talking
from experience!
Hello, Juri!
Hi.
So, then what?
So then I said,
“What the hell are you doing?!”
Seriously?!
Was I nasty?
Nah, you put him
in his place!
Yeah, that’s right!
In the end,
it’s back in my hands...
Even though
I managed to throw it away...
Why can’t I be stronger?
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Adult time, adult talk,
adult shops, the adult world...
What is the matter,
Master Utena?
They say when you’re an adult
you wanna go back to being a kid,
but when you’re a kid,
you can’t wait to be an adult.
Does me thinking that
mean I’m still a kid?
Why, Master Utena,
I am already an adult.
Huh? What do you mean
by “adult”...?
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
“Mitsuru’s Impatience”
Mitsuru’s Impatience
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.