Let’s live gallantly, let’s live with style
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
Take my revolution
In the sunlit garden, holding hands,
consoling each other, we swore:
“Never again will we fall in love”
In that photo, we’re cheek to cheek,
smiles touched with a little loneliness
Even in my dreams, even with my tears,
even enduring this pain,
even through reality’s frantic attacks,
I want to find my place and the worth of my existence
I’ll take the me I’ve been up until today...
...and bravely cast it all away, strip down to nothing at all
Like a rose spinning free!
Even if the two of us are torn apart...
I will change the world
Once upon a time...
...there was a young princess grieving
the deaths of her mother and father.
Before the princess appeared a traveling prince
mounted upon a white horse.
His appearance gallant
and his smile gentle,
the prince enveloped the princess
in the scent of roses...
...and gently wiped the tears
from her eyes.
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
“As a token to remember this day,
please take this.”
“We shall meet again,
will we not?”
“This ring shall guide you to me.”
Could the ring the prince gave her
be anything other than an engagement ring?
This was all well and good,
but so impressed was she by him...
...that the princess vowed
to become a prince herself!
But is that really okay?
Tracing a Path
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
Our meddlesome hero
has won yet another duel!
History is written
by the winners,
losers flop
like fish out of water.
The sway of a lily
in her step!
But, but O Brave Hero...
Hey, you!
Stop getting distracted!
Have you heard? Have you heard?
Oh, have you heard the news?
If the egg’s shell is not broken,
the chick will die without being born.
If the egg’s shell is not broken...
You’ve still not awoken?
Still here,
unable to break the egg’s shell?
Even the Student Council President
faced defeat.
In the end, she conquered
her seventh trial...
...the duel named “self”.
Seeing her covered in injuries,
yet still protecting the Rose Bride...
...brought back
some nostalgic memories.
I imagine even the Rose Bride
was slightly moved.
And now, it seems, you have begun
placing your hopes on her.
No, that’s not quite right.
Ever since her first duel
called “friendship”...
The unexpected one
with that Kendo Club captain...
You already had
expectations of her back then.
You’re captain of the Kendo Club,
aren’t you?
When? Where? Who? Which?
We’re gonna duel today
after school!
When? Where? Who? Which?
The power to revolutionize the world!
A bloodstream held by the cage of memory,
cradled in a thousand years of bliss
You’re pretty good...
...for a girl!
I am an actor, eternal metaphors
So, trying to be a prince
who saves damsels in distress?
Well...
A desert’s wintry Sphinx, Phinx
Wait a minute...
That trick sword...
Is it real?!
Of the flesh that is born and dies,
You challenge the Sword of Dios
with a useless wooden practice sword?
The Sword of Dios?
the sad winds tell you
You don’t know
about the Sword of Dios?
Who are you?
The holy actor, eternal metaphors
A prince on a white horse,
here to save the princess!
“Little one, who endures such hardship
all on your own...”
Margineaux of light and dark, fallen down to hell
“Please don’t lose your strength and nobility
even when you grow up.”
Brightly burn!
What?!
Awaken and sing!
Fool!
Born into the world, born into an instant
An endless cycle!
Impossible!
I... lost...?
Anthy!
Have a wonderful day...
...Saionji.
Man, this has been
one really weird day.
What was all that about?
Better to just forget about it.
You...
I’ve been waiting for you,
Master Utena.
I am the Rose Bride.
From this day forward,
I am your flower.
As you anticipated...
...she became engaged
to the Rose Bride...
...and began to walk
the path of the Duelist.
And then she faced
the second trial...
...the duel called “choice”.
It’s a Rose Seal.
Anyone who has that ring
is entitled to participate in the duels.
So, since you are
the current champion,
one by one, the other bearers
of the Rose Seal will challenge you to duels.
You’ve gotta be kidding!
No way I’m gonna keep fighting
those pointless duels!
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
My own birth, absolute birth
Apocalypse
A midwife amid the desert of darkness, a wet nurse
A gilded Shangri-La
Day and night invert
A time-gilded Paradise Lost
Darkness of Sodom, darkness of light
Darkness beyond, darkness unending
The absolute destiny: apocalypse
The absolute destiny: apocalyptic darkness
Apocalypse
apocalyp calypapo lypapoca caapolyp apolypca lypcaapo
A celestial time scale, the primordial sea
The power to revolutionize the world!
Erosion, sedimentation
3 billion years, the birth of life: a geological time scale
Cambrian, Ordovician, Silurian, Devonian
I thought you weren’t
fighting any more duels.
No choice. Apparently, if I don’t fight him,
I won’t be able to stay at the academy.
Stromatolite, bacteria, collenia
I have you now!
Triassic, Jurassic, Cretaceous
You’re not bad.
Lycopodium clavatum, Selaginella tamariscina
I’ll just lose on purpose.
There shouldn’t be a problem with that.
Pleuromeia
Caytonia, Bennettitales
We call it the Sword of Dios,
but it does not have any special powers of its own.
Ammonite
It’s a champion’s sword,
to be wielded by the best!
Sea Rose, Sea Lily
I let my guard down yesterday,
but we clearly have a vast gap in skill!
Sea Apple, Sea Bud
Sea Angel, Sea Mirror
Sea Gateway, Sea Haze
Carboniferous, Permian, Paleozoic
Sea You, Sea Me
Both the sword
and Anthy belong to me.
They are flowers blooming
just for my sake.
The Paleozoic within the flesh
Prepare yourself!
Continuing to live,
continuing to die
The Paleozoic tells a story
Just like a whale...
Just like a dolphin...
Just like a seal...
...the Sea Me, to the bottom of the sea
The grand history at the bottom of the sea
The bottom of the sea, which makes me myself
Ammonite!
It was from that moment
that your power,
the Power of Dios,
finally began unsealing itself.
Certainly, that girl
is quite fascinating.
Your power...
She may even herald
the complete rebirth of the Power of Dios.
The subsequent battles
were all highly unique.
I could never
match that timbre.
I have to recapture that music.
Theater
Exceptional minds
Collective phenomenon
And so, I need the Bride
no matter what!
Theater
Exceptional people
Imagined reality
Sitting at a piano
suits you better.
An operating table, a wrecked ship
A genuine play, the spira mirabilis
Whirlpools, spirals
Forever changing, the spira mirabilis
The Dream of Scipio
Theater
Illusory minds
So, are we giving it
another try?
Perpetual motion
Theater
You have to seize and protect the things
most precious to you with your own hands.
Illusory people
Perpetual structure
People are not above stealing, Mickey.
Ammonite shell, alchemy
He’s good!
Scarab, the spira mirabilis
Ever dying, just to live again, the spira mirabilis
The wondrous whirlpool
Snail, snail...
Never-ending theater
En garde!
On the geometric stage
I won’t lose!
She believes in me!
of the mystery of life and death
That’s it, Master Utena!
Get him!
Exeunt, all!
Death, rebirth, death, rebirth, death, rebirth, death
I should note that what confined them
was not the power to revolutionize the world.
In trying to possess a miracle,
the miracle possessed them.
Throw away your Rose Seal!
Your ring!
You make me sick!
That so-called
“nobility” of yours...
...is just a cheap act you put on
to impress a guy you like!
Universal light, mosaic light
Child of daybreak, angel Lucifer
Believe in miracles...
Apocalyptic light, Michael’s light
Child of darkness, androgynous
...so that your wish may come true.
Fire’s light, heavenly light
Hierarchia of the heavens
Are you all right,
O Prince?
We’ve barely even started.
Illusory light, eternal light
Fanciful machination, capricious birth
Nyx, Erebus, Uranus, Thanatos
Why don’t you at least
try to dodge?
Bodies shining bright, spherical in shape, gynous
Born into every possible miracle, gynous
The principle of pleasure, the principle of Nirvana
Death’s inevitability, in other words, the light
Pitiful.
You’re already spent.
But I won’t let you off.
Without having lived,
the moving phenomenon of life
When’s that miracle happening,
O Prince?
In the cerebral universe,
the shape of a life adrift
She’s fast!
So, I have absolutely no regrets
about stealing him from you...
Luminosity, an avatar seeking eternity,
You must hate me
for being this kind of person.
in other words, the imperfect return to the origin
“Believe in miracles”
was your favorite thing to say.
Male and female, positive and negative, both are me
But...
Up and down, left and right, both are me
There are no such things
as miracles!
Front and back, Heaven and Earth, both are me
Angel and devil, both are me
Inside I’m hollow, hollow, hollow,
hollow, hollow, hollow, hollow, hollow, hollow
This is it.
Indeed... The young
always seek the end of the world...
My brother got hurt
because of you!
All because of you!
Genesis of the Earth, stage props
Laplace’s nebula, spectatorship theory
Don’t underestimate me!
An immutable illusion, a riddle-solving clock
The baby carriage at immortality’s edge
My eternal self
Nanami, show me your power
as The End of the World’s chosen.
The eternal stranger
Two relations, two births
A mysterious scale, a constellation of the human body
I’ve been watching my brother,
and my brother only, since forever.
You hurt my dearest brother!
This is your fault.
You came between me
and my big brother.
This is your fault.
...your fault.
Time is a hypothetical illusion...
It’s all you!
...of the newborn stage prop
Destiny, choices, the theory of goodbyes
You and I are the Milky Way
No past, no future, we live solely for today
All alone in the theater of the cosmos
That’s me! Wait!
My last evolution, revolution, everlution!
Friendship,
choice,
reason,
love,
adoration,
conviction,
and self.
Even after clearing seven duels,
she is still a Duelist.
She could well be
the one we’ve longed for.
If she proceeds, she may just reach
the duel called “revolution”.
The day when you become fully free
might also be approaching.
Don’t glare at me like that.
It’s only natural
for me to eagerly anticipate that day.
We both stand
to gain much, after all.
But... A new stage
will soon be afoot.
I wonder how she will fight
the duels to come.
Ow! Hey, Chu-Chu!
I’m home,
Master Utena, Chu-Chu.
Welcome back!
Where were you?
Master Utena...
The clouds are moving
so quickly.
Master Utena!
My, what should I do?
The Absolute Destiny: Apocalypse
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
Embrace me tightly with your arms so true
The key to open up tomorrow is reality
I want to keep on dispelling lies
Even if we keep talking,
there’s no way you’ll ever see
Adults who reminisce too much
and excuses go well together
The rejected angels...
...have no need for wings!
Missing truth and forever, kissing love and true your heart
I believe that I’ll like the me of tomorrow,
and because I want to believe so,
I want the lies to keep hating me
Next Episode
Master Utena, allow me to introduce
my big brother.
Huh? You have a brother?
He doesn’t know about me being
the Rose Bride, or about the Duelist’s Code.
Please, Master Utena, I implore you
to keep these things secret.
I don’t want to burden him.
But it looks like some suspicious people
are after your brother’s fiancée.
Next time,
on Revolutionary Girl Utena:
The Boys of the Black Rose
“The Boys of the Black Rose”
The absolute destiny: apocalypse.