Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
The sun shines bright.
It’s a peaceful day off.
Sheesh!
There!
Mom, this illustration’s yours, isn’t it?
Correct! You really are my daughter.
Isn’t this me?
You know I don’t like my bedhair!
Why would you put it in an illustration?!
Oh, no, that’s just a character!
A completely fictional creation.
It doesn’t look like you at all.
Lemme see.
It’s Sis!
See?!
Oh, Sota...
Oh, dear, it seems
Wanpachi is calling.
What is it, Wanpachi?
W-What?
What’s that in your mouth?!
W-Wait a second, Wanpachi!
Wanpachi, come here.
There, there...
It’s a Mamepato.
But...
It’s not moving.
It’s fine.
It’s just unconscious.
What a relief.
Oh, yeah...
Something hit my window earlier.
It must have been
this Mamepato.
It’s injured.
Let’s look after it
until it can fly again.
Let me hold it, too!
Treating its wounds comes first.
Yeah.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
A Jealous Fit!
Wanpachi's Feelings
This is Sakuragi Park.
As usual, Satoshi is getting in
some early morning training.
Block it with Force Palm!
Good going, both of you!
Now, next is—
Satoshi!
Have you seen Messon?
What? No.
I can’t find it.
Again? Sure it’s not
just camouflaged?
I thought it might be,
so I looked around, but...
Found you!
Come on!
Oh, it was just Barrierd?
I couldn’t find it anywhere.
All right!
Let’s help look for Messon!
Go!
Yeah.
This means...
Messon is...
...definitely here...!
Messon!
Messon, where are you?
I know!
Butterfree! Morphon!
Stun Spore!
There!
Kairyu!
Do your thing with Messon!
What an appetite.
Yeah.
I guess it said
thanks for the food?
Mamepato, I’m Sota.
This is my sister Koharu,
and these are my mom and dad.
Mamepato, this is Wanpachi.
Hey, wait!
Oh, dear...
Wait! Wait!
Wanpachi, don’t chase after it.
What’s going on?
Looks like Mamepato
likes Wanpachi’s back.
But it was so scared of him
just a second ago.
It’s forgotten that it was scared.
What?
Mamepato follows its trainer’s orders
as best it can,
but they sometimes fail to understand
complicated commands.
It’s very forgetful,
and sometimes forgets that
it even received an order.
Really? That’s so cute!
Super cute!
Cute... Really?
I guess it is!
It’s nice to meet you,
Mamepato!
Make yourself at home.
Wanpachi?
Welcome in, Mamepato.
You want to see?
Quite a few girls in my class
read this magazine...
You like frizzy hair?
I guess you do.
Isn’t it beautiful?
Isn’t Mamepato cute?
Eat up.
Mamepato seems to be
doing better than yesterday.
Hey, Wanpachi, stop that!
You’ll tear my uniform!
Wanpachi?
What could be wrong?
It must be jealousy.
Jealousy?
Wanpachi is like our youngest child.
Everyone in the family loves him.
I suppose.
But now Mamepato has
taken that “youngest child” spot,
and even his precious Koharu
is fixated on Mamepato.
I see.
I don’t get it.
Dad, it’s time for us to go!
Oh, of course!
I’ll look into whether there are any reports
of a missing Mamepato.
Please do.
See you later!
It really has
taken a shine to them.
See you after school!
You’re doing great, Wanpachi.
It’s like you’re
Mamepato’s big brother.
That ought to do it.
That ought to do what,
Director?
We took in an injured
Mamepato yesterday.
Seems like it crashed into our window.
I just reported it on
social networking sites.
It might be a lost Pokémon.
I see.
I’ve had that happen, too.
Something crashing into my window.
If the glass is really clear,
bird Pokémon don’t always notice it.
Thankfully, it didn’t get hurt
that bad in my case.
It flew off again right away.
What’cha gonna do after school?
Let’s go to the bay
to look for Pokémon!
Great idea!
I’m sure Mamepato
is dying to fly like that again.
Let’s look after it
until it can fly again.
Until it can fly again, huh?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mamepato
Flying
Normal
See you tomorrow.
Wanpachi, Mamepato, I’m back.
What’s wrong, Wanpachi?
Oh, Koharu?
Is this the Mamepato
the Director mentioned?
Wanpachi?
What’s going on?
It’s jealousy.
Jealousy?
Wanpachi is annoyed at Mamepato
for hogging Koharu’s attention.
Really?
I’m treating them both
the same way, though...
So all he wants is for Mamepato
to stop clinging to Koharu.
So it seems.
This jealousy thing
is pretty bothersome.
Oh, don’t say that.
Wanpachi’s acting pretty tame
compared to how you were back in the day.
I remember what
she was like back then!
What?
Back when I was still a student
at the Director’s laboratory...
A friend from the Galar Region
sent me Wanpachi.
This was before Sota was born,
back when you were still an only child.
You got really jealous of Wanpachi.
I did?
Back then, it seemed like
you were thinking,
“Wanpachi’s gonna steal
Mom and Dad from me!”
Mr. Renji!
Stop petting Wanpachi!
You were even yelling at me.
I said that?!
I don’t remember at all!
But Galar Pokémon are a rare sight,
so I sneakily studied Wanpachi
when you weren’t looking.
Your mom and I were careful not to be too affectionate
to Wanpachi when you were around, too.
That’s really embarrassing...
I was way too childish!
It’s perfectly normal.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Speaking from experience,
Kikuna?
It was my little sister
I was jealous of, but yes.
So, how did Koharu and
Wanpachi become friends?
One day, Koharu told Wanpachi...
...that she wished he’d just go away.
What?!
Past me was awful!
And then the “incident” occurred.
Incident?
The Runaway Wanpachi Incident.
Runaway...?
I wish you’d just go away!
What could have happened?
Where could he have gone?
What’s wrong?
Wanpachi has disappeared.
Disappeared?
Don’t worry.
Your Dad will find him!
Just go back to bed.
Look, this is Wanpachi!
Don’t follow me.
No!
Wanpachi...
Wanpachi!
Where are you?
Where... Where did you go?
I went looking for Wanpachi,
then some Konpang
frightened me...
You remember?
Then Wanpachi came and...
That tickles, Wanpachi!
I told you it tickles!
Ever since then,
Wanpachi has only slept
in Koharu’s room,
and will only eat the Pokémon Food
Koharu puts out for him.
Wanpachi must have been happy...
...that Koharu went to look for him.
Wanpachi?!
Wanpachi! Mamepato!
Onidrill?!
Wanpachi...
Director, we have to do something!
Leave it to Koharu and Wanpachi.
Koharu! Wanpachi!
His jealousy shows how close he is to you.
Together, you can definitely
fight that thing.
Dad...
Hang in there, Koharu!
You got this!
All right!
Let’s go, Wanpachi!
Spark!
You did it!
You took it down!
Onidrill!
W-Wait! I wanna catch you!
You’ve taken such good care
of my Mamepato!
I really don’t know how
I could ever thank you!
This one is the leader
of my Mamepato Race team.
Leader?
It’s super quick,
and cares more than anyone
for its teammates.
Its leadership skills
are unmatched.
I see.
Mamepato’s leaving?
That’s right, Sota.
Mamepato’s going back to its real home.
Thank you for looking after it!
But we just became friends...
Sota.
Look at Mamepato.
It loves its real trainer a lot.
I guess you’re right.
Mamepato!
Come visit again sometime!
We’re waiting for you!
It sure is quiet here
without Mamepato.
Even though it was only here...
...for two days!
Did Dad write this book?
That’s right.
Looks complicated.
This book...
...is all about what
we should do in the world...
...to make sure people and Pokémon
can keep living together in peace.
How to make sure people and Pokémon
can keep living together in peace, huh?
Koharu! Wanpachi!
His jealousy shows how close he is to you.
Together, you can definitely
fight that thing.
I guess Dad’s pretty cool.
That’s right, he is.
Didn’t you know?
Through meeting and
saying goodbye to Mamepato,
Koharu has gotten just a little bit
closer to the Pokémon.
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Riolu’s in peak form! Satoshi’s totally engrossed
in training for the next official match with it!
Maybe I didn’t pay enough attention to Pikachu because of that, but...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Pikachu's Reluctance,
and Barrierd's Exasperation
Pikachu’s Reluctance,
and Barrierd’s Exasperation