Satoshi, who defeated
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
...and claimed victory
in the Masters Tournament...
And Go, who managed to meet Mew again
through Project Mew...
Okido Laboratory, Kanto Region
These two have returned
to their usual lives.
We did it, guys!
You battled marvelously, Satoshi.
Professor Okido!
Pokémon
Haiku
Allow me to recite a poem...
You set off from here
And to here you have returned,
Now reigning supreme
Couldn’t have done it
without Pikachu and the rest!
Indeed.
Keep that modesty
and you’ll surely keep on improving.
Right!
I get the feeling you won’t be
visiting us again for quite some time.
Mom! How could you tell?
Why, because I’m your mother.
I tend to have a pretty good idea
what my own son is thinking.
Here, your lunch.
Thanks!
Then I’ll be going!
Have a good trip!
Give my regards to
Sakuragi and the others.
Right!
You guys! We won’t get to see each other for a while,
so everyone take care!
Hey!
I did it! I met Mew!
All the time I spent
with you all really helped!
Thank you!
But now,
I have a lot on my mind...
Dad!
Are Go and Satoshi here yet?
Satoshi hasn’t arrived yet,
but Go’s in the park.
Okay, got it.
You’re all going camping today, right?
Have fun!
We will, thank you!
Then should we wait
in the park, Eevee?
Which is why...
I’d like to go on a journey.
But if I left to do that,
I wouldn’t get to see all of you.
And...
Eevee!
Koharu!
S-Sorry...
I wasn’t intending
to eavesdrop...
No, it’s fine.
Go, what was that about
going on a journey...?
On my way back
from Project Mew,
I had a lot on my mind...
You can tell me
if you want.
Right...
Meeting Mew
and becoming more fascinated by it...
It made me think I want to know more
about Mew, and get closer to Mew.
And to do that...
I need to be a trainer
who can properly face up to Mew.
A trainer who can face up to it?
I’m nowhere close to
good enough right now...
So, I had an idea.
I thought I’d like to travel across
all sorts of regions, like Satoshi.
So that’s why...
Yeah.
If I leave Kuchiba City,
and meet lots more Pokémon and trainers,
and learn lots and lots more
about Pokémon and the world,
then I might be able to face up to Mew.
So... you’d be going alone?
I’d end up relying on Satoshi
if he was there.
So I’ll go alone.
Have you told Satoshi?
Oh, he’d tell me to go for it.
I know what he’s like.
And... I feel kinda bad about it...
Like I’m betraying our friendship.
So you don’t know what to do...
Oh, there you are!
Sorry I’m late!
Huh? Something wrong?
No, um... I...
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Pokémon!
I'm Glad I Met You!
Go!
Our promise!
“Next time we meet,
we’ll meet with a smile!” Right?
We did it!
I want to hear
how you beat Mr. Dande!
And I wanna hear all about Mew!
Huh?
We’re about to miss the bus!
This is the forest
my father took me to.
Whoa...
It’s full of Pokémon!
Ooh! This place is great!
Right?
I knew you two would love it.
The campsite is just up ahead.
Tent, ready!
Food, ready!
That just leaves...
Huh?
When did you...?
Where did you find those?
Let’s go find
enough for everyone.
A Kamonegi!
It’s holding a plant stalk,
and it can swing it like a sword
to cut all sorts of things.
It’s a Dugtrio!
It’s amazingly strong!
It can dig to a depth of 100 kilometers!
You said the same thing
when we were little kids.
Huh? Did I?
A Cayce!
Wow, they’re rare to see!
That brings back memories!
What memories?
So...
When I was younger,
I was often home alone.
Once, when I was going through
my dad’s Pokémon Index...
Who are you?
After that, it started popping up
and vanishing every now and then.
Then, one day...
You’re “Cayce,” right?
You sleep for 18 hours a day,
and can even teleport in your sleep!
I thought it might’ve been teleporting
somewhere right nearby...
Are you home alone, too?
It was a sweltering day.
I never knew there were
this many Pokémon in the park!
Cayce!
So Cayce was like a playmate for you
when you were home alone.
Yeah.
And it led to me meeting
lots of Pokémon.
Do you have any
memories like that, Satoshi?
Me? Hmm...
None that make me go,
“Ooh, it’s that Pokémon.”
Huh?
You’re kidding, right?
If I had to say,
I guess I’d go with all the Pokémon I’ve met.
After all, I wanna make friends
with every Pokémon!
Friends with all of them...
That’s amazing!
Oh, Momon Berries!
A Nyoromo?
Oh, no!
Not good!
Run for it!
A Yadon?!
Yawn?
Eevee! Yawn!
Good job, Eevee!
And thanks, Yadon!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Nyoromo
Water
Huh?
What is it?
A Momon Berry...
Over there!
Maybe it’s thanking us
for saving it.
Huh? Do you think so?
Thank you, Nyoromo!
Satoshi and Pikachu
are a lot like one another.
I think so, too.
They’re both always charging ahead
and they have the same stubborn streak.
Well, we’ve been
together since forever.
Since I set out,
I’ve met lots of Pokémon...
I’ve helped them,
and they’ve helped me...
And there’s been times
I’ve said goodbye to them...
But Pikachu’s been by my side
since the beginning.
He’s my number one partner.
Your number one partner, huh?
You have a partner too, don’t you?
Huh? You mean this guy?
The first time it stood out to me...
That’d be seeing it
helping out its friends,
which made me think
I’d like to do the same.
And traveling together,
I realized...
...that helping out your friends
is lots of fun!
And that friends are the best!
Yeah!
You always used to be all alone,
and said you didn’t need friends...
You’ve really changed.
So have you, Koharu.
Huh? I have?
Yeah!
When we first met,
you didn’t like Pokémon...
...and just look at you now!
Yeah...
When I was lost, I met Eevee.
Seeing Eevee’s evolutions,
and their bonds with their trainers...
...filled me with interest
in Pokémon!
So my world has expanded
thanks to Eevee.
I know that feeling!
With Pokémon,
you can go anywhere!
you can connect with anyone in the world!
Yeah!
It sure is strange...
Catching Pokémon...
It feels like mere chance, but it’s not.
You mean it’s inevitable?
Or should I say, it’s destiny?
I don’t know about
all that complicated stuff,
but I’m glad we met.
Thank you.
I’ll say thanks, too!
Me, too... Thank you!
Satoshi.
What’s wrong?
No, it’s nothing! Sorry.
Okay.
The stars sure are pretty tonight!
Go...
I’m going on a journey.
I’ll be going on another journey,
with Pikachu.
Going on a journey...
All of a sudden...
How could you decide that
without me?
Go...
Weren’t we friends?!
We’re through!
Go wasn’t sure
what he should do...
He wasn’t sure?
He wanted to go on a journey.
Huh? Go too?
But he couldn’t decide alone...
He said it was like
betraying your friendship...
Because you’re the first friend
Go’s ever had.
Go...
Hey! Go!
Calling... Calling... Calling...
Calling... Calli—
Go...
Incoming call from Koharu!
Calling... Calli—
What was that for?!
Huh? Pikachu!
It’s Trancell.
They’re starting to evolve.
Will they be okay in the rain?
Butterfree scales repel water,
so they can even fly in the rain.
That’s what the
Pokémon Index says, right?
Yeah.
Go...
Hold on!
I haven’t forgiven you just yet!
Forgiven me for what?
We’re still through, you know!
Through!
“Through”...
But you were going to—
You should ask me first!
I’ll miss you!
Ask you first?!
You were going to go alone too,
weren’t you?!
Huh?!
No, I... Wait, how do you know that...?
Koharu?!
What’s wrong?
This air flow, temperature,
humidity, altitude...
It might appear!
“It”?!
Lugia!
Why is it here?!
Does it want us to come?
Let’s go find out!
Hey, hold on!
Go! Satoshi!
Sheesh...
What are you planning to do?!
Battle it!
Battle Lugia?!
Of course!
Then I’ll catch it!
I’ll do it first!
Lucario, I choose you!
Inteleon, go!
Lugia, it’s a Raid Battle!
The Legendary Pokémon Lugia
suddenly appeared before Satoshi and Go.
What will happen next?!
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Let’s go, everyone!
Pokémon really are...
...awesome!
I wanna see more of them, know more about them,
make friends with more of them!
The way that you go will determine
the Pokémon you’ll meet, and the adventures you’ll have.
And the choice is yours.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi and Go!
A New Departure!!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Here we go!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Championing the evils of truth and love!
Team Rocket Explorers!
Championing the Evils of Truth and Love
Team  Rocket  Explorers
Following an order
to catch new Pokémon...
...we made our first visit
to the Paldea Region.
Oh, meow?
There’s one, meow!
It’s not in here!
That means...
...it’s a new species of Pokémon?!
No, it’s not!
The Duckling Pokémon,
Kuwassu.
Its hair is slicked back
using a rich, moist cream?
Sounds like Musashi, meow.
Let’s catch it quick;
what a great feeling that’ll be!
Yeah!
Go!
What an awful feeling!
Today’s roundup-ssu!
Kuwassu thinks...
...good hair makes for
a good life-ssu, meow!
Good hair
makes for
a good life