Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Now, Pikachu!
Let’s go, Hibunny!
Oh? We can hear passionate cries
in the institute today.
Lightning Speed!
Well done, Go!
Hibunny!
What is Hihidaruma doing?
Looks like it’s gonna do something!
Is it telling Hibunny to
use a Fire move, too?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Hibunny's Fiery Kick!
Working For Tomorrow!!
Go! Satoshi!
You still haven’t had breakfast?
Barrierd was worried about you.
What are you doing?
Oh, well, you see...
Huh...? Why does Hihidaruma
look so smug?
Hihidaruma provoked Hibunny
into trying to use Ember,
but it can’t really pull it off...
Hang in there, Hibunny!
Try more like...
Graaaah! Open up wide,
then launch the heat
from your belly, like, “Ba-Ba-Ba-Bang!”
Yeah, that’s it!
What’s that mean?
I’m pretty sure that’s how Satoshi
tries to teach others...
But...
I don’t think there’s any need
to try so hard, though.
You should stop.
That’s enough.
Stop, Hibunny!
Your Lightning Speed and Double Kick
have gotten really strong.
It doesn’t matter if
you can’t use a Fire move.
Looks like Hibunny
doesn’t agree with you.
Well...
You can’t do
what you can’t do.
Hey!
Time for breakfast!
Go, you’re heading into the city
to catch Pokémon today, right?
Yeah.
Is catching Pokémon fun?
It’s super fun!
You should come with us!
No thanks.
Come on!
I told you no!
Why not? It’s fun.
Wait... Hibunny?
Don’t worry!
It’ll come right back once it gets hungry.
I guess.
Hibunny!
See?
Thank goodness!
All right, let’s go
catch some Pokémon!
I can’t wait to see
what kind of Pokémon we’ll find!
Me neither!
There’s nothing around!
I thought we’d find at least a Poppo
or something right off the bat.
What is it, Hibunny?
Hang on.
I’m looking up what Pokémon
are in this area.
Pelipper?!
What are you doing,
Hibunny?!
After it!
I can’t believe we found
a wild Pelipper...
We gotta catch it!
Do you have the thing?
Indeed I do!
Kuchiba City’s limited-edition
sea-breeze flavor potato chips!
Oh, yeah! That’s the stuff!
Let’s get right to it!
Time for some snacks!
Oh, man...
I ate way too much.
I need a break...
I got heartburn...
That’s a great idea, meow!
What?
Sonansu suggested we play
Nasty Plot Shiritori!
Oh, great idea.
Doing nothing
won’t do us any good!
Allow me to explain, meow.
Nasty Plot Shiritori is Team Rocket’s very own,
original method of image training,
where we play Shiritori
using nothing but nasty phrases,
so as to ensure that we’re
constantly thinking evil thoughts, meow!
I’ll go first.
Pitfall!
(otoshiana)
Knuckle punch!
(na kkuru panchi )
Insidious punch!
(go kuaku panchi )
Pure evil!
(ch ou gokuaku hidou)
Back-lying perpendicular armbar!
(u de hijiki juji gatame)
Bleeding gums!
(ha guki kara chi )
Chi...
Fatal wound!
(chi meishou )
U... U... U...
Time out for a sec!
It just occurred to me,
Nyarth...
Are you actually following up
on what Sonansu’s saying?
You ask that now?
You are, right, Nyarth?
Of course, meow!
Oh. Well, okay then.
Right, it was my turn...
U... U... U...
Back fist!
(u raken )
Oh, hold it!
Never mind what I just said!
No go! You totally had an “N”
at the end, there, meow!
You lose, meow!
You definitely said “uraken”.
No way!
I did not say “uraken”!
What I said was “urake ”!
(Back hair)
“urake”? Is that even a thing?
Yeah, it’s the...
hair in the back!
I’ve never heard of that, meow!
What kind of hair?
In the back of what?!
You don’t know?!
You know, eyelashes, eyebrows and back hair...
It’s all the rage these days!
There’s no way!
S-Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
She’s gotten violent!
Back hair is...
it’s this hair here, got it?!
We lost it.
I just don’t have
any catching luck today...
What’s this?
What? What?
What are you doing, meow?
Hey, don’t push!
You’re holding up the line,
so hurry up, meow!
T-Team Rocket?!
You’re the brat boy’s friend...
Brat boy Mk. II!
Where?! Where is he, meow?!
Hey, stop pushing!
Well... For starters...
Let’s get out!
W-Why’d you come out
from under that box?
I-It’s not a box!
It’s a phone booth!
Phone? Booth?
He doesn’t know, meow!
Kids these days don’t know
what phone booths are, meow!
I told you, didn’t I?
This is way too conspicuous an
entrance to our base.
What?! You’ve got
a base under here?!
Why, where ever did you
get that from?!
It’s too late now, Kojiro...
Let’s get him!
Yeah!
Vending, come on!
Huh?
Nothing’s coming...
From there?!
The Pelipper from before!
Which means that
this place getting exposed...
...was Pelipper’s fault!
Hey! Don’t run away!
Go!
Brat boy!
And...
Pikachu, meow!
You okay?
Yeah.
All right, this is perfect!
Like a Pikachu to a flame!
Yeah!
Nyarth!
Yeah, meow!
Rocket...
Vending...
Secret!
You’re up!
Come forth!
The Tadpole Pokémon,
Nyorobon!
The Snapping Pokémon,
Kamukame, meow!
You’re the thing
from the other day!
That thing that’s supposed to
get really strong when it evolves!
Hey... Can this baby even fight?
It’s saying “Bring it on!”, meow.
For real?
It doesn’t look strong, though...
But we can’t let this chance
go to waste!
Right!
Nyorobon! Water Gun!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Kamukamu! Water Gun!
Oh, wow!
That’s pretty impressive!
Hibunny! Dodge and
use Double Kick!
Hibunny!
Why Ember?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hihidaruma
Fire
Hibunny! Dodge and
use Double Kick!
Hibunny!
Why Ember?!
Well done, Kamukamu!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
We almost had them that time!
What an awful feeling!
Hibunny!
That Kamukame
was really strong.
Yeah...
Are you okay, Hibunny?
Say, Hibunny...
Why did you use Ember
instead of Double Kick back there?
Didn’t I tell you?
You should focus on the moves
you can actually use,
and fight in a way that’s true to yourself.
I told you, you don’t have...
Listen to me!
That’s just not good enough!
Ow!
Just accept that
there’s some things you can’t do!
Oh, what now?
Fine, then! Have it your way.
Hibunny!
Go, you’re not gonna follow it?
No.
What’s gotten into it?!
I tried so hard to bring out
Hibunny’s strength in battle.
Really?
Yeah!
Oh, I see.
But that battle was...
How do I put it?
You and Hibunny
weren’t really one.
“One”?
Yeah! Like how when Pikachu and I battle,
it’s like we merge into one being!
And then it’s like our chest
starts boiling and blazing up...
and we go all “Ba-Ba-Ba-Bang!”
I have no idea what you mean...
Then you’ve gotta stick
with Hibunny until you do get it!
Ow!
Where could Hibunny have gone?
Hibunny is dead-set on
using a Fire move, huh?
Hibunny!
That was...
Hey, wait, Hibunny!
Ow!
Hey, you!
Watch where you’re...
You again!
Team Rocket!
Again!
Second Pikachu encounter
of the day, meow!
This time, we will
get your Pikachu!
Kamukamu!
Use your Bite attack!
Dodge it, Hibunny!
Hibunny!
There might be a Fire move
you can use.
This time, we’ll win for sure!
Let’s do it!
Lightning Speed!
Kamukamu! Headbutt!
Are you okay?!
All right!
Use Double Kick!
Another Bite attack!
Here they come!
It dodged again!
Double Kick!
Kamukame?!
We’re fighting as one...
Going all “Ba-Ba-Ba-Bang!”...
I’ve never felt this way before.
Hibunny!
Wanna try your Fire move?
Then stand in place
and use Lightning Speed!
Faster!
And then kick this!
Blow it away with Water Gun!
W-What was that?
All right!
This is our Ember!
Hibunny evolved!
No way! How...?!
Go!
Ember!
Second failure of the day...
What an awful feeling!
You did it, Hibunny!
No, I mean...
Rabbifoot! Rabbit Pokémon!
Fire type!
Its thick and fluffy fur protects it from the cold
and enables it to use hotter Fire moves.
You did it, Rabbifoot!
Hibunny has conquered its trial alongside Go,
and evolved into Rabbifoot!
But what does this mean...?
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Aim to be the best!
Aim for the Pokémon
World Championships!
It’s your new challenge!
Yeah!
First, let’s see if there’s any
Normal Class trainers around...
Huh?! Is this the Kuchiba Gym’s...
All right, I’m fired up!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi Joins In!
The Pokémon World Championships!!