The festival of dreams
to crown the strongest Pokémon Trainer...
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
The eight mighty trainers
aiming for the summit...
...have begun battling.
The third match of the first round
pit the Champion of Sinnoh, Shirona, against...
...the Champion of Isshu, Iris.
Amid their fierce fight,
Shirona surprised everyone with Mega Evolution.
Though Iris put up a brave fight,
she lost by a narrow margin.
And the fourth match,
which is about to begin...
...is finally Satoshi’s turn to battle.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Satoshi Heads Into Battle! VS Daigo!!
Now, for the fourth match
of the first round!
The Champion of Hoenn, Competitor Daigo,
versus Alola’s first Champion, Competitor Satoshi!
This is it!
The brat boy, meow!
Against some impressive
strong guy!
The brat boy’s
got no chance, does he?
Hop, can you scoot over a bit?
Okay!
The Champion of Isshu?!
Hey!
I hear you’re
Mr. Dande’s little brother!
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you...
Wooloo! You’re so fluffy!
But what are you doing
in the stands?
She said she wants to feel
the stadium’s excitement firsthand.
Isn’t that what Satoshi said?
You may each use three Pokémon
in the first round.
No limit on
switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all three of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, you are allowed a single use of only one
of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolution.
Satoshi has all of them!
Yeah!
All his adventures
have led to this!
Mr. Daigo!
We’ll be heading on to the semifinals!
You sound quite confident,
given you’re facing me.
I can’t wait to see
what this battle will bring.
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Come out, Metagross!
Uonoragon, I choose you!
Both sides have sent out
their Pokémon.
Metagross and Uonoragon
will face off in the first clash.
Let’s see what you’ve got, rookie!
Let the battle begin!
Water Gun!
Agility!
Jaw Bite!
Psychokinesis!
All right!
Jaw Bite subdued
the Psychokinesis!
So you predicted that.
Good going, Satoshi.
The power of Jaw Bite increases
if it goes first, too.
Plus, its ability is Strong Jaw!
That makes it even stronger!
Shinji...
Our battle helped me out!
Approaching with Agility,
then using Psychokinesis...
That training really was meant to prepare me
for a battle with Mr. Daigo!
Return, Metagross.
Come out, Bossgodra!
Competitor Daigo is swapping out
his Pokémon already!
Bossgodra! Iron Armor Pokémon!
Steel/Rock type!
With a horn sharp enough
to perforate thick iron sheets,
it brings down its opponents
by ramming into them horn first!
Satoshi, did you know...
...that I’m the strongest and most impressive
trainer in the Hoenn Region right now?
But that’s not enough to satisfy me.
The Pokémon World Championships...
By winning this tournament, I’ll be able to call myself
the one true strongest and most impressive trainer!
I’ve never seen him
this passionate before.
Same goes for us!
For everyone who cheered us on,
all the way here...
...and for the Pokémon, too!
I’ve gotta win this!
Dragon Dive!
Heavy Bomber!
Can you keep going, Uonoragon?
Uonoragon is unable to battle!
Bossgodra gets the referee’s fan
in a clash of strength!
Uonoragon... lost...
Mr. Daigo’s strong...
See?
The brat boy just can’t cut it.
What’s got into you?
Are you... angry?
I am not angry!
Return, Uonoragon!
You really gave it your all.
This time, Gänger...
I choose you!
Let’s do it!
Will-O-Wisp!
A Fire move...
Looks like Bossgodra can’t keep its strength up
due to the burn condition!
Smart Horn!
The burn condition
saps away its strength!
G-Gänger, here it comes!
Rock Seal!
Magical Shine!
It’s still standing?!
Bossgodra...
Bossgodra is unable to battle!
All right!
You did it, Gänger!
Even steel armor
couldn’t save it from a burn?!
That training did come in handy!
Looking good,
Satoshi, Gänger!
That looked like
a pretty close win, though...
Return, Bossgodra!
Thank you.
Kudos to you.
Come out, Yuradle!
Competitor Daigo’s
third Pokémon is Yuradle!
Yuradle! Rock Crevice Pokémon!
Rock/Grass type!
Once it catches prey in its tentacles,
it digests them and absorbs their nutrients!
Power Whip!
Yuradle makes full use of its tentacles
with Power Whip!
Gänger has nowhere to run!
It got caught!
So this is why he chose Yuradle?!
S-Scary...
Take Root!
Take Root will stop him
from switching...
It’s a message,
saying he’ll take down Gänger here and now.
Break free! Sludge Bomb!
It’s recovering!
But that means all his attacks will do is make Gänger more exhausted...
What’ll you do, Satoshi?
Meteor Beam!
That’s it!
Fight light with light!
Gänger! Use Magical Shine!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
That’s it!
Fight light with light!
Gänger! Use Magical Shine!
Competitor Satoshi took advantage of
the colliding moves to carve Gänger an escape route!
Not bad.
Move in! Shadow Ball!
Power Whip!
Gänger!
Gänger is unable to battle!
Competitor Satoshi
has lost his second Pokémon!
Return, Gänger!
I won’t let your hard work
go to waste!
Pikachu, I’m counting on you!
There he is!
The flaming bolt of lightning, Pikachu!
Your greatest partner arrives.
Pikachu! Go for it!
Electric moves
aren’t very effective.
And he still has Metagross
to worry about.
This is looking tense.
Pikachu’s out, meow!
Can he turn it around?!
Pikachu! If you don’t win this,
it’s all over, you hear?!
Rock Blast!
Lightning Speed!
Use the rocks to get a big jump!
So high...
But what’s he going to do?
The recovery won’t stop.
He has to end this quickly...
Power Whip!
Electroweb!
What?!
All right! He got him!
That was his plan?!
Yeah! That’s what Satoshi does!
Now that’s good.
Intriguing!
Iron Tail!
Yuradle is unable to battle!
All right!
Daigo has lost
his second Pokémon.
Now both sides
are down to their last!
Marvelous! Each and every one
of your attacks surprises me!
Couldn’t do it without
Gänger setting up for Pikachu!
Oh, he’s so strong!
That’s our Pikachu!
This is the real thing, meow!
It’s looking like maybe
he just might...!
Return, Yuradle!
You did well.
Win or lose,
this will decide it all.
Come out, Metagross!
Metagross...
Now... For the fourth match
of the first round...
Which of them
will advance to the semifinals?!
Sparkle of stone...
Become our bond!
Metagross...
Mega Evolve!
Competitor Daigo sends
Mega Metagross into battle!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
It’s pointless.
Pikachu! Fire 100,000 Volts
again and again!
Pikachu can’t land a single hit!
Mega Metagross is accurately predicting
the trajectory of the lightning!
This is Mega Metagross!
It’s predicting every movement
Pikachu makes.
Comet Punch!
Pikachu!
Mega Metagross is said to have superior
strategic and information processing capabilities.
Every movement and breath
Pikachu takes...
It’s calculating them all instantaneously
and evading with ease.
You have a tough battle
ahead of you, Satoshi.
Iron Tail!
Psychokinesis!
Pikachu!
An overwhelming attack
by Mega Metagross!
Damage is piling up on Pikachu!
Competitor Daigo does not disappoint...
He’s coolly driving Competitor Satoshi into a corner!
Pikachu!
Let’s use our full power!
What’s that?
A Z-Move!
Yeah! He finally used it!
A Z-Move, huh?
A Z-Move...
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Pikachu! 10,000,000 Volts!
Metagross! Dodge it!
Luster Cannon!
What?!
All right!
He’s commanding
the electricity?!
Let’s finish this!
Iron Tail!
Metagross is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
As such, the winner is Competitor Satoshi!
We did it!
Competitor Satoshi wins!
Taking down the Champion of Hoenn, Competitor Daigo,
he advances to the semifinals!
He’s facing
Competitor Shirona next!
So you made it, Satoshi.
He won! He won! He won!
What an electrifying 10,000,000 Volts!
Pikachu, and the others under
Satoshi’s guidance, were incredible!
Today, we’re having a Galar special,
a curry party!
Yay!
Now there’s our Pikachu!
There’s our brat boy!
Now, isn’t this quite the upset?!
You know, maybe
they just might...!
Mr. Daigo.
The feelings you have
for your Pokémon partners…
And the feelings of those Pokémon,
responding to yours with all their might…
They came together as one,
and created an even greater power.
And thus, you were able
to grasp victory today.
A marvelous victory.
With this, the four trainers advancing to the
Masters Tournament semifinals have been decided.
Competitor Dande, Competitor Carne,
Competitor Shirona, and Competitor Satoshi.
The white-hot Masters Tournament
is far from over!
You’re facing Ms. Shirona next.
But I’m sure
you and Pikachu can win.
I believe in you.
Satoshi, you better win!
I’ll be waiting to hear you’ve won!
Yeah! Leave it to me!
You can’t let your guard down.
I know that!
I’m gonna battle Mr. Dande,
for sure!
Right, Pikachu?
Best wishes!
Give it your all!
The fierce first round
of the Masters Tournament has concluded.
Next is Dande versus Carne,
and Shirona versus Satoshi.
Now, which of these trainers
will win their way into the finals?!
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They’re all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they’re unique and you’ll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Bari-bari...
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
Bari Channel
Next Time :  "Koharu and Eevee    The Tracks of Evolution"
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Kikuna here!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Koharu and Eevee...
From their mysterious encounter
at school, up until now...
They’ve really tried their hand
at lots of things.
Greeting someone new is always fresh
Break it down for me, Bari-chan...
Koharu and the Eevee
that doesn’t evolve...
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
What do you think they’ll do next?
Mm-hmm...
Let’s have a fight!
Ooh, ooh!
1. Once the battle’s done
Next time: Koharu and Eevee
The Tracks of Evolution.
2. And we’re laughing or crying
Look forward to it!
On 3, let’s be friends!