The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament Semifinals.
The fierce fight concluded with
Satoshi defeating the Champion of Sinnoh, Shirona,
advancing to the finals at last.
With tomorrow’s decisive match ahead of them,
Satoshi and Go have arrived at Shoot Stadium.
I wonder what Mr. Dande
wants to show us.
Maybe the Pokémon
he’s gonna use in the finals?
Mr. Dande!
Hey.
Ms. Sonia!
Professor Magnolia!
Hello!
Nice to see you two again!
I’ve been watching your battles, Satoshi.
You’re amazing!
You’ve made it this far,
so give Dande a good thrashing, too!
Yeah!
Hey, Sonia...
Don’t be like that.
Um...
What was it
you wanted to show us?
This.
Come on out!
Mugendaina!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Go and Aceburn!
The Place It All Began!!
Surprised?
Uh... Um... Yeah...
That thing was so violent...
Which is why I left it
with Professor Magnolia...
After that, we temporarily stored Mugendaina
deep beneath the laboratory.
But if we just leave it to slumber,
there’ll be no future for us.
Mugendaina is deeply connected
with Galar particles,
the energy that flows
throughout our region of Galar.
It’s an integral part
of the lives of the people of Galar.
We need to coexist
with Mugendaina.
And that’s why we thought we’d start
by getting it used to human contact.
With a bit of help from Dande.
It was a tough job at first,
since it kept lashing out at me,
but look at it now!
Whoa... Awesome!
Now, if it can just learn to
control its power a bit more...
Um... Mr. Dande!
Can I...
leave Mugendaina with you?
Huh?
Go...
It’s an important Pokémon
to the people of Galar...
And...
I feel like Mugendaina’s
accepted you too, Mr. Dande.
Go...
Are you really sure?
Yes!
Someday, I want to become an amazing trainer
that Mugendaina will accept, like you!
Got it.
I’ll honor your wish.
Mr. Dande, make sure
you don’t get lost tomorrow!
You’re a cheeky one, Satoshi,
you know that?
I have Lizardon, so I’ll be fine!
Good luck, Lizardon...
Shoot City, Galar Region
So, what are your plans for today?
Training to prepare for tomorrow?
Nope, I won’t do anything.
Huh?
We’ve made it this far.
No point sweating it now!
We’ll have a good rest tonight
so we can fight at full power!
Right, Pikachu?
So we should start with
some good food.
The really nice-smelling
tiny thingies!
They’re scones.
I choose them...
Right, right...
Aceburn?!
Do you remember this place,
Aceburn?
This is where we met.
Mister!
Hello!
Oh, it’s you kids.
Have you been well?
Yeah!
Look at this!
The Hibunny from back then
has evolved into Aceburn!
Huh?
This is that same Hibunny?!
Come on, stop it!
What’s going on?!
What are those...?
Zigzaguma: Galarian Form!
Tiny Raccoon Pokémon! Evil/Normal type!
It runs in zigzags and wreaks havoc
upon its surroundings!
Somebody!
Look, Aceburn!
It’s your old followers,
the mischievous Kusune!
Thank you!
Hold on just a sec.
Here, have this as thanks.
Thanks for always helping!
Thank you for protecting our city!
Have this!
We’re counting on you!
Thanks.
Thank you.
Here’s hoping you keep it up!
As you can see...
They stopped stealing, and started helping people
and punishing mischievous Pokémon...
Now they’re famous around here.
Ooh!
Tomorrow, we’re taking the supreme jerk’s Pokémon
and the brat boy’s Pokémon all in one go!
Is that really going to work,
though...?
We just need to prepare
lots of strong Pokémon ourselves, meow.
Forget that, I’m hungry...
Don’t they look pretty evil?
Don’t they look a lot like Nyarth?
They even have Charms...
What, meow?!
They’re not clean and tidy like me at all, meow!
Nyarth: Galarian Form.
What?!
See, I told you.
Don’t interrupt me!
And the bigger one
is the evolved form, Nyaiking.
With them on our side, we could
get our hands on plenty of food or Pokémon.
We should try and
recruit them somehow.
That decided, I’ll make them my underlings
and form a Nyarth Army, meow.
Hey, you guys.
Ready? Listen up!
You’re going to be
my underlings, meow.
They’re all good!
You too, Pikachu and Sarunori!
What’s wrong, Go?
Nothing...
I was just thinking about
how much began right here...
I had decided Mew was going to be
the first Pokémon I caught...
...but when I met Hibunny,
and it wound up being
my first catch instead,
that’s when my new dream was born.
To catch every Pokémon
and work my way up to Mew...
Yeah, that’s right.
And now,
I might finally get to meet Mew.
Did something happen?
Give that back!
Give me that!
What’re you doing?!
Hey!
Stop!
Who are they?
Nyaiking and the Nyarth.
They turned up recently,
and have been running wild.
After them, Go!
Right!
Which way did they go?
A catch already!
Keep this up,
and whether it’s Pokémon or food...
...we’ll be raking ‘em in, meow!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Nyaiking
Steel
Hey! Kusune!
Where could they have gone?
This fountain...
I caught Messon here.
Of course!
Inteleon!
Inteleon,
we’re chasing after some Kusune.
Can you help us look for them?
Satoshi, this way!
Got it!
Give it up!
You’re not getting away!
You’re going to
serve Team Rocket!
All thanks to our
Boss Nyaiking!
Marvelous job luring them here!
Please keep it up!
Keep bringing us food and Pokémon, meow!
So... how did we end up
the underlings?
Relax...
Flattery is the road to success.
Team Rocket!
So you were the ones
controlling Nyaiking!
Nonsense!
We are underlings
of the great Nyaiking!
It’s the one that’s
controlling us, meow!
What?
Well, whichever way it is,
you’re gonna give back
everyone’s food!
Humph!
The brat’s mouthing off.
We’ll help ourselves to Pikachu,
and your Pokémon, too!
Hold on, Musashi!
Huh?
The plan is to take
the brat boy’s Pokémon tomorrow.
Oh, right.
Then...
Do we just back off?
What are you saying, meow?
Don’t put off until tomorrow
any evil you can do today, meow!
Oh, Nyarth...!
You’re the gold standard of evil!
Vending, come on, meow!
Rocket!
Vending!
Secret!
What’re we gonna get?!
The Serene Pokémon,
Tebrim!
The Devious Pokémon,
Gimoh!
Better get ready, brat boy!
Let’s move, Pikachu!
Aceburn?
Of course... Got it!
Satoshi, can you let us
handle this on our own?
Go...
All yours!
Thanks! All right...
Let’s move!
Aceburn! Inteleon! Sarunori!
Didn’t think we were done,
did ya?
Every Charm gives us
a spin of the Vending!
What?!
Rocket!
Vending!
Secret!
Rocket!
Vending!
Secret!
It’s a Vending fever!
The Big Rock Pokémon,
Ishihengin!
The Sheep Pokémon,
Baiwooloo!
The Rush Pokémon,
Sashikamasu!
The Gulp Pokémon,
U'u!
You still got this, Go?
Yeah!
If I couldn’t handle this,
I’d never be able to reach Mew, yeah?
We have Boss Nyaiking
on our side, too!
Tebrim! Brutal Swing!
Ishihengin! Stomp!
Baiwooloo! Tackle!
Dodge, Aceburn, Inteleon!
Gimoh! Surprise Attack!
What is that?!
A Sashikamasu projectile
from the mouth?!
I have to stop it!
Sarunori, go for it!
The Kusune!
They evolved!
Foxly! Fox Pokémon!
Evil type!
It steals its pickings with its lithe body
and sharp claws!
Boss Nyaiking!
Now, Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Inteleon, use Snipe Shot!
You’ve gotta be kidding me!
They were all defeated!
Kojiro! The Vending!
Vending!
Rocket...
Huh?
What now?
This guy doesn’t fit
in the Vending!
How come, meow?
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
For the first time in ages,
what an awful feeling!
You showed ‘em!
Here!
To celebrate you evolving!
Continue keeping our city safe, okay?
Good for you!
Now, you must be
hungry too, no?
Thank you!
The Foxly...
They’re taking after
your spirit as a street gang boss!
We ate all we could,
now just gotta sleep for tomorrow!
You really are battling Mr. Dande...
I’m so excited,
I might not get any sleep.
What’s wrong, Go?
I’m sorry, Satoshi...
I...
...can’t watch your
battle tomorrow.
I got an urgent summons
from Project Mew.
So I have to leave right now...
Really?
Well, make sure you meet that Mew!
Yeah! Make sure you
win too, Satoshi!
Yeah!
It’s a promise!
Next time we meet...
...let’s meet with a smile!
To achieve their own dreams,
Satoshi and Go each depart
on separate paths.
And waiting
before them...
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They’re all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they’re unique and you’ll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
The Pokémon World Championships!
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
The Single Biggest
Upset in History?!
I’ve got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Will we see the single biggest upset in history?!
Next Time :  "Climax!    Eve of the Finals, Satoshi VS Dande!!"
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The exhilarating Masters Tournament
is finally about to reach its climax!
The absolute monarch, Competitor Dande,
has won his way through the ranks!
Greeting someone new is always fresh
Facing him is a first-time
Masters Tournament entrant and first-time finalist,
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
the promising rising star,
Competitor Satoshi!
Let’s have a fight!
Which one will be the world’s strongest?!
1. Once the battle’s done
On the next episode,
complete coverage of the exhilarating finals!
2. And we’re laughing or crying
On 3, let’s be...
Don’t miss it!