Kaina City, Hoenn Region
After receiving an urgent summons
from Project Mew,
Go has arrived at Kaina City
in the Hoenn Region.
Um... The lab is...
Go!
Tokio!
The search for Mew
is finally here!
Yeah!
And we even
get to participate together!
I was so excited,
I couldn’t sleep last night.
That’s no good.
You ought to make sure
you’re in peak condition.
Shigeru!
Shigeru, friend!
What a pity, Go.
Huh?
Satoshi’s Masters Tournament
finals match is today, right?
Yeah.
But I just know he’ll win.
We promised each other...
...that next time we meet,
we’ll meet with a smile!
Interesting.
Yeah.
Hey, we should hurry.
Professor Hodaka will be waiting.
Satoshi...
Give it all you’ve got.
Give it all you’ve got...
...Go.
Shoot Stadium, Galar Region
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The Finals I - "Torrent"
The Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament.
Today, at last, we have the finals!
In this event, we saw a lineup
of Champions from various regions,
the rarely-matched spectacle
of an all-star Masters Eight!
The two who took down this lineup
of powerhouses to become finalists...
...are moments away from clashing
on the battlefield!
One will be the trainer standing
at the summit of Pokémon battling!
Everyone!
You ready to go?!
We’re gonna win!
Wha—?
Satoshi!
Excuse us!
Huh?!
Hikari! And Koharu!
We came here to cheer for you.
I’ll be cheering extra,
to make up for Go.
You will? Thanks!
Plus...
I wanted to show her
an official match, too.
I’ve been watching everything on TV too,
but I just couldn’t sit back and watch from afar!
The whole Institute’s
cheering for you, too.
Do your best, Satoshi!
Yeah!
Big Bro...
This is a nice sense of tension...
I wonder why...
...I’m reminded of
the first day I ever battled.
Now, the two Pokémon Trainers seeking to
stand upon the summit are finally arriving.
Pochama’s so cute!
Great, huh?
This is how we cheered him on
back in Sinnoh!
Would Eevee like to try it?
Huh?
That’s so cute!
You look great, Eevee!
Who’d have thought
the brat boy would make it this far?
Let’s take it up a notch
with live-streamed commentary!
Don’t forget our goal, meow!
Huh?
Today, we’ll finally find out who has
the strongest Pokémon, fit for Team Rocket, meow!
I forgot about that!
We can’t complete our mission
if we don’t catch them!
Let’s keep a diligent watch!
Yeah!
Now then,
the finalists are here.
Ranked 8th in the Masters Eight,
the first Champion of Alola...
Hailing from Kanto,
Competitor Satoshi.
Go for it!
Give it your all!
Satoshi!
I’m cheering for you!
Go for it, go for it, Satoshi!
Everyone’s cheering for Satoshi...
This is no time to be streaming!
You said it! Call it off!
We have to cheer
for the brat boy, meow!
Ever since entering the Championships,
he’s defeated strong opponents one after another.
The tournament’s
most promising trainer.
During the tournament, he’s defeated
Competitor Daigo, the Champion of Hoenn...
...and even emerged victorious against
Competitor Shirona, the Champion of Sinnoh.
Wielding Daimax, Z-Moves, and Mega Evolution,
he uses unique ideas in his Pokémon battles.
So, what inspired plays
does he have for us today?
And facing Competitor Satoshi...
...is the unrivaled Monarch
that everyone knows.
The object of admiration and goal
of Pokémon Trainers around the world!
Ranked 1st in the Masters Eight!
The Champion of Galar,
Competitor Dande!
Big Bro!
Hop.
Sonia! You made it!
Thought I had to
watch this up close.
Now, will Competitor Satoshi be able to
put an end to his undefeated win streak?
Or will Competitor Dande’s
win streak only be extended?
A truly climactic match!
Satoshi! So we finally meet
upon the battlefield!
Yeah! And...
...in the finals!
There’s no better stage!
No one has been looking forward to our battle more...
...than me!
Competing on equal footing with Champions...
He truly has grown remarkably!
Yup! Trust your Pokémon
and try your best, Satoshi!
The finals are a 6v6 full battle!
There is no limit on match length
or switching out Pokémon.
Whoever makes all six of their opponent’s Pokémon
unable to battle will be the winner.
Additionally, you are allowed a single use of only one
of the following: Daimax, a Z-Move, or Mega Evolu—
Hold it!
Competitor Dande...
“Only one” is no fun!
Use all of them, Satoshi!
All of them?
This is a serious match,
the climactic match!
I and my Pokémon will be facing you
with everything we have.
So I want you and your Pokémon
to face me with everything you have, too!
Daimax, Z-Moves, Mega Evolution...
I wanna fight them all!
And then beat them all!
Everyone, what do you think?
Don’t you want to see him
battle at full power?!
Yeah! That’s my bro!
What a great idea!
Woohoo! Yay!
What does that mean?
It means this is gonna be incredible!
Go get him, Satoshi!
Yes... Yes... Understood.
The Championships Management
has accepted Competitor Dande’s suggestion.
Competitor Satoshi, do you accept?
Of course! I’ll do it!
Unprecedented!
Competitor Dande’s suggestion will turn this finals match
into a never-before-seen, full-spec, super battle!
That’s just like Competitor Dande.
Yes.
This will be a heated battle
like none before.
Now then, both battlers,
send your first Pokémon out onto the field!
Three!
Two!
One!
Go!
Pikachu, I choose you!
Come out, Aceburn!
I’m counting on you, Pikachu!
I decided you’d go first!
No thought to tactics, then.
Let’s crush him, Aceburn!
Big Bro’s Aceburn
is the strongest striker.
Let the battle begin!
100,000 Volts!
Scorching Sands!
Aceburn and Pikachu’s attacks...
...both hit simultaneously!
Whoa! Aceburn was completely unfazed
by the 100,000 Volts!
What?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Let the battle begin!
100,000 Volts!
Scorching Sands!
Aceburn and Pikachu’s attacks...
...both hit simultaneously!
What?!
The Ground-type Scorching Sands
was super effective on Pikachu!
On the other hand, a direct hit
from 100,000 Volts left Aceburn unharmed.
Could this mean...?
Satoshi... first time
seeing the Ability Libero?
Libero...
When this guy uses an attack,
it becomes the type of the move.
Does that mean Aceburn’s...
a Ground type right now?
Pikachu, return!
If electricity won’t work...
...then that’s his only option.
You okay?
Come watch the others battle.
Return, Aceburn!
Come out, Inteleon!
Gänger, I choose you!
Now an Inteleon...
It’s like I’m battling Go’s Pokémon.
Let’s do it! Snipe Shot!
Shadow Ball!
Hit it!
Evil Pulse!
Gänger, dodge it!
That won’t work.
Aqua Jet!
What’s that?
Counter Shield...
It’s the spinning tactic Competitor Satoshi
and Pikachu used in the semifinals, replicated perfectly!
Satoshi! I added that interesting trick
of yours to my arsenal.
I’m impressed, Mr. Dande.
Gänger!
Quite a surprise, wasn’t it?
That means hiding’s pointless...
Satoshi’s under some real pressure.
Yes.
Competitor Dande’s greed... Even mastering
his rival’s techniques if it helps him win...
And Inteleon marvelously pulls it off!
Gänger! Use Will-O-Wisp!
Watch out, Inteleon!
Return, Gänger!
Let’s get huge!
Here it is.
Kyodaimax!
Competitor Satoshi
decides to activate Kyodaimax!
How will Competitor Dande
respond to this?!
Snipe Shot!
What? With both hands?
Big Bro’s Inteleon can dual wield!
Kyodai Phantom!
They both took damage!
All right!
You really went and did it.
Due to the effect of Kyodai Phantom,
Competitor Dande can’t switch Pokémon!
Big Bro can still do this,
even if he can’t switch!
Evil Pulse!
Dai Acid!
Gänger! Full power!
Fire!
Inteleon!
Dai Acid lands a direct hit
on Inteleon!
And perhaps the Evil Pulse hit a critical point,
because Gänger has returned to normal size.
Inteleon is unable to battle!
The first win of the finals
goes to Competitor Satoshi!
All right!
This can’t be real...
Big Bro...
He did it!
Begin with your first win...
Gäge-chan did well, too.
Good going, oh!
Ohh!
Gänger, good work, meow!
See that, supreme jerk?!
That’s what the brat boy can do, oh!
You okay, Gänger?
Return, Inteleon!
You fought well.
I’ll build upon that base.
I’ll catch up to you, Satoshi!
He’s ignited.
He’s amazing
when he gets like that.
Come out, Barrikohru!
Competitor Dande’s third Pokémon
is Barrikohru!
Sludge Bomb!
Freeze-Dry!
The Sludge Bombs were frozen!
Barikohru! Freeze-Dry!
It looks like Barrikohru
can’t manage to attack.
The ability Cursed Body, huh?
Yeah! You won’t be using
Freeze-Dry for a while!
You think that can stop me?
Gänger is frozen!
The fearsome power of Freeze-Dry!
No way...
Psycho Field!
A Psycho Field unfolds!
That’ll increase the strength of Psychic-type moves!
What do you think?
Now the battlefield
has become a stage for Barrikohru.
Wide Force!
Gänger!
Gänger is unable to battle!
With the effect of Psycho Field
and the powered-up Wide Force,
this time Competitor Dande takes a win!
In an instant, he’s evened the score!
All right!
He was done in, meow...
Return, Gänger!
You fought well.
I dedicate this victory to Inteleon.
His hard work is what enabled it.
As I suppose you know,
what you do in a full battle...
...is use your Pokémon
to build up damage on the opponent,
seizing each victory as a team.
The Masters Tournament finals
see a fierce battle unfold from the outset.
Dande and Satoshi
each claim one victory,
as an even more fervent, fierce fight shakes
the battlefield.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
The finals battle between Competitor Satoshi
and Competitor Dande!
Currently,
they’ve each lost one Pokémon!
The battle is even, meow!
And that... Barribarrikohru, was it?
That sure gets on my nerves.
It’s “Barrikohru”!
And come on, we’re live!
Look forward to
the next battle, meow!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Finals II: “Toyed With”
The Finals II - "Toyed With"
Let’s all tune in, meow!