Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Shoot City, Galar Region
This is Galar’s
Shoot City Station.
It seems a train
has just arrived.
Here at last!
Not quite yet.
We have to switch trains.
I know.
We’re going to
Lateral Town, right?
Which platform is it?
S-Sorry...
His ticket...
Hey, you!
You dropped this!
Hey!
Hey, look!
You dropped your ticket!
He went in there, right?
I guess...
Hey!
He’s not here.
I wonder where he went.
Platform 0, Lateral Town line,
is about to depart.
Passengers bound for this line
please enter the train now.
You hear that?
It’s going to Lateral Town.
Quick, Go!
The Ghost Train will now depart.
Yeah!
Please refrain from running
to catch the train.
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Ghost Train Will Now Depart...
Didn’t they call this the “Ghost Train”
or something just now?
Did they?
Well, as long as it’s going to
Lateral Town, it’s all good.
Either way...
I better return this.
Coach 1, huh...?
That means...
he’ll be in the passenger car at the very front.
Yeah.
‘Kay, you ready?
Ooh!
So fancy!
Is this one of those
luxury coaches?
What’s this thing?
Ow...
You okay, Satoshi?
Yeah.
Come on, Sarunori,
you need to be more careful.
Oh, no!
Phew,
it doesn’t look broken.
It’s heavy!
What are you doing?
It— It won’t budge...
What’s wrong with this rock?
It’s way too heavy!
What should we do?
We can’t just leave it here...
Oh, well. We’ll get someone
to help put it back later.
What was that?
Satoshi, are you all right?
Huh? Why’re you asking?
Never mind,
you seem fine.
Well, let’s go.
Oh... Yeah.
There’s something in there!
Huh? What’s up?
Didn’t you see that, Satoshi?!
What’re you so scared of?
You crack me up.
Huh?
What is it?
Even Pikachu looks scared.
What’s so strange
about me, huh?
Satoshi?
Come on, come on!
We need to get to
the next coach already!
Wait, stop!
And, bam!
What am I doing?
Sorry, Go...
What’s gotten into you
all of a sudden?
I think...
...there’s something
wrong with me...
Who are these guys?
Fuwante! Balloon Pokémon!
Ghost/Flying type!
It tugs on the hands of children
to drag them away to the afterlife!
The afterlife?!
It’ll be bad news
if they catch us...
Hey, don’t come closer!
Hey... Hey...
Hey, you!
Satoshi?
So, what kind of
bad news, exactly?
I-I’m saying weird stuff again!
Hey! Hey, wait a sec!
Stop! Stop!
This is such a laugh! I’m howling!
Cut it out!
Come, now!
If the Fuwante catch you,
off to the afterlife you’ll...
Go!
Nooo!
Huh? This doesn’t look like
the afterlife...
While it may tug on the hands of children,
sometimes the children pull it around instead!
You have to be kidding me...
You’re a riot!
I shoulda taken a photo of you!
What am I saying?
I’m being so mean...
Hey, Satoshi...
Don’t you think you’ve been acting weird?
I really have!
You think so?
I do.
What’s wrong with you?
You’re such a pain,
whining over a little prank...
Let’s hurry up
and keep going!
Ugh...
What’s wrong with me?!
Huh? What’s this?
You’re kidding me...
What’s wrong with this train?
You’re not scared again,
are you?
Bleh! Scaredy-cat!
Scaredy-cat!
Hey, me!
Stop being so mean!
I’m not scared!
Then you go first.
Umm...
Or how about some nice and fair
rock-paper-scissors to decide?
Oh, that’s more like it!
Okay, I accept.
So, you ready?
One match
crowns the winner!
Rock, paper... scissors!
Yay! I won!
You threw your hand late!
What are you talking about?
Got any proof?
C’mon, me!
Cheating is wrong!
Sorry...
I’m really sorry, Go!
What a creepy place...
Oh! Isn’t that
a will-o’-the-wisp?
A will-o’-the-wisp?!
Oh, it was just a Yamirami?
Yamirami! Darkness Pokémon!
Evil/Ghost type!
It feeds on gemstone crystals!
Hey, Go! Look over here!
There’s zombies!
What are those things?
Tsuchinin! Trainee Pokémon!
Bug/Ground type!
It can live underground
for more than 10 years!
It absorbs nutrients
from the roots of trees!
Huh? They couldn’t be...
They evolved!
Tekkanin! Shinobi Pokémon!
Bug/Flying type!
It is so quick, it is said
to be able to avoid any attack!
Here they come!
Oh, no you don’t!
Satoshi?!
I’m going numb...
Pikachu... Thank you...
Nukenin’s data will be
added to the Index!
Huh? Added?
Why?
Nukenin! Shed Shell Pokémon!
Bug/Ghost type!
A most peculiar Pokémon that somehow appears
in a Monster Ball when a Tsuchinin evolves!
Hey, you!
When’d you get in his Ball?
Hey! Hey!
Come on, stop that, Satoshi.
You’re no fun!
Oh, it’s him!
Why...?
Why are humans
on the ghost train?
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Mikaruge
Evil
Ghost
What was that?
The luxury coach...
But that’s...
Mikaruge...
It woke up...
Mikaruge! Sealed Pokémon!
Ghost/Evil type!
A Pokémon
that was formed by 108 spirits!
There are some
ill-natured spirits in the mix!
Ill-natured spirits?
It says, “Return the spirit”...
You can understand
what Mikaruge says?!
Kind of...
But more to the point...
That boy...
Mikaruge!
What happened, Satoshi?!
Inside him... there is an ill-natured spirit
that Mikaruge once housed...
How did that happen?!
Oh! Is that why Satoshi’s
been acting so odd?
Mikaruge...
Mikaruge!
Pull yourself together,
Satoshi!
How can we get him
back to normal?
If you know how,
I need you to tell me!
Well...
Mika!
The Fuwante...
Hurry, everyone.
You’ll be a bit safer in here.
This is bad...
That thing’s gonna derail the train.
If that happens,
everyone will...
I’ll stop Mikaruge!
So you have to
get Satoshi back to normal!
You know how,
don’t you?
But...
I’m Go. He’s Satoshi.
I’m begging you!
He’s my precious friend!
I’ll try...
Thank you!
Monster Ball, go!
Let’s go, Absol!
Yabacha!
May I ask you a favor?
Yabacha absorbs your life-force.
If this works, it may be able to flush
the ill-natured spirit out of Satoshi...
But Yabacha’s tea...
...has a heinous taste.
Yuck!
Yuck, yuck, yuck, yuck,
yuck, yuck, yuck!
Mikaruge!
You need to calm down!
We’re trying to return you
your spirit as I speak!
So stop rampaging, and...
Crossroad Kill!
What did you do to me?!
U-Umm...
The spirit...
Huh?
It’ll be okay...
I know it will...
It’s coming out!
Whoa...
Pikachu!
No!
That guy...!
Okay, if that’s what you want,
two can play at that game!
Come on out!
Ooh... That’s a good choice.
Gänger! Go and catch the guy
hiding in my shadow!
Okay, I’ll pull you back up!
Take that to Mikaruge.
Yeah, got it!
Dodge it!
This isn’t working...
It’s not giving me any openings...
Dodge!
Absol!
Gänger?
Satoshi!
Yeah! It’s me, Satoshi!
Gänger’s got that guy’s spirit.
I only need a moment.
Let’s stop it from moving!
I’ll use that opening
to give the spirit back!
Got it.
Good work, Gänger!
Absol!
Kick up some rubble!
Gänger! Now!
We did it!
They took it away.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Mikaruge wanted to go
to this graveyard.
The Ghost Train
carries Ghost Pokémon.
Ghost Pokémon?
Nothing else?
Only me.
That tired me out.
Sure was fun, though!
Maybe a little.
And we made it
to Lateral Town.
Geez, you always find a way
to look at the bright side.
Oh, right!
I almost forgot.
Here’s your—
Huh?
Where’d...?
The whole Ghost Train’s gone...
What’s going on here?
We really did
ride that thing, right?
The strange
and slightly scary Ghost Train...
Maybe someday you, too, might ride it
by mistake just as Satoshi and Go did.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Let’s do our best, Gänger!
If it drinks Dai Soup,
it can Kyodaimax.
Oh, I think I’ve heard of that!
If a Pokémon drinks Dai Soup
made from Dai Mushrooms, it can Kyodaimax!
But... It won’t be easy.
Watch out, Satoshi!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Gänger Goes All In!
The Road to Kyodaimax!!