Project Mew, an operation to search for Mew,
is underway.
Go, who hopes to join the search,
must clear various Pokémon-related Trial Missions.
Every successfully cleared mission
nets the participant a token.
The three candidates who obtain
the most tokens will be accepted.
Will Go be able to join the official Mew search team,
and become a Chaser?
Go!
Heard you got
your next Trial Mission!
Yeah...
Someone’s bummed!
What’s wrong?!
Well... This time they’re measuring
our battling skills and cooperation.
Battling? That’s great!
The problem is the cooperation...
Huh?
It’s a Raid Battle...
The mission this time...
What’re you up against?
The Legendary Pokémon, Freezer...
Whoa! That’s so exciting!
You getting excited doesn’t help me.
But you’ve been in a Raid Battle before,
against that Golugh.
Well... I guess.
Right? With me helping you,
it’ll be fine!
I’m starting to feel like
I can do it.
Freezer! Freezing Pokémon!
Ice/Flying type!
A legendary bird Pokémon
that can control ice!
It is said to live in snowy mountains
riddled with permafrost!
Snowy mountains
riddled with permafrost, huh?
Where should I look...?
How about Twins Island?
Twins Island?
Kikuna,
put it on the main monitor.
Right.
Twins Island is an island in southern Kanto
with a pair of adjacent mountains.
There’s apparently a permafrost cave inside the island
connecting the two mountains.
It wouldn’t be strange
to find Freezer living there.
Thank you, Director.
The future lies in my hands!
Okay then, off to Twins Island...
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Trial Mission!
A Freezing Raid Battle!!
Seeking to attempt the Trial Mission,
“Have a Raid Battle against Freezer,”
Go and Satoshi
have arrived at Twins Island.
Will Go be able to
complete the mission?
Twins Island, Kanto Region
A cliff!
That looks like somewhere
we can cross.
Be careful, there’s a strong wind.
Yeah, I know.
Golbat?
Pikachu, use 100,000–
I’ve got this!
Monster Ball, go!
Nice!
Golbat’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Which way?
Hmm... I don’t know.
Why don’t we try this way first?
Right.
Another split...
This place is like a maze!
What do we do?
Let’s try the left first.
Huh?
In that case...
Another dead end?
One more try!
This has to be it!
What’s wrong?
Are you okay?
I’ve been lost for ages...
You’re in Project Mew, too?
Yeah, I’m a Challenger.
You can come with me, then!
I’m a Challenger, too!
No...
My Pokémon are all weakened
from battling Ishitsubute.
I can’t have a Raid Battle
with Freezer like this.
You’re giving up?
I have no choice.
Another split...
Again?!
Oh, that sounds nice.
Yeah.
Wait, a sound...
Then what about...?
Inteleon, go!
Okay, Sarunori, hit it again!
Inteleon! Pick up the vibrations
in the air and find us the exit!
In here?
That looks deep...
Maybe that’s the entrance
to the cave.
Thanks, Inteleon.
You should get in
your Ball now too, Sarunori.
Freezer will be somewhere
in this cave...
What is it?
A Gorone!
Monster Ball, go!
Great!
Gorone’s data will be
added to the Index!
Is that your second catch?!
Yeah, I’m on a roll!
At this rate,
even Freezer’s no match for me!
What’s wrong?
Go, look at this...
A hole?
Let’s try going down there.
Caterpie, come on!
String Shot!
Bayleaf! Vine Whip!
Tokio?!
Go!
Huh? Someone you know?
It’s been a while!
So your Chicorita evolved
into Bayleaf?
Yeah!
My Rabbifoot evolved, too!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
All right!
Now’s your chance
to catch it, Go!
Then I won’t hold back!
Excellent!!
Pearshen’s data will be
added to the Index!
Got it!
That’s my third catch today!
Thanks, Tokio!
You helped me out, too, Go.
I nearly ended up dropping out
before even getting to meet Freezer.
Huh?
Does that mean you’re
a Project Mew Challenger too?
Yeah. You are too, right?
Course, yeah.
I knew it!
But weren’t you chasing
after Celebi?
Huh? Celebi?
Let me introduce you.
This is a friend of mine,
and another research fellow.
I’m Satoshi. This is Pikachu.
I’m Tokio. I became friends with Go long ago
when our paths crossed at a place he was visiting.
This is Bayleaf.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
If you’re chasing after Celebi,
why’re you in Project Mew?
Ah, well...
Celebi’s an Psychic/Grass type.
I thought that if I track down
every Psychic type, including Mew,
that might lead me
to Celebi, someday.
Ooh, you kinda sound like Go.
Let’s work hard
and become Chasers!
Yeah!
But first, we need to find Freezer!
That’s right.
I met some Challengers
on the way here,
but they all got lost in the maze,
or were attacked by Pokémon...
We saw them, too.
Can’t we do something for them...?
What do you mean?
I feel sorry for them.
They made it all this way to Twins Island...
They were so close to reaching Freezer.
Even so, this is our mission...
Still...
You’re really kind, Tokio.
I didn’t mean it like that...
What’s that sound?
A waterfall!
Let’s have a look!
What is this thing...?
I can’t see the basin...
What’s that?
An ice temple?
Guess it kinda looks like one.
There’s light shining in
from outside?
Good grief...
I never expected to see
you two here.
Shigeru?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
What’s that “Good grief...” for?!
See? It takes nothing
to rile you up.
That’s what exasperates me.
Do you know him?
Yeah... He’s not a bad guy,
at least...
Shigeru.
I’m Tokio.
Nice to meet you.
We should work together
from here.
Tokio! Don’t just decide that!
He even waited here
for us, though.
Just ‘cause one person
isn’t enough for a Raid Battle!
Correct.
The way I see it, clearing the mission
should be priority number one.
I suspect that Freezer
is over there.
So choose.
Will you come investigate
with me or not?
Go...
Let’s go.
You’re not scared, are you?
Of course not!
I’m coming! Just you watch!
It’s cold...
Get back!
Freezer!
This is a message
from Project Mew.
You may use up to three Pokémon
for the Raid Battle.
Recording will begin now.
Here we go!
Everyone, get ready!
You don’t have to tell me!
Go, Banguirus!
Hihidaruma, come on!
Negigaknight, I choose you!
You’re up, Yessan!
Stay focused.
Next Pokémon!
Blacky!
Aceburn, go!
Lucario!
Sirknight!
Eerie Light!
Absolute Zero?!
A one-hit KO move...
It’ll sweep you up
if you stick too close!
Try to battle from a distance!
The Eerie Light confused it.
Now’s our chance to attack!
Pyro Ball!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
The confusion wore off!
Here it comes!
Reflector!
Good choice!
Thanks, Tokio!
Don’t look away!
Focus on the battle!
Windie!
Pyro Ball!
Guiding Wave Sphere!
Moonforce!
Reflector!
What was that attack?!
That’s Triple Axel.
The Reflector
cut its strength in half.
Aceburn and Lucario,
grab onto Freezer!
Don’t just order them around!
Go, let’s do it.
Aceburn, grab onto Freezer!
You too, Lucario!
Flamethrower!
Blaze Kick!
Go, Lucario!
Heal Pulse!
Thank you, Tokio.
Don’t let your guard down!
Yeah, I know!
Satoshi,
let’s pile on the pressure!
Yeah!
No! Freezer’s not some
easy little pushover!
Aceburn!
Use Blaze Kick again!
Lucario, use Guiding Wave Sphere!
Sirknight, use Light Screen!
Windie! Flamethrower!
Aceburn!
Gantle, come on!
Here we go, Bayleaf!
Pikachu, I choose you!
Go. We’re not alone here.
Let’s work as a team.
I know that already!
You don’t understand!
That’s what Shigeru’s
been trying to do!
In a Raid Battle,
you need to cooperate as a team.
It’s such a basic idea,
I never thought to bring it up.
From now on,
you should follow my commands.
Have Bayleaf hold Freezer
with Vine Whip.
Then Pikachu, Gantle,
and Windie can attack!
Bayleaf! Vine Whip!
All right! 100,000 Volts!
Flamethrower!
Stone Edge!
It might use Absolute Zero!
Split up!
No, don’t! If it uses Blizzard,
we’ll all be done for!
Cluster together behind Gantle!
Absolute Zero?!
Windie!
Pikachu!
Tokio! Bayleaf can’t
fight Freezer on its own!
No, I have to try.
Bayleaf, use Energy Ball!
Bayleaf!
The Raid Battle against Freezer
has concluded.
Stand by for contact from HQ.
Freezer was really strong...
Go?
Tokio... If you guys weren’t here...
I wouldn’t have stood a chance.
Don’t say that.
You taking the front line allowed me
to focus on defense and recovery moves.
You’re too optimistic.
The Raid Battle would’ve gone better
if not for his selfish actions.
Mr. Tsurugi.
We’ve collected valuable data
on Freezer.
Thank you.
As proof of clearing the mission,
we will send you each three tokens.
Furthermore...
Shigeru gets one extra token for his strong leadership,
and Tokio for his dedication to teamwork.
Mr. Tsurugi. Is cooperation
going to be necessary for finding Mew?
Think about that yourself.
Let me say something, too.
A certain someone used to be selfish,
and a poor team player,
and he still managed to get picked
to be a Chaser somehow.
That will be all.
Well, this is where
I say goodbye.
Right...
Cheer up, Go.
There’ll be more missions.
If you keep at it,
I’m sure you’ll make it!
Thanks.
Sometimes,
kindness can be a cruelty.
Accepting someone who isn’t ready,
allowing them hopes and dreams,
and forcing them beyond their means
can lead to the worst possible outcome.
What do you mean by that?
I cooperated with you today
because the mission was a Raid Battle,
but we Challengers don’t need to
play nice and pretend to be friends.
It’s fine! We can help
each other out as friends!
You’re as naïve as ever.
I agree with Mr. Tsurugi’s
strict mentality.
Without that strictness,
we’ll never encounter Mew.
You’re starting to realize that now,
aren’t you, Go?
First time you’ve said my name
in a friendly tone.
By provoking people,
you make them realize something new.
I’m starting to understand
your ways too, Shigeru.
And that’s the first time
you’ve even said my name.
I look forward to our next meeting.
See you!
Go, Tokio, and Shigeru have
cleared the mission with flying colors.
Will the three of them be chosen
as Project Mew members?
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Messon
Wanpachi
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Messon
Wanpachi
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Wanpachi
Electric!
Messon
Wanpachi
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Dragon
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Steel
Psychic
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poi
Pois
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Betobeta
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fly
Flyin
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Flying
What type is this Pokémon?
Kokogara
Kaiross
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Kaiross
Yabacha
Gho
Ghos
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Yabacha
Ghost
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
My opponent this time is Ms. Dracaena
of the Kalos Elite Four!
And she’s a Dragon user.
She’ll be a tough opponent!
I thought this might happen...
The time has come for science
to usher in our future!
Citronic Gear, on!
I’m Eureka.
Nice to meet you!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Satoshi and Citron!
The Great Friendship Training!!