Satoshi, Go, and Koharu traveled to
the Crown Snowfield for Pokémon research.
Meanwhile, Lilie, Gladio, and Lusamine
found Professor Mohn, their missing father.
However, he had lost his memory
and believed that Utsuroid was his daughter, Lilie.
But when his family’s feelings
managed to make him recall his real memories,
Utsuroid became a new member
of their family.
And now...
Alola Region
That’s Alola!
Satoshi and his friends are headed
for the Alola Region with Mohn’s family.
This is making me
a little nervous.
You haven’t been to Alola before,
have you, Koharu?
Don’t worry.
Everyone’s really nice there!
I want to ask your friend
all about Eevee!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Homecoming!
The Champion of Alola!!
Everyone!
Today is a most joyous day...
...for Mohn has returned to Alola!
Glad you’re safe!
Welcome back home!
Lilie!
Welcome back!
Mao! Suiren! Māmane!
I’m back!
We’ve missed you!
Yeah!
You really did it, Lilie!
I am so glad to see you again!
Master! Madame!
James...
I am glad you came back
safe and sound...
We’ve been waiting for you
to return for so long!
Sauboh, Wicke...
I’m sorry for making you
worry about me.
Professor!
Professor Mohn!
I am a researcher for Aether Paradise!
Rotom, Pokédex Forme-roto!
Pleasuroto to meet you!
Pleasuroto’s all mine, Rotom.
Now, let us begin the feast!
All right, everyone...
...come on out!
Wow, this is amazing!
It’s incredible!
It really is...
Have as much as you want!
Um, Suiren...
It’s Koharu, right?
With the Eevee.
Yeah!
You see...
I wanted to ask if you could
tell me about your Eevee.
Sure!
Hey, Suiren.
What are you going to evolve Sandy into?
Evolve?
Eevee and I have come across
lots of her evolutions.
But I still don’t know...
...which of the eight
Eevee wants to evolve into.
One more choice.
The Eevee path.
Huh?
Staying an Eevee.
Like Satoshi’s Pikachu.
Satoshi’s Pikachu?
I get it!
So Eevee have nine paths, not just eight!
Lots of possibilities!
Lots of...
Possibilities!
Yeah!
Hey, where’s Kaki?
Oh, about that...
The moment we told him Satoshi
was coming back with Lilie...
What?! Satoshi?!
There’s no time to waste!
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Hold on, Kaki!
“Go”? Where are you going?
To seclude myself
in Wela Volcano and train!
That’s just like him.
I wanna battle Kaki, too!
Satoshi, you were marvelous
in your promotion match!
Huh?
You saw that, Lilie?
Yes!
I watched an online stream
with Big Brother!
We saw it, too!
Everyone gathered at the Pokémon School
to cheer you on!
After all, you’re the first
Alola League Champion!
Thanks!
Champion Dande is taking part in
the Masters Tournament too, right?
Yeah!
Beating Mr. Dande
is my goal now!
Classic Satoshi!
Go for it!
I will cheer for you!
We need to get training, too.
A Battle Royal?!
Yeah!
Dah!
Ooh!
Were you copying
your big bro Satoshi?
Lei’s so cute!
Um, what’s a Battle Royal?
It’s a type of Pokémon battle
held at Alola’s Royal Dome.
Four teams of competitors
clash and battle, all at the same time.
Who am I fighting?
That’s a secret until the day.
Wha...? No way...
Well, I’ll tell you one opponent.
Yeah, yeah!
It’s me!
Professor?!
All right!
You gotta battle as Royal Mask!
Huh?!
Okay? Royal Mask!
Enjoy!
That’s...
...Royal Mask?
That was cool!
But you see, Satoshi...
...I won’t be wearing my mask.
Huh?!
You’re the star of this battle!
The star?
You’re Alola’s Champion!
So I’ll battle you as myself.
Okay?
Got it.
All right!
Time to get training!
I made it in time.
The dome is packed!
This is the Champion of Alola’s
homecoming, after all!
Excitement rising!
It’s starting!
Everybody, say Alola!
Alola!
Put some more energy into it!
Put some more passion into it!
Alola!
This is what you always wanted,
right, me?
This is the stuff!
Thank you all for coming to the
First Alola League Champion Homecoming Battle Royal!
Your emcees today will be the passionate adorer
of Royal Mask and Battle Royals, Sauboh...
...together with me, Wicke!
And now...
Let’s welcome the competitors!
The first one in the ring is,
naturally...
...a trainer set to compete in the Masters Tournament
to determine the strongest in the world!
It is our Champion,
Competitor Satoshi with Pikachu!
Let’s do our best, Pikachu!
And for the next corner...
The founder of
the Alola Pokémon League!
Competitor Kukui with Gaogaen!
Next up, in the third corner...
Akala Island’s blazing
Island King in the making!
Competitor Kaki with Garagara!
And last but not least!
The Alola League runner-up!
Competitor Gladio with...
...Lilie the Utsuroid!
Lilie?!
Yes!
The newest member of my family.
Huh...
Cool! Ultra Beast Lilie!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Zoroark! Night Burst!
Lilie...
You want to battle?
Let’s show them
the fruits of our training!
Battling with Utsuroid
right out the gate, huh?
We have truly marvelous
competitors here today!
Well then, let the Battle Royal...
...begin!
Pikachu!
Use Iron Tail on Gaogaen!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
As usual, a calm and composed choice from Royal Ma—
I mean, Competitor Kukui!
Garagara, use Iron Head!
Lilie! Venom Shock!
Gaogaen! DD Lariat!
Pikachu!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Gaogaen
Evil
Fire
Pikachu!
Is it just me,
or are they only targeting Pikachu?
So this is a Battle Royal...
A cutthroat battle
where anyone can attack anyone.
That’s what a Battle Royal is!
Lilie! Meteor Beam!
Garagara, use Flare Drive!
Gaogaen! DD Lariat!
Pikachu!
Dodge them with Lightning Speed!
He’s fast!
Shadow Bone!
Psycho Shock!
Build Up!
Gaogaen, stop Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
Gaogaen lost its balance!
Pikachu, you’re amazing!
You’ve gotten even stronger,
haven’t you, Satoshi?!
I’ve been training every day
so I can beat Mr. Dande!
You’re...
...not the only one...
...who’s been training!
Garagara! Shadow Bone!
Lilie! Venom Shock!
Gaogaen! Blast Burn!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Now! Electroweb!
Dodge it!
One more 100,000 Volts!
Gaogaen, use Hell Thrust!
Iron Head!
Pummel him with Hell Thrusts!
Counter with Iron Tail!
Meteor Beam!
Good work, Lilie!
Shadow Bone!
I’ll be the one to take down Satoshi!
No, I’m gonna defeat Satoshi!
Lilie, use Venom Shock
on Garagara!
Dodge it, Garagara!
Iron Head!
Utsuroid is unable to battle!
Competitor Gladio
is out of the running!
You did well, Lilie.
Let’s train together some more.
Gladio’s really become
a lot tougher.
Yes.
He’s just like you
when you were young.
Satoshi!
I’ll use my full power!
Face me with your full power!
Of course!
Let’s do this!
Garagara!
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Use 100,000 Volts to dodge it!
Now!
He dodged the Z-Move!
That was great, Pikachu!
And that’s what makes you my rival,
Satoshi!
You don’t have time
to stand around!
Gaogaen, use DD Lariat!
Lightning Speed!
Shadow Bone!
Garagara is unable to battle!
Competitor Kaki is out of the running!
Thanks.
That was a good battle.
Don’t let your guard down, Pikachu!
Doesn’t this take you back,
Satoshi?
Yeah!
Champion! Champion! Champion!
Champion! Champion!
Everyone’s cheering for
Satoshi and Pikachu...
He’s a celebrity!
Go for it, first-ever
Champion of the Alola League!
Our Champion!
You’ve gotta win this!
Champion! Champion!
Go for it!
Never forget
you’re representing Alola!
Everyone’s cheering for you!
Everyone...
Bring home the win, Satoshi!
In the Masters Tournament!
Kaki... Gladio...
Use your full power!
Pikachu.
All right!
Here we go, Pikachu!
Is this it?
Gaogaen!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the ring ablaze
with the flames of victory!
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Hyper Dark Crusher!
Pikachu!
10,000,000 Volts!
Thought I’d find you here.
Professor! Alola!
Alola.
What’s on your mind?
Just...
I’m glad I came.
To Alola.
I see.
Kapu-Kokeko?!
Kapu-Kokeko is praying
for your victory.
I’ll do my best
in the Masters Tournament!
His family in Alola...
Alola’s people and Pokémon...
Its scenery...
Its battles...
And Kapu-Kokeko,
the guardian deity...
...are all pushing Satoshi forward
as he heads toward the Masters Tournament.
Super Effective Type
Water is super effective on Ground!
Soak them and watch them dissolve!
Ground is super effective on Electric!
They don’t even feel a shock!
Electric is super effective on Flying!
Hear the thunder rumble through the sky!
Flying is super effective on Bug!
They’re easy marks when flying high above!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Swiftly swimming: the Water type!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Pulsing with electricity: the Electric type!
Which type is super effective?!
Pikachu
Electric!
Milokaross
Pikachu
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Ice
Evil
They’re all unique and all intriguing
Ghost
Dragon
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon
What type is this Pokémon?
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Fighting
Otosupus
What type is this Pokémon?
Dustdas
Learn how they’re unique and you’ll like them even more
Poi
Pois
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Poison
Dustdas
What type is this Pokémon?
Sonansu
Psy
Psych
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Psychic
Sonansu
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
B
Bu
Bug
What type is this Pokémon?
Agilder
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Finally, the Last Mission!
Let’s hurry there, Go!
No.
I’m going alone this time.
Wha—?! How come?!
Shigeru?!
I never imagined we’d someday
end up walking together.
Layla and Shun'ya...!
Shigeru, let’s work together!
I’ve been waiting for you
to say that!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Last Mission!
Catch Regieleki/Regidrago!!
Catch Regieleki and Regidrago!!