Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
What could it mean?
Good morning!
Oh, it’s you guys.
Good timing.
Satoshi and Go,
have you heard?
There’s something strange
going on in the Johto Region.
Huh? What is it?
The sky in one town suddenly went pitch-black,
and they haven’t seen the sun rise since.
The sky went pitch-black?
When do they eat breakfast
if it’s always night?!
That’s your question?
Satoshi has a point, though.
This has to mess with
their daily rhythms.
It must be hard
for the people there.
We don’t know what caused it,
but Pokémon may be suffering, too.
We’ll check it out!
I wanna know what
a never-ending night is like!
Of course. Would you go
and investigate, then?
All right! Off to Johto!
Let’s go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
The Py That Became A Star
Johto Region
A small town in the Johto Region.
It’s currently morning, and yet
the dark of night covers the town.
It really is pitch-black...
But it’s not night right now...
It’s morning, right?
Good morning!
Looks like another
dark day today.
The laundry never dries.
It’s such a pain...
It’s kinda weird.
Yeah...
Easy does it...
Good morning!
Oh, morning...
Not even exercising can cheer me up
when it’s this dark...
Is it always night here?
Yeah.
Been about a week by now.
That long?
Without knowing the time,
I can never tell when to eat...
Look. Do you see that?
With the sun gone,
even the flowers are wilting...
The Yamikarasu are sulking.
Everyone thinks they’re bad luck.
Bad luck?
Yamikarasu! Darkness Pokémon!
Evil/Flying type!
It is believed to bring misfortune
to all those who see it at night,
so it is feared and
loathed by many!
You don’t look too happy.
Wanna come with me?
Monster Ball, go!
Yamikarasu’s data will be
added to the Index!
I’m feeling sleepy...
Let’s go home, Usokki.
Bye, mister.
Be careful in the dark.
Right. Good night...
Looks like everyone’s
having trouble...
Yeah.
Ooh!
Good job, Sarunori!
So it really is night
all the time here...
Oh! A shooting star!
Huh?
Oh, it vanished.
Yeah...
Still, the sky’s really pretty.
There’s so many stars!
Good evening!
Oh, good evening!
It’s actually morning though,
so shouldn’t you say “Good morning”?
What a headache...
Were you watching the stars, too?
Yeah, we were.
I was, too!
My name’s Kirara.
I’m Satoshi.
He’s my partner, Pikachu.
I’m Go.
This is my partner, Sarunori.
Hey...
Py!
Kirara, do you like the stars?
Yeah!
I was looking at them to find Py.
Py turned into a star.
Py...?
Py! Star Shape Pokémon!
Fairy type!
Because of its starlike silhouette,
it’s believed to be a star reborn!
Kirara!
We should be heading home.
Good evening!
Good morning.
I was watching the stars
with those boys.
Oh, thank you.
Mom, can I stay out a little longer?
Just a little bit longer.
She always watches the stars
just like that.
She says
she wants to find Py’s star.
Py’s star?
Py and Kirara were good friends,
and they were always together.
but a couple of days ago,
we finally had to say farewell,
and Py went back to heaven.
Kirara was really upset,
so I told her that Py became a star.
And then...
She’s been stargazing ever since.
I get it.
She must be thinking
about her dear Py.
Oh, there was one strange thing...
It’s something Kirara said.
She said she saw a strange Pokémon last week,
and that’s when the endless night started.
Is that true?!
But could a Pokémon really
cause night to last forever?
It has to be
some sort of coincidence.
Mom! Here I am!
All right. Then let’s go.
Oh, hold on!
The strange Pokémon you saw,
what did it look like?
Umm...
It was small,
but it had a big eyeball.
It was black,
and shaped like a stick.
Now then,
we should get going.
Thank you, you two!
Yeah! Bye bye!
See you!
What meal is this?
Lunch.
Feels weird eating lunch at night.
What do you think
about that, from before?
The strange Pokémon?
Yeah.
The timing fits far too well
to be a coincidence...
Black, and shaped
like a stick, right?
I wonder if it’s in the Index...
You found it?
Of course,
right near this town...
I knew it!
Huh?
We don’t have time to eat.
Thanks for the food!
Let’s go, Satoshi, Pikachu!
Where’re you going, Go?!
An archaeology museum?
I have to look into something.
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
Pikachu!
Ms. Shirona?
Satoshi!
It’s been such a long time.
I never expected
to run into you here.
Have you been well,
too, Pikachu?
Satoshi, I hear you’ve entered
the Pokémon World Championships.
Yeah!
You’re in the Masters Eight,
right, Ms. Shirona?
I’m gonna make it there
someday, too!
Yes, I’ll eagerly await that.
You’re the Champion of Sinnoh,
Ms. Shirona, yeah?!
I’m Go!
Satoshi and I are
research fellows at Sakuragi Institute!
So, what business
brings you here today?
Actually, despite my title,
my forte is archaeology.
I study the history
and myths of Pokémon,
and even investigate
rare Pokémon.
Really? That’s incredible!
I’m always traveling
around the world to study ruins.
Conducting a study
is what brought me here, too...
We heard it was always night in this town
and came to check it out!
Someone in the town told us a certain Pokémon
might be involved, so we came here to investigate.
A certain Pokémon?
You figured it out, Go?
A Pokémon that’s small,
with a big eyeball,
black, and shaped like a stick!
It’s Unknown!
Unknown! Symbol Pokémon!
Psychic type!
When alone, nothing happens!
However, if there are two or more,
an odd power emerges!
Unknown are Pokémon
shaped like ancient letters.
28 shapes have been found so far,
and they’re a subject of my research, too.
But all we know is that they’re often found near ruins,
and they’re largely a mystery.
Unknown, huh...?
Satoshi. Go.
Could you tell me the story in full?
Sure!
I see.
What’s your opinion?
It’s very possible that
a number of Unknown gathered together,
and made that girl’s wish come true
using some unknown power.
So it really was her...!
The Unknown might’ve responded
to her strong emotions.
I’d like to meet and talk to her myself.
Let’s go see her together.
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Unknown
Psychic
Kirara!
Oh, it’s those boys!
Good afternoon!
We meet again,
Pikachu, Sarunori!
Here to watch the stars?
Yeah!
May I watch them with you?
You too, miss?
Yeah! I even brought
some doughnuts as a snack.
Ta-daah!
They look great!
Have whatever you want.
Let’s eat!
Want half, Pikachu?
I’ll share half with you,
too, Sarunori.
Finished already?
That was fast!
Wow...
Py...
Kirara, do you mind
if I ask you something?
What is it?
The strange Pokémon
you talked about yesterday... Was this it?
Yeah, that’s it! Li’l Eyeball!
How did you meet?
Well...
Py...
If only I could
watch the stars forever...
Who are you?
Is that so...?
So the Unknown
really were involved...
Kirara, do you know
where the Unknown went after that?
Li’l Eyeball?
Yeah.
Why?
It’s never gonna be day again
if things stay like this.
Everyone’s having trouble, right?
Trouble?
Yeah. So we’re looking for
a way to fix it.
No!
I wanna keep watching the stars!
Kirara?
I don’t want it to be dawn!
Unknown!
I want it to stay night!
Kirara!
Leave this to us.
Kirara...
Pikachu?!
Watch out.
That’s an illusion
created by the Unknown.
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Follow up with Iron Tail!
You okay, Pikachu?
All right! I’ll help, too!
Aceburn, go!
An illusion of Aceburn, huh?
Aceburn, Pyro Ball!
Follow it up with
Blaze Kick!
No good...
It’s blocking with the same move!
The same moves and equal power.
This could go on forever...
Leave it to me.
Gaburias!
Gaburias versus Gaburias?!
Yeah!
Gaburias! Scale Shot!
Gaburias! Sandstorm!
Now!
Take to the skies, Gaburias!
She jumped!
She used the sandstorm to hide!
Knowing the enemy
would use Sandstorm...
Scale Shot!
That was awesome,
Ms. Shirona!
Thank you, Gaburias.
Good work, Aceburn.
Kirara!
Py...
I’m glad you’re all right.
I was selfish for thinking
night should last forever. I’m sorry.
It’s all good.
The stars really are great.
I used to climb up here
and play with Py all the time.
This was Py’s favorite place.
Ms. Shirona...
Why didn’t the Unknown
make an illusion of Py?
Kirara’s greatest wish
must’ve been to see Py again.
Right...
Kirara probably just needed a little more time
to accept parting with Py, I suppose.
Py... You became
a shining star.
You’ve got lots of friends...
I’m sure you’re really popular up there.
So...
I wanted to tell you...
...that I’ll be fine by myself now,
so don’t worry about me.
But...
But I’m so lonely...
I wanna see you...
The Unknown!
Hold on.
Here we go!
Py...
I’ll be fine, so don’t worry.
Thank you, Py.
Kirara?
Yeah!
Kirara!
No matter how far apart you are,
you and Py are always gonna be friends!
That’s right!
Yeah!
You can’t see them in the daylight,
but the stars are always shining.
Py’s up there,
even at this very moment.
Really?
Yeah! I get it!
Huh? Where’s the Unknown?
They’re gone!
They disappeared, huh?
There’s still much
we don’t know about them.
Li’l Eyeball,
I’ll see you around!
A mysterious experience
in a little town.
There’s many more Pokémon shrouded in mystery
all over the world, just waiting to be found.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Lucario, time to Mega Evolve!
Hold it!
What about the tools
you need to Mega Evolve?
That’s what we’re gonna look for!
Corni’s gonna help out, too!
Let’s try our best, Satoshi!
Satoshi!
Go! Lucario!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Lucarionite!
A Great Adventure on Mega Island!!
A Great Adventure
on Mega Island!!