Satoshi and Go headed to Galar...
...to investigate the mysteries of Daimax.
In the forest,
they encountered mysterious Pokémon.
As more and more secrets of the legend
were coming to light,
Rose revived the ancient calamity Black Night,
under the name Mugendaina.
Can Satoshi, Go and Dande
stop Mugendaina?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need to hesitate! Try!
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Sword & Shield IV
"The Ultimate Sword and Shield"
This is horrible!
We’re getting more and more reports of
Daimax Pokémon running rampant!
And look at this!
Knuckle Stadium is under attack by
an unidentified gigantic Pokémon!
Could the legendary calamity
have come back?!
Mugendaina!
He’s catching up!
Stop it, Nyarth!
This is not the time!
Did you forget Sakaki’s orders?!
Sa... ka... ki...?
That’s right! Sakaki!
You can get that monster
now, can’t you?!
All right!
Let’s follow him!
Come back, Lizardon!
We’ll battle with Kyodaimax!
Sakaki...
There! Go get it!
Kyodai... Charm...!
W-What?!
What an awful feeling!
What is this?!
Behold!
Mugendaina is absorbing Galar particles,
in order to assume its final form!
We will soon see the ultimate Pokémon,
bringing us infinite energy.
Mr. Dande will seal it
before that happens!
Riolu! Force Palm!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Nutrey. Iron Defense!
Daioudou,
use Heavy Bomber!
Dodge it!
Riolu! Force Palm!
Heavy Bomber!
One plays offense,
the other defense...
In that case...!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Riolu, use Shadow Clones!
Run around!
Break their formation!
I see...
Now, Rabbifoot! Ember!
Milokaross.
Water Pulse.
Use a flurry of Embers!
Rabbifoot! Are you okay?!
Useless.
I’m amazed that you thought
you could stop Mugendaina, as weak as you are.
Mugendaina...?
You mean Black Night?
Indeed. Mugendaina is
Chairman Rose’s dream itself.
I, too, must
bear witness to his dream.
So kindly stop wasting my time
and fall!
Dragon Claw!
Lizardon!
Nutrey, Daioudou.
Beat them down with Power Whip!
Pikachu, to the right!
Riolu, retreat to dodge!
Pikachu, to the left!
Are you attempting to
stall for time?
Dodge by leaping back!
There is no escape.
Power Whip!
Now! Jump!
Was this your plan?!
Good job, Pikachu, Riolu!
I guess Ember won’t work.
Rabbifoot, change of plans!
Dodge the attacks
with Lightning Sp—
Rabbifoot...
Besides, I really wanted
to settle the match with Ember.
Because that’s the move Rabbifoot
and I made together!
I see... You...
You wanna win with Ember, yeah?
Water Pulse!
Rabbifoot!
It’s over. Milokaross,
finish them with Aqua Tail!
Dodge it, Lizardon!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
What?!
It can’t be...!
W-What?
Mugendaina?!
We have to stop it!
Can you fight, Pikachu?
I will not let you go.
Power Whip!
Riolu!
Crush it.
Don’t push yourself
too hard, Riolu!
You...
Think! Think!
How can we win with Ember?
I know!
Rabbifoot, attack from an angle!
Use the walls and ceiling!
It’ll be fine! Let’s win together!
Fire a flurry of Embers!
Now!
Aqua Tail!
Knock them all down!
Good! Keep pushing them back
with Ember!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Riolu evolved into Lucario!
Lucario. Guiding Wave Pokémon.
Fighting/Steel type.
It controls waves known as auras,
and it can sense what is in people’s hearts.
All right! Use Vacuum Wave!
Ah, I gotcha.
Lucario! Guiding Wave Sphere!
Another Guiding Wave Sphere!
You did it, Lucario!
Let’s go meet up with Mr. Dande!
Are you all right,
Daioudou, Nutrey?!
Rabbifoot... evolved!
Awesome!
Aceburn! Striker Pokémon!
Fire type!
Its Pyro Ball attack strikes its opponents hard
with a burning soccer ball, leaving them scorched!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
O-Oh, no...
You did it, Aceburn!
Satoshi, we’ll be right there!
Duraludon! Wide Breaker!
Y-You’ll regret this!
Um... Thank you.
Don’t sweat it.
Now, then...
I would like to invite you
on a date or something,
But it looks like those unruly, rampaging Pokémon
just won’t leave me alone.
See ya later, babe.
Let’s go, Duraludon!
What about Black Night?
Lizardon! Air Slash!
That’s it!
Focus the attacks on its mouth!
All right!
Lizardon’s pushing it back!
Satoshi!
Lucario?
I see! So you beat Chairman Rose?
Yeah!
Hey, Satoshi!
Go! And...
This is Aceburn!
Rabbifoot evolved!
Whoa! Awesome!
Wait... Is that Riolu?!
Riolu evolved, too!
Into Lucario!
For real?!
Way to go!
So that’s Mugendaina?
Yeah.
It really is a legendary calamity!
It’s given us some trouble,
but we finally cornered it!
It’s Champion time!
Now, Lizardon! Air Slash!
Now I’ll catch it!
You did it!
Wait!
Watch out!
Come back, Lizardon!
The sky!
Is this Mugendaina?!
Mugendaina’s gotten
way bigger than it was!
Is that its final form?
You two... Run...!
Mr. Dande!
Oh, how magnificent! Yes!
What is that form?
Show them your power,
Mugendaina!
We’ll stop it!
Yeah!
Let’s go at full power!
Lucario, use Guiding Wave Sphere!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
It didn’t work?!
Again!
Pikachu! Lucario!
Aceburn!
Gah... It’s too powerful...
Did these...
...just glow?
What are these?
I found them in
the Slumbering Weald.
Could they be...
...the legendary sword and shield?
Dande!
Sonia?
Here it comes!
Go! Satoshi!
They glowed again?
Well, then... I guess we just gotta
become the legend, yeah?!
You got that right!
Come on, Mugendaina!
I will... battle it...!
No! Don’t push yourself!
We will protect...
...Galar’s people and Pokémon!
Is that...?
Zamazenta!
Zacian!
They transformed!
You’ll fight with us?
The sword and shield
the legendary heroes wielded...
They were actually
Pokémon themselves?!
You guys... Let’s do this!
We will defeat Mugendaina!
Yes! It’s working!
Hang in there, Mugendaina!
You are Galar’s future!
Aceburn! Pyro Ball!
Lucario, use Guiding Wave Sphere!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
We did it!
Maybe...
...we can catch it now?
Whoa!
Go!
Let’s do it!
Ready, and...
Monster Ball, go!
Mugendaina’s data will be
added to the Index!
All right!
Zacian! Zamazenta!
The black clouds are gone.
Yeah. Just like in the legend.
Thank you, everyone.
Mr. Dande.
You have saved Galar.
You two really were incredible!
You are the legendary heroes!
No, it wasn’t us.
It was Zacian and Zamazenta!
That must have been quite tough.
And Chairman Rose’s whereabouts
are still unknown?
Yes. Though Dande is
helping search for him.
Although Mugendaina remains asleep,
contained deep beneath the earth,
the possibility remains
that it may reawaken.
We need to look into countermeasures,
should that ever happen.
I will be counting on you for that...
Professor Sonia.
Of course!
I’ll do my best to live up
to this professor’s coat you gave me!
Thank you, Zacian.
Let’s battle someday!
Zamazenta,
I’ll catch you someday!
With this grand case revolving around
Galar’s legends behind them,
Satoshi and Go
have both grown once more.
The door to another adventure
surely awaits them!
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Mew!
MIYU
U
OOGU
RU
Warrgle!
NPAP
PA
Runpappa!
UWA
U
Pawou!
RUGAMO
SU
Ulgamoth!
TORAI
KU
Strike!
RESERI
A
Cresselia!
MAKA
JI
Amakaji!
RAA
CHI
Jirachi!
YOBOMA
KI
Chobomaki!
BA
GO
Kibago!
N
BE
Gonbe!
IRII
FU
Bayleaf!
RII
ZA
A
Freezer!
ZA
SHIA
N
Zacian!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
Even if it ends in an “N”, I still love it
Okay, let’s go one more time!
Mew!
MIYU
U
Wooper!
​
PA
A
Pachirisu!
PA
CHIRI
SU
Sunaba!
NABA
A
Absol!
BUSO
RU
Lunala!
NAAA
RA
Rabbifoot!
BIFUT
TO
Tropius!
ROPIU
SU
Sunahebi!
NAHE
BI
Vibrava!
BURAA
BA
SHAA
MO
Burshamo!
Mokuroh!
MO
KU
RO
O
Rotom!
RO
TO
MU
URAN
DO
Mooland!
Dodorio!
DO
ODORI
O
Otosupus!
TOSUPA
SU
Swanna!
WAN
NA
Nazonokusa!
ZONOKU
SA
Samehada!
MEHA
DA
A
AKURA
I
Darkrai!
WAN
KO
Iwanko!
Cortoise!
KO
OTA
SU
Scorupi!
KORU
PI
P
Pippi!
PI
NPU
KU
Pinpuku!
NUGIDA
MA
Kunugidama!
N
KI
I
Mankey!
Kimori!
Ligray!
RE
KKUU
ZA
Rekkuuza!
MAZEN
TA
Zamazenta!
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you’re set for success!
(Mew → Zamazenta Ver.)
Let’s play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
You see, we’ve detected psychic energy
believed to belong to Mew.
What?!
The isolated island of Cello, huh?
Why have you come here?
A talking Pokémon?!
Mewtwo...
Show me what you can do.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Battling & Catching!
Mewtwo Rises Again
Battling and Catching!