Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of
their lives and adventures.
This is Sakuragi Park’s flower field.
A place where everyone can relax,
full of flowers of many colors.
Does that feel good?
Taking a shower is the best, right?
Ooh, are the Flabébé racing?!
Looking good! Go for it!
They evolved!
Floette’s data will be
added to the Index!
Floette! Single Bloom Pokémon!
Fairy type!
It flutters around fields of flowers
and cares for flowers that are starting to wilt!
It draws out the power of flowers to battle!
All right, now I’ve got
all five colors of Floette as... well... Huh?
The white Flabébé is missing?
Hey! Where are you?
One of the petals is missing!
So that’s why she
couldn’t fly right...
What do we do, Go?
We don’t have a choice.
We have to find her a new flower!
You’re right. But where?
I don’t think there’s any here...
I caught them in Kalos,
so there must be flowers there!
It’ll be okay, Flabébé.
I’ll find you a new flower.
So, to find Flabébé a new flower...
Let’s go to Kalos!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Flabébé's White Flower
Shala City, Kalos Region
I think the spot I caught them
was around here...
Flabébé,
where do your white flowers grow?
Oh, hold on!
That one isn’t safe to fly with.
Riding on a flower must
really make her wanna fly...
Yeah.
So I’ll look after your flower.
Huh?
What’s going on?
Maybe she feels at home up there?
She even has something to hold onto.
Huh? Do you?
Hey... What are you...?
It’s like she’s telling you to “Go!”
I get it!
So you’re controlling me
like you would a flower...
Okay...
Whoa!
My body is moving on its own!
Looking good, Flabébé.
Keep going!
Wah!
Where could I be going?!
Ow!
Sarunori,
you’re pulling too hard!
Stop!
Oh, is this it?
Don’t tell me...
The spot where your flower grew
is under this rock?!
Never would’ve expected that
they’d be flattened under a rock...
There weren’t any white flowers
nearby either...
Guess we gotta try somewhere else.
We’ve only just started looking.
Cheer up, yeah?
Hey, Flabébé.
Would you like to have
some honey?
It tastes good!
She’s laughing!
I see... That must’ve been
a disappointment.
Director Sakuragi,
do you know any other place they grow?
The thing is, white Flabébé are rare,
so unfortunately, their flowers are hard to find.
I see...
Either way, I’ll try looking into it.
I’ll call you if I discover anything.
That would be great.
This might be harder than I thought...
But we’ve gotta do it!
Yeah.
We should try and find some on our own.
Yeah!
Flabébé?
Where are you going?
Figures you’d have trouble sleeping...
There’s something nice about
the air at night, isn’t there?
It’s not like during the day.
Like... It feels special.
You want to go for
a little walk?
Today, we’re gonna look everywhere
for Flabébé’s white flowers!
Yeah! We’ll find them for sure!
Hey, Go!
How about this one?
No luck,
even with all our searching...
There were plenty that
looked right...
But Flabébé must be able
to tell the difference.
Maybe we should go back to the Institute,
and try and come up with ideas...
Here.
She’s getting used to your head.
Guess so.
Flabébé looks quite comfortable
up there, too...
So don’t worry, Flabébé.
Until we find you a flower—no, even if we never find one,
you’ll always have a home on my head!
Then maybe someday
you’ll start flying like a flower!
That’d be awesome!
Oww...
That’s right.
Even if it’s no problem for me,
you’ve been suffering...
Tomorrow,
we’ll find you a new flower for sure!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Flabébé
Fairy
All that happened...?
Sorry, I had no idea.
It was late at night.
That reminds me, I went for a walk with Flabébé
the previous night, too.
Do you like nighttime
or something?
Director Sakuragi!
Did you discover anything?
Yes. I managed to contact someone
who knows about Flabébé’s white flowers.
All right!
So?
She researches plants.
I’ll send you her location.
Hello!
Welcome!
You must’ve had quite the long trip
to get here.
Professor Sakuragi
told me everything.
Florges!
That’s Flabébé’s final evolution.
Florges! Garden Pokémon!
Fairy type!
In times long past, governors of castles would invite Florges
to create flower gardens to embellish the castle domains!
Don’t worry. Just watch.
That was... Grass Field?
Yes. She can give energy to the plants
by doing that.
Flabébé looks really happy.
They are both species that love flowers,
and live alongside them.
It’s said that Flabébé are drawn to flowers,
Floette tend to flowers,
and Florges devote their lives to
protecting flower gardens.
Actually, that Florges once lost
her orange flower, too.
They’re about as rare as the white flowers are,
so finding one was quite the task.
She must have taken interest in your Flabébé,
seeing her facing a similar plight.
These are Florges’ flowers.
It seems these plants
are prone to stunted growth,
and they don’t propagate much,
even with Florges’ help.
I... I want to find Flabébé
a white flower too!
About that, a researcher friend of mine reported
seeing a cluster of white flowers...
...deep in the mountains
northwest of here.
A cluster of them?!
Best of luck finding them.
Right! Thank you!
Good news, huh, Flabébé?
I’m sure we’ll find them this time.
Oh, is that Grass Field?
I see you’re copying Florges.
She must’ve really liked it!
You’ll just have to make your own
flower garden someday, then!
They should be somewhere around here...
But I don’t see anywhere they could be.
Pikachu, they’re white flowers, you hear?
Lemme know if you see any.
Did you find them?!
Those are pink...
Yeah...
Let’s look over there.
Yeah.
We didn’t see a single flower,
let alone a cluster...
She did say they have
a tough time growing...
Maybe something happened to
the flowers here, too...
What?
She says she wants to
go that way.
But that’ll just be
going backwards...
Owww!
Okay, okay!
The flowers we saw earlier...
But they’re pink, not white.
The pink buds bloom
into white flowers at night...
So that’s it!
Go on, get on.
You did it, Flabébé!
You got a white flower!
Huh?
There’s another one...
She’s not riding a flower.
Is she choosing a flower
for the first time?
Take care!
Right.
But now,
there’s just one flower left.
Yeah. I hope there’s
more of them somewhere...
But what if they all get wiped out?
That’s...
Grass Field?!
She evolved into Floette!
Floette...
You did it! That’s Grass Field!
That was amazing, Floette!
It’s said that Flabébé are drawn to flowers,
Floette tend to flowers,
and Florges devote their lives to
protecting flower gardens.
You’ll just have to make your own
flower garden someday, then!
I get it. You want to stay here
and protect the white flowers, don’t you?
Go...
If that’s your choice,
I’ll support you.
I can’t let the flowers you treasure
be wiped out, can I?
That’s far enough, Floette.
Thanks for the send-off.
Do a good job out there!
Take care, then...
Sarunori really likes Floette...
So do I, Sarunori...
That’s why we have to
say goodbye for now.
So Floette can do her best!
Then someday,
we’ll come and visit.
And see your beautiful garden
of white flowers.
Okay?
See you, Floette!
Go and Satoshi bore witness
to Flabébé’s growth.
Through meetings and farewells,
their adventure still continues.
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Pokémon Shiritori
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Utsubot!
TSUBOT
TO
Trancell!
RANSE
RU
Lugia!
GI
A
Achamo!
CHA
MO
Morpeko!
RUPE
KO
Koduck!
DAK
KU
Cleffy!
REFFU
I
Eevee!
IBU
I
Ishitsubute!
SHITSUBU
TE
Teppouo!
PPOU
O
Onisuzume!
NISUZU
ME
Metagross!
TAGURO
SU
Subame!
BA
ME
Me...
TAMO
N
Metamon!
Shiritori set to Pokémon Techno
Chain the names of Pokémon
If it ends in an “N”, you lose
Okay, let's go one more time!
Pikachu!
PIKACHU
U
Usohachi!
SOHA
CHI
Chicorita!
KORII
TA
Tamatama!
MATA
MA
Mamepato!
MEPA
TO
Togedemaru!
GEDEMA
RU
Lucario!
KARI
O
Odoshishi!
DOSHI
SHI
Seadra!
IDO
RA
Laplace!
PURA
SU
Starmie!
TAA
MI
I
Miniryu!
MI
NIRYU
U
Windie!
IND
I
Iwark!
WAA
KU
Kucheat!
CHII
TO
Togekiss!
GEKIS
SU
Sleep!
RII
PU
Ptera!
TE
RA
Raikou!
IKO
U
U'u!
`
U
Wooloo!
RU
U
Ruriri!
RU
RI
Leafia!
IFI
A
Armorgaw!
AMAAGA
A
Abagoura!
BAGOU
RA
TIA
SU
Latias!
PI
A
Spear!
GUNO
MU
Agnome!
Muma!
MU
U
MA
Madatsubomi!
DATSUBO
MI
Mew!
YUU
Shiritori with the Music Club
Chain the names of Pokémon
Learn lots of Pokémon names
All right! Now you're set for success!
(Pikachu → Mew Ver.)
Let's play Pokémon Shiritori
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Whaaaaat?!
Pikachu got arrested?!
Electricity was stolen?!
If it wasn’t Pikachu, then there must be
someone else behind it!
You two...
Will you help me investigate?
Sure!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Pikachu the Suspect?!