Pokémon World Championships News!
A special for the impending exhilarating finals!!
A special for the impending exhilarating finals!
The Masters Tournament
finally reaches its climax!
Great Blaze-style battle commentary!
Today, we present the most in-depth special...
Exclusive finals ■■■■■■ reveal!
Satoshi and Dande's secret promise!
Great Blaze-style battle commentary!
...you could hope to see about the impending finals!
Exclusive finals ■■■■■■ reveal!
Well then, let’s get right to it!
Satoshi and Dande's secret promise!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
Climax!
Eve of the Finals, Satoshi VS Dande!!
Today, we’re bringing you a special
on the impending finals.
And let us welcome our guest commentator...
Battle Reviewer
Mr. Great Blaze
A Battle Watcher who spectates 1000+ matches a year
Favorite moves: Explosive Punch, EM Cannon, Purgatory
Mr. Great Blaze, the Battle Reviewer.
Thank you for being here today.
I’m gonna Super light this show on fire!
Take it away!
This tournament
has been called “a festival of dreams.”
Champions compete to be the world's strongest
Let’s recap the all-star cast of competitors
who have thrilled all of us Pokémon fans!
All-stars!
The tournament competitors
Ranked 8th
Satoshi
Ranked 8th, Competitor Satoshi!
100,000 Volts!
Ranked 7th
Iris
Ranked 7th, Competitor Iris!
Ononox!
Use Dragon Pulse!
Ranked 6th
Alain
Ranked 6th, Competitor Alain!
Dragon Claw!
Ranked 5th
Carne
Ranked 5th, Competitor Carne!
Checkmate!
Moonforce!
Ranked 4th
Wataru
Ranked 4th, Competitor Wataru!
Destroyer Beam!
Ranked 3rd
Daigo
Ranked 3rd, Competitor Daigo!
Sparkle of stone...
Become our bond!
Ranked 2nd
Shirona
Ranked 2nd, Competitor Shirona!
Mega Evolve!
Ranked 1st
Dande
Ranked 1st, Competitor Dande!
Me and my Pokémon
will take down all comers!
They are the members of the Masters Eight,
The top eight, who reign over 10,000+ trainers
The Masters Eight
who reign over more than 10,000 trainers.
Don’t they make an amazing group, Mr. Great Blaze?
1st Round, 1st Match
Dande vs Alain
Oh... It’s a miracle! A miracle!
Getting to watch
a tournament like this is just...!
1st Round, 2nd Match
Wataru vs Carne
With all the hot battles,
ever since the first round,
1st Round, 3rd Match
Iris vs Shirona
everyone’s probably
singed by now, hmm?
1st Round, 4th Match
Daigo vs Satoshi
Because of the hot battles!
Mm-hmm, you’re on fire today.
Now then, next up...
An in-depth look at the key moments from
the fiercely fought semifinals, with Mr. Great Blaze!
Called...
“Great Blaze’s
Now That’s SUPER!”
Great Blaze's Now That's SUPER!
Well then, over to you.
Explained!
The fiercely fought semifinals
All right!
First, let’s take a look at the battle between li’l Dande and li’l Carne!
Dande
Champion of Galar
Carne
Champion of Kalos
Competitor Dande's
Pokémon
Competitor Carne's
Until the endgame, Competitor Dande
set the pace of the match.
Competitor Carne struggled
to find a way out.
Mmm... Her strategies
ended up backfiring.
When Competitor Carne
was down to her last Pokémon,
she sent in her ace, Sirknight!
Competitor Dande also sent out Lizardon,
making for a showdown between aces!
100,000 Volts!
Now that’s powerful!
Whoa! Kyodaimax Lizardon
was greatly shaken!
Kyodai Hellfire!
Competitor Dande picks Kyodai Hellfire
to bring the match to a quick end.
Competitor Carne was trapped!
But then...
Super!
Make sure you don’t miss
what happened next!
Psychokinesis!
What?!
Snatching control of the opponent's move
with Super strong psycho power!!
It stole that Kyodai Hellfire with Psychokinesis!
That’d usually be impossible.
That’s the Super psycho power
of a Champion’s Sirknight!
Mr. Great Blaze,
that was the first time someone had ever blocked
Kyodai Hellfire in an official match.
You may be right there...
Even I hadn’t seen that before.
Li’l Dande must’ve been panicking back then!
But it was stopped at the last moment!
Semifinals, 1st Match
Dande vs Carne
Competitor Dande ended up taking the match.
Next, if you would go over the battle between
Competitor Shirona and Competitor Satoshi.
Shirona
Champion of Sinnoh
Satoshi
Champion of Alola
Competitor Shirona's
Pokémon
Competitor Satoshi's
Oh, there were so many highlights,
I could go on for hours!
It was a battle where they both
fully played to their strengths, wasn’t it?
You know it was.
Li’l Shirona picked Mikaruge for her first move.
Her strategy was really sharp!
Mikaruge
Sealed Pokémon
Yes.
That combo of Hypnosis and Dream Eater...
Plus, striking first with Surprise Attack...
Competitor Satoshi looked like
he was having a real tough time.
Mikaruge is a Pokémon
of few weaknesses.
She must’ve planned to use Mikaruge
as a starting point...
...to build upon, no matter
what Pokémon li’l Satoshi picked.
So that explains it...
Indeed, she went on to swap Pokémon
again and again, sending Mikaruge in at vital points.
And then...
Super!
What happened next left me
shaking and shivering— shakevering!
Don’t worry, Pikachu.
I have a plan.
Spin around using 100,000 Volts!
It’s too early for a victory dance.
Hypnosis!
Wow! Blocked by Pikachu’s 100,000 Volts,
Mikaruge’s Hypnosis can’t reach him!
That can’t...
Finish it!
Pikachu conquers the Hypnosis!
I hear that offensive-yet-defensive
100,000 Volts even astonished Competitor Dande.
I’d never seen anything like it!
So you’re rating his incredible tactic as “Super!”, then?
Oh, no, no.
That wasn’t it.
The shakevering was from this part!
Now! Iron Tail!
Mikaruge, go ahead!
All right!
Wh-What is this?
What?!
Pikachu!
It’s Drag Along!
Mikaruge and Pikachu are both
unable to battle!
Li’l Shirona really showed her scary side.
I wanna watch that again to be sure,
but li’l Shirona
didn’t even command that move!
Now! Iron Tail!
Mikaruge, go ahead!
Oh! You’re right!
Her elaborate strategies and meticulous planning to guarantee her victory were Super!!
Does that mean she commanded the move
just with that “Go ahead”?
I think she must’ve predicted something like this
and trained for it with Mikaruge.
Her desire to win was truly Super!
A Champion through and through!
There were more Super moments
in their battle, weren’t there?
I’ve still got plenty of highlights left!
Competitor Satoshi lost his ace, Pikachu,
and had his rhythm completely thrown off,
but he followed it up with Uonoragon
and Negigaknight, who played their parts well,
allowing him to hang on somehow.
Negigaknight’s chivalrous mind...
Uonoragon’s guts...
Their inner strength
helped him escape his dilemma.
Competitor Satoshi builds up
to his final Pokémon, Lucario.
Competitor Shirona sends Togekiss
onto the battlefield.
And then...
Super!
Li’l Shirona’s usually such an angel,
but she looked downright demonic...
Return, Togekiss!
Huh?!
What? Yet another recall?
A Daimax band!
Tower over all, white wings!
Daimax Togekiss!
Togekiss
Jubilee Pokémon
If I got started on how amazing that was,
I could talk the rest of the show away.
But you have to admire the keen judgment
she showed in picking Daimax over Mega Evolution.
Emotionally, she must’ve wanted to save Mega Evolution for her ace, Gaburias.
I think she wanted to press the win
while she had the advantage.
After all, if li’l Satoshi gets going,
there’s no stopping him.
What do you suppose Competitor Shirona’s aim would have been?
Mmm... Well, pushing through with the power of Daimax must’ve been part of it...
But take a close look.
Bullet Punch!
Dai Jet!
Charge up your Guiding Waves!
Simulating every possibility and thinking several moves ahead with Super predictive power!!
She kept commanding Dai Jets.
Yeah! She was raising its speed
with the effect of Dai Jet!
Speed up enough,
and your opponent can’t land their attacks.
Li’l Shirona, always thinking
several moves ahead...
I bet you can see the future, can’t you?!
Her Natio-class predictive powers are Super!
And then,
this next part was just incredible...
We interrupt this program to bring you breaking news.
Announcer Josie, please go ahead.
[Breaking News]
Competitor Shirona to retire as trainer
This is a news flash.
According to an insider, Competitor Shirona had decided to retire as a trainer after this match.
What?!
While the exact reason is unclear,
Hold on a sec!
Li’l Shirona, you’ve got so much potential!
it is thought to have been to focus on research in her other profession of archaeologist.
Mr. Great Blaze?
Please calm down,
I can’t hear the news.
However, after her match with Competitor Satoshi,
she withdrew her intention to retire as a trainer.
[Breaking News]
Competitor Shirona intends to stay trainer
She is not retiring.
Competitor Shirona will not be retiring.
That concludes the news flash.
Oh, what a relief!
She did seem to be having lots of fun
in her battle with li’l Satoshi!
Maybe that battle reminded her
of the joys of childhood!
Thank you, li’l Satoshi!
Indeed.
While it may have interrupted this program,
In-depth look at the highlights of the finals!
that was a news flash reporting that
Competitor Shirona will not be retiring.
After the break,
what you’ve been waiting for!
An in-depth look at the two finalists!
We’ve also obtained
exclusive confidential info to reveal,
so don’t miss it!
First look! The latest poster unveiled!
Now, it’s time for our feature on the impending finals!
Today, through our exclusive sources,
we have obtained the latest poster for the tournament ahead of anyone else.
Unveiled! The latest poster
Let’s take a look at it.
“The Climax Concludes”!
The Climax Concludes
What do you think, Mr. Great Blaze?
H-Hold on a sec. These are the full teams
heading into the finals?!
That’s right!
Let’s take a closer look.
If you would start with
Competitor Satoshi’s Pokémon.
Right!
Look!
The Pokémon in the finals
First...
The Yellow Lightning of Masara
The yellow lightning of Masara, Pikachu!
Exclusive Scoop
The smallest and lightest in the tournament, yet a big eater
Pikachu
Mouse Pokémon
The way it moves is so enchanting.
Does it have wings or something?!
It shows impressive versatility in
pulling off Satoshi’s novel insights, too.
Sometimes seen stuffing its cheeks with local delicacies
Indeed!
That small body has
first class speed and power!
Not to mention its mind.
Its favorite is ketchup-filled Miruhog Buns
It’s like it has “I’m not gonna lose to
those big guys!” written on its face!
It’s definitely well trained.
Next...
The Guiding Waves' New Star
The Guiding Waves’ new star, Lucario!
Exclusive Scoop
Barrierd was often its training partner as a Riolu
Lucario
Guiding Wave Pokémon
When it Mega Evolves,
its concentration goes way up!
It can already read
its opponents’ moves with Guiding Waves,
but add that into the mix,
and it’s marvelous!
It watches over its pupil on the screens of the Sakuragi Institute
Oh!
It did manage to precisely catch
Togekiss, despite its raised speed.
Yeah!
Its final move was timed perfectly, too!
It is said to have a proud expression, and misty eyes
Li’l Satoshi too, giving the command
like, “It’s now or never!”...
Maybe he can control the Guiding Waves, too?
Just kidding!
Next...
The Unyielding Leek Swordsman
The unyielding leek swordsman, Negigaknight!
Exclusive Scoop
An Elite Four member taught Negigaknight its knightly mentality
Negigaknight
Spot-Billed Duck Pokémon
Great Blaze thinks
he’s the semifinals’ MVP!
Lucario only had its chance to shine
because of Negigaknight, after all.
It protects Competitor Satoshi and his friends even outside battle
Destroying the Stealth Rock...
Defeating Milokaross...
And decimating the opposing ace
Gaburias’s stamina with Star Assault!
Seeing it drive away the press has become a post-battle tradition
I bet Negigaknight’s gallant battle
inspired Lucario, too.
Next...
The Ruler of Ancient Galar
The ruler of ancient Galar, Uonoragon!
Exclusive Scoop
Uonoragon can't help but bite onto wiggling things
Uonoragon
Fossil Pokémon
I’m awarding that one
the hard-worker prize!
It worked so hard,
not giving in to the poison!
I get the feeling its power
has been rising rapidly lately...
It seems to be after Competitor Shirona's Milokaross's tail
Mmm... Perhaps its ancient senses
are returning to it.
It’s a species without much data,
so I can’t wait to see it battle in the finals!
But so far Gaburias has kept it from taking even one bite
Oh, it’s a Pokémon even you don’t know
all that much about, Mr. Great Blaze?
I think that’s a mystery
our program should look into!
Next...
The Elusive Black Demon
The elusive black demon, Gänger!
Exclusive Scoop
Gänger loves to scare people and Pokémon
Gänger
Shadow Pokémon
The Will-O-Wisp it learned for the Masters
Tournament has given it a good presence.
Get burned and oh, your stamina
gets sapped, your strength falters...
It even pulls off pranks in the waiting room during the tournament
It’s bad news!
Gänger has Kyodaimax to use
as a trump card, too.
It scared Competitor Shirona's Mikaruge, though it took its revenge
Yeah!
Mega Evolution...
Z-Moves... Daimax...
What’s li’l Satoshi
gonna choose to use in the finals?
Lastly...
Meteor Incarnate
Meteor incarnate, Kairyu!
Exclusive Scoop
It has a kind and gentle personality and loves giving hugs
Kairyu
Dragon Pokémon
Kairyu is sure to be key
in aerial battles in the finals.
Competitor Dande’s Pokémon
are strong at aerial battles, too.
Oh, it looks like
it has so much fun flying...
Apparently, receiving its hugs can comfort you
According to an insider report,
Competitor Satoshi is the one
who taught Kairyu how to fly.
Even Competitor Iris's Kairyu couldn't help but smile when hugged
Huh?! Li’l Satoshi can fly?!
Our program should
look into that mystery, too!
Now then, let’s continue with a look
at Competitor Dande’s Pokémon.
I’ve been wondering about those!
He even has some
he hasn’t shown off in battles before.
That’s right!
Lizardon
Gorillander
Drapult
Lizardon, Gorillander, and Drapult
showed their skills in the semifinals,
but today, his remaining three
have also been revealed.
Aceburn
Barrikohru
Inteleon
Aceburn, Barrikohru, Inteleon...
That’s a real bunch of tricksters!
Could you enlighten us about them, then?
Sure!
Sample Footage
Aceburn
Striker Pokémon
Then, first up is Aceburn!
But wouldn’t you say it’s odd?
Hmm? In what way?
It’s a Fire-type, just like Lizardon.
That’s not exactly balanced.
I can’t tell what li’l Dande’s plotting!
It really is exciting, isn’t it?
Sample Footage
Inteleon
Agent Pokémon
Next is...
...Inteleon, huh?
Now there’s a skillful Pokémon.
It could be anything at all,
depending on its Trainer’s skills.
Which means a Champion’s Inteleon
has no bounds.
Barrikohru
Comedian Pokémon
Last up is Barrikohru!
The one I’m most excited to see!
It doesn’t appear to be
very strong, though...
Ain’t that a good thing?
If it’s li’l Dande’s Pokémon,
it has to be two-faced—
No, belly-faced!
The Climax Concludes
Wow... I really can’t wait!
What kind of battle is it gonna be?
I bet it’s gonna be something I can’t even imagine!
Actually, there’s a special meaning behind these two battling.
Competitor Satoshi and Competitor Dande's unknown promise
This program has obtained rare footage diving into these competitors’ past.
Rare! Competitor Satoshi and
Competitor Dande's First Battle
Let the battle begin!
Unofficial Battle
Competitor Satoshi vs Competitor Dande
This footage is from when Competitor Satoshi
and Competitor Dande had an unofficial battle.
What the—?!
They’ve battled before?!
Pikachu!
All right!
Use 100,000 Volts!
Flamethrower!
Don’t give up!
Lizardon?!
The Kyodaimax was a success!
Li’l Satoshi’s Pikachu
can Kyodaimax?!
That’s right.
Apparently Competitor Satoshi got his
Daimax Band from Competitor Dande that day.
Kyodai Heavy Thunder!
Now, enjoy the climax!
Kyodai Hellfire!
Pikachu!
Pikachu is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Dande!
I like young,
unrefined trainers like you.
But if you want to satisfy me,
you’ll have to pop more!
“Pop”?
Put on more of a show!
Later, then.
Mr. Dande!
Please, battle me again someday!
Our next match will be
an official one, with a crowd!
Yeah!
So the finals will fulfill their promise
from that day at last!
Apparently, the two of them also fought side-by-side
against the Legendary Pokémon Mugendaina.
The two stars that protected Galar’s peace
will finally clash in an official battle!
That’s another reason that the upcoming finals
have a very special battle in store.
It’s sure to be the match of the century!
Yeah! Everyone,
let’s cheer them on together!
This is a nice sense of tension...
I wonder why...
...I’m reminded of
the first day I ever battled.
Everyone!
You ready to go?!
We’re gonna win!
Come on, Satoshi!
THE CLIMAX
CONCLUDES
Pull yourself together!
We’re here watching you!
Big Bro!
Satoshi...
Satoshi.
Satoshi. Go for it!
Now, show me more!
This battle...
Everything since me and Pikachu met...
All our adventures
come together in this battle!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Dredear
Lugarugan
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Grass!
Lugarugan
Dredear
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Steel
Fairy
They're all unique and all intriguing
Evil
Normal
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
St
Ste
Stee
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Steel
Gegegear
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Fi
Fir
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Fire
What type is this Pokémon?
Rokon
Kireihana
G
Gra
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Grass
What type is this Pokémon?
Kireihana
Koorippo
Ic
Ice
What type is this Pokémon?
Koorippo
Pokémon World Championships
Masters Tournament News!
It’s finally here!
The Masters Tournament
Finals Battle!
Competitor Dande’s bound to send out
super strong Pokémon, meow!
Go for broke, brat boy!
No matter what he sends out,
you better not lose to that supreme jerk!
And there you have it! The final showdown
the whole world’s been waiting for is about to begin!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Finals I: “Torrent”
The Finals I - "Torrent"
Let’s all tune in, meow!