Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Wild Area, Galar Region
I’m gonna have an endless
Wild Area Pokémon catching spree!
Well, that was the plan...
You’re too eager to leap in,
Sarunori.
Oh, well.
Let’s have dinner, go to bed early,
and try again tomorr—
Dinner!
Why didn’t I think of that?
We can use tasty-smelling food
to lure Pokémon out!
Ooh! Good idea!
All done!
Let’s dig in!
Curry really is the best!
Oh, no!
We ate it all!
Go!
Shush!
Bachinkey! Beat Pokémon!
Grass type!
The faster a Bachinkey can
beat out a rhythm with its two sticks,
the more respect
it wins from its peers!
I’ve never seen one before!
That’s your evolved form, Sarunori!
Its two sticks...?
It’s getting away!
Monster Ball, go!
What?!
Go!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
I choose you!
The One-Stick
Bachinkey!
Bachinkey really batted
the ball with that baton!
They’re not batons, they’re sticks.
But it only had one stick,
unlike what the Index said...
Did that Bachinkey get you kids?
Huh? Oh. Yes.
Oh, I’m a Wild Area
ingredients vendor.
If you have any concerns
about food, I’m your man!
An ingredients vendor...
Oh, do you have
curry ingredients, then?
Aye! One set of
curry ingredients coming up!
That guy’s been spotted
around here a lot lately.
He steals food from campers
every now and then.
And that’s where I come in.
Well, you kids
better take care too!
We will!
And so...
Operation:
“Catching With Curry: Vengeance!”
Is he really gonna come?
Definitely!
A tasty curry like that
is completely irresistible!
Look, there he is!
You’re right.
Okay, now’s my chance!
Monster Ball—
Go?
Stop, Sarunori!
Gah...
What is it doing?!
What’s that...?
Grooming!
Something that Bachinkey do
to cheer up their friends!
It’s said to be
a mark of friendship and trust!
That does look nice.
Yeah...
Oh, Sarunori!
Go, let’s follow!
R-Right!
Where’d they go?!
Over there!
I wonder what they’re doing.
Kinda looks like a lesson.
I’ve never seen Sarunori
listen so intently before.
They get along so well together!
He might be a good role model
for Sarunori to learn from!
Hey, Bachinkey!
Why don’t you come with us?
Instead of being alone out here,
you can be with Sarunori, me, and all our friends—
What was that?
Loads of Bachinkey?!
They look angry.
Is this their territory?
What’s going on?
Who’s that Pokémon?
Gorillander! Drummer Pokémon!
Grass type!
The one with the best drumming techniques
becomes the boss of the troop!
It has a gentle disposition
and values harmony among its group!
So this is the beat
of wild Bachinkey...
I think I’m starting to like this!
You’re not the only one.
Look at Pikachu and Sarunori!
Huh? What happened?
I get it!
He can’t keep up with everyone else
with only one stick!
The poor guy...
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Pocket Monsters!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Bachinkey
Grass
I think this was
the way he went...
He must have it hard,
not being able to drum like his friends.
Can’t we do something for him?
If we could find
a stick that fits...
Even if it fits,
they want a certain feel...
They can be picky
with their sticks.
Of course...
Sarunori?
It’s giving up its own stick...?!
It’d go that far for him?!
Sarunori!
Bachinkey...
Huh?!
Of course!
He can just
drum twice as fast instead!
Look how well Sarunori’s doing it!
You’d be able to do it even better!
Come and train with us!
All right!
Let’s get training, Bachinkey!
Catch Pikachu
with a whoosh and a vwoosh!
Negigaknight! Use Brutal Swing!
Keep at it, Bachinkey!
Put your whole body into it!
Negigaknight!
One more time!
Why don’t we leave this to Satoshi,
and look for some food
while we have the chance?
What is it?
Isn’t that...?
Ooh! Nana Berries!
That’s my Sarunori.
You’ve already made a new friend!
They would usually
live in troops, after all...
Of course they form
strong bonds.
Huh?
You’re giving them to us?
Thank you.
That’s a great help!
You’re worried about him...
I’m sure he’ll be fine.
So just wait a little longer, okay?
Huh, really...?
So that’s it...
I wonder if she’s still
watching us in secret.
That’s the spirit!
What’s he doing?
Sword fighting?
But...
That’s great!
It looks like so much fun!
Let us join in, too!
Yeah!
Pikachu!
Use Iron Tail!
Go! Negigaknight!
Yokubarisu!
Use Seed Machine Gun!
Great job, Bachinkey!
What’s going on?
Go, is he...?
That Bachinkey...
He really did it!
They’re calling for Bachinkey!
Let’s go, Bachinkey!
Now, they’re about to start!
Give it all you’ve got!
All right!
He’s in perfect sync!
Wow!
That’s the power Sarunori has...
The power to breathe life into the forest!
Yeah.
You were trying to catch Bachinkey,
but I guess you don’t
feel like that anymore, huh?
Ooh, Sarunori looks happy too!
Yeah...
That sounded great, Bachinkey!
Go on, I won’t mind.
I mean...
If you want to stay here, then—
Wh-What’re you doing?!
Isn’t that grooming?
Grooming...
Grooming!
A mark of friendship and trust!
Of course...
I’ll keep trying to be
a great partner for you!
So let’s keep getting along!
Satoshi and Go managed to reunite
the Bachinkey who lost his stick with his friends.
Having deepened their bond
with Sarunori,
their adventure yet continues.
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Sarunori
Gantle
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Sarunori
Gantle
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Gantle
Sarunori
Grass!
Gantle
Sarunori
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Normal
Ice
They're all unique and all intriguing
Fighting
Poison
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nor
Norma
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Normal
Kabigon
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Wa
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Water
What type is this Pokémon?
Nyorotono
Bachin'uni
Elec
Electr
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Electric
What type is this Pokémon?
Bachin'uni
Hariteyama
Figh
Fightin
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Hariteyama
Fighting
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
Heard you got
your next Trial Mission!
It’s a Raid Battle...
My mission this time...
Against who?
The Legendary Pokémon, Freezer...
Whoa! That’s so exciting!
Tokio?!
Go?!
My, oh, my.
I never expected
to see you two here.
Shigeru?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Trial Mission!
A Freezing Raid Battle!!
Trial Mission! A Freezing Raid Battle!!