Satoshi, who aims to battle
the Supreme Monarch, Dande...
And Go, who dreams of catching every Pokémon
to work his way up to Mew...
This is the story of their lives and adventures.
Satoshi and Go have arrived at
Yadon Island, the home of many Yadon.
They have been here before.
It’s been a while.
Today, I’m going to catch
my old rival, Yadon!
Found them?
There they are!
So many...
...Yadon!
Hey, you still not ready? C'mon, hurry up!
You all packed and ready to leave?
I'll show you this wide mysterious world
And skip the slow send-off
Be it through fire or through water
I'm fumbling blindly through the days
When I don't even know what the next second will bring
Each and every one of my memories
Can always be found inside a Ball
On 1, 2, 3, dive in!
I've got my plans for when I grow up in my pocket
Greeting someone new is always fresh
No need (No need!) to hesitate! Try! (Try!)
Let's have a fight!
1. Once the battle's done
2. And we're laughing or crying
On 3, let's be friends!
Any day and every day, that's always been my rule
With this unpredictable, unfathomable world awaiting
Let's go! Every time you trip and fall
Let's go! You pick yourself up by my side
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
I choose you!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Yadoking!
A Curry-ously Great Encounter!!
What’cha doin’, Yadon?
Had a dream ‘bout wakin’ up with the sun
Let’s join ‘em!
Wha?!
As it slept ‘til noon, that Yadon
Man, this feels great...
Its pink skin isn’t due to being overboiled
Gah, why...?
It always looked like that, that Yadon
Saton!
Its large mouth is like a convenience store; open 24/7, that Yadon
Go!
Hold it!
No, no, no!
I did not come here
for a nap!
Its tail is so sweet that...
Monster Ball, go!
...kids sometimes use it as a snack, that Yadon
It’s so slow that it never ever blurs in photos
Is it proud of that? Yadon...
Yadon’s data will be
added to the Index!
Yes! I caught a Yadon!
What’s going on?
What was that just now?
No idea...
When I look at these guys,
all my cares just disappear...
What?!
Hey!
Wake up, Satoshi!
Whoa!
Those Yadon have yellow heads!
You’re right.
Yadon! Galarian Form! Dopey Pokémon!
Psychic type!
Only found in Galar!
Although it is normally zoned out,
its expression abruptly sharpens
on occasion!
Galarian Yadon, huh...?
Those guys weren’t here before.
They’re all making
like a “nice to meet you” kinda face.
They are?
They all just look zoned out to me...
I can’t tell what
they’re thinking at all...
Maybe it’s checking the taste.
Yadon tails are
supposed to taste sweet.
I guess it didn’t like the taste.
Was it bad?
Now that one’s doing it!
Huh?
What’s wrong, Yadon?
Are they spicy or something,
Sarunori?
Weren’t they
supposed to be sweet?
Maybe Galarian Yadon
taste different.
Because it eats the seeds of Galanuts,
which only grow in Galar,
its tail has developed
a spicy flavor!
Huh, so that’s it.
Maybe their diet is the reason
they look a bit different, too.
A Yadoran!
You want those nuts?
Another Yadoran?
That one’s gotta be
a Galarian Yadoran.
It looks a little different.
Yadoran! Galarian Form! Hermit Crab Pokémon!
Poison/Psychic type!
If it squeezes the tongue
of the Shellder biting it,
the Shellder will launch a toxic liquid
from the tip of its shell!
They’re not moving at all...
They gonna battle, maybe?
I doubt they’re even thinking...
It had its food stolen...
Are you sure?
Where’s it going?
What’s that?!
PocketMonsters
ＰＯＣＫＥＴＭｏＮＳｔｅＲｓ
Yadoking
Psychic
Poison
Yadoking! Galarian Form! Hexing Pokémon!
Poison/Psychic type!
A combination of toxins and the shock of evolving
has increased Shellder’s intelligence...
...to the point that Shellder
now controls Yadoking!
That thing looks pretty scary...
It really stands out!
It’s saying something.
A magic spell?!
Psychokinesis?!
Wh-What’s it trying to do?!
Let’s follow ‘em!
Huh?
Was that mountain always here?
I’m certain there was
sea there before...
Sarunori!
Are you okay?
Up close, it’s even scarier...
“Follow me”?
What is this?
This must be their home!
You’re giving them to us?
Thank you.
What are they?
Galanut seeds!
Galarian Yadon love them!
Huh, so they’re edible?
Time to dig in!
Too spicy!
But...
So tasty!
I could get...
hooked on these...
Maybe the tails of the Galarian Yadon
turned spicy because they’re always eating these.
Those Galanut seeds were tasty!
I get it. You were trying to give the Yadon
these seeds before, to make friends with them.
We should help you out, then!
Hold it...
This couldn’t mean...
I have to relive that nightmare?!
I knew it!
Hey, Satoshi...
Come on, come on, come on!
I’m Galarian Satoking!
Tell the historian
today I’m changing!
Come back to me, Satoshi!
I’m always gonna be
a sen-sa-tion!
When my rap hits
there ain’t no con-ten-tion!
Yo, yo, yo!
Guh...
This is hopeless...
The Index said Galarian Yadoking
were controlled by Shellder...
Does that mean Satoshi’s
being controlled by Shellder, too?
Cor-rec-to!
Thank you so!
Lotsa nice guys in
this Galarian band!
Makes me wanna
lend ‘em a hand, yo!
Yo, yo! Help me out, yo!
I don’t really get it,
but you want me to help, too?
Cor-rec-to! Tosakin-to!
What am I supposed to do?
Okay. Right, right.
With the Yadon?
Got it.
You. Got. It. Bro.
But how do you intend to make the Yadon
and the Galarian Yadon friends after that?
Yo! I got myself a master plan!
Lemme worry ‘bout it,
gonna be utopian!
We gon’ crush it, macho man!
Everyone! Listen up!
That Galarian Yadoking’s
band from before...
They might look a little scary...
But they’re not bad guys!
You’re all part of
the Yadon family!
Could you go
and meet with them again?
No, I still can’t tell anything
from those expressions...
Well, the Yadon are clustered
pretty close together already...
Yadoking!
It’s been a while!
Have you been doing well?
You’ve got great timing!
Hey, Yadoking...
Right now,
Galarian Yadon are visiting this isla—
Yo! Thanks for waiting, yo! Yo!
Yo, yo, yo!
Galarian Satoking
is on the scene!
Wh-What’s that pot for?!
Come on, Go!
A ladle?
Time to rap battle!
Hey, come on!
Whaaaaat?!
Huh?
No way...
Wait... Stop!
Goking has arrived!
Yo, Goking!
Hey, Satoking!
Yo!
Hey!
Put your hands up!
Here we go!
Yo! Yo! Yo!
Battle with me, Goking!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Let’s have a rap battle, Satoking!
Yo! Yo, yo, curry time, yo!
Tasty, yo!
Spicy, yo! Yo, yo, curry time, yo!
Spicy, yo! Tasty, yo!
No! No! No!
Udon only, I’m on a spree!
That’s a Yadon guarantee!
I’m sorry!
Some more for me!
I’m Galarian Satoking!
Gimme some Galanuts
and I’m cooking!
Crazy spice, curry’s my choice!
Eat it and you’ll be friends,
forever!
What’cha sayin’?!
Try again!
When ya think Yadon,
ya gotta have udon!
What’cha sayin’?!
Try again!
We don’t need curry!
Sorry, not curry!
Curry is heavenly!
Oh, it’s lovely!
Missing out is hell!
You’re outta your shell!
Udon’s the best,
beats out the rest!
Chewy and tough,
and revolutionary broth!
This is the life, so here we go!
Yo! Yo! Yo, yo, yo!
Hey! Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Yo!
Hey!
Curry... udon?
How the heck?!
Yo! That looks tasty!
Hey! Why don’t we try some?
Yo! What is this, yo?
The flavor’s off the chain!
For real, straight outta some god’s pantry!
Our cookery!
This is a discovery!
Utter victory!
Yo! Yo!
Hey! Hey!
Yo, yo, yo!
Hey, hey, hey!
That was great.
Isn’t that nice?
Yeah!
W-Wow...
Let’s meet again somewhere!
Take care!
See ya!
And so,
Galarian Yadoking’s band set off.
Perhaps they’re off to plant Galanut trees
all over the world...
Super Effective Type
Fire is super effective on Grass!
Burning Embers are hot-hot-hot!
Grass is super effective on Water!
Grow big and strong, soak it all up!
Water is super effective on Rock!
Next thing you know, you’re stuck in the mud!
Rock is super effective on Fire!
Set them on fire and they don't care!
Learn how the 18 types interact
Now then, everyone, think about this!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Quick to take root: the Grass type!
Amamaiko
Usokki
Hard and tough: the Rock type!
Which type is super effective?!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Grass!
Usokki
Amamaiko
Lots of Pokémon with all sorts of types
Psychic
Ghost
They're all unique and all intriguing
Dragon
Fighting
Everyone, what types are your Pokémon?
W
What ty
What type is
What type is th
What type is this
What type is this Po
What type is this Poké
What type is this Pokémo
What type is this Pokémon
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Gro
Groun
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ground
Mogurew
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Learn how they're unique and you'll like them even more
Psy
Psych
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Psychic
What type is this Pokémon?
Ponyta (Galarian Form)
Usohachi
R
Roc
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Rock
What type is this Pokémon?
Usohachi
Numera
Dra
Drago
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Numera
Dragon
What type is this Pokémon?
Now, off to the next adventure!
Go!
So this is
the Pokémon Circus tent?
We’ll get to see them evolve
into Thunders and Booster!
The evolution stones...
...swapped around?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
The Pokémon Circus!
Booster and Thunders!!