The endlessly expanding universe...
On a single planet
in a corner of this universe,
at some point long in the past,
strange creatures were born.
Over a hundred
different species of them, in fact.
People took to referring to
these creatures shrouded in mystery...
...as Pocket Monsters,
or Pokémon for short.
Oh, it’s Gänger!
And its opponent is...
The Rock-type behemoth, Iwark!
There it is!
Gänger’s Destroyer Beam!
Oh?
Iwark withstood the attack!
Iwark’s Fissure bursts forth!
It’s super effective!
This young man is Satoshi,
age ten.
At the age of ten,
those who live in Masara Town...
...are eligible to receive a starter Pokémon
from Professor Okido,
the town’s local Pokémon researcher,
at which point they may embark on a journey
to become a Pokémon Trainer.
The Pokémon Satoshi received...
...was a Pikachu.
The beginning of his journey
proved difficult.
A horde of Onisuzume
immediately descended upon him.
Cut it out, Onisuzume!
Pikachu!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
I’m gonna be the greatest Pokémon Master in the world!
I’m not gonna lose to you!
I’m gonna catch you all!
Come and get me, Onisuzume!
You did that... for me?
What’s that?
No data. In this world,
there exist phantom Pokémon yet to be identified.
Thus, Satoshi’s journey began.
People entrust Pokémon
with their own personal dreams.
There are trainers, such as Satoshi,
who aim to become Pokémon Masters...
...as well as those who
pursue phantom Pokémon...
The phantom Pokémon Mew, huh?
Some say it possesses divine power,
with which it caused a cataclysmic flood...
Others say it made crops grow in barren land,
to share them with the people.
It has all sorts of
legends to its name.
Is it an angel, or a demon?
Or perhaps it’s just capricious.
Some also claim
it possesses eternal life.
But it’s extinct, isn’t it?
Supposedly, but even in recent times,
there have been reported sightings of Mew.
Unconfirmed sightings.
Yes...
Nobody’s ever gotten
a single good photo of it.
True.
This is Mew.
And this is the fossil we just excavated
on our latest expedition.
A part of Mew’s body...
Or so we believe.
Let’s bring it back
to the laboratory at once.
If it truly is a Mew fossil...
Yeah...
We may be able to create
the mightiest Pokémon.
What is this place?
Who am I?
Why am I here?
This one’s no different
from all the other copies.
Why won’t it wake up?
In theory, nothing should be
wrong with it...
Perhaps it doesn’t want to be born?
Someone is speaking of me...
That’s absurd.
But what are they saying?
That’s the language of humans.
Who are you?
I’m human...
But I’m just like you, too.
Human?
Am I a human, too?
Since you can talk,
you could be!
Or maybe I’m a Pokémon!
Human? Pokémon?
What are those?
Which am I?
It doesn’t matter.
You and I are a lot alike!
There’s others just like us here, too!
What’s happening?
Mewtwo and Aitwo
are communicating.
The other copies
are reacting, as well.
Telepathy?
I’m unable to confirm,
but it is a plausible explanation.
Ai...
Everyone here is a copy!
So we’re not “one,” but “two”!
Am I also a “two”?
I’m Aitwo.
But the real me is Ai.
Ai...
What are you saying?
My beloved daughter, Ai...
Darling...
What do you think
of this holograph?
Isn’t it beautiful?
I managed to electronically replicate
Ai’s mental patterns!
What good will that do?
Ai is never coming back.
You’re wrong!
Just look.
This is undeniable proof of consciousness.
Ai is in this light!
I...
I don’t want to live my life
burdened by old memories.
Goodbye.
I’ve dubbed this holograph
“Aitwo.”
A Mew fossil?
The phantom Pokémon, Mew.
It’s said to possess
eternal life force.
We successfully obtained
a fossil of its eyelash.
I will create Pokémon copies.
I will create the mightiest Pokémon.
If I can discover the secret to
their resilient life force,
I may be able to endow Aitwo
with true life.
Ai... Come back to me...
Ai...
This is my memory of the place where
Ai was born and grew up.
What is that?
That’s called the sun.
The sun?
It gives us light and keeps us warm.
This is wind.
Wind?
Sometimes it kindly pushes us
to keep moving...
And sometimes it’s a bit fierce.
It’s dusk.
It’s telling us,
“Let’s meet again tomorrow.”
What are those?
The stars and the moon.
They tell us that we aren’t alone
so we won’t feel lonely when it gets dark at night.
Hitokagetwo’s signal is weakening...
It’s fading away.
So, it’s begun...
Zenigametwo and Fushigidanetwo
are also fading.
Another failure...
Where did everyone go?
Aitwo’s signal is weakening...
She’s fading.
Ai...
What’s wrong, Ai?
What happened?
It looks like...
it’s time to say goodbye.
Ai...
Something is coming out
of my eyes...
What is it?
Tears.
Tears?
I heard that most creatures don’t cry
unless they feel pain.
It’s only humans who shed tears
when they feel sad.
Thank you...
Thank you for your tears.
But don’t cry.
You’re alive.
And being alive...
...must be nice...
Ai... My tears won’t stop...
What should I do?
Please answer me, Ai!
Mewtwo’s brain pattern is unstable.
It appears to be suffering.
We can’t shock it!
Inject the sedative!
Put it to sleep!
Injecting sedative.
Ten...
Twenty...
Thirty...
Forty...
Fifty...
Sixty...
Seventy...
Eighty...
Brainwaves returning to normal levels.
Ninety...
One hundred.
Sedative injection complete.
Brainwaves are stable.
Mewtwo is asleep.
I slept for a long, long time...
Long enough for Ai...
...and the other Pokémon
created here...
...to fade beyond
the borders of my slumbering mind...
And now...
What is this place?
Who am I?
I’ve long been dreaming of
this world outside my memories...
Who are you?
Wait!
I...
...cannot forget the world
that being flew off to.
What is this place?
Who am I?
Who brought me here?
Why am I here?
No...
I simply am here.
As of yet...
...I have not been born
into this world.
Who am I?!
Oh! It woke up!
Did it do that by itself?
Magnificent!
Mewtwo is complete!
“Mewtwo”...?
That’s you.
We created you from
the Pokémon said to be rarest in the world!
Indeed...
This is the Pokémon
said to be rarest in the world:
Mew!
“Mew”...?
Is that my progenitor?
My father?
My mother?
In a sense, but not quite.
You were based off Mew,
but created to be much stronger!
By whom?
You say neither a father,
nor a mother...
So then by God?
Is God the one who created me?
The only beings capable of creating life in this world
are God and humans.
So it was you?
Humans created me?
This is a scientific triumph!
We finally have proof
that we were right!
We can continue our research!
This has become a new holy land!
We’ll get increased funding
for sure now!
Our next step is to create
an even greater version!
I’ll contact the other departments!
Congratulations!
It’s the birth of a new Pokémon!
Are we ready to deal with the media?
Who am I?
What is this place?
What was the purpose
of my birth?
Creating the mightiest Pokémon
in the world...
Our dream has...
Is this power my own?
Am I truly the mightiest
Pokémon in the world?
Mew...
Am I stronger than you?
You may very well be
the mightiest Pokémon in the world...
But there exists something else in this world
that is just as powerful.
Humans?
If you join forces with us humans,
the world will be ours.
The world will be ours...?
But if your power
is left unchecked,
the world will be brought
to its knees.
You must control your power.
“Control”?
Are you content to rely on brute strength alone
and allow the world to burn like you have this island?
What should I do?
Restraining my power with this armor
that protects my being...
What is it that
you want me to do?
It’s simple, really.
Just do as everyone else
has done on this planet.
Everyone?
Fight, destroy, and plunder.
The strong succeed here.
But even so, who am I?
Where am I?
For what purpose do I fight?
Why am I alive?
You’re a Pokémon.
Pokémon live for humans;
to be used by them.
So you mean to say
I should fight for you?
That I should fight for humans?
You’re a Pokémon
created by humans.
What other worth could you have?
“Worth”?
Who am I?
Why am I alive?
What are you doing?!
Humans may have created me...
But I am no human...
As an artificial creation,
I am not even a true Pokémon!
Who am I?
What is this place?
Who asked that I be born?
Who wished for my creation?
I resent everything
that led to my birth.
So this...
...is neither an attack,
nor a declaration of war...
It is me striking back at
that which has created me.
Satoshi continues training on his journey with his friends,
aiming to become a Pokémon Master.
They’re currently taking
a quick break in this field to enjoy the weather.
Takeshi, is it done yet?
Satoshi!
You could help, too!
I can’t...
I’m so hungry I can’t move
a muscle...
Sheesh!
Gently simmer...
Slowly nurture...
Soup and Pokémon training alike
can’t be rushed.
Hey! My homeboy!
You’re the homie from Masara Town named Satoshi
who got eight badges, am I right?
Yeah. Why?
Can you battle with your Pokémon?
Okay!
I can’t say no to a good battle!
What happened to
not moving a muscle?
I can make room for a
Pokémon battle or two before breakfast!
Except in this case
it’s before lunch...
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka ano ko no sukaato no naka (kyaah!)
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl's skirt (Eek!)
naka naka naka naka naka naka naka naka taihen dakedo
It's really, really, really, really hard to handle,
kanarazu getto da ze pokemon getto daze
but I'm gonna get them all! I'm gonna get Pokémon!
masara taun ni sayonara bye bye
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
ore wa koitsu to tabi ni deru (Pikachu!)
I'm going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
kitaeta waza de kachimakuri
I'll win each battle with the moves I've mastered,
nakama o fuyashite tsugi no machi e
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
itsumo itsu demo umaku yuku nante
There's no way to know for sure
hoshou wa doko ni mo nai kedo (sorya sou ja!)
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
itsu demo itsumo honki de ikiteru koitsu tachi ga iru
But with my companions by my side, we'll live life to the fullest!
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka ano ko no sukaato no naka (shitsukoi!)
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl's skirt (Knock it off!)
naka naka naka naka naka naka naka naka taihen dakedo
It's really, really, really, really hard to handle,
kanarazu getto da ze pokemon getto daze
but I'm gonna get them all! I'm gonna get Pokémon!
tatakai tsukarete oyasumi good night
Weary from battling, I bid you goodnight
mabuta o tojireba yomigaeru (Pikachu?)
When I close my eyes, I'm taken back (Pikachu?)
honoo ga moete kaze ga mai
to the roaring fire, the dancing wind,
nakigoe todoroku ano batoru ga
and the echoing shouts of that battle
kinou no teki wa kyou no tomo tte
"Yesterday's foe is today's ally"
furui kotoba ga aru kedo (furui to wa nan ja!)
According to some old saying (What do you mean "Old"?!)
kyou no tomo wa ashita no tomodachi sou sa eien ni
But an ally made today is my friend tomorrow, and will be forevermore
aa akogare no pokemon masutaa ni
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
naritai na naranakucha zettai natte yaru
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Oh my God!
We did it!
His opponent was weak,
that’s all.
His Pokémon weren’t well raised.
Pikachu shines brighter by the day!
He’s dazzling!
We haven’t gotten the best of them
even once...
But the words “give up”
don’t exist in our vocabulary, meow!
His Pikachu will be ours!
But just look at that...
I’m starving, meow...
I have a frying pan.
Yeah, but without any meat or vegetables,
a pan’s just a slab of iron, meow.
Master, shall I extend an invitation
to them as well?
Understood.
Who are you?
Is this for me?
Please pardon the sudden letter.
What a pretty lady!
Having recognized you as
promising Pokémon Trainers,
my master, the mightiest Pokémon Trainer,
has formally invited you to his party.
It will be held in
the Pokémon castle on New Island.
Please check the appropriate box on the reply postcard
indicating whether or not you will be present.
We hope you will accept this invitation
from the mightiest Pokémon Trainer.
The pretty lady...
What should we do?
Let’s go! We gotta do it!
Feels pretty good to be called
promising or whatever!
So put a check next to “Yes”
on the postcard!
Yes! Yes!
You’re not going bye-bye
without saying hi to us first, are you?
Oh, a postcard.
Calm down!
I said calm down!
Kingler, enough already!
The weather was so nice, too!
The weather by the sea
is always fickle.
What?
The ferry’s not coming?
We can’t go to New Island?
No way!
We’re lucky we
were even invited!
Quiet down, everyone!
The woman standing next to me
is in charge of this wharf.
I’m Voyager.
If you wish to know the sea,
ask the seagulls by the wharf.
Though you need not bother.
Simply gaze at the clouds.
I’ve never witnessed such a hurricane.
It’s that bad?
I grew up by the port,
yet I’ve never seen such a raging storm.
Worse yet, the eye of the storm is offshore
above the skies of New Island.
I simply cannot subject you all
to such peril.
As the protector of this port,
that is my wish.
There you have it.
The ferry is canceled.
I’ll be just fine with my Pokémon!
It’s good in the water.
We’ll cross the ocean,
no problem!
Please, wait.
I know the ocean,
and I’m telling you no.
That’s right!
Besides, if your Pokémon
were injured,
you’d have no way of getting them treated
at the Pokémon Center right now!
What do you mean?
Ms. Joy from the Pokémon Center
went missing.
We can’t treat any Pokémon’s injuries
without her.
That missing person poster
over there is for her.
She’s pretty!
Huh?
I feel like I’ve seen her before...
Stop!
Stop or you’re under arrest!
I suppose trying to stop them
was a fool’s errand.
What?
They’re Pokémon Trainers,
after all...
Adventurers.
If they were the sort of people to quit after being told no,
they wouldn’t have gathered here.
Let us pray for their safety.
The mightiest trainer is
waiting across the sea!
I can’t back down now!
But there’s no way we can
cross the raging sea with our Pokémon.
You’re right...
You lot look stuck.
Wanna ride?
Not saying it’s gonna be free,
but we could be convinced to help you out.
Our ship has come in... Literally!
We really lucked out!
But will we really make it
in a boat like this?
These waves are nothing!
Our lot were bathed in the crashing waves of
the Guren Strait when we were newborns!
That so, meow?
Togepi, stay still just a bit longer.
It’s you guys!
You three!
You really don’t let up!
What do you want?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of—
Now’s not the time, meow!
Satoshi! Kasumi!
Where are Satoshi and Pikachu?
I can’t tell!
Hold on tight, everyone!
Is that...?
We’re delighted you could make it.
Please present your invitation.
This thing?
This message is to confirm that
these people are among those invited.
I knew it was you!
What?
The Ms. Joy I saw on
the missing person poster at the port!
They do kinda look alike.
What do you mean?
I’ve been in service of this castle
since I was born.
If you would,
please come with me.
Our other esteemed guests
have already arrived.
The trainers over there
are the ones who arrived before you.
Only three of them?
But there were so many
at the port!
The invitations given to the trainers who
could not brave the storm were wasted.
Are you saying the storm
was a test?
Please release your Pokémon from their
Monster Balls and take a seat.
You are chosen trainers.
So, if we want to sneak our way
into the castle...
...we’ll just have to
take the exit, won’t we?
What exit?
Down there.
Th-Th-The sewage pipes?!
I’m not some lousy rat!
Quit whining!
What’s up, Musashi?
Nothing...
Come on, let’s go!
So you guys made it here, too?
Oh, I know you!
I flew here.
My Pidgeot glides
right through hurricanes.
Say hi, you guys!
Isn’t that...?
That’s my Gyarados.
I braved the ocean on its back!
Those puny waves were nothing for it!
Gyarados is the
Atrocious Pokémon, right?
Yup.
If you can handle one,
you’ll never find a more reliable partner.
These are my Pokémon.
Esteemed guests,
I apologize for the wait.
The mightiest Pokémon Trainer
will be with you shortly.
What’s that?
Indeed...
The person before you is
the mightiest Pokémon Trainer,
as well as the mightiest Pokémon.
Master Mewtwo.
Mewtwo...?
A Pokémon who’s
a Pokémon Trainer?!
Yeah right!
Is that wrong?
I set my own rules.
This voice!
Telepathy?
It used Mind Power?
Go, Gyarados!
Gyarados,
use Destroyer Beam!
Gyarados!
Much too easy.
I have no further need of you.
Ms. Joy!
Where am I?
What am I doing here?
I brought you here from the Pokémon Center
so that you could care for me.
Having a doctor who is familiar
with Pokémon anatomy is convenient.
You’ve proven your worth.
Though you surely
have no memory of it.
What was that?!
With my powers, I can easily
control you humans however I see fit.
That’s horrible!
Easy does it...
What’s this place?
What a cutie, meow!
You call that cute?
None of this looks
like treasure, does it?
Phew...
This is— of our res— rch.
These are the bluepr—
the device— create Pok— copies.
The co— are cre—
from Pokém— DNA.
For this purpose—
a sample proved necessary—
Wh-What?!
What? What’s this thing?!
What?!
Nyarth!
Stop...!
Help me, meow!
Oww!
M-My fur... My fur!
Oh! Three strands of fur!
Even a small sample will do...
By studying the composition of
the Pokémon in question...
...we should be able to create
a perfect copy of the original.
Who’s this?
Nyarth!
Nyarth?!
I’m Nyarth, meow!
Then, is this...?
A copy of Nyarth?
Aww geez...
But the copy we created
exceeded our imagination.
The Le— ary Pokémon we discovered
d-deep within the jungle...
It is called Mew.
We managed to procure
a fossilized Mew eyelash.
After bringing it back,
from its composition...
...we were able to create Mewtwo
with this m-machine.
To create the world’s mightiest Pokémon
with our own hands...
That was our dream.
Howeve-e-e-er...
M-M-Mewtwo exhibited
immeasurable ferocity.
We are doomed.
This laboratory will be d-d-destroyed.
The only option left to us...
...is to abandon this place and flee.
Was he talking about this place?
Must be.
Yeah...
Uh-huh...
But it looks perfectly fine to me...
Maybe someone rebuilt it?
Huh? Like who?
I had once hoped to work
with you humans.
Yet your kind failed me.
Humans are the lowest of creatures,
beneath even Pokémon.
If weak, heartless beings like you humans
control the planet...
...then we’re all doomed.
So you want your kind—
you want Pokémon
to rule the planet?!
Pokémon cannot, either.
Because...
...this planet is already
controlled by humans.
There are even Pokémon who
live for humans!
What?
You say you’re not a slave?
You stay with your trainer
out of mutual affinity?
That very act was a grave mistake.
Oww...
Pikachu!
Weak Pokémon
nestle up to humans.
Satoshi, are you okay?
Yeah.
How dare you hurt Pikachu?!
You may be strong,
but there’s no Pokémon that can’t be caught!
Go, my Saihorn!
Saihorn!
A vain attempt.
I was born stronger than
any and all Pokémon living on this planet.
You can’t say that without fighting!
Do you volunteer?
My pleasure!
What a scary feeling!
It cried?
It flew?
“Mew”?
Any humans aspiring to become Pokémon Trainers
would first wish to acquire...
Hitokage...
Zenigame...
...or Fushigidane.
And these are my creations;
their evolved forms...
...copied.
Copied?
They’re fake?
An arena?
You mean you want to have
a Pokémon battle?
I have my Fushigibana, Bernard!
And I have my Kamex, Exex!
I’ve got my Lizardon, too!
Lizardon, I choose you!
Lizardon, no surprise attacks!
Quite an ill-mannered Lizardon.
Who will face us first?
I let my guard down earlier,
but that won’t happen again!
Go, Bernard!
Use Razor Leaf!
Vine Whip.
Bernard!
I’m next!
Go, Exex!
Exex! Hydro Pump!
Exex!
Satoshi, be careful!
Their moves are really powerful!
I know!
Lizardon!
Instead of strength,
we’ll fight with speed!
All right! Go!
How is that
“fighting with speed”?!
His opponent is too fast!
Lizardon!
Globe Throw.
Hang in there!
Are you okay?
It lacks in both speed and strength.
Stop it!
Do you plan to
steal people’s Pokémon?!
“Steal”?
No...
I will create far superior copies of
the Pokémon you’re so proud of!
Ones befitting of me!
Copies?!
Cut it out!
That’s against the rules!
Don’t give me orders!
I make my own rules.
Here they come!
Run, everyone!
Gyarados!
Stop it!
I know!
Everyone! Call your Pokémon back
into their own Monster Balls!
Return, Zenigame, Fushigidane!
How pointless.
Nothing is impossible
for these Monster Balls I’ve created.
We can’t stay here!
Let’s go outside!
Yeah!
My Koduck!
Rokon!
Run, Pikachu!
Pikachu!
Don’t give up, Pikachu!
Who’s this?
Strike!
Dewgong!
Rafflesia!
Sandpan!
Nidoqueen!
Showers!
But this is definitely Nyarth, meow...
Oww...
Ouch...
Brat boy?!
Team Rocket?!
Sorry, but I don’t have
time for this today!
Who’s this?
Pikachu!
Come on...!
Let go, already!
Let go of my Pikachu!
Let him go!
What’s going on, meow?!
Pikachu!
So many copies!
Oh, my, they’re coming out...
My copy, too!
Those are all copies?!
Oh? Where...
...are the copies going, meow?
Oh, my! Here come
the real ones, too!
Zenigame!
Fushigidane!
Humans!
I will not take your lives.
You are free to leave.
That is, if you’re capable of
braving the storm.
What is happening?
Unforgivable...
I’ll never forgive you!
Satoshi!
Koduck!
Rokon!
Did you free them?
My Pokémon...
My friends...
I’ll protect them!
Satoshi!
Stop!
What?
Are you...?
Over there?
What is that?
A Pokémon?
Mew!
The Pokémon said to be
the rarest in the world!
Mew?
It is true that I was
created from you...
...but I am the stronger one!
I am the real one!
Mew and Mewtwo...
Mewtwo was created
from Mew...
Only I will survive!
Why do you retreat?
Do you avoid battle out of fear?
It appears you can
fight back, at least.
It’s time to determine
who is real!
Am I stronger than Mew?
Are we stronger than
you so-called originals?
We were created to
surpass you in strength!
So that’s it, meow.
What’s it saying?
“Real is real. If they battle with physical strength alone
rather than using their moves,
“the real Pokémon will not lose to mere copies,”
is what Mew said, meow.
“Real is real,” you say?
Very well.
We can determine who is real
without our moves!
We are the stronger ones!
Go!
What kind of a battle is this?
Real or copy...
They’re all still alive!
They’re all living creatures.
Even though they’re artificial,
they’re still living, breathing creatures.
Real ones and copies...
But both living creatures...
Neither is “winning” this fight.
If you ask us about this...
I just don’t know...
This is really depressing...
It’s like they’re
bullying themselves...
It’s like looking at
my past self...
Like looking at
my current self...
What an awful feeling!
You’re...!
These gotta hurt, meow...
All the other Pokémon are fighting,
so don’t be such a coward, meow!
What?
“You’re the coward,” meow?
“Why won’t you fight me”?!
“Those claws must hurt”?
Your claws gotta hurt way more!
“I bet the moon
is round tonight”?
Yeah, meow...
It’s gotta be a full moon, meow.
Talking about the moon
at a time like this...
You’re quite the philosopher, meow...
Pikachu!
Oww...
That’s enough!
Stop!
Satoshi!
I have to make them stop...
You can’t.
Unless Mew and Mewtwo stop,
the fighting will continue.
Living creatures never yield their territory
to others of their kind.
Oh, no...
They’ll fight until they’ve
driven their foes away.
That’s what living creatures do.
That’s what living creatures do...
But Mewtwo was created by humans.
But... now it’s just like
any other creature.
Now...
just like any other creature...
Mew and Mewtwo...
And Pikachu...
And the other Pikachu, too...
Stop!
Satoshi!
Please, just stop!
Stop!
Satoshi!
Impossible!
A human attempted to
end our battle?!
Pikachu...
Pikachu!
Indeed...
As it stands, you and I are both
Pokémon who came to exist in this world.
It may be best that no one
know of this incident.
Perhaps it is best left forgotten.
Where are you all going?
We have been born...
We are alive.
We will live on...
...somewhere... in this world.
We can’t send out any ships
in this storm!
The hurricane is drawing closer.
Please, seek shelter.
There’s no need to worry, everyone.
We’re opening the Pokémon Center
to be used as a shelter.
Anyone who wishes to use our services,
please come with me.
Ms. Joy, Ms. Junsa, Ms. Voyager...
All three of them look stunning today,
drenched in rain...
But... what are we doing here?
Not sure...
We’re just... here, I guess.
Well, whatever.
Yeah!
Huh?
Is this even possible?
The hurricane...
It’s like it never happened...
I’d say the ships can
set sail tomorrow.
Look!
What?
I don’t see anything.
Just a bunch of clouds.
The day I set off to become a Pokémon Master,
I saw a phantom Pokémon.
And I think I just saw another.
Maybe you’ll get to
meet another one!
A phantom Pokémon.
Yeah!
I’m sure someday I will!
Pocket Monsters...
This is the tale of those aiming
to become Pokémon Masters...
and their encounters with the
strange creatures known as Pokémon.
Their journey will go on and on.
You know,
with this island being deserted and all...
It’s kinda refreshing!
A nice change of pace!
What a great feeling!
aruki tsuzukete doko made yuku no
How much farther will you walk?
kaze ni tazunerarete tachidomaru
The wind calls out, and you come to a halt
tanjoubi iwau rousoku fueta kedo
Though you've added more candles to celebrate your birth,
tatta hitotsu no furusato tabidatta
and you've left your one and only hometown behind,
ima mo nanika o motomete
still, you seek the unknown,
ookina hitomi kagayaite
your wide-eyed gaze shining bright
kimi no poketto no naka ni wa
Contained within your pockets
kimi janai dareka to no...
lie memories you share with someone else...
ikutsumo no deai
Innumerable meetings
ikutsumo no wakare
Innumerable farewells
maboroshi no you na omoide mo sukoshi
And precious few dreamlike moments
aruki tsuzukete doko made yuku no
How much farther will you walk?
kaze ni tazunerarete sora o miru
The wind calls out, and you gaze toward the sky
aruki tsuzukete doko made yukou ka
How much farther will we walk together?
kaze to issho ni mata aruki dasou
Together with the wind, we will set out once again
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
Stepping out onto the road, let us go on and on
mezashita ano yume o tsukamu made
Until we seize that sought after dream
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
Stepping out onto the road, let us go on and on
mezashita ano yume o tsukamu made
Until we seize that sought after dream