Yo, yo, yo, yo!
Oh! On the vast plains of Table...
...ripen the fruits, the young Oranges!
Hey!
As you gaze at the Great Crater,
friends and teachers gather!
Respect tradition,
grow bigger and stronger,
and seek out knowledge!
Oranges!
Louder! Louder and louder!
Hey!
Come on!
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Whozat? It’s Nanjamo!
Shocked to see me popping in?
Today, I’m collabing on a vid
all about Orange Academy!
They say they want me to introduce
Paldea’s Gym Leaders!
Gettin’ all cozy with all the students...
This’s bound to send my popularity rising
like a Shibirudon going upriver!
So howzabout... Time Attack!
The “Can You Name
Paldea’s Gym Leaders?” Game!
Wellzen...
Ready... start!
First up: me!
The Electrical Streamer!
Whozat? Nanjamo!
The lines are always long
at her adorable Bug Poké-Sweets shop!
The owner of Pâtisserie Soapberry,
Madam Kaede!
Are the rumors true?
Does he really jump off windmills?!
The Nature Artist, Sir Colza!
The wise advisor of Carafe City!
The Surging Chef, Haidai’s da guy!
His fave lunch spot
is the Treasure Eatery?!
With 25 years of service
to the Pokémon League, Sir Aoki!
Her biggest hit track is Ghost Father!
The globe-trotting
Soulful Rapper, Madam Rhyme!
You’ll see ads for her cosmetics brand
Rouge Magic every day in Hakkou City!
Madam Lip!
Is there really a nonstop stream of fans challenging
the treacherous Mt. Nappé Gym just to meet him?!
The former Pro Snowboarder,
Sir Grusha!
And... done!
Barely made it...
What a great video!
I never dreamed we’d actually
collab with Nanjamo!
Ohara, your club’s music
was incredible, too!
Thank you!
Everyone in the Wind Ensemble
really enjoyed making it!
And Dad...
...said he had fun, too!
I’m glad to hear it.
Man, doesn’t it feel great to see
everyone’s ideas finally coming together?
Aliquis, you’ve really changed.
Huh? What’s this about?
You used to be, um...
Scarier.
You said it!
Hey! That’s going too far!
Sorry!
I forgot all about
the News Club meeting today!
What’s your next article
going to be about?
I’m going to write about that battle
between you and Nemo.
Huh? Oh...
I want to rewrite it into
a proper rundown of the battle!
Last time, all I could think about
was trying to stand out...
So this time,
please allow me an interview!
Yeah! Sure!
Thank you.
Well then, I’ll see you tomorrow!
Let’s go, Welcamo.
I should get going, too.
Where to?
I’m going home.
My brother’s back from Blueberry Academy,
and I promised him a battle.
We’re gonna show him
our new battle style!
Right, Masquernya?
Give it your all!
I will! Okay, see you!
Let’s go, Masquernya!
Hogator!
Shall we get going too, then?
Oh, no!
No, it’s nothing.
Let’s go, Hogator!