C’mon, let’s go!
Okay!
Original Animation
Pocket Monsters Scarlet & Violet
Afterschool Breath
Bye-bye.
Episode I   "Breathe Out"
Hulkujira lives on Mt. Nappé,
which is covered in snow all year round...!
It absorbs nutrition from
the cold and ice... Hmm, I see!
U-Um... The Director really
sprung this on us out of nowhere, huh?
For the benefit of all
new students and transfer students...
“...I ask that you create a video
showcasing the splendor of our Academy!”
...were his exact words.
What do we do with that?
I never knew!
Director!
Why did you choose us three?!
Terastallize your Pokémon!
That way the moves of that type
get even stronger! Got it?
Let’s have fun!
O-Oh, and you were going to
battle Nemo again soon, right?
Give it your all, Aliquis.
You think I hadn’t
been giving it my all?
N-No, that’s not what I...
How about you, Ohara?
Aren’t you playing a flute solo
at the next concert?
I was real surprised you got picked.
Congratulations.
Thank you...
Your old man's conducting, right?
My dad—
Big news!
They just published a theory about
Pokémon that communicate using sound waves!
For instance, Hulkujira use something called
“echolocation” to find one another!
Hohma! I was talking with Ohara!
Whuh! Kuwassu!
Are you... um... all right?
Cut it out already, Hohma!
Control your Kuwassu!
I’m sorry!
Get back here, you!
Oh, no...
I just can’t deal with this!
Quit running!
Treasure hunting on Mt. Nappé, eh?
Quite a remote destination.
Um... I’m very sorry
I abandoned the video project.
But... I think it’ll work out better
without me there.
I did believe you were
the perfect person for the job...
But I suppose I mustn’t push.
But how are things proceeding
with regards to the concert?
Have you spoken to your father?
Um...
Oh, I apologize.
I seem to have spoken out of line.
But please, do drop by my office
if you are concerned about anything.
Okay...
I hope you find your treasure.
Using the treasure hunt
as an excuse to run away...
I’m just the worst.
Hogator! Come here!
Huh...?
Hogator?
Where are you?
Hogator!
Wasn’t he from the Academy...?
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
That guy there... Whozat?
Some really important guy from
our esteemed Academy’s 800-year history!
You sure this’ll work?
It’ll be a huge hit, guaranteed!
Oh! Ohara!
Where are you going
with all that luggage?
Uh...
Off to do some treasure hunting...
Where you headed?
Mt. Nappé.
All the way out there?!
Bringing your flute
to the snowy mountain...
Just... for the ascent.
Oh, I get you!
Spicy!
Are you all right?!
Another miss...
Mt. Nappé is where
the Hulkujira live, isn’t it?!
Research says that the soundwaves they emit when
at their most relaxed sound very similar to a flut—
Be quiet!
A flute!
I’m sorry... I’m so sorry...
Hogator!
Are you all right?!
I’m saved...
Say... Were you the one
who distracted the Hulkujira?
You’re really good at the flute, huh?
My dad... taught me...
Huh...
You and your parents
get along, then.
I wouldn’t say that...
I wouldn’t have managed to play
if it hadn’t been for Hogator.
I see.
I suppose I should
be thanking you, too.
Thank you.
Look after your partner Pokémon, okay?
I’m never letting go!
Oh... I see...
Thank you, Hogator!
Let’s get back to school!