“Prodigy Nemo on a three-win streak against Aliquis!
A battle playing out like a rerun!”
Why would you reject my article?!
Well, I just feel like that’s not
the right angle for covering that match.
So, next suggestion.
Allow me.
How about an exclusive report
on Team Star?
Who was that particularly
nasty group? The Caph Squad?
But yeah, if we report on Team Star,
that’ll really capture people’s attention!
Nah, it’s just too dangerous!
Why was my article not good enough?
Hmm?
Episode 3   "Take a Breath"
Um, about before...
Sorry I lashed out at you!
I went a bit too far, too...
But you still have something
to say to Hogator!
Right...
I’m sorry.
Now Nemo’s beaten me three times...
But we’re not done just yet!
Here to join you now...
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
Even if we get the Wind Ensemble
to help us with music...
...the footage just isn’t up to snuff.
This won’t make for
much of a school presentation...
Then we should get someone to help us
get some more impressive footage.
Like who?
Uh...
Nanjamo, maybe?
Wha—?! Do you really think someone
as famous as her will give us the time of day?!
The two of them seem...
different, somehow...
We won’t know unless we try!
Would someone as great
as her really help us?
Not good...
I’m being left behind, even here...
Do you have any other suggestions?
If we report on Team Star,
that’ll really capture people’s attention!
Of course! Team Star!
If I deliver an exclusive scoop on
Caph Squad, all eyes will be on me for sure!
Where’d this come from?
Team Star?
What are you talking about?
Oh, well, just an idea for the video!
Just imagine how great it would be
if we had footage of Team Star!
Huh? That’s so dangerous, though.
The name Hohma will be known
to everyone in the academy!
Prepare yourselves!
I will nab that exclusive scoop!
Who the heck’re you?
U-Uh...
U-Um...
F-Fantastarric work!
My name is Hohma.
Please let me join Team Star!
Hang on a sec.
And stay out of
that storeroom, you hear?
I smell a scoop!
A three-person cart,
propelled by mounting a Burorom—
No, two Burorom!
Two, and a Burororoom!
I can’t believe they were hiding
such a nasty secret weapon...!
Eek!
I told you to stay out!
No need to yell.
I’m sorry I scared you.
Name’s Biwa.
You?
I-I’m... Hohma.
Pleasure!
Thank you for coming
to the Caph Squad.
Right, let’s get started!
Eh?
First up, a run!
Why do I have to run...?
Next, pose practice!
Fantastarric work!
F-Fantastarric work...
You take a break,
and you gotta start over!
Please, spare me!
Congratulations!
You’ll be ready for anything now!
Biwa-chan!
Konoyozaru!
A Lum Berry!
Sorry...
Calm down... Calm down...
Are you okay, Hohma-kun?
Ah... Y-Yes...
Biwa-chan, thank you!
But don’t push yourself
too hard on our behalf.
Nah, you’ve got it all wrong.
I push myself because y’all
give me the strength to.
Oh... Biwa-chan...
That’s our line...
Team Star...
The rumors were all wrong.
They were kind, compassionate people...
And... it’s gone.
What was the point
of anything I did today?
I came all this way,
but with no scoop to show for it...
Nobody’s gonna know my name...
What’s gotten into you?
Could you...
...have been trying to
cheer me up all along?
You were always watching,
right by my side...
We sure took
quite the roundabout path.
Now, let’s go home, Welkamo.
I’m sure the club president
will yell at me again...
Oh, well.
Not getting a reply from Nanjamo.
Maybe it was too much to hope for.
Um! May I make a suggestion?
Why not make the sort of video
that will make Nanjamo-san want to participate?
What’s that supposed to mean?
Nanjamo-san is an influencer.
She might just latch on to us
if she thinks our video will go viral!
“Go viral”?
We’ll get plenty of people
all over Paldea to participate!
Such as Gym Leaders
or the Elite Four!
That could work if we ask
Chairwoman Omodaka for advice.
Or we could approach Rhyme-san!
Ohara and the band’s performance,
coupled with Rhyme-san’s rapping...
That could be fun.
It’ll go viral for sure!
But that won’t really be much of a presentation
of the school... That was the assignment.
Don’t worry!
Life here at the academy
reaches far beyond its walls!
One could say that all of Paldea
is our place of learning!
Don’t you think?
That does make sense.
The Treasure Hunt
covers all of Paldea too, after all.
Let’s film the people and lifestyles from all over Paldea,
and how the Treasure Hunt connects them all!
Great idea!
Of course, we have to
introduce the teachers!
Ooh! We definitely need
footage of Table City.
I would like to go shoot
the Ten Sights of Paldea, as well!
All right! The plan’s starting to
come together!
We start filming tomorrow!
Yeah!