Masquernya! Leaf Storm!
If I were you,
I wouldn’t use Masquernya again.
Huh?
A Pokemon that’s lost has tipped its hand,
so I don’t use it again.
But Bro...
Masquernya’s—
I know, it’s tough.
But you wanna beat Nemo
and be number one at your school, right?
Nemo’s on a roll!
That’s the power of a Champion Rank!
That Nemo girl is incredible!
Aliquis is tutored by his big brother,
who attends Blueberry Academy...
She is a genius.
Well, choice is yours.
See ya.
Got it, Bro.
I get it.
If I want to win...
I’m sorry, Masquernya.
Episode 2   "Breathe In"
Ohara?
I-I’m back.
U-Um...
Sorry for slacking off on the video!
But... I’ve been thinking...
Oha-kon-hello-ciao!
I want to play the flute after all.
The flute? What do you mean?
Hmm? Huh?!
The principal’s assignment!
The video will need music!
I want to showcase the merits of
the academy with the timbre of my flute!
W-Well, sure then.
Oh right, where’s Hohma?
He said News Club was running long.
I see.
I saw the news.
Too bad, huh?
Hmph, the nerve of that Hohma,
laughing it up...
Well, I analyzed the reason
for my loss.
I’ll win next time.
You’re the strongest battler
in our class, Aliquis.
You evolved your Nyahoja
into Masquernya ahead of everyone!
Hogator, you wanna evolve soon, too?
You think that guy can even evolve?
Its head is always in the clouds.
But it’s really reliable when it counts!
Like before, right?
Hmph. But it can’t
win you battles, can it?
Y-You didn’t win
your battle either, Aliquis.
That was Masquernya’s fault!
I won’t use Masquernya next time!
I’ll use a different trump card!
It’s not gonna be—
You’re not going after it?
Y-You’re always
eating those sweets, Aliquis.
Are they your favorites?
Not exactly...
Just a pre-battle ritual.
If there’s sugar candy inside—
Masquernya?!
Aliquis, what good timing!
Please tell us!
What lost you the battle against Nemo?
I’ve analyzed the reason.
But I’m not telling you.
Next time, I’ll win!
Ooh! A rematch?!
That’s big news!
Tch. Struck out.
Thanks.
Let’s grow stronger... together.
Aliquis is backed into a corner!
On the other hand,
Nemo still has strength to spare!
What do I do?
A battle’s not decided
‘til the very end!
The way this is going...
I’m so lame.
Losing to the same person
again and again!
Huh?
What am I doing, now of all times...?
Huh?!
Let’s grow stronger... together.
Just hold on a sec.
Oh!
Sugar candy!
The grand prize!
The grand prize...
I’m sorry...
Masquernya!
You were always by my side...
But somehow I lost sight of you...
...when you’re... the whole reason...
I’ve even made it this far!
Huh? What? A blackout?
Masquernya!
Sorry I lashed out at you!
I wanna battle with you after all—
Ah!
Hey!
Don’t hog them all!
It’s that really strong Masquernya!
Nemo! You sound confident!
A battle’s not decided
‘til the very end, right?
That’s right!
Even your partner
is itching to get battling!
Let’s go, Masquernya!
We’ll keep on fighting,
even if we struggle in vain!
Masquernya!
Terastallize!
Kentauros!
Time for us to shine, too!
Kentauros! Desperate Tackle!
Masquernya! Evil Pulse!
Now! Acrobatics!
Masquernya! Trick Flowers!
Kentauros! Use Infight!
Masquernya toughed it out
so he wouldn’t feel sad!
Amazing!
Go for it, Aliquis! Masquernya!
Let’s have us a fruitful battle!
Let’s show ‘em what our bond can do!
To the very last blow!
Masquernya!