I choose you!
Leaving her home
of Mashiro Town for Tokyo,
Madoka entered the world of creators,
as she had dreamed of doing.
While she struggled
in her first battle with a client,
Iwakura
Madoka
she won splendidly with
a super effective presentation!
It’s super effective!
And so, the curtain rose
upon a new adventure...
Good work!
How much longer is the break?
We’ll be leaving in about five minutes.
We managed to get some good photos.
Mt. Tsukimi   Day of the poster photoshoot
Like this one...
This one look pretty nice, doesn’t it?
Right?
Ooh, that one’s good.
Please... Wake up, Hitokage!
Gah...
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
Hitokage is
sleeping soundly.
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
Pounding away at
a sleeping foe again and again...
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
Purin
Hitokage
Asleep
The enemy Purin's
Pound attack!
There’s a real cutthroat behind that cute face, Purin.
Fight
Item
Pokémon
Run
Purin
Hitokage
Move Type
/Fire
Growl
Ember
Scowl
Scratch
Growl
Ember
Scowl
Growl
Ember
Scowl
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Ember!
Purin
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Ember!
Purin
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Ember!
Purin
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Ember!
Purin
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Ember!
The enemy Purin fainted!
Phew.
That Miniskirt on the mountain trail
is one fierce girl...
Hitokage
...Oh?! Something's
happening to Hitokage...!
Huh?! No way!
...Oh?! Something's
happening to Hitokage...!
It’s evolving!
Ooh! Lizard!
Okay then, once everyone’s here
we’ll be leaving.
Right, sounds good.
I just sent over the files for
the ad going in the Tozai Line cars.
Yes. Huh?
There are a lot of different jobs
at an ad agency.
Understood.
In a nutshell, we take requests from companies
and shops selling goods and services,
and think up how to promote them.
Sales
The sales team receives jobs.
Designer
Planner
The planners come up with plans.
And the designer brings them to life.
Oh, hello, is this Kamo-chan?
Oh! You’re downstairs already?
Hahaho-kay!
Huh? He’s already here?
Yeah!
That was fast...
We have a visitor?
Yes, Kamo Oshou-san,
who’s doing the slogan for the next poster.
Huh...?
Kamo Oshou...
You mean...
Growing words. The book on moving slogans
Kamo Oshou
That big-shot?!
Nice to see ya!
Ta-daah!
Water-Blessed
This is Niigata’s new brand of rice.
“Water-Blessed”...
Quite a stylish design, ain’t it?
Kamo Oshou
Leading Slogan Writer
Height
Weight
Coming up with advertising
catchphrases is his specialty.
Very particular and hard to
please.
It has large grains,
and they taste great!
Take fluffy white rice, top it with
miso-pickled aubergine, and mmm!
Pretty good, right?
Okay, Akagi-kun will
give you all the details.
Sure.
Treat us kindly, Kamo-chan!
Okay, Yado-chan!
Um...
Let me reintroduce myself.
My name is Akagi, I’m a planner.
Please treat us kindly.
Oh, you’re...
Yes.
Well then,
I’ll begin with the explanation.
Um... This new rice brand, “Water-Blessed,” was grown
with the spring water flowing from Mt. Tsukimi—
Oh, okay, okay.
I got the gist, so I’ll be off.
Oh, um, I still have yet to explain—
I’ll read it over!
How long d’ya think I’ve been doin’ this?
Send the rice to my office!
Yado-chan, see ya!
Good work!
Please treat us kindly!
Stuff Your Pocket With Adventure
Ooh... The great scenery of Mt. Tsukimi...
What a great photo!
Water-Blessed
Niigata Rice
A new rice grown in Niigata
Water-Blessed
Yeah.
So, where’s that all-important slogan?
Episode 2  "It Won't Obey!"
It’s not here yet.
He must be taking his time
to come up with a masterful slogan.
You think?
Ah, look, here it is.
“Is this rice?”...
Is this rice?
Um...
This is rice... Right?
Yeah.
No, hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Maybe it’s not a question...
It’s the slogan.
The slogan?
Oh, the slogan arrived?
Well, it arrived, I guess... Probably?
It’s just this odd phrase...
Hmm.
Then why don’t you visit
Kamo-san’s office?
Slogan writer Kamo Oshou's home and office
If you could stand by
in that waiting room for now.
Right.
Sorry, I need to use the bathroom quick...
Sure.
I wonder if Koide-kun’s okay.
Yeah.
He has a sensitive stomach.
How far are you in Pokémon?
Huh? How do you know that I...?
Well... You blurted out “Iwark” before...
Using Scratch
on Iwark won’t get me anywhere...
Iwark?
Also, the driver saw you playing it.
Oh...
Yes, I am.
For the first time in ages.
Hmm.
The new one?
The original.
The original?
It was in a package from home.
Hmm...
So? How far are you?
Are you a fan?
No.
That so?
Yeah.
I’m at Hanada Gym now.
Hmm.
Fire is so bad there.
I can never beat Starmie.
Hmm.
And if I lose, I get my money taken.
Right.
So I write a Report before the battle,
and if I lose, I turn it off right away.
Whoa, how sneaky...
What, you didn’t do that?
Well. I did.
How sneaky...
Nah, nah...
Oh... Maybe I should
leave the Gym for later,
and just move on and
catch some stronger Pokémon.
How...
...sneaky.
Sorry, I have to go again...
Sensei, I’ve brought them through.
Oh, thank you. Sit.
Excuse me.
He’s an hour and a half late...
Firstly, thank you for sending over
an idea for the slogan.
Right.
And so we’re here today,
as we felt it required
a little more explanation...
Whuh?
You think?
I feel like it should get
everything across.
Hmph!
Uh... By combining
a beautiful photo of Mt. Tsukimi...
...with a slogan from the peerless
hit-maker Kamo Oshou-san,
we hoped to convey the appeal... of the richness...
and sweetness... that the... client dedicated...
Sensei.
Oh. The natural, sweetness.
Right. We were wondering if
this slogan truly described that...
You were?
Every single word...
...expresses that, doesn’t it?
Uh, um...
I see. While it’s very innovative,
and wonderful,
I fear some people may find it
hard to understand.
It may be hard to understand?
Can you tell apart
different types of rice?
Ugh, it’s time for
my next appointment. I gotta go.
Oh, um, then, lastly,
would you take a look at this?
Um... I came up with this as a draft.
A slogan?
Whuh?!
Huh?
Is the meeting over already?
I guess you should never
show a slogan to a slogan writer.
I feel like that is kinda taboo.
My, loitering around again?
Midori? Why are you here?
I’m having a meeting
over dinner with Kamo-san.
I brought him a big job
involving the government,
so he got super motivated to do it.
Oh? Well, Kamo-san just wrote us
a gem of a slogan!
A gem?
A gem!
Well, we’re paying him a lot more,
so don’t take him ignoring you too personally!
Oh, Sensei! Good work!
The taxi’s waiting for you.
Right.
Friends really get along well, huh?
Quiet.
Café and Snacks
Kamonegi
OT/TRAINER
Please take good care
of Kamonegi.
Madoka traded Onisuzume
for Kamonegi!
I just don’t get it!
It doesn’t make sense!
Ads are made to be understood!
Anger sparks motivation.
Here. Masako’s Whimsical Nasi Goreng.
Whoa! Thank you for the meal.
It’s just, he’s called a master,
he doesn’t keep to deadlines,
and he’s just given us
“ko, re, wa, o, kome, ka, question mark”...
Only seven characters!
Well, doesn’t that sound like
he’s taking you for a fool?
Huh? Surely not...
Is that the original?
Maybe there’s hope for you after all.
Huh? Um, what?
Sorry, he can be cheeky.
Masako's son   Karasawa Sora
That’s my son, Sora.
Go on, say hello to her.
I’ve played all of them.
Red/Green, Gold/Silver, Ruby/Sapphire,
D/P, B/W, X/Y,
Sun/Moon, Sword/Shield,
and this is Scarlet/Violet!
Right.
You really like those.
Ah—
Wanna see?
Yeah.
Huh? This is Pokémon?!
Is that what it’s like now?
Yeah. Open world’s default now.
What?
Huh? You can see the wild Pokémon.
Can you just avoid them?
Yeah.
And I won.
The latest game’s amazing...
Huh?
Biriridama
Kamonegi
It attacked itself
in its confusion!
Huh? What’s wrong, Kamonegi?
Oshou fainted!
Pokémon you get from other people
won’t obey you if you don’t have the badges.
Badges?
The ones from beating Gym Leaders?
Hanada for 30,
Hanada Gym
Up to level 30
Tamamushi for 50,
Tamamushi Gym
Up to level 50
and beat Yamabuki for the Gold Badge, and up to Level 70 will listen to you.
Yamabuki Gym
Up to level 70
Oh... So it’s because
I didn’t beat Hanada Gym.
Oh, and as well as not obeying,
they can slack off, fall asleep,
or pretend not to notice too.
Huh?
That sounds familiar.
Biriridama
Kamonegi
Oshou pretended
not to notice.
Hmph!
Kamo Oshou pretended not to notice!
Kamo Oshou began to nap!
Oh, okay, okay.
Kamo Oshou slacked off!
Well, going ahead without getting
the badge is itself slacking off, you know?
You’re harsh, Sora-kun.
When I used to work in Ginza,
it took quite some time
for the girls to accept me.
I wonder what Badge
I needed back then.
If I want Kamo-san to accept me...
I need rice?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey...
Why not just give up?
Huh? You want some, Hiyama-kun?
I have “Dragon’s Tears,”
“Tosa Girl,” and “Sparkling Star.”
Leave me out. I don’t even want to
understand what a big-headed big-shot thinks.
Huh? But we’ve got such a great photo...
I wanna pair it up with
a peerless slogan from Kamo-san.
I want to get it out of him, by my stubbornness
as a planner... or my pride as a creative...
Dang, I am really fired up!
Sheesh...
Well then, give it
all you’ve got, Ms. Creative.
Huh?
Hmph...
He’s not very kind.
“It has a unique natural rich sweetness
and a sticky, springy texture.“
I give thanks for this meal.
It tastes good!
Is this sweet?
It might be different.
Something is different...
It tastes so good,
but I’m full!
I’m full, but it tastes so good...
Back to “Water-Blessed.”
I give thanks for this meal.
The natural,
rich sweetness!
Thank you for the delicious meal.
The Blue Badge?
Grown with the Delicious Water
of Mt. O-Tsukimi
Sensei, I’ve brought them through.
Now, the battle begins.
Kamo Oshou
appeared!
Come all you wish.
I won’t change that slogan...
Never!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou's
Rebuke!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou's
Rebuke!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou's
Rebuke!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou's
Rebuke!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou's
Rebuke!
In that case,
we’ll just proceed with it as is...
“Is this rice?”
Through that slogan, you tried to convey the richness
and sweetness imbued to it by the brilliance of nature,
which go beyond
the expected tastes of rice.
Isn’t that right?
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka attacks
head-on!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka attacks
head-on!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka attacks
head-on!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka attacks
head-on!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka attacks
head-on!
Whuh?
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Kamo Oshou started to
take interest!
“Water-Blessed” is grown
with the soft water flowing from Mt. Tsukimi,
making the grains fluff up
standing on end when cooked,
and overflow with
richness and sweetness.
I’d never really paid attention
to the varieties of rice,
so I was surprised to learn
rice could taste so different.
I feel like I now
better understand... the soul...
...you put into that slogan...
I apologize for not even
trying to understand it.
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka's
Sincerity!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka's
Sincerity
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka's
Sincerity!
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka's
Sincerity
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
Madoka's
Sincerity!
What dish ended up tasting best...
...with “Water-Blessed”?
After some reflection...
It was miso-zuke.
I guess you have learned something.
But if it takes that much effort
to understand that slogan...
Maybe a rewrite is in order.
Huh?
How ‘bout I give it another go?
Kamo Oshou
Madoka
listened to you!
Thank you!
Here you go.
All right!
Thank you.
I quite like this one.
Oh, this one won’t work.
Huh? That one was pretty good...
If you describe it as sweet...
Madoka managed to tame the big-shot,
and open up his heart.
But there are still many more
strong allies to be found in this world.
Fill yourself with tasty rice,
and tomorrow’s another adventure, Madoka!
Koide: He came up with lots of ideas for rewrites!
Koide: "An enchanting journey with every bite"
Koide: "Rice is why I head home"
Koide: "The search for its match begins"
Koide: "Super Rice"
You took your time...
I see... So your name
is Kageaki!
Ah! A wild Caterpie
jumped out!
Caterpie...
A blank white space for all your loves to shine
And as you scrawl them down, time goes by
Spun by society, press New Game... It’s a new start, an adventure
But still... No doing this, no doing that
Here it’s... No straying, no veering away
Here it’s... No faltering, no tossing away
But your loves... Still there to love, you still love them
Let your true self bloom
Blank white, blank white, head to the unknown
To mountains, to seas, taking your quirks along
Stuff them in your pocket and bring them with you
Blank white, blank white, to a future you can love
To a town where you can watch the moon and stars
Break out of your fate line, someday you’ll reach beyond the ring road
The highs and lows will keep coming, round and round you’ll go
Next Episode
This time, Koide-kun...
Koide-kun?!
Flopping around with all his strength,
yet nothing ever happens.
Guardie
Koiking
Koiking's
Flop attack!
But nothing happened.
He’s a Koiking!
The selfish actress.
Shoot my face from my right side.
Bang-and-boom!
What do you mean?
Please, do something!
Don’t you ever hope to change?!
This drama is a work of fiction, and the depicted people and organization names are fictional.
Sale and support has concluded for Pocket Monsters Red / Green. Some depicted controls
and game screens using the Game Boy series and Nintendo Switch are dramatized.
Oh, it’s okay.