Life is always an adventure
My adventure begins now.
Madoka, did you get everything?
Yes. I’ll be fine.
Right.
All kids leave home some day.
Akagi Madoka
Bye, then. I’ll be off.
This is Akagi Madoka, 28 years old.
She grew up in Mashiro Town,
a port town in the Kanto Region.
She graduated from a local university,
and worked for
a local kamaboko company, but...
...she has aspired to become a creator
since her student days.
This spring, she found a new job
at a small ad agency in Tokyo...
This is Masara Town.
Masara, the pure white
blank of the beginning.
Mashiro Town
Madoka!
Your very own story
is finally about to begin!
A world of dreams
and adventures awaits! Let’s go!
Stuff Your Pocket With Adventure
Episode 1  "It's Super Effective!"
Good morning!
Morning.
Huh? You want to change it? Now?
No, it’s just so far along...
What I’ve learned in
my two months working here...
Sales   Kogusuri Kazuchika
Mr. Kogusuri the salesman...
I understand.
I’ll make it work somehow.
He’s too nice,
and easily persuaded by others.
Um... Mr. Kogusuri.
Yeah.
I drew up the schedule.
Oh!
Koide, the youngest here.
This schedule says it’s for 2013.
Yes.
Planner   Koide Yuuki
No, don’t just say yes.
That’s ten years ago.
He fills me with worries.
How about something you can handle?
Can you tidy up the office?
Yes.
All right! I matched up
with a well-off gentleman!
Designer   Meguro Youko
Ms. Meguro the designer
spends her life in dating apps.
Hiyama the salesman is my age.
Oh, Mr. Yadoya, do you mind
if I fall behind on that last job?
Sales   Hiyama Kageaki
Something about him creeps me out.
I completely forgot!
Hermit crab snacks
President   Yadoya Kouichi
What do I do?!
Our president, Mr. Yadoya,
has a few screws loose.
And the biggest thing I’ve learned...
Sorry!
The creator life I dreamed of...
...had none of the charm I imagined.
I forgot the most
important thing of all!
What is it now?
Prez!
The SAIjirushi job...
...was going to be
a pitch competition.
Huh?!
SAIjirushi’s a huge client,
aren’t they?
That’s the thing. They have
a new president—the third one...
Our company’s advertising contract...
...will be decided through
a pitch competition.
Iwakura Takeshi
SAIjirushi's 3rd President
Height
Weight
The 3rd president of
a cookware manufacturer
founded 80 years ago.
A big spender that props up
ADventure's profits.
And... by the time I realized...
Don’t give me that
“By the time I realized”...
But if we lose this,
we’ll be in trouble...
Um... What’s a pitch competition?
Oh... “I’ve been dating you all this time,
Pitch competition:
Clients make agencies pit their plans
against each other to re-select an ad agency.
“but now I wanna see other girls too.”
Lose, and his attention?
Zero!
He wants the competition because
you don’t satisfy him, so you start with a handicap.
Meaning... It’s a company crisis?
So... Who’s doing the presentation?
Huh?
What do I do?!
If we lose this contract, we...
...might not be around next year...
Huh?
This might be our last year!
What’ll I do next year?!
President!
Let’s make it to next year!
Akagi...
Well, I accepted it...
But am I really
the right person for this?
New product!
The world’s fastest-boiling!
Electric Thermo Pot!
Search for products
Thermo Pots
Kettles
Rice Cookers
Hup.
Doing OK? How's work?
Your mom is OK
I sent you the things you left in
your room
Oh...
Mashiro Specialty
Kamaboko
She didn’t have to...
It’ll just get in the way.
Huh?
Akagi Madoka
The Game Boy... I still had it...
Whoa, Pokémon!
This takes me back!
We only had the one console,
and I only got to have a turn
when my big bro was done playing.
Huh?
There’s no batteries...
Um...
Not doing it.
Aren’t pitch competitions
exciting, like battles?
Perish the thought.
A new handler means a new world.
A new key figure?
That resets everything.
Don’t drag me into this.
You said you’d do it.
I want us to fight this together!
What sort of plan would be good?
The selling point’s the quick boil, right?
They’ll want that in there for sure.
Well, SAIjirushi does like
stuffing commercials full of product features.
Oh, by the way... Wonder Create is
one of the competing companies.
Wonder Create...
It’s over.
Well, better come up
with a flawless plan,
Ms. Planner.
Huh? Hey, wait,
help me out a little!
They ran away...
Why did he stop
liking our proposals?
Time for the convenience store.
Huh?
Why...?
No, I can’t.
There it is!
That’s it!
This opening scene...
It’s so nostalgic!
Look, Madoka!
There are 3 Pokémon
there, right?
Ho-ho!
There are Pokémon
inside the Monster Balls.
In my old age, I have only
3 Pokémon left,
but I'll give you one!
... Now then, choose!
“Now then, choose!”, he says...
Aw! Not fair! Gramps!
I want one too!
The biggest decision,
thrust upon you...
Well! Don't you fret,
Green!
I used to like being different from
my big bro, so I picked Fushigidane,
Green!
Have whichever you like too!
but its evolution wasn’t what I expected,
and I went crying to mom.
So this time...
Yeah.
I choose you!
Hitokage
Lizard Pokémon
Height
Weight
Born with a fire on its tail.
Its life ends when the fire
goes out.
Madoka received Hitokage
from Okido!
Poppo!
Nice to see you again.
Well then, if you’ll allow me...
Monster Ball
Back
Poppo
Monster Ball
Hitokage
Madoka used
a Monster Ball!
Hitokage
Poppo
Madoka used
a Monster Ball!
All right!
You caught Poppo!
I caught it!
Poppo
Tiny Bird Pokémon
Height
Weight
Does not like to fight.
It hides in tall grass,
catching small bugs
and other such prey.
Oh, Poppo...
You’re my first catch.
Can’t say how long
I’ll keep you for, though.
Tokiwa Forest... So nostalgic...
Madoka found
an Antidote!
Didn’t this place have Pikachu?
Hmm...
Aww... Li’l Pikachu...
I don’t mean you any harm,
so won’t you show yourself?
I haven’t worked on the plan at all...
“It’s Heartwarming Too!
SAIjirushi’s Electric Thermo Pot”...
Project Plan 1
It’s Heartwarming Too!
SAIjirushi’s Electric Thermo Pot
That’s your plan?
Yeah.
I thought I’d pun “water boiling”
and “heartwarming”—
water boiling: o-yu ga waku
heartwarming: kokoro ga waku
N-No, I get that.
By the way, why am I the only one
you roped into this?
Mr. Yadoya said
I’d need someone from sales.
The client’s president hates gags.
Stop complaining for once
and help me here, Hiyama.
I’m a salesman.
I didn’t want your job title.
I wanted all of us to—
Even if all of us helped, it’s hopeless.
Huh?
At this company?
Well... Well, you know...
Would you like to help?
Here, gum to wake you up. Take it.
Excuse me.
I can’t do anything to help.
They all ran away...
Café and Snacks
So picking Hitokage sends me
straight into hard mode, huh...?
It’s been so long, I forgot.
Oh, I lost.
Aww, Scratch can’t cut it...
Haven’t I seen you here before?
Yeah...
Um... This café is so calming,
I felt at home.
My name’s Akagi Madoka.
Owner of Rouge   Masako
I’m Masako of Rouge.
So, what brings young lady Madoka here
to play games all alone?
Hmm...
Escaping from reality.
Oh, how I envy those
who can get away.
Here you go.
Masako’s Whimsical Curry.
Ooh!
Enjoy.
Wow!
Thank you for the meal.
Tasty!
What meat is this?!
The ingredients are whimsical too.
Normal and Fire
are bad against Rock,
Rock
Normal
Fire
Weak
and instead I need Water or Grass.
Water
Grass
Strong
Ah... I’m starting to remember.
What’s all that?
Oh, Pokémon types.
Iwark
Hitokage
Hitokage's
Scratch attack!
It’s like “rock beats scissors,”
I guess?
It's not very effective.
You know, though...
People have them, too.
Types and compatibility.
Simply clashing heads
doesn’t always work, right?
Oh...
That’s very deep.
I used to be a proprietress in Ginza
before running this café,
and I dealt with
all types of customers.
This guy likes being praised.
But this guy, he prefers
not being flattered... and so on.
Hmm...
Types, huh...?
Morning.
You’re here early.
Whatcha looking at?
Just thinking that using Scratch
on Iwark won’t get me anywhere...
Iwark?
Huh?
Oh, it’s nothing.
The day of
the pitch competition
We have an appointment.
We’re ADventure.
We’ve been awaiting you.
Please—
Madoka?
Midori?
Kudou Midori
It’s been a while.
It has.
So you joined ADventure, Madoka!
Never thought you’d go into adverts.
Something wrong?
Don’t they have 6 employees?
A thirtieth the size of my company.
Your presentations must be so tough.
Well, we’re an elite few!
An elite few...
This world is teeming with
talented creators all over,
so you better learn quick.
Oh, by the way!
With our presentation...
...we just captured
President Iwakura’s heart.
See ya!
Huh?!
You know that Wonder Create woman?
We were in the same club back at home.
Hmm.
A friend!
A friend? Really, you’d say that?
Then, ADventure,
please begin your proposal.
Please treat us kindly.
Now, the battle begins.
Iwakura the 3rd
has challenged you
to a battle!
Well then, please allow me
to begin my presentation.
As a veteran manufacturer founded
80 years ago, in an intensifying market,
Cookware market movement
Financial Year 2021     Financial Year 2022
considering how you can appeal to consumers with your new product...
...is of the essence.
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Silent Pressure!
Madoka steels herself!
And so, this is the commercial plan
that we propose.
Project Plan 1
—A sigh of relief, SAIjirushi's Electric Thermo Pot—
Bedroom, a pained mother sick in bed
Peeking in from the next room worried,
an elementary-school age
brother and sister
Brother notices something
View over mother,
brother and sister rush back to the next room
Mother hears noises from the next room
and wonders about them
Mother: Mmph...
Sister: Mom... Are you okay?
Brother: ...I know!
Sister: Ah! Big Bro!
Project Plan 1
Brother and sister pouring water from the electric
thermo pot, seeming to prepare something.
Mother arrives from the next room and watches
Hot soup and SAIjirushi Electric Thermo Pot
atop the table
View over table,
standing brother and sister call to mother
Mother with relieved expression
that turns into a smile
View past SAIjirushi
Electric Thermo Pot and soup,
warmly embracing family.
Mother pats the children
on their heads
Sister: Almost done? Almost done?
Brother: Done!
Sister: Done!
Brother: Mom!
Sister: Mom! All done!
Narrator: Safer appliances for everyone.
What is this?
It looks like
the product is barely in it.
Yes.
Our plan depicts children boiling water in a thermo pot
to make soup for their mother, who is sick in bed.
If that’s all... how do you plan on showing off
our new product’s quick boiling feature?
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Furrowed Brow!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Furrowed Brow!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Furrowed Brow!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Furrowed Brow!
Iwakura
Madoka
Iwakura's
Furrowed Brow!
Are you sure about this plan?
Isn’t this subverting guidance?
I read through every interview
with the third president I could find,
Subverting guidance:
To propose something contrary
to the client's job request.
and he always brings up
the teachings of his grandfather.
Passing Down the Feelings of his Ancestor, the Founder
“SAIjirushi’s business ideals are rooted in the feelings of its founder, my grandfather.”
The second president insisted on
performance above all.
The 3rd President Everyone is Talking About
The Secrets of SAIjirushi’s President
Inheriting the Founder’s Principles, and Aiming for the Future...
But the third president...
He might be wanting to go back to basics.
When my ancestor was young,
he once boiled water in a pan
and burned himself...
...which led him to make electric thermo pots
that anyone could use safely.
Yes. While features and
performance are important,
we thought the scenes
that the product can create...
...are even more valuable
than the product.
I see.
As president, I hope to value
the spirit of SAIjirushi my ancestor treasured.
Iwakura
Madoka
Fight
Item
Friend
Run
Madoka's
Ancestral Feelings!
Iwakura
Madoka
Madoka's
Ancestral Feelings!
Iwakura
Madoka
Madoka's
Ancestral Feelings!
Iwakura
Madoka
Madoka's
Ancestral Feelings!
Iwakura
Madoka
Madoka's
Ancestral Feelings!
It's super effective!
It’s super effective!
Thank you for
the marvelous presentation.
Thank you very much.
Iwakura
Madoka
You defeated
Iwakura the 3rd!
Congratulations
on your winning pitch!
Or I should say,
thank you so much!
How long’s it been since
we’ve won a pitch competition?
Isn’t it, what, three years?
Miracles really can happen!
Ahem. Koide?
Oh! Sorry!
Right, right, well, well...
Well, I’d call it a last-ditch defense
more than a win...
So modest.
Hey! It may have worked this time,
but please, give me a break with the wild ideas.
Shouldn’t you open with some praise?
No, I’ve got no praise for you.
What’s this?
You two might make good partners.
We are not partners!
Besides, Hiyama,
you need to be more fired-up.
I am fired up, though!
There’s no fire in you!
There is!
No, I would agree...
Right?
There is, though!
Madoka’s exploits have saved
the small company from its crisis.
But her adventure has only just begun.
What Pokémon...
No, what allies will she meet next?!
Mashiro Town
Rules of the Sea
- Making fires on the beach is prohibited.
- Poisonous jellyfish live here. Take care not to touch them.
- Take your trash when you leave.
Pick up the trash, let's all protect this pure white town
A blank white space to fill with all you love
And as you scrawl them down, time goes by
Whirled by society, New Game, it’s a new start, an adventure
But still... Don’t do this, don’t do that
Here it’s... Don’t bring this, don’t miss that
Here it’s... Don’t touch this, don’t toss that
And your loves... Still there to love, you still love them
Let your true self bloom
Blank white, blank white, head to the unknown
To mountains, to seas, taking your quirks along
Stuff them in your pocket and bring them with you
Blank white, blank white, tread beyond your likes
To the next town, the city you desire
Break out of your fate line, someday you’ll reach the heart line
The highs and lows will keep coming, on and on they come
Next Episode
It’s evolving!
Is that the original?
The original?
What, you like it?
A super big shot...
Oh, okay, okay. I got the gist.
Well, doesn’t that mean
you’re being taken for a fool?
Kamonegi
OT/TRAINER
That’s a big hurdle.
Whoa! Now I’m really fired up!
This drama is a work of fiction, and the depicted people and organization names are fictional.
Sale and support has concluded for Pocket Monsters Red / Green. Some depicted controls
and game screens using the Game Boy series and Nintendo Switch are dramatized.
My adventure begins now.