Yes, you have reached
the Paldea Post Office.
Are you calling to
ask about a delivery?
Feel free to ask anything.
Bring your refrigerated parcels for
the Alola and Isshu Regions to this counter!
Thank you.
Attention all mail carriers.
Delivery-related bulletins to follow:
For deliveries to Mt. Nappé today,
snowfall has been forecast,
so please review the precautions
for delivering in snow.
In addition, an outbreak of Watakko
is currently occurring in South Area 6.
Please watch out for Cotton Spores
when passing through for deliveries.
To repeat...
For deliveries to Mt. Nappé today,
snowfall has been forecast...
Welcome back, Kairyu!
That was fast!
That’s our ace mail carrier for you!
Oh... Kairyu really is
just as cool as I thought...
I wanna be an ace
mail carrier too, someday!
Mmm...
Hana-chan.
Are you getting
used to sorting letters?
Postmaster!
I wanted to do letter deliveries too,
not just boring work like this...
This, too, is an important step
towards becoming an ace mail carrier.
It’s a rare chance
to experience a workplace,
so be sure you and Hogator learn all you can
to bolster your future prospects, hmm?
What’s that?
A gift of fluff?
There’s neither a recipient
nor a sender.
Now, how are we ever
supposed to deliver this...?
Ooh! Ooh! Please leave it to me!
It must’ve just completely
slipped their mind to write the recipient!
I’ll go and find the sender!
That fed up of sorting letters, are we?
Er...
Th-This, too, is an important step
towards becoming an ace mail carrier!
Huh?
Let’s go, Hogator!
Oh, sorry!
Hana-chan?
Hey!
Be back before it gets dark!
Okay!
Now then...
The sender has to be
somewhere in town!
I’m gonna find them for sure!
Um, excuse me!
This...
...unaddressed...
...letter full of yellow fluff...
Do you have any idea...
...who sent it?!
No...
Give that back!
Sorry!
Haven’t the foggiest.
Ugh...
I can’t find them anywhere...
At this rate, the sun’s gonna set
before I find them.
Maybe it was hopeless to start with.
Was this really what I wanted to do...?
What I really wanted to do was...
Hey, hold on!
That tickles!
Stop that!
Wanpachi!
Mom, help me!
Hana-chan?
Miss?!
Why are you sleeping out here?
Um... I was looking for
someone who sent a letter...
...with yellow fluff in it,
just like this...
Did you send the fluff?!
Ah! That’s my letter!
Huh?!
Rio, you sent a letter
all by yourself?
Yeah.
But we can’t deliver this
without the recipient.
I’m sorry.
I wrote a birthday letter to Pop,
but I didn’t know what to do...
It’s not too late to fix that.
Where are you sending it?
Right now, Pop is on a work assignment
overseas, in the Kanto Region.
The Kanto Region, huh?
Well then, it’ll go by standard mail,
so it’ll arrive next week.
Huh?! Next week?!
What’s wrong?
Well... Pop’s birthday is today.
Oh...
Can’t you deliver it today?
I-I’m just a plain old letter sorter,
I can’t really...
It’s a bit much to ask,
this late and all...
How about we call up Pop later?
Would that be all right?
Kairyu!
Please!
Deliver this boy’s letter to his pop!
Even if I can’t make it in time,
I know you can, Kairyu!
Please!
Huh?
Thank you, Kairyu!
Get on!
Let’s go deliver your letter
to your dad!
Rio... Bring him enough birthday cheer
for the both of us, okay?
Hana-chan! Look after Rio!
I’ll tell the post office!
Thank you so much!
So fast! So fast! It’s so fast!
Rain?
Why so suddenly...?
Awesome!
Hana-chan, did you see that?!
That was unreal!
I’ve never seen anything like that!
Rio... You finally smiled.
Hearing a beautiful sound brought back the memories
All the things that you told to me
I love to talk with you, but...
But, still, somehow
Maybe I feel a bit more open when writing
Fly out into the blue, blue sky
Go and see what it’s like
You once told me, that “words are wings”
If I, in the blue, blue sea,
could be that crystal clear light
that wraps around the world, then... then...!
The horizon looked like amber to me
It’s true...
I’ll tell you exactly how I feel
Rio...
You’ll get to see your pop very soon!
This welling of emotions
Hana-chan...
Do you think Pop’ll even like it?
Getting something like a letter
as a birthday present...
that can’t be fashioned into words
He’s gonna be really happy.
Letters are strange things.
They can make your feelings
many times stronger.
I filled the page to the brim with them
I’m sure it’ll be okay.
Look, we can see it now!
Whoops...
Chief...
Do you have a moment?
Oh... What is it?
The chief’s coming...
Get ready!
Happy...
...birthday!
Are you okay, Kairyu?
Rio... How?!
Why is there a Kairyu here?!
Is that the chief’s son?
That outfit...
Are they mail carriers?
Ri—
“Dear Pop!
“How are you doing?
This is Rio.
“Me, Mom, and Wanpachi are doing well.
“Thank you, for always
doing so much for us, at your job”...
“Hana,
“how are you doing?
“Grandma and Grandpa
are so busy with work this year...
“...that we can’t celebrate your birthday
with you in person. We’re sorry.
“But,
“no matter where we are,
you are always what’s most important to us.
“We hope you like your present.”
“I’ll put in some of
Wanpachi’s fluff as a present.”
“Hana...
“Pop...
“Happy...
“...birthday!”
Rio!
Congrats!
Rio-kun!
Thank you, all of you!
Good morning!
Morning!
Thanks as always, Kairiky.
Here you go!
An important delivery just for you!
Kairyu and the Mail Carrier