(Pokémon GET da ze!)
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka ano ko no sukaato no naka (kyaah!!)
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt (Kyaah!!)
nakanaka nakanaka nakanaka nakanaka taihen dakedo
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
kanarazu GET da ze!
but I’m gonna get them all!
Pokémon GET da ze!
I’m gonna get Pokémon!
masara taun ni sayonara bai bai
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
ore wa koitsu to tabi ni deru (Pikachu!)
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
kitaeta waza de kachimakuri
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
nakama o fuyashite tsugi no machi e (matteru)
then head to the next town and make friends along the way! (We’re waiting!)
itsumo itsu demo umaku yuku nante
There’s no way to know for sure
hoshou wa doko ni mo nai kedo (sorya sou ja!)
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
itsu demo itsumo honki de ikiteru
But with my companions by my side,
koitsu tachi ga iru
we’ll live life to the fullest!
aa akogare no Pokémon masutaa ni
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
naritai na naranakucha
I wanna be one! Gotta be one!
zettai natte yaru!
Will be one!
I long… I long…
How I long to see you…
Here goes, here goes...
The Ghost Pokémon
and the Summer Festival
Any ship at sea
is heading for a port.
Having left Aopulco behind,
our heroes aim for Yamabuki City, and now find themselves at…
I can see the port!
All right! We’re almost at our stop,
Maiden’s Peak!
Is it just me, or does
even the sea breeze feel like Fall?
Another Summer where
nothing happened…
What are you talking about?
Loads of stuff happened.
Summer for children means time to swim.
For grown-ups, it’s a season of love…
But not for me.
Summer… Swimsuits…
Ladies!
The seaside season is
coming to an end!
Why do we gotta…
…travel like this?
No budget. But it doesn’t matter.
The ocean’s the same,
no matter how you cross it.
The ferry from Aopulco Island
has stopped at the Maiden’s Peak port.
Maiden’s Peak is currently holding
its Summer Festival.
Wow, a festival?
Sounds fun!
Let’s take a look!
The festival of love
is done and gone...
Who’s that?
So beautiful!
What? She’s gone…
Cheer up! It’s a festival!
That’s right! A festival!
A festival, they say…
A festival means a lot of people.
They might have
dropped some money.
Well, dropped or not,
it will be ours!
A coin for a cat!
And for us evildoers…
Such beauty!
Stay focused!
It’s time to make some money!
Come on, let’s go to the festival!
Festival, meow!
What?
She was so beautiful…
Hold it!
Yes, what is…
A dried-up kappa?!
Who are you calling dried-up?!
You should beware, however…
Not of dried-up kappas, but of a beautiful maiden.
Or else, you will face misfortune.
A beautiful maiden…
You mean her?!
Oh, come on…
I’d never bring misfortune to Takeshi.
I said a beautiful maiden.
I didn’t say a bratty little girl!
Bratty little girl?!
Yup, such a brat!
You’re one to talk, brat boy!
Come on, you two! We’re leaving!
A beautiful woman… Misfortune…
I’d be fine with it if it were her…
Nothing! Not a single coin
dropped anywhere!
No 100 yen coins, 10 yen coins
or even 1 yen coins!
What a stingy festival, meow!
Agh! Look harder, meow!
Oh, a five yen coin!
Hold it!
Oh, you were watching?
Indeed… Foul things are
most clear to me.
You ought to exercise great caution.
Of what, patrols? Police?
Firefighters?
No.
What you must be wary of is a maiden,
or else you will face great misfortune.
That’s nothing new...
Women always cause me
no end of trouble.
What woman, exactly?
What seems to be the problem?
When in trouble, dial 110!
We make house calls, too!
Oh, you found a dropped coin?
We appreciate any found money,
even if it is just five yen.
It’s so admirable of you
to give it straight to the police!
We need to fill out some forms,
so come with me to the police office.
Police office?
Oh, no, we leave that to you!
Please, do whatever you see fit!
Don’t let us get in the way!
Bye bye, now!
Behold! Behold the treasure
of Maiden’s Shrine!
This painting is a treasure that has been kept in
the Maiden’s Shrine for two thousand years,
and which is only shown to the public once a year,
on the Summer Festival!
Watch it closely while you can!
That’s…
Oh myeow!
It’s her?!
H-How?!
How can you be so beautiful?
Indeed! Oh, how wonderful.
I’m so moved…
Hold it!
This maiden has been dead
for two thousand years!
Two thousand years?
The maiden had a lover,
but he sailed off
to fight in a war.
I will wait…
I will wait for you forever…
And wait she did.
She waited, and waited, and waited…
Yet the man never returned.
Even so, she continued waiting...
...until at last, she turned to stone,
and she still waits to this day.
It is a legend from
two thousand years past.
Where is that rock right now?
You don’t know of
the Maiden’s Rock?
So that’s the Maiden’s Rock…
Oh, what a beautiful rock!
So beautiful!
My heart is racing!
If that were a Pokémon,
I would cherish it until death do us part!
I would not let anyone
steal it from me!
Not even Team Rocket itself!
We could never steal
anything that big!
But we can steal
the other thing, meow!
Other thing?
Pokémon are gold.
So are treasures.
And so is that painting!
I get it! That painting
would sell for a ton!
Steal it if you want,
but don’t drop me!
Oh, you’re hopeless…
What an awful feeling!
Nothing short of death
will kill those two, meow…
You know, that rock isn’t
going to stop being a rock…
Let’s go to the festival
and have some fun.
You go without me.
I want to stay here a little longer.
Do you know where we’re staying?
The Pokémon Center at the port, right?
I’ll be back before closing time.
Don’t worry. I’m an adult.
It’s 11 o’ clock!
Closing time, po!
So it’s closing time…
Where’s Takeshi?
I’ll go look.
Hold it!
It’s time for kids to go to bed!
But…
I’m the one in charge here!
Staying up late is bad for the skin,
and just as bad for kids! I won’t allow it!
Now go back to your room!
It’s time, meow… Hey, it’s time for work,
so wake up, meow!
Chopped pork...
Oh, how beautiful…
I so long to see you…
What?
Who are you, meow?
I have longed…
I have so longed to see you.
Hmm? Who’s there?
It’s you…
It is, isn’t it?
Two thousand years, huh…?
I waited.
I waited so long for you.
It’s you! It really is you!
Takeshi!
Where’d you go?!
Kojiro! Kojiro!
If you’re not here,
then answer us!
Yeah, meow!
Takeshi!
It’s you!
Who’s this?
Ghos!
Ghos
It’s you!
Today, we’ll finally
settle the score!
No, never mind.
You’re not who
I want to see right now.
You guys are looking
for someone, too?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”…
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
It feels wrong to
do this alone, though…
To protect the world from devastation.
Rose!
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains…
M-Musashi…
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy…?
Like a white hole…
A white tomorrow awaits us!
We found Kojiro!
What?!
I’m here too.
We found Takeshi, too!
Pull yourself together, Takeshi!
What happened to you?!
It is just as I feared.
Old lady!
The two were possessed
by the maiden’s ghost!
The maiden’s ghost?
I long to see you…
Well, this isn’t good.
Pikachu!
Who am I? Oh, yes,
I am Takeshi.
He’s back!
I am Kojiro of Team Rocket.
He may be back…
But he’s still a mess, meow.
Every year around this time,
male travelers get attacked.
They then have their very essence
sucked out of them,
and are found in this hall
in a mummy-like state.
It is the work of the ghost of the maiden
who died waiting for her lover!
But if I could be with her…
He’s not back at all…
Scary! Scary! It’s so scary!
There is a way to avert this.
Namely, these!
Tags to ward off evil!
However…
However?
I can’t give them to you
free of charge!
Well, if this is the only way…
Then we’ll hang ’em up,
hang ’em up and then hang up some more!
Hey, will this really work?
Honestly?
Keep your mouth shut.
Will it come?
It will, meow.
But if it does…
Then from where?
There!
It’s you!
I have waited so long for you.
I feel as though
I’ve waited for you, too.
Scary! Scary! It’s so scary!
I have longed to meet you.
As have I.
Takeshi?!
Why?! I’ve got the tags on!
I knew it, meow!
You see, these tags…
Well…
”Well”, what?!
We got them for free.
We had her cut the price right down,
and throw in yours
for free with his.
Freebies?! You cheapskate!
Sorry!
Well even if they were freebies,  I don’t want to get
taken away as a freebie alongside that guy!
You really, really don’t?
We’ve been through
so much together!
I don’t want to go!
I really don’t want to go!
Don’t go!
Stop!
Everyone!
Oh, come on!
Nooooo!
Hey lady, don’t get
too ahead of yourself.
Don’t you hear him
yelling “Nooooo!”?
Musashi!
Don’t get the wrong idea.
As a woman, seeing other women
refuse to let men go makes my skin crawl!
When rejected, you accept that
luck was not on your side.
Cry, smile, and say
“See you tomorrow!”
That’s a woman’s pride!
What are you even
trying to say, meow?
I do not understand.
But you are a nuisance.
What’s that?
A Pokémon?
No Pokémon detected.
It’s not a Pokémon?!
Pokémon detected.
Ghos. Gas Pokémon.
This Pokémon is normally invisible.
Its specialty is Hypnosis.
Ghos? You’re a Pokémon?
Well, I suppose my cover is blown.
At times, I am a legendary maiden.
At other times, a mysterious fortuneteller.
They say there’s no such thing as ghosts.
But in reality...
Ghos is who I am, ghos!
Fight an enemy Pokémon
with your own Pokémon!
Pikachu!
Hypnosis affects Pokémon,
too, you know.
You are the Electric Mouse, yes?
Fight a mouse…
…with a mousetrap!
Then I’ll go, meow!
Distract a cat with
a coin or cat food…
Or a ball filled with catnip!
Purr, purr, meow…
Abo, attack!
Snakes are but snacks
for their natural enemy;
The mongoose!
Tag out!
Dogas, attack with Poison Gas.
Gas mask!
All right, Hitokage!
I choose you!
Fight fire with…
a fire extinguisher!
Now, what will you send out next?
Zenigame! Fushigidane!
Both of you go!
What a bother.
I’ll just make this easy.
Fushigidane’s evolved form, Fushigibana,
and Zenigame’s evolved form, Kamex!
Then throw in a fusion
for good measure!
What do you think?
I call it Fushigix!
It’s hopeless.
We don’t stand a chance!
Well then, how’s this?!
What’s that?
A crucifix!
And then garlic, a stake
and a hammer!
I’m not Dracula!
What’s wrong?
I may not be a vampire,
but the night is the time for ghosts!
Please don't forget the maiden’s ghost
before next Summer!
What was all that?
No idea…
It’s morning, meow!
The departed come to visit us
during the Obon season,
and they go back
onboard those lantern boats.
It’s an old folktale
here at this port.
Another Summer has passed.
Your legend will surely live on.
Thank you, my dear Ghos.
Oh, there’s no need to thank me. I simply try
to pass on legends that are about to be forgotten,
as my once-a-year part-time job.
I hope to see you again
next year.
I will stay here, waiting for the day
when he comes back to me… Forever…
I am a ghost Pokémon.
I might run into
your lover somewhere.
If I do, I will be sure to
tell him how you feel.
Yes… Thank you.
If only you were
two thousand years younger…
Maybe I’ll come here
next year, too.
(Heave-ho!)
(Come on!)
(Do-Do-Dogas Do-Do-Da-Do Sha!)
Drum! Drum! Drum!
Forget it all!
Keep on dancing!
(Do-Do-Dogas Do-Do-Da-Do Sha!)
The swirling whirlpool is a Nyorozon’s belly (Come on!)
The gas Pokémon Ghos, huh…
I’m ready!
It’s really, really, really, really tough,
What are you doing?
Let’s dance!
Come on, (All right!) do the rabbit dance
Oh… Sure.
You, too, Pikachu!
Poké-Poké-Poké-Pokémon Ondo
After Obon passes,
Fall is just around the corner.
On one, two and three, catch them, yeah, yeah!
But we’ll never fall out of love
with the world of Pokémon!
Dance, dance, be surprised (Utsubot!)
We keep on looking forward… Where does our future lie?!
Be surprised, surprised, and withdraw (Golbat!)
Oh, over there?
It lies over there,
does it? I see…
Yes, yes… Oh, wait for me!
nakama no kazu wa
How many friends?
sorya yappari zettai gatchiri
Well, I’d say, surely, that must be...
ooi hou ga ii!
The more the merrier!
gutaiteki ni wa
Specifically?
sorya hakkiri kikkari tappuri
Well, plenty, to be precise, exactly...
hyaku-go-juu-ichi
151 of them!
sukoshi yuuki ga
With a little courage
arya batchiri shikkari nikkori
Oh, great, perfect, with a smile...
nakama o getto!
I get a new friend!
dakedo mo tama nya
But yet sometimes
arya? ukkari sukkari gakkuri
Oh? Distracted, it vanished, dismayed...
nakama nigetto!
They get away instead!
kimitachi to no deai wa zenbu
I remember quite well
chanto oboeteru
Meeting each and every one of you
kizutsukeatta koto mo atta kedo
Though we have hurt each other at times
sore wa (e~to) wasureta
Those were (er...) I forget
mada-mada takusa~n
I know that there are
kanarazu dokoka~ ni
many more friends to meet
nakama wa iru hazu
somewhere out there
hyaku-go-juu-ichi no yorokobi
151 joys...
hyaku-go-juu-ichi no yume
151 dreams...
hyaku-go-juu-ichi no omoide
151 memories...
mezashite~ ganbaro!
Let’s seek out every one!
Next episode
A flock of Butterfree
crossing the sea!
The Butterfree are setting off
for their season of love.
My Butterfree is really happy about
having found himself a cute girlfriend, too!
But now Team Rocket’s
shown up again!
They’re catching her
and the others with a giant net!
All right…
Let’s do this, Butterfree!
We’re gonna save
everyone, together!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters:
Bye Bye, Butterfree
You guys all get Pokémon, too!
Next time
Bye Bye, Butterfree