Pokémon Trivia Quiz!
Let's put your Pokémon prowess to the test
with some tough questions!
Today's question is this!
Question
Which three Pokémon are convenient to have
when eating hot pot?
Which three Pokémon are
convenient to have when eating hot pot?
Hint
- Three in the same evolutionary line
- When making hot pot, you use a...?
Hint!
The three belong to
the same evolutionary line.
When making hot pot, you use a...?
All right, did you all get that?
The answer will be announced at the end of the broadcast!
We'll announce the answer at
the end of this broadcast, so don't miss it!
Now then, here's what
you've been waiting for!
Pokémon starts now!
The strange creatures of this planet,
Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short!
Now, the tale of young Satoshi
and his encounters,adventures and battles
with the Pokémon begins!
With resounding courage, burning enthusiasm
yuuki rinrin genki hatsuratsu
and brimming curiosity, we will live on!
kyoumi shinshin ikiyou yo
Someone was singing that
yume wa itsuka hontou ni naru tte
"Your dreams will someday come true"
dareka ga utatte ita kedo
Just like how buds will eventually blossom into flowers,
tsubomi ga itsuka hana hiraku you ni
dreams will eventually come true
yume wa kanau mono
It's a clash of Solar Beam
and Ice Beam!
Onigori!
Jukain!
Onigori and Jukain are both
unable to battle!
The Hoenn League Saiyu Tournament...
Satoshi is facing Tetsuya
to enter the top four,
but his first Pokémon, Onigori,
fell in a double knock-out against Jukain.
The first round came to a shocking end!
The Final Clash! The Path to Victory!!
Have a look!
This store will be your castle!
Castle? This shabby stand?
What do you want us to do here?
I know it doesn't look like much...
But you can modify it
any way you want!
So long!
Man, did I dream too big?
You've gotta be kidding me!
How is this making us "the lords of the castle"?!
I'm done!
Getting strong Pokémon
is far more lucrative!
That's right!
Sonansu!
Huh? Come to think of it,
Nyarth's gone.
Dirteng is quick!
It's dodging all of the
Fire type moves it's weak against!
When is that Nyarth in boots
going to come out, meow?
Dirteng's Mega Kick
makes contact!
If we could just
land a Flamethrower...!
Dirteng! Shadow Ball!
Cortoise, let's finish this
once and for all!
Flamethrower!
Dodge!
Don't let it get away!
The Flamethrower hits!
It's super effective!
Dirteng is unable to battle!
Cortoise wins!
Contestant Tetsuya
lost his second Pokémon!
Well done, Cortoise!
That Satoshi really made me nervous!
Tetsuya really is strong.
But now Satoshi's got
a one point lead.
They're still in the
first half of the battle.
He's gotta stay focused!
Go, Hariteyama!
Cortoise, I'm counting on you
for this one, too!
Go! Use Flamethrower!
Hariteyama! Use Arm Thrust!
Remarkable! Hariteyama is utterly unfazed by the Flamethrower!
It's pushing forward using Arm Thrust!
N-No way!
I don't believe it!
Hariteyama's really tough!
Is it immune to Flamethrower?!
No, that's not right.
Hariteyama has the ability Thick Fat.
Thick Fat?
What's that?
Hariteyama's body fat cuts the damage from Fire and Ice type moves in half.
Hariteyama! Use Brick Break!
Brick Break makes contact!
Its power is immense!
Cortoise is unable to battle!
Hariteyama wins!
S-So strong!
Now they're both
down to four Pokémon.
Counting on you, Heigani!
Contestant Satoshi's
third Pokémon is Heigani!
Heigani! Bubble Beam!
Dodge and use Brick Break!
Dodge!
Crabhammer!
Focus Punch!
Heigani is unable to battle!
Hariteyama wins!
A spectacular battle is
unfolding before our eyes,
but Contestant Satoshi has
lost three Pokémon,
so we will now be
going into an interval.
When will it enter the fray, meow?
Hey, Satoshi!
You beat me,
so you'd better not lose now!
Yeah, I know.
Pikachu, let's give it our all
in the second half of the fight!
So this is the storage room where
they keep all the contestants' Monster Balls.
I'm sure they're all strong,
usable Pokémon!
Well, then, let's just help ourselves.
The second half of the match
will be on a rocky battlefield!
Contestant Satoshi currently
has three Pokémon left.
His opponent, Contestant Tetsuya, has four.
All eyes are on the second half of their match!
And their first Pokémon out are...
Ohsubame! I choose you!
Go, Hariteyama!
Contestant Satoshi's fourth
Pokémon is Ohsubame!
Contestant Tetsuya continues battling with Hariteyama!
Ohsubame! Use Peck!
Peck is a Flying type move!
It'll be super effective if it hits!
Block it!
What?!
Amazing! Hariteyama charged straight into the Peck attack,
and completely stopped
Ohsubame from moving!
It can do that?!
It's far faster than you'd expect,
given its size!
Hariteyama! Use Seismic Toss!
Oh, what is this?
That attack seems to have ignited Ohsubame's fighting spirit!
Impressive! That's more like it!
Hariteyama! Focus Punch!
Ohsubame! Aerial Ace!
Aerial Ace makes a direct hit!
It's super effective!
Hariteyama is unable to battle!
Ohsubame wins!
Well done, Ohsubame!
Starting the second half with Ohsubame
was the right choice!
What do you mean?
If Ohsubame's fighting spirit syncs up with Satoshi's competitive spirit,
they should be able to turn
the tide of the battle!
I'm not sure it'll be that easy...
Ohsubame's pretty badly injured.
No problem! They can do this!
Go, Donphan!
Contestant Tetsuya's fourth
Pokémon is Donphan!
Donphan! Use Sandstorm!
Oh, no!
Donphan unleashes
a ferocious Sandstorm!
They can't see anything now, no?
His plan is to divide
Satoshi and Ohsubame!
Ohsubame! Flap your wings and blow the Sandstorm away!
Now! Rollout!
Ohsubame!
Donphan used the rocks as a jumping ramp
to land a Rollout!
All right! Another Rollout!
Donphan's Rollout hits
in rapid succession!
Rollout is a fearsome move
whose power increases every time it hits!
The next one will finish them!
Go, Donphan!
Ohsubame is collapsed on the ground
and can't move!
Is this it?!
Don't lose, Ohsubame!
Stop Donphan!
Unbelievable!
Ohsubame blocked Donphan's
Rollout with its legs!
What?!
Now, throw it!
Donphan is unable to battle!
Ohsubame wins!
With spirit and guts, Ohsubame snatched victory
from the jaws of defeat!
Well done, Ohsubame!
That's the spirit!
Did ya see that?!
He can get through it
with fightin' spirit!
You're right!
He might be able to win like this, no?
I didn't expect you to
get out of that one.
But I won't let you
have the win that easily.
Go, Metagross!
So, the Steel type
Metagross is up next.
Which means Ohsubame's
Flying type moves won't do much.
That ain't gonna matter one bit!
No matter how tough the enemy is,
men push through and win with spirit!
Masamune's as
passionate as ever, no?
Metagross! Psychic!
Psychic has Ohsubame trapped!
Get out of there!
Fly, Ohsubame!
But Ohsubame is unable to break free
from the chains of Psychic!
It's an immensely powerful move, which even restrains Ohsubame's tremendous guts!
Even Ohsubame's in big trouble
in a situation like this!
Ohsubame is unable to break free from the chains of Psychic!
Even Ohsubame's in big trouble
in a situation like this!
Ohsubame! Show them your guts
with a Quick Attack!
Ohsubame's Quick Attack was deflected,
and it ended up taking damage itself, instead!
Ohsubame!
How naïve of you! My Metagross boasts the ultimate defense!
Metagross! Hyper Beam!
A clean hit with Hyper Beam!
Ohsubame is unable to battle!
Metagross wins!
The gutsy Ohsubame
goes down at last!
Metagross is fearsome!
It gives no opportunity to strike back!
Is that...
Thanks, Ohsubame!
Thanks to you, I see a path
to take down Metagross!
Juptile, you're up next!
Contestant Satoshi's fifth
Pokémon is Juptile!
Grass type moves won't do much
against Metagross!
It's all gonna work out if he's
fightin' with spirit!
Go, Juptile!
Juptile draws near Metagross
with impressive speed!
Use Bullet Seed!
Keep it up! Bullet Seed combo!
Juptile does not let up its
Bullet Seed onslaught!
I get it. You're going to focus your fire on a single point, to let the damage build up?
Sorry, but that's not gonna work!
Metagross, charge in!
So fast!
Metagross! Hyper Beam!
Dodge!
Oh, no!
Bullet Seed!
Metagross is immobilized, and once again facing an assault of Bullet Seeds!
Tetsuya messed up the timing
of his Hyper Beam!
Yeah! After all, once you use that attack, you can't move for a bit afterwards!
Juptile continues its concentrated assault on a single point of Metagross's body!
Right! This'll end it!
Juptile! Leaf Blade!
Don't lose, Metagross!
Use Meteor Mash!
Metagross unleashes
a ferocious Meteor Mash!
Juptile!
Juptile is unable to battle!
Metagross wins!
Juptile put up a formidable fight,
but it is down!
Contestant Satoshi now
only has one Pokémon left!
Contestant Tetsuya
still has two left,
meaning he has Satoshi in check
when it comes to moving onto the semi-finals!
Now it's all on you.
Give it your all, Pikachu.
Contestant Satoshi's
final Pokémon is Pikachu!
Pikachu! Thunderbolt!
He goes right on the offense
with a Thunderbolt!
But Metagross is standing strong!
Metagross! Psychic!
Dodge and use Iron Tail!
Iron Tail makes a clean hit!
Now grab on to Metagross!
Not happening!
Metagross is twisting its body all it can, but it's unable to shake Pikachu off!
Now, Pikachu! Use Thunder!
Metagross!
A point-blank-range
Thunder explodes!
Metagross is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
Well done, Pikachu!
All right!
Now Tetsuya only has one left, too!
Don't celebrate just yet.
Huh?
Tetsuya's next Pokémon...
The one that hasn't battled yet is...
I'm counting on you, Nyarth!
There it is, meow!
Hang in there, meow!
The last battle is
Pikachu VS Nyarth!
Whoever wins this,
wins the match!
It's saying it'll go all-out for the sake of
the trainer who saved it, meow!
I'll go all-out in cheering
for you, too, meow!
Here!
Keep putting'em in the bag.
What do you think you're doing?!
B-Boss!
You ditched the restaurant I so generously gifted you,
and went off to steal from others?!
You've got some nerve!
Nyarth! Use Slash!
Dodge and use Thunderbolt!
We'll use Thunderbolt, too!
Two Thunderbolt attacks clash!
What's going on?
Even if it does hit Pikachu with Thunderbolt,
it won't be very effective...
That move isn't meant to attack.
Huh?
If that's how you wanna do it, then...
Pikachu! Use Thunder!
Thunderbolt!
The two fighters' electricity
clashes once more!
Their tremendous power
shakes the entire arena!
That Thunderbolt is
meant to block Pikachu's electricity.
You mean...
...that Pikachu's Electric moves are completely useless?
No way!
Amazing, meow!
I knew it'd be strong, meow!
Well, then, let's fight up close!
Pikachu! Quick Attack!
Double Team!
So cool, meow!
Now! Iron Tail!
We'll use Iron Tail, too!
Now we see a mighty clash
of Iron Tails!
This is so intense, meow!
Pikachu! Quick Attack!
Nyarth! Use your Slash attack!
Another fierce clash
between the two fighters!
Neither side is willing to yield
a single centimeter!
Go, Pikachu! Use Thunder!
Thunderbolt!
Another fierce collision
of Electric moves!
This is truly a worthy last battle!
Let's end this, Pikachu!
Use Iron Tail!
Nyarth! Use Iron Tail!
Wow! Both moves
made a direct hit!
Both fighters are down!
Pikachu, get up!
Get up, Nyarth!
Nyarth! Get up, meow!
You can't lose, meow!
They're up! Both Pokémon
stood up using sheer guts!
Will the last battle go on?
Can they still fight?!
No, meow!
Pikachu!
Pikachu is unable to battle!
Nyarth wins!
As such, the winner is
Contestant Tetsuya!
He did it! The one to advance to the semi-finals
after an intense battle...
With resounding courage, burning enthusiasm
...is Contestant Tetsuya!
and brimming curiosity, we will live on!
I'm so moved, meow!
That was a great battle, meow!
Are you all right, Pikachu?
Thank you, Pikachu.
You really gave it your all!
Thank you, Satoshi.
That was a fantastic battle!
I'm the one who should be
thanking you!
Thank you so much!
I ain't ever seen such a
great battle before!
I ain't even gonna care 'bout
who won anymore!
Masamune, I think you're
a bit too riled up, no?
But this is the same outcome
as in the Johto League...
Maybe. But look at their faces!
They lost the match,
but they're beaming!
I'm so glad, meow!
This is wonderful, meow!
Musashi! Kojiro!
Nyarth!
What are you doing here?
Hey!
Someone was singing that
You three!
"Your dreams will someday come true"
I picked you up, thinking perhaps
I could make you into some decent folks!
Just like how buds will eventually blossom into flowers,
But you spat on my face and committed evil...
You will pay for that!
dreams will eventually come true
What's so wrong with committing evil?!
We are the Rocket Gang!
In any case,
thank you for looking after us!
All right! I gotta make sure I won't lose
to that one, either, meow!
What an awful feeling!
Thank you very much!
The Hoenn League Saiyu Tournament,
which has excited us with many spectacular battles...
Glory Day, when you don't know the way...
...has finally come to an end.
Glory Day, just ask the wind
The winner is Contestant
Tetsuya from Kinsetsu City!
Glory Day, listen closely
So in the end, Tetsuya won...
and you'll hear a call: "Believe in myself!!"
I guess gourmet really does
have its own taste, no?
I don't think that has
anything to do with it...
But all the battles we've seen
were great, huh?
I'm starting to feel like battling, too,
for the first time in a while.
Friends rushing over, shouting "You did it!!",
Man, I really want to
become a trainer, already!
And then I'll participate in
the Pokémon League tournament!
are like shining diamonds
Satoshi!
I'm gonna win the
next tournament, ya hear?
Their shine will never fade,
No, I'll beat you then, too.
as long as I believe in them
Yeah, as if!
We'll have gotten way
stronger than we are now!
Glory Day, I'll take them all with me,
Well, then, we'll just get
way, way stronger!
Right, Pikachu?
and shine, on that glorious day!!
Thus, the curtain closes on the
Hoenn League Saiyu Tournament.
But the world of Pokémon
will go on and on!
Satoshi's journey of dreams and adventures with his friends will likewise continue!
GLORY DAY doshaburi no ame mo
Glory Day, the rain pouring down...
GLORY DAY tsuyoi kitakaze mo
Glory Day, and the strong Northern wind
GLORY DAY zenbu uketomete
Glory Day, accept it all
tsukisusume!! GLORY DAY
and move forth!! Glory Day
honki de butsukatta toki shika
We could never see it, except in the times
mienai keredo
when we faced each other head-on
kitto deau hazu sa
But I'm sure we can meet
koboreru yo na egao
an overflowing smile
"yatta ne!!" tte kakeyoru nakama wa
Friends rushing over, shouting "You did it!!",
kirameku daiya
are like shining diamonds
zettai kumoranai
Their shine will never fade,
shinjita nara minna o
as long as I believe in them
GLORY DAY mabushii taiyou mo
Glory Day, the blinding sun...
GLORY DAY nagareru kumo mo
Glory Day, the drifting clouds
GLORY DAY zenbu hikitsurete
Glory Day, I'll take them all with me,
tadoritsuku sa!! GLORY DAY
and reach that glorious day!!
Next episode
On my way back to Masara Town, I ran into Mr. Enishida.
It seems like Mr. Enishida is looking for challengers for the Battle Frontier.
There are trainers there who are strong enough to face the Elite Four...
I gotta do this!
I'll beat the Battle Frontier, for sure!
Next time, on
Pocket Monsters Advanced Generation:
Enishida and the Battle Frontier!
You guys get Pokémon, too!
Next time
Enishida and the Battle Frontier!
Pokémon Trivia Quiz
answer announcement!
This was the question for today.
Today's question
Which three Pokémon are convenient to have
when eating hot pot?
Did you all get it?
The answer was these Pokémon!
Answer: Nyoromo, Nyorozon and Nyorobon
Nyoromo, Nyorozo and Nyorobon! Why?
Because they're all the "Otama Pokémon"!
All three are the "Otama Pokémon"
Tadpole/Ladle
Making hot pot is no problem if you have a ladle!
Well, then, see you next time!
Look forward to the next episode!