Last up is the Ferris wheel.
Let’s go, Pikachu.
What?
Was it a dream?
Or was it...
A new curtain rises
March 18, 2005:
A spring day with a lingering chill in the air.
I took quite a detour,
but now we finally meet
Everyone here has gathered
to open the door to dreams.
You cast a spell on me,
clearing away my doubts
Let’s open the heavy door!
Now, let’s go!
Our adventure begins
Come on, leap out!
Let’s discover what’s beyond the sky
Now, onto a 192-day journey
of dreams and adventures...
Let’s go!
Hello and Thank You, everyone!
October 28, 2004: Event Outline Press Conference
October 28, 2004: Pokémon The Park 2005
Event Outline Press Conference.
Will be one!
March 12, 2005: Private Preview for Collaborators
March 12, 2005:
Private preview for collaborators.
I hope that the dreams we share
with Pokémon really do come true.
There is a brightness
Thank you very much!
It’s like the sunshine
Hello! Thank you!
That comes down among the trees
And kisses the ground
The city is like a maze
We all never fly
■ March 12-13, 2005
PokéPark: The Kick Off Party
March 12 and 13: The grand
“PokéPark: The Kick Off Party.”
We feel the loneliness
There is water
It’s so beautiful
They keep running towards a dream
Reaching to be free
Okay, thank you!
Hello! Thank you!
What wonderful words!
■ March 18, 2005
March 18: The Grand Opening.
Grand Opening
They make everyone happy
The dreams we share with Pokémon have begun!
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark! (Let’s go!)
Lugia’s Spinning Ships
Dancing Pokémon Mini Tour
Everyday’s a merry-go-round
Dizzying! Colorful! Filled with dreams!
If you count up all the things you love,
Battle Coaster Rending the Sky
you’ll forget about bad times
What should we do today?
Encounters with all sorts of Pokémon.
Holding your hand’s a wonderland
With my powers and your powers,
Alto Mare Gondola Cruise
let’s play catch!
Pokémon Merry-Go-Round
Pokémon Exciting Safari
Everyday’s a roller coaster
Exciting! Thrilling! Filled with emotion!
You smiling? You crying? Which is it?
I’ll take a peek on the sharp curve
Your friend Dodo has evolved!
Here, congrats on catching
six Pokémon!
Race on towards the goal
You caught Gomazo!
Here, congrats!
Even overtaking the wind
Then end it by posing in unison
Smiles and peace signs
Mizugoro’s Splash Adventure
Hello! Thank you!
Team Aqua VS Team Magma:
Crash Car Battle
Hope I see you tomorrow
Let’s hope it’s a sunny day
Pokémon Starry Sky Trip
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark!
Hello! Thank you!
Thanks for everything
Let’s sing it together!
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark!
The Pichu Bros. Mischief Train
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark! (Let’s go!)
Pikachu Forest
Pokémon Big Ferris Wheel
Walkthrough Adventure
Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario
The Guiding Waves...
flow within me!
Lots of Pokémon guided guests
into a world of dreams.
Everyday’s a merry-go-round
Dizzying! Colorful! Filled with dreams!
If you count up all the things you love,
The smiles of the children
filled us with energy and strength.
you’ll forget about bad times
What should we do today?
Holding your hand’s a wonderland
The dream’s not over yet
Keep it up
!
The dream’s not over yet
Keep it up
!
With my powers and your...
The card isn’t ready to use yet, so remember to
add money using the charging machine here.
Edy Card Sales Area
First, put your card here.
Okay.
Okay, thank you!
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
Information
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Fun-27!
Walkthrough Adventure: “Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario”
Reservation Ticket Issuing Area
Please line up outside the attraction
with your card.
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
PokéPark Help Center
Lost Children - First Aid - Lost Property
I’m going on a journey with this little guy
PokéPark Help Center
We do have it.
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
PokéPark Fishing Tournament DS Distribution
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Keep tapping the A Button!!
Harisen - Level 13
PokéPark was opened on March 18,
and today, on its 46th day,
May 2: The Millionth Visitor Ceremony.
■ May 2, 2005
The Millionth Visitor Ceremony
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
it’s successfully welcoming
its millionth visitor!
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
A Million Visitors to PokéPark!!
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Walkthrough Adventure
Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario
June 19: A new attraction opens:
Weary from battling, I bid you goodnight
■ June 19, 2005
New Attraction
Walkthrough Adventure:
"Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario"
New Attraction
Walkthrough Adventure:
"Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario"
New Attraction
Walkthrough Adventure:
"Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario"
New Attraction
Walkthrough Adventure:
"Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario"
“Walkthrough Adventure:
“Mew and the Hero of Guiding Waves, Lucario.”
When I close my eyes, I’m taken back
A press preview was held the day before opening
The dream has expanded yet again.
to the roaring fire, the dancing wind,
and the echoing shouts of that battle
“Yesterday’s foe is today’s ally”
According to some old saying
PokéPark Bon Odori Special
Let's Dance Together!! The Pokémon Counting Song
But an ally made today is my friend tomorrow, and will be forevermore
■ August 14, 2005
August 14: Summer vacation brings
the PokéPark Bon Odori Special.
PokéPark Bon Odori Special
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Sing and dance, Pokémon-mon
We met so many children, too.
Dance and count
How many now?
At the count of three, Mizugoro smiles
mittsu
Four Million Visitors
to PokéPark!!
■ September 22, 2005
PokéPark was opened on March 18, and today,
September 22: The dreams we shared with Pokémon had reached four million people.
The Four Millionth Visitor Ceremony
only three days before closing,
it’s successfully welcoming its four millionth visitor.
Messages
Pokémon...
The Pokémon Company
Representative Director and CEO
Ishihara Tsunekazu
The Pokémon Company
Representative Director and CEO
Ishihara Tsunekazu
Q. What is PokéPark to
Q. The Pokémon Company?
It began with the games
Pocket Monsters Red and Green,
and then it expanded to various types of media.
For example, when we began the animated series,
released the first movie, launched the card game...
We’ve built these
various pillars of Pokémon.
But a Pokémon theme park, a PokéPark,
was a big dream of mine as well,
so realizing it means
one of my Pokémon dreams came true.
I was very happy.
Well, the eighth movie was this year,
the animated series has been running for 8 to 9 years,
it’s also the tenth year for the games,
and the card game is about to turn 10, too.
We’ve built all these long-running pillars.
With PokéPark, we thought we’d start
by holding one in Nagoya this year.
When I see all the smiling guests,
it makes me very happy that we did it.
And throughout its run,
about four million guests visited the park.
That almost rivals one of the movies’ goals,
of four million moviegoers.
The movies’ four million moviegoers
are spread across 300 cinemas,
but the same number of people
all came to one place for PokéPark.
It impressed on me the incredible power
of the media, the power of the place.
I’d love to open a PokéPark again,
someday, somewhere.
The Pokémon Company
Representative Director
Tajiri Satoshi
The Pokémon Company
Representative Director
Tajiri Satoshi
Q. How did you feel when you saw PokéPark?
Animation, games... and the card game. And manga.
When expanding into different types of media,
we always think about where
we should go next, beyond that dream.
Providing a Pokémon world, as a place
kids can touch, can play with, like a theme park...
We had been thinking it’d be an amazing goal
to aim for, for the upcoming tenth anniversary,
but this was even a little sooner.
A Pokémon theme park like that,
actually being realized,
and then having
millions of kids visiting it...
I think it was a really wonderful,
a really fulfilling event.
Because all the staff kept working hard,
we managed to make PokéPark a reality.
Q. Give us a message for the PokéPark staff.
I’m very grateful to them.
Connecting with all the kids,
sharing in the fun with them...
Doing that constantly,
for such a long time,
means they really shared
a kind of professionalism.
So many staff constantly
maintaining that professionalism,
it was just so incredible,
it really won me over.
That’s a necessary accumulation of expertise,
and something they can be proud of.
Working at expanding the connections
between Pokémon and reality.
Q. Please tell us your dreams for the future.
It’s just a question of where,
and at what scale, we should do it.
Another dream is using the stories,
the life energy, the... workings of the Pokémon,
staying true to them,
and creating things that can support the core.
Like how we’ve kept making Pocket Monsters games
for different game consoles...
I think that’s something we’ll still be working on,
even ten years from now.
Even though it’s a movie world—
a game world— which is, naturally, 2D...
PokéPark Project
General Producer
Saito Nobukazu
PokéPark Project
General Producer
Saito Nobukazu
Q. What hardships did you face with PokéPark?
When the kids get engrossed in it,
they can imagine they’re actually there, in 3D.
So even though it’s 2D,
they’re experiencing it in 3D.
And bringing that 3D Pokémon world
to life through PokéPark...
I think that was
the hardest struggle for all of us.
Q. Give us a message for the PokéPark staff.
We had a cold March,
cold enough that it snowed.
And now in August,
it’s a very hot summer.
There hasn’t been much rain, and it’s been
a hot summer even through the rainy season.
All these months...
There’s staff that start work at 6 AM,
and even staff that are still here at midnight.
And even late night staff
supporting them.
I think everyone gave it their all, all this time,
all these months, through the heat and the cold.
They have my heartfelt gratitude.
Together, we managed to make our dream
of the world’s first PokéPark come true.
Q. Please tell us your dreams for the future.
So if we can open a PokéPark once again,
someday, somewhere...
I think we can make
a lot of children happy.
Making that happen
is one dream of mine.
Also, everyone worked together,
to make the PokéPark dream come true...
So once this is over,
I hope we can work together,
this time to make the dreams of everyone
who helped with that effort come true.
I’d like to make all their dreams come true.
That’s another dream of mine.
I silently stood and watched
my little one’s sleeping face
A tiny wrinkle forming on your brow
Most of all,
that it was just a lot of fun.
Ito Ayano
If you’re having bad dreams, open your eyes
At the start, I didn’t know any
of the girls here, and didn’t know what to do.
My hesitance, scared of the water...
But now, I’ve made friends
with everyone and I’m really enjoying it.
I’ve had amazing training
and amazing experiences here,
Those summer memories flood back
so I hope I can use those
as a stepping stone to improve myself.
You gave me the push I needed to swim
It’s as vivid as yesterday
Initially, I applied just hoping
I’d have the chance to operate attractions,
Hanai Shiho
but I’ve met so many guests here,
adults and children, and really enjoyed it.
I can still hear your voice
Pointing me in the right direction
Most of all, I’m glad everyone on the cast
were such wonderful people.
I’m glad I worked here.
Alone among the billowing winds
That’s it from Hanai,
but thank you! Yay!
I sing on
At the start, and at the height of summer,
it’s been physically exhausting at times,
Shimizu Chiho
and I think everyone has probably been
mentally exhausted at times too.
“A little one,” that describes me
But being surrounded by such great friends,
it was a lot of fun.
It fits me, without any doubt
Every day was fulfilling at PokéPark.
In the mirror, all I see is loneliness
I hope we can always keep
meeting up as friends, I’d like that.
I love PokéPark.
Thank you.
Tomorrow, I won’t let anyone defeat me
And so I return, little by little,
Golden Week was the toughest time,
then once that was over...
Mio Nanae
It was like we all opened up
to one another, and I really enjoyed it.
to a younger time
It was like we all opened up
to one another, and I really enjoyed it.
To the day you praised me for singing a love song
But now, thinking back,
I think there were a lot of tough times.
without even knowing what it meant
Don’t forget about me,
all you guys!
When I look to the sky,
my voice comes back to me
I’m glad I got to see the hopes and dreams
of everyone involved with Pokémon worldwide.
Kashiwagi Kazuma
Among the billowing winds
To me, PokéPark has been about
meeting people, and parting with them.
You should fly with me
I can still hear your voice
It was fun. I’d like to use these experiences
to move ahead in the future.
Pointing me in the right direction
Alone among the billowing winds
I sing on
Day 191...
I finally realized, your precious ones are those by your side
■ September 24, 2005
All-Hands Meeting
September 24:
The final all-hands meeting.
When I look to the sky,
my voice comes back to me
Just one day left,
let’s go!
Among the billowing winds
Day 192...
Days to the finale:
You should fly with me
I can still hear your voice
September 25:
The PokéPark Farewell Party.
PokéPark had its grand opening
on March 18, 2005...
■ September 25, 2005
PokéPark Farewell Party
...and has had over
four million visitors up until today.
PokéPark has etched all of your memories
into history, together with Pokémon.
And now, it has reached its finale.
Please enjoy this moment
together with the lovable Pokémon.
PokéPark only exists together with you.
Ahem! Ahem!
Everyone gathered here!
The PokéPark Farewell Party
starts now, meow!
Hello! Thank you!
What wonderful words!
They make everyone happy
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark! (Let’s go!)
Everyday’s a merry-go-round
Dizzying! Colorful! Filled with dreams!
If you count up all the things you love,
you’ll forget about bad times
What should we do today?
Holding your hand’s a wonderland
With my powers and your powers,
let’s play catch!
Everyday’s a roller coaster
Exciting! Thrilling! Filled with emotion!
You smiling? You crying? Which is it?
I’ll take a peek on the sharp curve
Race on towards the goal
Even overtaking the wind
Then end it by posing in unison
Smiles and peace signs
Hello! Thank you!
Hope I see you tomorrow
Let’s hope it’s a sunny day
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark!
Hello! Thank you!
Thanks for everything
Let’s sing it together!
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark!
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark! (Let’s go!)
I was very happy
working alongside
the Pokémon I love.
I loved it!!
.......................Ayumi
This is the last time
we will all gather on these park grounds.
Afterwards:
The PokéPark Staff Farewell Party.
The PokéPark Staff Farewell Party starts now!
■ September 25, 2005
PokéPark Staff Farewell Party
Hello! Thank you!
What wonderful words!
They make everyone happy
Happy! Come, come! PokéPark! (Let’s go!)
Our lovable boss!
Who could that be? That’s right!
Let’s welcome
Mr. Producer Saito!
Producer Saito!
Saito! Saito! Saito! Saito!
Huh? Where is he coming from? Huh?!
Three, two, one, go!
Thank you for the fun memories!
Yeah!
Thank you
for the fun memories!
Ooh! There’s an amazing
round of Saito cheers!
Louder, everyone!
A new curtain rises
Oh, wow, wow!
I took quite a detour,
but now we finally meet
So you really did have a surprise for me.
I never suspected!
You cast a spell on me,
Now, we have a bouquet for Producer Saito
from all of the staff! Yay!
clearing away my doubts
Let’s open the heavy door!
There you go,
a bouquet from Ito Megumi!
Now, let’s go!
Thank you!
Our adventure begins
Nobody told me anything about this!
Come on, leap out!
Thank you.
Thanks for your hard work!
That’s right, this is where it all began
It’s been months, but felt so short...
Trust so strong it could shake the earth
Have you all enjoyed PokéPark?!
Never giving up on a dream, no matter how small
It’s been fun, hasn’t it!
Well, thanks to all of you,
PokéPark has come to a smooth end.
That’s the world where friends lie waiting
The details,
we’ll have to work out tomorrow.
When a tear may slip out on the odd night...
But for tonight,
we should say cheers to stop our tears.
So I’ll just say a quick word.
We caught PokéPark!
We’ve had fun!
Thanks for your hard work!
Thank you!
It’s been fun.
Thank you, everyone!
Thanks for your hard work!
Thank you.
Cheese!
Thanks for your hard work.
Thank you!
It wasn’t just a dream...
It really happened
!
The dreams we shared with Pokémon
came true!!
Thank you for these 192 days of dreams!
Let’s do it again, someday, somewhere...
..............................................Saito Nobukazu
Thank you for these 192 days of dreams!
Let’s do it again, someday, somewhere...
..............................................Saito Nobukazu