Pikachu!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Go! Monster Ball!
Gyarados!
Let’s meet again!
This boy is
Satoshi from Masara Town.
He battles and catches alongside
his partner, Pikachu.
Aiming to become a Pokémon Master,
he continues his training journey.
Destroyer Beam!
.
See ya!
Oh, Mom...
What’s up?
Tonari Town is
close to where you are now, right?
Yeah.
It’s just up from here.
That’s great!
You see, I’m meeting someone
at the Pokémon Center there.
Meeting who?
Your dad!
Huh?! Dad?!
Would you come with me?
I’ll be there!
So, when is it?
Tomorrow.
I know it’s pretty short notice.
Okay!
Bye!
Oh! Hold on a—
Getting to see Dad
for the first time in ages...
Isn’t that exciting, Pikachu?
All right!
Time to head to Tonari Town!
You hear that?
Sure did!
The brat boy is headed to
Tonari Town, meow.
We can get ahead of him...
And then we nab Pikachu...
What a great feeling!
A Berolinga?
What was that for?
Hey, Pikachu...
Huh...?
Pikachu!
I know!
You’re looking for
a Pikachu, right?
How did you know that?
I saw them last night.
These weird guys in weird suits.
Weird guys in weird suits...?
Pikachu’s ours!
What a great feeling, meow!
Let’s celebrate with a feast!
Yea-hey!
Wait, that’s just
a single biscuit, meow?!
What are you talking about?
Once we’re promoted to admins...
...we can bid
our days of hunger goodbye!
All right, shall we split it?
Yeah...
That’s them.
Team Rocket...
The brat boy!
Team Rocket!
Give Pikachu back!
That capsule blocks
electricity, meow!
And without this key,
you’ll never get it open!
We’ll let you know,
in commemoration of our promotion...
Even if you don’t ask us
about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation!
To preserve world peace!
Championing the evils
of truth and love!
We’re the lovely, charming villains!
Musashi!
Kojiro!
The Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
I got the key.
Huh?!
What an awful feeling!
Pikachu!
I was worried about you!
What a relief!
He’s safe, thanks to you.
I never got your name.
Haruto.
I’m Satoshi.
This is my partner, Pikachu.
Nice to meet you.
Your Pikachu’s cute.
Huh?
Yeah! I set out
on my journey with him.
Hey, what’s it like?
Huh?
To touch Pokémon!
Umm... They’re warm and soft,
and cuddling them even cheers you up.
You mean
you’ve never touched one?
That’s right.
I love Pokémon, though.
Every single one of them
feels different!
I know! This forest’s full of Pokémon!
Let’s go see what it’s like to touch them, Haruto!
Yeah.
Ooh! A Digda!
Now’s your chance, Haruto—
Are you okay?
I’m totally fine!
Now for the next one!
Calm down, Dodrio!
We just wanna touch you a little!
Stun Spores...
I’m not giving up yet!
Konpang!
The sun’s up, but good evening—
kon-pang-wa
This time...
it’s Sleep... Pow... der...
Madatsubomi! Wait for us!
It’s a Cocoon!
Cocoon won’t run away.
Spear!
Haruto... Are you okay?
Yeah. I know this area well.
Good to hear it.
Now I feel kinda hungry...
I know a spot with lots of berries!
Sounds great! Let’s go!
Oran Berries!
There’s so many sky paintings...
That sky is my favorite.
See it?
That one by the stool.
Hmm...
My favorite one is...
Huh?
The Distant Blue Sky
PocketMonsters
I’m sorry.
Did I surprise you?
I’m sorry, too.
Sorry for peeking around.
Right?
Huh? Where’d he go?
A friend of yours?
Yeah.
That’s weird.
He was just here...
What’s wrong?
It’s nothing.
I just had a little surprise.
Oh, um, I was looking for berries
and ended up here...
Sae...
I’m fine.
I know it couldn’t have been, I just...
Um...
If you’re after Oran Berries,
have as many as you want.
Sorry about that.
He’s not angry.
He can just be a little blunt.
Right. It’s okay.
I’ll help you pick
some Oran Berries.
Oh, you don’t have to!
It’s fine, don’t fuss!
If you want,
you can have this, too.
That looks tasty!
I baked it with
berries from the forest.
I’ll put another in
for your friend.
Thank you!
Satoshi!
Haruto! Where’d you go?
Sorry... I spotted a Pokémon
and chased after it.
The lady in that cabin
is really nice!
Look, she gave me all this!
Wow! Berry loaves!
There’s one for you, too.
Let’s dig in.
Thank you.
But I ate too much
for breakfast...
...so if you want,
you can have it.
Huh?
Okay...
What a beautiful sky...
Huh?
Yeah!
Weather’s nice again today.
Is the bread good?
It’s the best!
You sure you don’t want any?
Yeah.
Watching you eat,
I feel like I’m eating too.
I’m stuffed!
Huh...?
When I watch someone eating,
it just makes me feel even hungrier.
And hey, you know how if you suddenly
can’t eat something you’ve always had,
you really wanna eat it, right?
I do!
I’d love some of
Mom’s croquettes right now!
I know that feeling!
Right. Then let’s have half each.
Wow!
You can understand
what Pokémon say?!
Huh?
Nah, it just feels
like I do sometimes.
I have a little favor to ask you.
Huh?
So that’s what
they took from you.
Yeah. A precious cap
my dad gave me.
My cap’s been stolen
by a Mankey once, too.
Okay then, leave this to me.
As much as I’d like
your help, Pikachu...
I’ll work something out by myself!
That’s Haruto’s precious cap.
Give it back.
Hold it!
Hey!
Sorry, Mankey.
That’s my friend’s precious cap.
I have to take it back.
Huh?
You like it that much, huh?
No choice, then.
I’ll give you mine instead.
Haruto! I got it!
Oh, what is it?
Oh, um...
We were about to go for a walk,
why don’t you join...?
Huh?
That cap...
Is something wrong with it?
That’s what I’d like to ask!
Where did you find that cap?
Where?
I took it back from the Mankey.
Haruto asked me to.
Haruto?!
Don’t lie to us!
I’m not lying!
Or wait, you know Haruto, too?
Know him...?!
Haruto is...
Haruto is our...
So Haruto got sick, and...
Yes. Last year.
But I really did...
Ever since he was little,
he often went to play in this forest.
He and the wild Pokémon
would all end up covered in mud.
When I get older,
I wanna become a Pokémon Trainer,
catch lots of Pokémon,
and battle a whole lot, too!
He always liked to
look at the sky...
Since losing him, the sky is
all my husband has been able to paint...
Haruto said this one
was his favorite sky.
I see... This sky...
I remember it well.
With me working in the city
and my husband shut up in his atelier,
we often ended up
missing one another.
But that day, the three of us got to be
together for once, and the sky was like that...
Losing him was the first time
I realized...
...the comforts you take for granted
may not always be there,
and how joyful it is
just to have them.
Now, I’ve started telling
those ordinary comforts...
...“Thank you.”
I won’t just paint skies anymore.
I’ll paint the forest
and the Pokémon Haruto loved, too.
Right.
Haruto...
Satoshi...
Oh, yeah.
You never got to touch any Pokémon.
Don’t worry about it, really.
Don’t hold back, go on!
I guess I really can’t.
Stay still.
Yeah, you’re here.
I am. You are, too.
Put your hand over mine.
Like this?
It’s just like you said.
They’re warm and soft,
and cuddling them even cheers you up.
Thank you.
Yeah.
When I get older,
I wanna become a Pokémon Trainer,
catch lots of Pokémon,
and battle a whole lot, too!
Now, I’ve started telling
those ordinary comforts...
...“Thank you.”
Thank you, Pikachu.
Huh?! Dad left already?!
Yes. Something about an emergency...
Sounded like he had to go somewhere far away.
Really? That’s too bad,
but it is what it is.
Pikachu, maybe another time.
This is from Dad.
All right!
I got a new cap!
All right! I’ll borrow the Pokémon Center’s kitchen
tonight and cook us up a feast!
Here you go.
Croquettes!
Thank you, Mom!
Dinnertime!
Here, have these.
I ended up making too many.
Oh, and I’m making dessert too,
so you can have some of that if you’d like.
Sorry for the trouble!
And thank you!
Huh? How come...?
Mom!
If you want breakfast,
it’ll be a while.
No! Entei appeared nearby and
everyone’s rushing to catch it!
I’ve gotta hurry too!
Then take this, at least.
Thank you! I’ll be off!
He’s already gone.
Well, at least
he’s doing well.
Those croquettes were great, meow!
Buono!
C’est bon!
This boy is the ten-year-old
Satoshi from Masara Town.
He battles and catches
alongside his partner, Pikachu.
He continues his training journey.
Aiming to be a Pokémon Master,
Satoshi’s journeys with his friends continue.
If I say they continue, continue they will!
The Distant Blue Sky
PocketMonsters