The wind is great!
We’re almost there, Champion!
That’s former Champion.
Hold it, you!
Once more!
I request another battle!
Yeah!
It’s a Dai Mushroom!
Hey! Where are you going?!
It’s this way!
Long time, no see...
Dande, me boy.
Master!
It really has been quite a while.
Here you go.
Ah, thanks. Much appreciated.
What was that?!
Please let me dow—
What is going on?!
Huh?!
Enough!
As formidable as always, Master.
You’ve gotten stronger,
too, me boy.
I still have a long way to go.
Heh.
Still on your way, are you?
Encounters with strong rivals
lead one to even greater heights.
I, too, quite look forward...
...to battling all-out.
So, you figured out
why I was here.
What will you do now,
me boy?
I...
...am off to meet
some strong trainers.
For me, too?
Very well.
I will show them
the power of pink!
How many years
has it been?
We’d best give it our all!
I thought I said
I don’t do encores?
I think it was in here...
Sonia, I wanna ask something
about this report...
Huh? You’re leaving already?
Yup! I managed to
book the research trip!
That’s great!
I gotta go!
Oh, right! This is for you.
Huh... Yeah, guess you’ll need me,
all right!
Hey.
I presume...
...your successor will also be there,
of course?
Where to next?
Get off my back,
you stupid old man!
Why?!
Shaku-chaaan!
C’mon, Shaku-chaaan!
Listen to your Papa!
Thank you all
so much for waiting.
Many brave challengers who represent Galar
have gathered here today.
See, I’ve spent my whole life battling with myself
to try to become the greatest trainer...
But...
I have learned...
...how much further you can go
when you have a rival...
...to compete and
refine yourself against!
And...
...now that I’ve taken over running the League
from Chairman Rose...
I’m thinking I want to bring even more thrilling battles
to our wonderful Galar region!
So for both these reasons,
I would like to take this moment...
...to declare the
Galarian Star Tournament open!
Now...
Let’s start another
heated battle!