Can you hear the cheers
echoing through the stadium?
Look at that, Wooloo!
It’s my bro’s Lizardon!
Galar Karate practitioner Saito is facing...
...the mightiest man;
Champion Dande!
The Champion is amazing!
I’m so proud of my big bro!
Pay attention, Wooloo!
If you wanna be the League Champion,
you gotta be able to do
what he does!
See that?
That’s what I’m talking about!
Lizardon’s Flamethrower
is really powerful!
That’s great!
That Flamethrower’s amazing!
Was that an impression
of Lizardon?
But you’re not a Fire type, are you?
And look at his flying technique!
Nobody’s beating that!
What are you doing, Wooloo?
The only moves you know are
Tackle and Curl Up...
I guess we’re not reaching
my bro’s level any time soon...
All right!
Let’s keep studying the match!
But I will enter the
Pokémon League someday...
...with you, Wooloo!
Wooloo?
Hey, look at this little cutie!
Do that breathing thing again!
Turn this way, please!
Where did you come from?
Oh, you ran away from home?
I’m sure someone out there
is worried about you by now, don’t you think?
Could you take this Pokémon
to the address listed on this tag?
Did it get lost?
Doesn’t it wanna go home?
You’ve got this, right?
Yes, there, there...
Oh, thank you!
Wooloo!
Where’d you go?!
Wooloo! Wooloo!
Wooloo! Where are you?!
Wooloo!
It’s me!
I’m sorry about earlier!
I know there’s things
only you can do!
Let’s go to the
Pokémon League together!
I can’t...
I can’t do it without you!
Armorgaw, land here.
Wooloo, I was so
worried about you!
Another Lizardon impression?
Just be yourself, Wooloo!
Doesn’t look like it’s hurt.
Easy does it...
Want a ride?
That really caught me off guard.
Your Wooloo went and just jumped
out the window!
You and that Wooloo
must be really close, huh?
Hmm? Are you listening?