Can you hear the cheers
echoing through the stadium?
The match hasn’t even begun,
yet the supporters filling the rows...
...can hardly contain their excitement!
The big match between the Champion
and a Pokémon League Gym Leader!
Galar Karate practitioner Saito is facing...
Hurry, Tommy!
...the mightiest man;
Champion Dande!
I made it!
Let the match begin!
Go, Dande!
Lizardon!
Lizardon takes off and uses Flamethrower!
But Kairiky dodges!
Yeah! Great!
Kairiky’s as strong as ever!
There! Go!
Lizardon unleashes its Slash attack!
All right!
Kairiky can’t get back up!
Lizardon won!
It’s over!
John!
Dande’s awesome, isn’t he?
Just once...
I’d love to watch one of
Dande’s matches in the stadium.
Chairman.
You should get going
to the hospital.
A taxi is waiting for you outside.
What a magnificent Armorgaw.
Sorry, this one doesn’t
take to anyone but me!
Though its speed is
unmatched in all of Galar!
Chairman. Hurry.
C’mon, hurry!
Now, now, don’t run!
I’m so nervous!
Chairman Rose will be here soon.
Chairman Rose?
Huh? They told us Chairman Rose was
visiting the hospital today, remember?
You didn’t know?
Chairman Rose...
The Chairman Rose?!
Aren’t you coming?
I’ll write him a letter.
I’m gonna ask him to invite me
to one of Dande’s matches!
What? One of Dande’s matches?
There’s no way. You know how hard it is
to get tickets to the Champion’s matches!
And anyway, isn’t it easier
to ask him directly?
A letter is better.
I’m going ahead.
Thank you.
It’s done!
Chairman Rose left already!
What?!
He probably went to the roof!
What’s wrong?!
Oh... You must be the child that
didn’t show up earlier.
Thank you.
I’m fine.
That’s impossible!
Do you... like Pokémon?
Y-Yeah.
It seems Pokémon like you, too.
Chairman.
That’s a letter for you!
Um...
Please read it!
John!
You gave him the letter?
Yeah.
Young man.
The fact that Pokémon like you
proves that you can become a great trainer.
Hmm? You got something
from him, Sir?
I was afraid you’d
collapsed on the way!
This...
...is quite good, don’t you think?