The Champion?
Well, Dande is...
Strong.
He is strong.
Severely unrelenting.
His fighting style is unique.
He sometimes puts on this expression
where I’m not sure if he wants to win or lose.
D-D—
Our matches almost feel more like
fun playtime than a battle.
I’m busy.
Look at that!
That guy is the
strongest Champion!
Hey!
Dande has support from
many different trainers.
Now it’s time for a special interview
with Chairman Rose.
I think Dande battles for the fun of it...
He’s... not really laughing... is he?
What are you talking about?
John!
You really were still here!
I fell asleep? Again?!
I’ll get ready right away!
Don’t rush.
Driver!
Right!
John!
Have fun.
But don’t push yourself too hard.
All right!
Mr. Taxi Driver,
will we make it in time for the match?
Don’t you worry!
My Armorgaw is
the fastest in all of Galar!
Whoa, there!
The headwinds are awfully bad...
Mr. Taxi Driver, stop!
Wait, where’s John?
Was he there
when we left the hospital?
Even John wouldn’t forget this,
would he?
Chairman. Dande isn’t here.
Champion!
What are you doing here?
Oh, I just got a little lost.
“Got lost”...
All the way out here?
This one looks fast!
I’m facing a tough opponent today,
so I didn’t want to tire out Lizardon.
Think you could give me a ride?
Sure. As it happens,
I was already taking this kid to the stadium.
But the winds are awful today.
I’m not sure we can make it.
I know!
You can leave the taxi here
and ride Armorgaw to the stadium!
We’ll come after you.
Thank you!
Aren’t you cold?
I-I’m fine!
Did you oversleep?
Yeah... I always do.
I keep doing that, too.
It... It was my dream...
...to see one of your matches
in person... Mr. Dande.
Just “Dande” is fine!
You know, Armorgaw.
If you weren’t worried about us,
you could fly much faster than this, right?
Brace yourself.
You really are an oddball.
Aren’t you scared?
Not at all!
Me neither!
Mr. Dande still isn’t here?!
Check the changing room again!
Isn’t that Dande?
Look! It’s the Champion!
Everybody!
The show’s about to begin!
Who’s that child?
Was seeing the match enough
to fulfill your dream?
You want to be
a Pokémon Trainer yourself, don’t you?
Next time we meet,
let’s battle!
But I won’t hold back
against any opponent.
You’re late, Dande!
I thought you’d run off
with your tail between your legs!
Dande looks like he’s having fun.
Someday...
I’ll become a Pokémon Trainer, too.
And then...
Excuse me!
Could you give us a ride?
Sure thing!
Where can I take you?