Training in the Wild Area?
Yes.
So the Gym will be left
unattended for a few days.
I see.
Saito?
I’m sorry for
the short notice.
It’s quite all right.
Thank you for letting me know. Bye.
That’s very much like her.
Losing to Dande
must have really hurt her.
I just hope she doesn’t
push herself too hard and get hurt.
I’m getting off here!
Miss! Are you sure this is
where you want to be?
Let’s go!
Not good enough...
Not even close!
Right...
Now, come at me!
What are you waiting for?
Do it!
It’s no use...
I guess I’ll just have to
call for help.
There might be
another exit somewhere.
I wonder how...
...I looked to them back there.
I’m sorry...
...for being such an
inexperienced trainer.
Forget Dande, I’d have a hard time
winning against anybody like this.
Thank you.
It’s so good!
I can see outside!
Why are you here...?
Oh, thank goodness!
I looked everywhere
for you, miss!
Here you go.
You forgot this.
What were you doing here,
by the way?
Just...
...seeking shelter.