D-Did he go away?
Um...
I’m Tommy.
Um... Please give me an invitation
to one of the Champion’s matches!
M-Mr. Dande’s matches?
Why w-would you ask m-me?
I just thought a Gym Leader
might be able to get one...
Um...
It’s not for me.
It’s for my friend,
John!
I wonder if someday I’ll get to
be a Pokémon Trainer and go on a journey...
A Pokémon Trainer?
There’s no way,
and you know it.
Well then,
what do you want to do?!
We don’t...
...even know when we’ll get
discharged from this hospital!
But Chairman Rose said
I’d make a great trainer...
But he still hasn’t replied
to your letter, has he?!
Stop holding on to
impossible dreams!
Why would you say that?!
Why did you stop?
Don’t hold back!
Because it’s just not possible!
Then I got discharged by myself
before I could apologize.
John really loves Dande.
I thought I could make it up to him by
giving him a ticket to one of Dande’s matches...
So...
W-Wait...
I-If you want to make up...
T-Then you should just talk to him!
T-To the hospital...
Please!
Huh? What?
Tommy?
It went all right?
Yeah.
They said they’d keep an eye
on my recovery for a while.
I see.
John.
I wanted to apologize.
I take back what I said last time!
Tommy...
When you’re really into something,
you lose sight of everything around you,
and put yourself in danger.
But once you make up your mind,
you never, ever back down.
So I’m sure you’ll become
a great Pokémon Trainer!
As soon as you get discharged...
I’ll help you out again.
Let’s become the best trainers,
together!
Yeah!
Thank you.
They sure are taking their time...
Are those kids okay?
Sir, why did you want to go
to the hospital so late at night?
Does my face really look like this?