Oh! Watashiraga dodges
Kajirigame’s Crunch...
...and unleashes a Dai Grassland!
It’s over!
This is Competitor Rurina’s second loss in a row!
How can she recover from this?!
Too bad about today’s match.
I saw these.
It seems your modeling career
is going well.
Thank you...
But working both as
a Gym Leader and a model...
...must keep you
rather busy, right?
What are you getting at?
Oh, well...
It’s just...
You’ll have to figure out
just how high...
...you should be aiming.
Isn’t that right?
He’s telling me to
quit modeling, isn’t he?!
Hmm, is he?
You sure you’re
not overthinking it?
But...
It depends on what you
wanna do anyway, right?
Ms. Rurina!
Okay, that’s good!
Next up we’ll be doing some shots
with Water Pokémon!
I’ve been here before...
Rurina, don’t get too close
to the edge!
You’re all bruised up...
Did they bully you?
You can’t give up, though!
You should evolve
and get back at them!
Hey... When you get bigger...
Will you...
You’re in perfect sync with
the Pokémon!
Just as you’d expect
from a Water Gym Leader!
Director!
There isn’t a single
Pokémon around!
No Pokémon?!
But then how are we
going to film?!
Ms. Rurina?!
What is that?!
Get the camera!
Oh, Rurina?
I saw your commercial!
Isn’t this a Milokaross?
That’s amazing!
I couldn’t believe my eyes!
Yeah...
I’d never seen a
wild Milokaross before.
It was so... beautiful.
You know, Milokaross is called
the most beautiful Pokémon of all...
But at the same time,
it’s really strong, right?
So what I’m saying is,
you should just be more like Milokaross!
Hey... When you get bigger...
Will you let me ride you?
Let’s go swimming together!
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
The chairman is away right now.
I’ll aim to be the best Gym Leader
and the best model.
Pardon me.
Oh, that’s right.
I’ll make sure to win
today’s match!
Hmmm? Already done, miss?
Take me to the stadium, please.