As I’ve said many times,
the difference of 0.00002548
shown in these figures...
...will have much greater ramifications
on the results than you speculated.
Hierarchical analysis of every phenomenon
at a microscopic level...
...cannot lead you to understand
the behavior as a whole.
As I’ve explained before,
to understand the full picture—
All right, I get it already!
It’s a new variation.
This might finally be viable...
It won’t stabilize.
This is hopeless.
Why, this is incredible!
I didn’t expect to find a diamond in the rough
here, of all places...
What is your name?
Yes.
Yes. I understand.
No, there is no problem.
I will deal with it.
Yes.
Goodbye, then.
Vice-President, it’s time.
Good morning, everybody.
The Chairman is not here today.
Regardless, please concentrate on your work
and do your best.
All right.
I’ll be counting on you all!
That’s our Ms. Olive!
She’s a natural!
Oh... I wish I could be like her.
Vice-President!
About these documents...
Excuse me, Ms. Olive,
I have a question...
Um, Ms. Olive,
are you free tonight?
Ms. Olive!
Vice-President,
your transport is here.
Let us be off.
Thank you so much!
It was no problem at all.
Have a nice day.
Yes?
I see. I’ll be right there.
Olive.
I thought it was you.
Chairman...
I saw you from the air.
I’m heading to the office.
Would you like to come along?
I understand you had
quite the busy day.
Were you all right?
No problem at all.
Every issue has been taken care of.
I see.
Seems you can keep the company afloat
even without me.
Not at all.
I need you to work hard, as well.
I just can’t beat you, it seems.
I’m so glad to have you by my side.
I’m just doing my job.
Sir! Ma’am! Look at this!
It’s a real spectacle!
Daimax really is incredible,
don’t you think?
That isn’t Daimax.
It’s Kyodaimax.
This phenomenon, unique to certain Pokémon,
where they don’t just change size,
but display visible changes in their appearance
is called Kyodaimax.
Huh?
For instance, the enlarged Laplace’s shell
has a logarithmic spiral structure within,
Miss...?
which made us realize that maybe
the shell isn’t part of its body, as we once thought.
Sekitanzan’s entire body morphs into
a furnace-like structure,
All right, I get it already!
and its shoulders
emit heat of over 3,000 Kel—
Listen to me!
I don’t know how much more
I can take.