Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Poké-Golf
Poké-Ping-Pong
Poké-Soccer
Poké-Rugby
What is the sport played today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Ms. Kahili!
You are Ms. Kahili, correct?
Will you answer
some questions for us?
You’ve been on a losing streak lately...
Quite a long slump, don’t you think?
What are your reasons for
coming home to Alola in secret?
There’s been rumors that
you’re retiring, but...
Katsuo!
Ah...
Please...
Wait!
She got away...
Thank you, Katsuo.
What am I going to do?
Maybe I really should quit golfing...
Do your best, both of you!
I’m gonna hit it!
It’ll be a Sparking Gigavolt Homerun!
I’ll stop you,
with my full body and soul!
The odds that Satoshi will hit a homerun...
Calculating... Calculating...
Here I come!
Right on!
All right!
That’s quite the foul...
It did go really far, but...
Oh, no! The ball’s...
Watch out!
Awesome!
She hit it back?!
Cool...
This lady and her Dodekabashi
pulled off an incredible out of the blue...
Who could they be?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Hole-In-One at Poké-Golf!
Thank you for
sending the ball back!
That was so cool!
It’s fine, Katsuo.
I’m sorry.
This one was just
trying to protect me.
Some reporters were
really bothering us just now...
Um, where am I?
This is the Pokémon School.
Pokémon School?
Yes.
You’re Ms. Kahili, aren’t you?
W-Well... Yes...
Ms. Kahili! I know you!
You’re that amazing pro golfer
from Alola, right?!
I see! That explains that shot!
I’ve seen your name pop up
a lot on the news online!
I’m Mao!
It’s such an honor to meet you!
I’m Satoshi.
Suiren.
My name is Lilie.
I’m Māmane!
I just know Daddy’ll get jealous
when I tell him I met you!
I’m Rotom-roto.
It’s a pleasuroto!
I’m Kaki.
Your super shot shook
my body and soul!
The pleasure’s all mine...
Is this what you
hit the ball with just now?
It’s called a golf club.
I see!
Let me see, too!
Me, too!
And me!
What? Um, oh...
Ah... Thank you.
This is my partner,
Katsuo the Dodekabashi.
Amazing!
It’s helping you out?
It’s like it’s your caddy!
It’s so thin!
I’ve never held one before!
It’s surprisingly heavy,
yet surprisingly light at the same time.
I know!
Um... Ms. Kahili?
If you have time, um...
It’d be nice...
...if we could play Poké-Golf
with you!
Poké-Golf?
Golf played together
with your Pokémon!
It’s the most popular sport
in Alola right now!
Sounds fun!
I wanna try!
I wanna try Poké-Golf!
I want to try, too!
But...
Hey, now, you shouldn’t
make her feel uncomfortable.
Katsuo?
Wait, Katsuo...
Katsuo...
You want to play
with them, too?
All right, I got it!
Let’s play Poké-Golf together!
Thank you! All right!
Thank you so much!
This is great!
All right...
In that case, we’re changing
the afternoon classes to Poké-Golf!
All right!
This is the Poké-Golf course?
It’s enormous!
From beginners
to high-level players...
This place has courses for anyone,
no matter their skill level!
Don’t ruin the grass-roto!
There are Pokémon who
live out on the course.
Oshamari, let’s go!
This is the teeing ground,
where we start.
Thank you.
How can Katsuo tell
which club you should use-roto?
Probably because we’ve been
playing together since childhood.
All right, I’ll go first.
Please show them
how it’s done.
Please!
The rules of Poké-Golf
are simple.
You just have to
hit the ball from here,
and make it go into the cup
in the putting green.
The putting green is
that area over there!
The cup is
where that flag is raised.
What?
All the way over there?!
Seems difficult.
And whoever can get the ball in the cup
with the fewest swings, wins.
But the most important rule of all...
...is that the Pokémon and
their trainer work together!
Hold it!
Me’s the one person you must
don’t forget when you play Poké-Golf!
Who might you be?
Me’s the Poké-Golf Caddy Guru!
A legend with a 40 year
Caddy Guru Life behind me!
Caddy Guru?
Do you know him?
No.
In me’s 50 years of
Caddy Guru Life...
...to clear this course without
me’s help’s been impossible!
You just said it was forty years-roto!
Now that me’s here, you be like
a mighty demon wielding a club of gold!
He ignored me-roto?!
Let’s play!
Let’s go, Katsuo.
That’s Tailwind-roto!
What speed!
It’s a hole-in-one!
It went in...
I knew you could do it,
Ms. Kahili!
Awesome!
I’ve never seen
a hole-in-one before!
Ms. Kahili and Katsuo were
perfectly in sync with each other!
Thank you...
In me’s 60 years of
Caddy Guru Life—
60 years?!
It got even bigger-roto!
Me was the one first to think of
using Tailwind on this Hole 1.
Since then,
everyone’s been copying me.
All right...
Would you all like to try now?
Yes!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Dodekabashi
Type:   Normal/Flying
Right, I’m first!
All I gotta do is hit the ball, right?
What is it, Katsuo?
Are you saying you want me
to give him advice?
Advice? I’m all ears!
Well then... When you swing the club,
try to put your entire body into it.
Something like this.
Um...
Like this?
That’s right!
Right, I got it!
He sure made it fly high...
Oh, of course!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
You did it, Pikachu!
Yes! Mutual trust and
cooperation to hit the ball!
That’s what Poké-Golf is about!
Ms. Kahili, could you please
give me some advice, too?
I suppose.
First, when you aim, try to keep
a shoulders’ width between your legs.
All right.
Yes, like that.
Now swing like
you’re drawing a circle!
Got it?
Yes!
I did it!
Stop!
Xiemi!
I was wondering
where it had gone.
Nice shot!
Not knowing what’s gonna happen is
another thing that makes Poké-Golf fun!
In me’s 70 years of
Caddy Guru Life...
Me’s seen miracles of this sort
many number of times!
The Xiemi that trots about
finds a b—
I’m up next!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame Shot!
...is what I’ll pretend to do,
and then...
Shadow Bone Shot!
Don’t worry!
That was a very good attempt.
Next, try like this...
Okay?
Okay! One more time, Garagara!
It’s on the green!
Well done!
Yup, Poké-Golf really is fun!
Can I hit it right, I wonder?
Calm down!
You can realLilie do it!
A-All right...
I have to make sure the ball
doesn’t hit the Nasshi...
Oh...
One more time!
I can still do this!
You’re far too tense.
Let’s take a deep breath,
together.
Snowball...
Thank you.
I hit it!
Nice shot!
Yes, well done!
Don’t forget how that felt!
For all me’s 80 years of
Caddy Guru Life...
The relaxation through deep breaths be something
me told people to do every d—
The putting green isn’t flat.
You have to really look at the sloping and the grass
in order to aim straight.
I’ll have to calculate...
Um...
The right slope is at
a 1.9 degree incline, so...
Togedemaru,
I’m a bit busy right now.
Great work!
That was a super putt!
Amazing, Togedemaru!
If you’d asked me, with me’s 90 years of Caddy Guru Life
experience, me’d have told you an easier way...
Oshamari! Balloon!
Katsuo?
Katsuo seems to be having fun.
Yes. It’s been a long time since
I last saw it acting like this.
It must have been happy
to see you having so much fun.
Could Katsuo have told me to play Poké-Golf
with these children in order to cheer me up?
Thank you, Oshamari!
Single-Hook Fishing-Style!
Excellent shot!
All right!
Oshamari, use Surf!
It’s on the green!
Great approach!
Thank you very much!
You are quite impressive!
You could be qualified to face
the sealed-off Tenth Hole of Doom!
Tenth Hole of Doom?
The wind is ferocious!
Where is the putting green?
There!
This is the sealed-off
Tenth Hole of Doom!
Is very hard course, yes.
All balls that don’t go into the cup fall into the valley.
How would you beat this hole?
After me’s 99 years and 3 months
of Caddy Guru Life,
the time has finally come
to show me’s seriousness power!
You’ll show us how to do it?
The truth is,
before me becomed the Caddy Guru,
me was the Legend Poké-Golf Guru!
The ideal club for this course is...
...this!
kurabu
Wait, when you said club,
you actually meant Crab,
the Freshwater Crab Pokémon-roto?
It is time...
You were showing us
how to fail-roto?!
Of course!
Even me, with me’s 99 years and 6 months of
Caddy Guru Life, ends up like this if making even one misstep!
Now, you!
You will give it try
since you’s a pro, yes?
The odds of getting the ball into the hole
on this course is 0.00001%-roto.
I accept the challenge!
Ms. Kahili!
We’ll be fine.
Right, Katsuo?
Break leg!
Thank you.
You can do it, Ms. Kahili!
Relax!
Remember to have fun!
I know you’ll be fine!
You can do this!
Don’t hesitate!
Thank you, everyone!
Watch me...
This is Katsuo and my...
...Poké-Golf!
The wind!
Katsuo!
Beak Cannon!
Go!
You did it!
Katsuo!
Me has lived 99 years and 9 months
of Caddy Guru Life...
But on this hole,
what’s left for me to teach you is nothing.
Next, me will wait for you
on the Eleventh Hole of Doom.
If Competitor Kahili
can pull off this putt...
It’s in!
Competitor Kahili wins!
She did it!
Amazing! Just amazing!
Watching children having fun
playing Poké-Golf for the first time...
...reminded me of how I felt
when I first started out.
Pokémon School kids...
I won!
Through playing Poké-Golf
with Satoshi and the others,
Kahili has learned what
the most important thing is.
She’s completely back in the game!
Me will wait for you on
the Eleventh Hole of Doom...
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
The sport played today was Poké-Golf!
Ms. Kahili’s partner, Dodekabashi,
is the Cannon Pokémon and a Normal/Flying type.
Its Beak Cannon ignites the internal gases
within its beak to launch seeds.
It was impressively powerful!
It’s all on you, Warrgle!
We’re not playing catch here...
Well, it’s fine, I guess...
Next episode
Joy and sorrow both are but
a momentary twinkle of a star...
Those who eat,
those who are eaten...
And those who go after
the scraps left behind...
The most dangerous Pokémon,
capable of changing fate, has awakened.
Love... Friendship... Dreams...
All returns to nothing.
As Nyarth dreams
of electric Mareep,
clusters of gallium
bring the brat boy to tears.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Landfall in Alola! Melty Metal Panic!!
No one can stop it now.
Next time
Landfall In Alola!
Melty Metal Panic!!