Ta-dough!
I’ll be giving you today’s PokéProblem!
Blacky
Lugarugan
Silvuddy
Crobat
What Pokémon does Gladio send out
in today’s episode?
Blue: Blacky?
Red: Lugarugan?
Green: Silvuddy?
Or Yellow: Crobat?
Get the answer at the end!
The curtain has raised on
the Alola Pokémon League’s final tournament.
Matches one through four of the first round
have taken place,
and their winners were
Satoshi, Guzma, Hau and Suiren.
Raichu! 100,000 Volts!
All right! We did it!
Aqua Jet!
Amajo! Tropical Kick!
Matches five through eight remain.
Now, who will join these four
in the next round?!
Next up is match number five!
It’s Māmane’s turn-roto!
You’re up against
Ms. Matsurika, right?
Oh, no... I’m so nervous!
Calm down, Māmane.
If you’re nervous,
take a deep breath!
Thank you.
That calmed me down a little.
I can’t wait to battle Kaki!
Me, too!
Let’s make our battle as heated as
Wela Volcano itself!
Great idea!
Big brother.
I have a request.
Request?
Please do not hold back.
I know full well that you are
far more skilled than I am.
Lilie...
Even so...
Snowball and I will face you
with our full power!
So, please use
your full power, as well.
Of course.
That was the plan.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Musashi VS Kojiro!
A Battlefield of Truth and Love!!
The first-ever Champion
of the Alola Pokémon League...
...is Competitor Musasina!
Thank you, thank you!
Thank you, Alola!
What would you say
clinched your victory?
But of course...
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
It was my flawless beauty and skill,
blooming in this fleeting world!
Hey, you!
What are you doing?!
We’re waiting to start an important battle,
and you’re just lazing off?!
No biggie...
There’s plenty of time left.
That’s right, meow.
It’s a battle between Team Rocket members.
We already know who’ll win, meow.
The winner will be me!
Case closed! No objections!
Yeah, but you’re taking it too easy!
You think you can just show up to a battle
looking like that?!
‘s all right,
no worries at all...
And they plunge straight into
an intense air battle!
Go!
Go, go!
Hang in there!
I’ll be sure to
record the battle-roto!
Kuwagannon! Zap Cannon!
So quick!
Very good, Aburibbon!
We can’t do a thing with it
buzzing around like that!
Pollen Puff!
Dodge it, Kuwagannon!
Ms. Matsurika and Aburibbon
are amazing!
Psychokinesis!
Kuwagannon!
All right!
Now for our counterattack!
Zap Cannon!
Dodge it, Aburibbon!
Kuwagannon predicted Aburibbon’s path
and grabbed hold of it!
Signal Beam!
Aburibbon is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Māmane!
The winner of the intense aerial battle
in round 1’s fifth match was Competitor Māmane!
You gave it your all,
Aburibbon.
Thank you.
We won...
Thank you, Kuwagannon!
Ow! That hurts!
Counting on you, meow.
Thank you!
Come again, meow!
Thank you for waiting!
The fighters are entering!
It’s starting, meow.
The sixth match is between
the elegant actress...
...who floats like a Butterfree and
stings like a Spear, Musasina, and...
Um... Wait...
What? Oh, I see.
Excuse me.
We have not received a profile on
Competitor Dekojiro.
What?!
I forgot to send it!
Oh, well...
I’m losing here, anyway.
I’m winning here, anyway.
Um... We will now begin
round one, match six.
Let the match begin!
Hidoide. Spike Cannon.
Sonansu, do a thing!
Good, very good!
Let’s keep this up!
Sludge Bomb.
Do something,
I don’t care what!
Hidoide delivers powerful attacks!
But Sonansu’s perfect defense
deflects them!
A marvelous, heated battle is
unfolding before our eyes!
We’re not...
getting anywhere, are we?!
I... I have to... do something...
Hidoide.
Pretend to be incapacitated.
The way this is going,
the battle’s not gonna end.
So just pretend...
You...
You want a serious battle,
don’t you?
You’re right.
Who wants to lose on purpose?
Got it!
You can leave the rest to me!
Say, is it just me,
or are they acting super weird?
We’re putting all our power
into this next move!
Spike Cannon!
Why is this happening?!
Sonansu!
Sonansu is unable to battle!
So the winner is Competitor Dekojiro!
No way... What about my Champion title?
My victory interview?
You did it, Hidoide!
Don’t do that...
Next up is Kaki and Acerola’s
battle-roto!
I’m rooting for
both of them!
What Pokémon will Kaki send out
against the Ghost-type user Acerola?
Kaki!
You got this!
Bring forth your Pokémon!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ju'niper
Type:   Grass/Ghost
Huge!
That thing is Totem-sized!
I have no data on this-roto!
Acerola went and brought
Greedy Lapoo with her?
So, Kaki chose
the Fire/Ghost-type Garagara...
Ghost types are super effective
on each other.
This might be a short match.
We shall now commence
the seventh match of round one!
Let the battle commence!
Lapoo! Shadow Ball!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
Lapoo! Shadow Punch!
Use Shadow Bone!
Kaki’s Garagara sure is nimble!
Lapoo!
Another Shadow Punch!
Bone Boomerang!
Garagara!
Garagara?
Oh, my!
Garagara has stopped!
This could be Gänger’s
chance to win!
What happened to Garagara?
I got it-roto!
Gänger’s ability is Cursed Body-roto!
Cursed Body disables the moves of
any opponent who touches it-roto!
Lapoo! Use Thief!
It took it?!
His bone was stolen!
Without that,
he can’t use Shadow Bone.
Yeah... Or Bone Boomerang...
Or Flare Drive...
Kaki and Garagara will
figure something out!
Shadow Ball!
Endure it, Garagara!
Shadow Punch!
Garagara... Hang in there
until the disable effect wears off!
One more time!
Now! Iron Head!
Garagara?!
What’s this?
Garagara is nowhere to be seen!
Where could it have gone?!
Looks like he... went inside...
“Went inside”?
Garagara!
All right!
Time to fight back!
Lapoo! Shadow Ball!
Shadow Bone!
Lapoo!
Gänger is unable to battle!
Accordingly, the victor is Competitor Kaki!
Thank you, Lapoo.
That was such a fun battle!
Great job, Garagara!
We’re moving on to round two!
First Satoshi, Suiren and Māmane...
Now Kaki’s moving on to round two as well!
Now, the eighth match...
...is a sibling showdown!
President Lusamine’s son VS her daughter!
Hooray, hooray, Lilie!
Give it your best, Gladio!
Hooray! Yes! Yes!
Little Miss—
Oh, Mother...
Sauboh...
I made it!
They’re just about to start.
Let the battle commence!
Snowball, use Hail!
Let’s do this before she can
boost her defense!
Blacky! Evil Pulse!
Dodge it, Snowball!
She dodged!
Snow Cloak, huh?
You’re growing stronger!
Shadow Ball!
Use Aurora Veil!
Right now, there is only one way
we could possibly win this...
Our Z-Move!
Get ready, Blacky!
Snow silently fluttering down
from the heavens...
Countless glimmering crystals of ice...
O, freezing Z that covers the land...
Along with my heated soul,
return now once more to the heavens!
Raging Geofreeze!
Iron Tail!
Dodge it, Snowball!
Snowball!
Thank you, Snowball...
Rokon is unable to battle!
Accordingly, the victor is Gladio!
Lilie was so great!
As was Young Master Gladio!
That was an excellent battle.
Lilie! Gladio!
Mohn...
How I wish I could show you...
...how well your children
are growing up.
After intense battles, eight competitors
have made it through the first round!
Now for the match-ups
for round two!
Us?!
Hau, huh?
Satoshi!
Hau!
Mokuroh, calm down!
Mokuroh?!
What will happen in
the second round?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon Gladio sent out...
...was Blacky!
The first round of the Alola Pokémon League is over,
and the top 8 have been chosen!
Tomorrow, the second round starts,
and it’ll be even more intense!
Xiemi! Amajo!
Let’s cheer everyone on
with Lilie and Snowball!
It’s finally time to battle Satoshi, huh?
You’re excited, too, huh?
All right!
We’re gonna win our rematch,
for sure!
Next episode
Mokuroh certainly does
sleep a lot.
Watching him
makes me sleepy, too...
Yeah, same...
And me...
Somehow...
Me, too...
Nap time...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
Overcome Ju'niper...
This is no time
to be sleeping-roto!
Next time
Overcome Ju'niper!
It’s time to battle Ju'niper-roto!
Oh, right!