Alola!
It’s me, Kukui!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Shizukumo
Tsutsukera
Ametama
Samehada
Which of these Pokémon
takes a shine to Suiren today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
We are in a deep, deep forest
on Melemele Island.
Within is a brilliantly clear lake.
This Pokémon is Shizukumo,
the Water Bubble Pokémon.
And this is Onishizukumo,
which is known by the same classification.
It is Shizukumo’s evolved form.
The Shizukumo leave their nest
in search of a new home.
Today, let us follow this one.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Shizukumo Gets Suiren!
Without this helmet-like water bubble,
Shizukumo can’t breathe.
On the second day of its journey,
Shizukumo sees the ocean for the first time.
Ashimari! Balloon!
Yes, it’s perfect!
What was that sound?
It came from over there, I think.
It’s a Pokémon.
This is Shizukumo-roto!
Shizukumo?
Oh no!
Suiren?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Shizukumo
Type:   Water/Bug
What’s gotten into her?
Shizukumo. Water Bubble Pokémon.
Bug/Water type.
It crawls onto the land in search of food.
Its water bubble allows it to breathe
and protects its soft head.
What bubble?
The water bubble on its head-roto.
That Shizukumo didn’t have one.
That’s why it couldn’t breathe-roto.
Shizukumo! Shizukumo!
What a relief.
Oh?
Look, Ashimari. It’s all better!
No! Both of you!
Don’t get lost on your way home,
Shizukumo.
How’s Shizukumo?
I heard it couldn’t breathe earlier?
Yeah. But it’s all right now.
That’s good.
And thanks to that balloon,
you were fine underwater.
Yeah. Now I can finally take
a stroll under the sea.
Sounds fun!
Ashimari, put a balloon on me too!
Hey, Bebenom!
Get it back in the water, now-roto!
Shizukumo,
please forgive Bebenom.
All right?
It’s really attached to Suiren.
Her balloon looks like
its helmet,
so there’s a high chance
it sees Suiren as one of its kind-roto.
Could be fun.
Satoshi, it’s about time
to go to school.
Yeah.
Let’s show it to everyone.
So, are you gonna have that
on your head all the time?
Yeah, Shizukumo likes it.
So cute!
It’s sticking to you like glue.
Actually, Suiren, it kinda looks
like Shizukumo’s caught you.
Caught her?
Sounds nice.
Right, I guess Shizukumo’s
joining us for class today, then.
Then we’ll have
lunch and stuff together.
But Suiren, what are you
going to do when eating?
For that, I’ll...
Huh?
What’s wrong, Shizukumo?
It probably can’t recognize Suiren,
now that the balloon’s gone.
What?
Pikachu!
Snowball!
It’s running away!
Oh...
Wait!
What’s this?
Hey, what’s going on?!
It’s Shizukumo!
Shizukumo?
The Water Bubble Pokémon.
It got away.
No, it’s still here!
I get it.
That’s a Shizukumo that’s
just left its nest.
What?
Once a Shizukumo can find food for itself,
it leaves its tribe,
and seeks out waters that it can claim
as its own territory.
That means it might be staying here!
Isn’t that great, Suiren?
After it evolves, it starts looking for others of its kind,
to start its own tribe.
In human terms, the Shizukumo
who first found the territory could be called their king.
King?!
Cool!
Well, that makes Suiren the princess,
since that Shizukumo caught her, right?
Yeah, sounds nice.
Nice?!
Huh? It came out!
Guess it didn’t like the water here.
What a letdown.
How about we help it
find a water hole?
Yeah, that sounds great!
I agree.
We can’t, Satoshi.
A king needs to find his own castle!
That’s a good one, Suiren.
All right, change of plans!
Today’s class will be observing Shizukumo.
All right!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
I gripped my small palms tight
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
Hey!
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
That’s a no-go.
Yeah.
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
He lost!
I choose you!
Don’t laugh, Bebenom!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
That was a serious battle!
Well done!
Incredible!
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Doesn’t it look like he’s happy?
Oh oh!
He’s shooting strings!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
That’s Shizukumo’s move,
Spider Web.
Looks like he’s chosen his territory,
and is starting to build his nest.
You’re my sunshine and I love you
You found it.
It’s Ametama!
This place was taken, too?
Ametama. Pond Skater Pokémon.
Bug/Water type.
It moves as if skating on
the surface of the water.
This is bad. Shizukumo and Ametama
don’t get along.
They often fight over territory.
Just like Habunake and Zangoose!
What will you do, Shizukumo?
That thing is so infuriating!
Shizukumo has to win this
in order to become king!
Yes. That’s a rule of nature!
Not good! That’s a Signal Beam!
Shizukumo!
Good going, Shizukumo!
Ashimari!
Shizukumo!
Shizukumo! Win!
He deflected it!
Mirror Coat?!
It evolved into Amemoth-roto!
The time had come for Ametama
to leave its nest, too!
It evolved and set off
for a new world!
Which means...
The pond belongs to Shizukumo!
Congratulations!
That was amazing!
Tenacity wins the day!
Shizukumo got his territory!
Yes!
Shizukumo, you were so cool!
I wonder how Shizukumo’s
doing now.
I’m sure he’s making a castle...
...to bring Suiren home to.
Sounds lovely. I’ll be a princess
clad in a balloon!
You’re serious?
Just kidding.
Sheesh...
Just kidding about kidding.
Eh? Which was the joke?
That’s a new pattern!
Thus, Shizukumo was able
to get his territory.
But it looks like it’ll take a little longer
before he can get himself a partner.
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon who took a shine to Suiren
was Shizukumo!
The Water Bubble Pokémon Shizukumo
is a Bug/Water type.
It prefers clean water because
it’s easier to store in its bubble helmet.
This helmet doesn’t just serve
to protect its head,
but also to provide it with
oxygen dissolved in water.
Ashimari,
use Balloon on Ho and Sui!
We’re Shizukumo!
Shizukumo! Shizukumo!
Sui
Ho
The Water Bubble Pokémon.
Next episode
Everyone! What’s your favorite bread?
pan
I like yakisoba bread and
croquette bread!
Oh, and...
I like croissants.
Mine’s the cream bread
we make from our Moo-Moo Milk.
Coppépan made with
sweet bean butter.
What about you, Satoshi?
Um...
Pumpjin, Konpang and Sandpan!
panpujin
Figures...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Ta-Dough!
Burn With Passion, Mao’s Family!!
Next time
Ta-Dough!
Burn With Passion, Mao's Family!!