Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Gladio
Joy
Hapu'u
-
I'a
Who does Satoshi battle today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Poni Island.
Satoshi and the others have been
hard at work since early morning...
...on their personal Pokémon School
research projects.
Garagara!
Kaki is training together with
Bakugames and Garagara.
One! Two! One! Two!
Māmane is building up Denjimushi’s strength
to prepare him to evolve.
Mao has gone to the market in order to find ingredients
for her new, Poni Radish-based dish.
Suiren continues fishing for something spectacular,
awaiting the arrival of her master I'a.
Lilie is observing the Pokémon
on Poni Island.
And Satoshi...
Time for a battle!
I won’t lose this time!
...is barging in on Hāpu'u’s house,
hoping to battle her.
Alola, Hāpu'u!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Lugarugan Showdown!
Satoshi VS Gladio!!
Nobody’s here-roto...
Where did Hāpu'u go?
Oh, Satoshi!
Ms. Joy!
Going somewhere-roto?
I’m out for my morning patrol.
It’s part of my job at the Pokémon Center
to help Pokémon who get into trouble.
I see-roto!
Um... Do you know
where Hāpu'u is?
If she’s not in the field,
then she might be at the Ruins of Paradise.
Ruins of Paradise?
O, Kapu-Rehire.
Land God of the water,
who protects our pure island of Poni...
Please, hear my prayer.
Please let the visage and voice of my grandfather,
Sofu'u, appear before me.
Please come to me,
Grandfather!
I wish to continue
in your footsteps.
I wish to be the Island Queen!
What do I lack?
Why does Kapu-Rehire not accept me?
Tell me, Grandfather!
Kerarappa!
Dekagoose!
Kaiross!
Granbull!
So cute!
What is it, Snowball?
That’s good. Keep going!
B-Big Brother!
Lilie?!
Once again,
I received no answer.
Shall we go?
What seems to be the matter,
Banbadoro?
She said it was
just past this stretch, right?
Calm yourself!
Why will you not be still?!
What is the matter with you?!
What has happened?!
Hāpu'u!
Quiet down!
Oh, it is you.
What’s happened to Banbadoro?
I know not!
It simply ran wild out of nowhere!
Danger! Danger!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
Isn’t this...?
Oh? This is a piece
of a Sunnygo branch.
It’s all right now,
Banbadoro.
I see. You must be relieved,
Satoshi, you are a good fellow.
On the other hand, I...
...failed to notice the reason
why my friend was suffering...
Who knows what would have
befallen us had you not arrived?
Oh, of course!
Will you let us
thank you somehow?
Banbadoro is in your debt!
Well, then...
That! That’s it!
T-This is an heirloom
from Grandfather!
You may not have it!
No, that’s not what I mean.
I want a Pokémon battle.
Oh, a mere Pokémon battle?
What brings you to this island,
Big Brother?
I wanted to ask Kapu-Rehire
for a Grand Trial.
What is it?
Satoshi said the exact same thing!
What?!
I see...
Indeed!
I have one other reason for
wanting to meet Kapu-Rehire, too.
Apparently Kapu-Rehire has the power
to let you meet people who have passed on.
I want... to meet Dad.
Thank you, Blacky.
He passed away
in an accident, didn’t he?
While researching Ultra Holes...
I don’t know the details.
I was too young.
It’s just... Dad’s big hand,
patting my head...
I could never forget
how warm it was.
I don’t even remember
that much.
All I know is his face
from the photographs.
I never felt I could ask Mother
about him, either.
Judging by how she tends to react to things,
it just seemed like a question I shouldn’t ask.
Me, too.
But when I heard the legends of Kapu-Rehire
they tell on this island,
I couldn’t stay still.
That’s why I’m training my Pokémon here,
so that I might summon Kapu-Rehire.
If I show Kapu-Rehire the bond I share
with Silvuddy and the others,
I’m sure it will answer my prayers.
Let’s make sure Kapu-Rehire
does answer them!
I’ll be your opponent in battle!
You?
Right, Snowball?
Impressive.
All right, then!
Your grandpa was
the Island King, right?
He must’ve trained you real hard!
Your Golugh was super tough!
C’mon, let’s have
a Pokémon battle!
Argh, be quiet!
I will not do it.
Why?
I do not battle
for mere amusement.
But you fought me yesterday,
remember?
Merely because I thought
you were the radish thief.
Regardless, did you not
come here with your comrades?
Can you not simply battle them?
Well, sure...
But I wanna battle lots of different trainers
to prepare for my Grand Trial!
Grand Trial?
Despite there being no Island King?
I’m thinking of fighting
Kapu-Rehire!
What?
Good idea, right? I thought if I battled Kapu-Rehire,
it might count as having done a Grand Trial!
What’s wrong?
Have you no concept of
what a Grand Trial is?
Of course! You battle the Island King or Island Queen,
then you get a Z-Crysta—
You comprehend nothing!
Hearken! I have watched
Grandfather’s Grand Trials all my life!
A Grand Trial is a grand ritual where an Island King trains
and raises a challenger on behalf of the Guardian Deity!
You wear a Z-Ring despite
not comprehending such a simple fact?!
There’s no need to be angr—
Silence! Go cleanse yourself
and start anew!
Why?!
What did I do-roto?!
Ow...
I’ll break-roto...
Satoshi?!
Lilie?!
Huh?! Gladio’s here, too?! Why?!
You took the words right out of my mouth.
How do you keep falling out of the sky?
Well, I got kicked into the air
by Banbadoro, you see...
All I did was ask for
a Pokémon battle...
She’s so stingy...
Who do you call stingy?!
T-They’re back!
You...!
Run-roto!
Hang on a sec, Hāpu'u!
You insolent child! You comprehend not
what a Pokémon battle even is!
S-Sure I do! Pokémon battles are where you get fired up,
like, wham, then have a burning showdown, like, fwoosh...
That makes no sense!
It’ll make sense if you just try it!
I said I will not!
C’mon, let’s do it!
That’s quite enough!
Who might you be?
This is my first time
properly greeting you, yes?
My name is Lilie.
Satoshi is my classmate.
Oh, how well-mannered you are.
This is my big brother.
His name is Gladio.
I see. It is a pleasure
to meet you both.
Your clothing is quite unsightly.
Shall I mend it for you?
No need.
W-What?!
Have you no manners?!
Would you like to have
a Pokémon battle with me?
For real?!
Is that okay with you, Lilie?
Of course! A battle with Satoshi would be
a far greater and more enjoyable challenge for you!
Besides, Big Brother also
wants to battle Kapu-Rehire!
Huh?
Why must you all be so...?
Hey, Hāpu'u! Please watch
our Pokémon battle!
I’m sure you’ll understand
if you see it!
Good grief...
Satoshi, there’s something
I want to try.
What?
A battle between our Lugarugan.
Wanna try?
Great idea!
That sounds super fun!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Odoridori
..                    (Mai-Mai Style)
Type:   Ghost/Flying
I shall serve as referee.
Sure! Counting on you!
What is that Lugarugan?
Satoshi’s Lugarugan is called
the Dusk Form-roto.
Dusk? I have never
heard of this form before!
It’s a rare case.
One of a kind-roto!
Who is Satoshi?
This battle will be between
Satoshi and Gladio!
It will last until either side’s Pokémon
is unable to continue battling!
Begin!
Let’s go!
Lugarugan, Accelerock!
Counter!
Break through it with speed!
This Counter...
...is quick!
Not bad!
Lugarugan!
It is doing fine!
Despite all the damage he took...
You managed to withstand
our Counter?
You’re something else!
Let’s go!
Another Accelerock!
Remarkable! They are taking
advantage of the terrain!
This is what makes Satoshi
so formidable!
He doesn’t just fight using moves.
He makes everything around him an asset!
Use Bite!
Jump!
What?!
Amazing!
He lessened the damage by taking Satoshi’s
Lugarugan’s attack before they could build up speed-roto!
That boy is quite formidable,
as well...
Your Lugarugan’s changed, too.
Last time, he was so fussy about getting dirty
that he couldn’t even battle properly...
You’ve conquered
that weakness, huh?
Yeah, ‘cause we trained
with Kapu-Bulul!
What?!
Truthfully?!
He and Kapu-Bulul have
shared berries with each other-roto.
U-U-Unbelievable! He is on close terms
with a Guardian Deity?
I must know, who is Satoshi?
You... Lilie, was it?
This battle does indeed appear different
from what I have been taught.
Though I know not
how to describe it...
The trainers are bringing out the pinnacle
of their Pokémon’s strength!
Yes. I have learned a lot
from Satoshi, too...
Like how a Pokémon’s strength and its trainer’s strength
stimulate and heighten each other...
Or how an Island King or Island Queen
will bring this to light during their Grand Trial.
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Crush it!
Impressive!
But we’re not done...
Swords Dance!
That’s...
Reversed Scale!
Accelerock!
There’s no time for him
to fight back-roto!
This is quite the rampage.
They used Swords Dance right before attacking,
so the move’s power has increased!
Use Bite to stop them from moving!
Lugarugan!
Hang in there! Reversed Scale causes confusion
after the user calms down!
That’ll be our chance
to turn the tables!
There! It’s confused!
Now!
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
A Z-Move?!
This is our...
...full power!
Radial Edgestorm!
How’s that?!
It’s snapped out of its confusion!
Good job withstanding that.
Surprised?
We made practical use of Counter!
Counter?
Analysis complete-roto!
After that Reversed Scale caused confusion,
Satoshi used his strongest move
to finish the battle immediately-roto!
But Gladio’s Lugarugan used the impact
from that move to snap out of confusion-roto!
Unbelievable!
He made an all-or-nothing bet?
This would not be possible unless
the Pokémon and trainer fully believed in each other.
I see.
Big Brother fights almost
exactly like Satoshi does!
Now that you’ve just used a Z-Move, you must be exhausted.
You can’t even fight back properly, can you?
You’re awesome, Gladio!
This battle’s great!
Now behold, our new power!
Power?!
Is that...?!
Vividly shining light,
take flight!
Engrave into the battlefield...
...the name of the ultimate fighter!
Ultimate Dragon Burn!
Unbelievable!
Lugarugan is victorious!
Oh, but the defeated party
is also a Lugarugan...
In any case,
this battle is concluded!
Lugarugan, are you all right?
You did well!
Big Brother.
So you’ve obtained a Dragon-Z?
Yeah. It’s not like I’m just
pretending to train.
Gladio!
I won’t lose next time!
I’ll catch up to you in no time!
Got it!
I see...
They are both burning bright.
I knew not that this kind of
Pokémon battle was possible.
This voice...
It cannot be!
Kapu-Rehire...
Kapu-Rehire!
Satoshi and Hāpu'u...
Gladio and Lilie...
Will their wishes
reach Kapu-Rehire?
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you very much for waiting!
Satoshi battled my big brother, Gladio!
Blacky is the Moonlight Pokémon,
and an Evil type.
With its black fur,
it blends into the darkness.
It waits patiently for its foes
to lower their guard.
It’s the perfect partner
for my brother!
Are you staying at
the Pokémon Center, as well?
No. I’ll be camping out here
for a while, training my skills.
Training? Well, then I’ll—
Later.
Next episode
Let’s work hard
and evolve you, Denjimushi!
Denjimushi’s evolving?!
What’ll he become?
He’ll become a Kuwagannon.
Kuwagannon?!
Sounds really strong!
His body will become
black and sturdy...
Withstanding any attacks,
like, pow!
He’ll learn to fly...
Quick, like, zoom!
It’s amazingly powerful, too!
Clang! Kuwagannon-Z, launch!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
There’s the Sea, There’s the Canyon!
Pokémon Evolution Training!!
Satoshi... What kind of Kuwagannon are you imagining?
Next time
There’s the Sea, There’s the Canyon!
Pokémon Evolution Training!!