Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Kuwagannon
Heracross
Kaiross
Tsundetsunde
What does Denjimushi evolve into
in today’s episode?
Blue: Kuwagannon?
Red: Heracross?
Green: Kaiross?
Or Yellow: Tsundetsunde?
Satoshi and the others are on Poni Island
to work on their personal research projects.
What will they be doing today?
I got all kinds of different vegetables
at the marketplace,
so I’m gonna start working on
that new menu item!
I’m gonna keep training
with Bakugames and Garagara!
My brother, Gladio,
went off on his own to train,
so I will keep observing
the Pokémon on Poni Island!
You’re really giving it
your all, Lilie!
No, not at all! I still have
so much more observing I need to do!
What about you, Satoshi?
I wanna battle
strong trainers on this island,
but Hāpu'u just won’t battle me.
You called?
Hāpu'u?!
Materializing like a phantom-roto!
W-What brings you here?
I have some freshly plucked
Poni Radishes from my fields.
I thought to let the
Pokémon here eat some.
I’m sure they’ll be happy to!
What are you folk doing?
We were going over our plans
for our research projects.
Oh?
I’m planning on going
to Vast Poni Canyon.
Canyon?
Here.
Isn’t this...
Yup, it’s near the
Altar of the Sunne!
Oh, there?
Apparently, going here will make it easier for Denjimushi
to evolve into Kuwagannon!
For real?! Why?
I don’t know...
Oh...
Then you don’t know if
he can evolve there or not...
He speaks the truth!
Tales from ages past tell of how
Vast Poni Canyon...
...possesses a mysterious power which
eases Denjimushi’s evolution.
So it is true!
All right, let’s go, Denjimushi!
Time to evolve into Kuwagannon!
Sounds fun! I’ll go, too!
You’ve piqued my interest, too!
There they are!
Master!
Suiren!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
There’s the Sea, There’s the Canyon!
Pokémon Evolution Training!!
‘s been a while!
It really has!
So glad to see ya doin’ well!
Ain’t that the one ya wen write about?
This is Sandy.
‘s a pleasure.
Looks like y’all doin’ well. Great!
Alola!
Wait, where’s Oshamari?
Oh, right here!
Ashirène?! Oshamari evolved?!
Sure wen do!
I didn’t say nothin’,
‘cause I wanted ta surprise ya!
Yeah, what a surprise!
Ashirène?!
Ashirène. Soloist Pokémon.
Water/Fairy type.
It controls its water balloons with song.
The melody is learned from others of its kind...
...and is passed down from
one generation to the next.
Ashirène! Balloon!
Amazing!
Isn’t it lovely?
Yeah! It’s awesome!
Master, please train me!
Well, ‘bout that...
Whaddayaknow, Hāpu'u!
Ya friends with Suiren?
Ya always been on yer own...
Good on ya!
They are mere acquaintances!
You know I'a and Kanoa, Hāpu'u?
The seafolk have resided
on this island since ages long past.
However, I'a and Kanoa here are
constantly roaming back and forth.
We treasure hunters!
We go out ‘n’ find treasure!
Did you find any treasure?!
Yeah, an amazing treasure!
...‘s what I wanna find.
Oh...
And for that purpose,
we set on goin’ on a long journey!
Kanoa dead-set on goin’, so...
I goin’ with ‘im.
Really lookin’ forward ta
lettin’ people in other regions see our show!
We settin’ off
tomorrow morning.
Oh, no...
But we only just met again...
Suiren...
We ain’t got much time,
but wanna train ‘til we go?
How much ya get outta it
depends on ya, though.
Of course! I’ll give it my all!
Good for you, Suiren!
Please do your best.
Of course!
We’ll learn all of Master’s moves!
Won’t we, Ashimari?
All right, see you later!
Train hard!
You, too!
You’re coming with us, Hāpu'u?
I, too, am intrigued about
Denjimushi evolving.
It’s a pleasure to be
working with you, Master!
Well then,
time for lesson one!
Is this really training?
It looks as if they’re just singing...
But it must be.
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Bakugames! Dragon Tail!
We did it!
All right!
I see Satoshi is not the only formidable one...
Kaki, you are as well!
Hey... We’re here today
to make Denjimushi evolve, remember?
Let us battle, too.
Oh, right.
Sorry, I couldn’t help myself.
It’s a Golduck-roto!
All right...
Let’s go, Denjimushi!
Discharge!
Togedemaru, that was
Denjimushi’s battle...
Oh, what am I going
to do with you?
Māmane is not quite there yet...
The place where it’s easier for Denjimushi to evolve
is supposed to be around here...
Huh? The map’s being weird.
Is that not the place which you seek?
A cave?!
I didn’t expect to meet you here!
Long time, no see!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
Yeah!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ashirène
Type:   Water/Fairy
Long time, no see!
Who goes there?!
You guys!
Who are you, again?
I’m Hayate!
From Team Red Meteor!
From the Denjimushi Race,
remember?
Oh, that guy!
What brings you here?
Isn’t it obvious? I’m here to evolve
my red Denjimushi into Kuwagannon!
You, too?
I let you win back then,
but this time, I will be the first
to evolve my Denjimushi!
Can you really pull it off, yo?
Dude...
Did you say something?
Nothing, yo!
Nothing, dude!
In any case, my Denjimushi will be the one to
obtain the Bug Stone and evolve into Kuwagannon!
Bug Stone?
Searching...
What’s that?
Bug Stone... No matches-roto.
You don’t know?
The Bug Stone is a legendary stone that can
make any Bug-type Pokémon evolve!
He told them, yo...
That was top secret info, dude...
P-Pretend you didn’t hear that!
How are we supposed to do that?
Does that stone even exist?
I’ve never heard of it, either.
This is information that Daddy spent
an exuberant amount of money to buy!
I will get it!
Don’t get in my way!
Hayate, I challenge you!
I won’t lose!
Like an Alolan bug to a flame...
The rules are simple:
Whoever evolves their Denjimushi first, wins.
No getting help from the others.
Got it.
Let’s go, Denjimushi!
Togedemaru, this is a challenge that
Denjimushi and I have to do on our own.
Wait with the others.
Satoshi, look after
Togedemaru for me.
Got it. Hang in there, Māmane!
We’re rooting for you!
You wait here, too.
Got it, yo!
I hope he’ll be okay...
How so?
I mean, caves are really dark...
It’s dark... I’m scared...
Later!
Togedemaru always keeps
the light on for me, so I forgot!
You’ll help me in
Togedemaru’s stead?
Thank you...
You can stop now,
Denjimushi.
Now, let’s go!
I see. There’s a strong
magnetic field here...
...which affects Denjimushi...
Wait, where do we go?
Feels like we’ll be
jumped by monsters...
I was right!
Denjimushi!
Master, is this really training?
They just playin’, ain’t they?
What?!
They were just playing...
I thought for sure
it was something more...
Ya know, Suiren...
The ocean unbelievably vast.
But it shows its frightenin’ side
every now ‘n’ then.
You understand, right?
Yes.
As long as ya get that,
then ya be fine.
The ocean teach ya the rest.
The ocean...
The sound of the waves...
The heartbeat of the sea...
Right!
Never forget that rhythm!
I won’t!
Let’s go, Denjimushi!
Use String Shot!
Then a Discharge!
All right! Now’s our chance!
All right! I was faster, after all!
That’s it.
Yes! It’s the exit!
Gah! He’s here already?!
Let’s go, Denjimushi!
No, be careful!
You expect me to fall for that?
I’m falling! I’m falling!
What do we do?
This is...
You evolved!
Amazing, Denjimushi!
I mean, Kuwagannon!
The Bug Stone!
Kuwagannon,
can you go get it?
The Stone!
Here.
My Denjimushi
has already evolved.
I see...
Huh? It’s not evolving!
What? Why?!
This is just me guessing,
but that stone might not have any special powers at all.
The strong magnetic field here is what
caused Denjimushi to evolve.
I hope Māmane is doing all right...
We’d better go check.
Yeah.
Sorry I took so long.
Māmane, you managed to evolve him
into Kuwagannon? Congratulations!
He’s so cool!
Well, yeah!
You did it, Denjimushi!
Kuwagannon. Stag Beetle Pokémon.
Bug/Electric type.
It zips around,
on sharp lookout for an opening.
It concentrates electrical energy within its large jaws
and uses it to zap its enemies.
Bro, are you okay, yo?!
Dude?!
I’m not done!
I’m gonna train and
evolve Denjimushi, too!
Next time, we’ll face off
in a Kuwagannon Race!
We’re leaving.
Sure, yo!
Dude!
Oh, that’s not...
The stairs are over there, yo.
Tell me sooner...
Kuwagannon Race, huh?
Sounds fun!
Yeah! We’ll give it our all!
Won’t we, Kuwagannon?
Māmane is quite formidable, as well.
We’re back!
Everyone!
Welcome back!
I see Denjimushi was able to
evolve into Kuwagannon!
W-Well, yeah!
Congratulations,
Kuwagannon!
Perfect timing! Then we’ll make this dinner
a celebration of Kuwagannon’s evolution, too!
Looks delicious!
Let the farewell party
for I'a and Kanoa...
...begin!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Thank ya, everyone!
Lemme show ya my thanks!
Ashirène!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
Here we go!
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
The sound o’ driftin’ waves...
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
Deliver the singin’ voice
o’ the vast ocean!
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
Amazing!
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
I can’t believe they can make
such a huge balloon...
It’s shining in all the colors
of the rainbow...
You were the one who taught us
They truly have gotten
more formidable...
Yeah, haven’t they?
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Sea God’s Symphonia!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
Awesome!
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
It’s like a scene from a dream!
Step forward!
Amazing!
It’s beautiful!
I got it all on camera-roto!
Sea God’s Symphonia...
What an amazing Z-Move!
Sea God’s Symphonia is a Z-Move
ya ain’t usin’ without evolvin’ to Ashirène.
Keep trainin’ hard so
ya can use it, too!
Yes!
I want to show Master
the best we can do right now...
Don’t you, Ashimari?
Let’s train!
What? Where’s Suiren?
Maybe she doesn’t want
to say goodbye.
I’ll go look for her!
Master!
Suiren?
This is our best!
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Bigger!
She’s singing...
Good, Ashimari!
You evolved...
Amazing, Ashimari!
You’ve worked so hard!
Master, this is our best!
Yeah, thanks for showin’ me!
We’ll keep training, so that someday
we can use Sea God’s Symphonia, too!
Ya can do it!
Here! An Ashirène-Z!
What? But isn’t this your Crystal?
It fine. I found that one
divin’ in the ocean!
I look forward ta
seein’ yar Z-Move.
Thank you so much!
Denjimushi has evolved into Kuwagannon,
and Ashimari has evolved into Oshamari.
Māmane and Suiren’s evolution projects
have certainly paid off!
Wonderful!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
Denjimushi evolved into Kuwagannon!
The Stag Beetle Pokémon Kuwagannon
is a Bug/Electric type.
It produces electricity via
an electrical organ in its abdomen.
He’s gotten super cool,
but his nature is still as mild as it was
when he was a Denjimushi.
It appears that
I'a and Kanoa have set off...
Take care of yourselves.
Next episode
Hello! This is the new
comedy duo, Satoshi and...
...Kaki!
By the way, who’s the funny man?
You callin’ me funny?!
Not like that!
So who’s the straight man?
Street man?!
You callin’ me a beggar?!
Straight man!
If you want strong seasoning,
then Poni Radishes are the best there is!
Hāpu'u!
Wait, were we actually
a comedy trio?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Run, Kaki! Surpass Yourself!!
It is quite fun,
making merry with you all.
Next time
Run, Kaki! Surpass Yourself!!