Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Principal Okido
Index Rotom
Lilie
James
Who writes the script for
the play we perform today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Have some delicious
Kiteruguma brand doughn—
What?
Musashi,
the doughnuts are done!
Honey...
So sweet and yet so strong.
It fills in the hole that was
torn open in my heart...
So wonderful!
That’s right! Truly, this must be...
My Sweet Honey!
All right,
here’s your Sweet Honey.
No! It’s a line!
A line from a play!
This flew at me.
What’s that?
There’s so much text!
Can’t you tell? It’s a script!
Now, let us depart!
“Depart”?
I am an actress.
On the stage is where you’ll find me!
This means...
Yeah.
There’s no stopping her now.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Liliel the Hero
and the Scepter of Alola!
Today, the class is putting on a play!
What sort of play will it be?
The curtain is just about to rise!
Perfect!
That’s not right...
That’s better, I think.
O, Guardian Deities of Alola!
Deities... Guardian Deities...
Amajo, when I give the signal,
you hand her the scepter.
At this part here,
you use Bubble Beam.
Oh, sorry!
You don’t have to do it now.
Huh... Where’d my script go?
Don’t tell me
you forgot it-roto?
Sheesh... Then use mine-roto.
Thanks, Rotom!
Is everybody ready-roto?
Your families are here to watch you today,
so you’d better give it your all-roto!
Huh?
You mean Mom’s here, too?
Does Dad really have time for this?
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
Thank you for taking such
good care of Satoshi!
I should be thanking you,
Satoshi’s mother!
Lilie and I owe your son
so much for all he’s done!
Gah! She is here!
Now I’m nervous!
Everybody! Sorry for the wait.
I offer my sincerest apologieShimama!
It’s showtiMarill!
There she is! It’s Lilie!
A long, long time ago,
when Alola had lost the power of the earth...
A lone young hero rose up!
Your Majesties!
I, Liliel, have come!
Hero Liliel.
I, King Māmamamamāne,
address you on behalf of the people!
Oh, my!
Māmane’s the king!
Yeah, that’s amazing!
Go gather the power of the Legendary Pokémon
into the Scepter of Alola!
Scepter of Alola?
Queen Amajo, the scepter.
Very well.
Hero Liliel,
please take this scepter.
Amajo! Give Lilie the scepter!
Oh! So this is
the Scepter of Alola!
It’s going great-roto!
I’m next, right?
That’s right-roto!
I’m counting on you-roto!
See that, Bari-chan?
That’s Satoshi!
Your line’s up next,
right, Lilie?
I can’t play my part before
all the Kapu are in place!
Where’s Māmane?
He’s still changing!
Māmane, hurry-roto!
I am!
Hang in there-roto!
O, Guardian Deities of Alola!
Bestow upon me your power!
Pokémon of Alola,
Pokémon of Alola...
Satoshi! Hang in there!
What was the line?
Pokémon of...
Oh, that’s right!
Pokémon of Alola!
Heed our call!
Heed us and assemble!
And dance!
Everyone, follow our lead.
Ready, and...
You’re doing great, Ashimari!
Keep it up-roto!
All right, this is it!
My name is Kakigaleo!
I am the Legendary Pokémon!
Kakigaleo is so cool-roto!
They just have to really nail this scene,
and we’ll be at the finale-roto!
Oh, so you are Kakigaleo!
Hero Liliel, you have done well
to make it this far!
We’re getting out of here as soon as
Musashi’s had her fun, got it?
I know, meow.
The stage is so grand...
Kakigaleo!
Can I truly entrust it all to you?
You needn’t worry...
What’s that-roto?
Awesome! It’s Lunala!
Lunala! Solgaleo!
Solgaleo! Lunala!
I am the emissary of Lunala,
Musabarbara!
Now, Kakigaleo... Together,
let us bestow our power upon the Hero Liliel!
There’s nothing like this
in the script!
What’s going on, Rotom?!
We have to lower the curtains
for a bit-roto!
That concludes act one-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Amajo
Type:   Grass
This is where the show begins!
A show for me, and me alone!
Who are you?!
When asked “Who are you?!”...
Let me tell you my name!
A star actress...
...playing to a full-booked theatre!
Whoever called and whoever they called for,
on the stage is where you’ll find me!
And they call me...
...the great actress...
Musabarbara!
Great actress?
Did you call her, Rotom?
I didn’t call anyone-roto!
It was the stage that called me!
Hey... What’s going on?
The script didn’t have
any appearances by Lunala, did it?
No.
My script goes on!
This script’s nothing but
Musabarbara lines-roto!
Of course it is!
I’m the star of this play, after all!
Then it won’t be
our play anymore!
Lilie was so cool!
I can’t wait for act two!
How about you, Bari-chan?
What do we do?
Leave it to me-roto!
I’ll write a continuation-roto!
Continuation?
My database contains
over forty thousand stories-roto!
I’ll use those as reference material
to power this play up into a thrilling spectacle-roto!
But for that purpose,
I would want some more actors-roto.
Are there any around-roto?
How about Professor Kukui?
He’s in charge of lighting,
isn’t he?
How about Principal Okido?
I’m so happIwanko!
I can be counted oNasshi!
Wish me lucKucheat!
Now?!
I’m not prepareDeathkan!
Um... Isn’t there anyone else?
There!
Continue! Continue!
Hurry! Hurry!
It’s time to continue, everyone.
Please give a round of applauSaidon!
There!
Now, come at me!
If you can hit my pitch,
I will grant your wish, meow!
What’s that?
There’s been a crime, there’s been a crime,
there’s been a crime!
Nobody move!
The one who committed this crime
was smart indeed-roto!
Who are you?!
I, Alolan Detective Rotom,
will get to the bottom of this case-roto!
The emissary of the sun
illuminates the darkness!
I, Kakigaleo,
will bring the truth to light!
You needn’t worry...
My big line was
interrupted again!
I, Musabarbara,
will handle this case!
Solving this case
is my role-roto!
This has taken a crazy turn!
Yeah!
Oh, no! If nothing is done,
something dreadful will befall Alola!
Somebody, shine light upon Alola!
Well then, leave it to me!
Who was that?!
I-I am Satoshizma!
I will shine at full power!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Searching... Searching...
Hey, is this the next part?
No, a bit earlier.
The part with Pikachu!
Thanks, Māmane!
Rotom...
The rest of the script’s blank.
What’s going on?
I’m writing it now-roto...
I wonder how many acts are left?
Next!
Nex-
Where did the hero Liliel go-pika?
I need to find her,
or she’ll fail Satoshizma’s challenge-pika!
Game!
You shall not pass-game!
Only if you can defeat me,
may you pass-game!
I can’t defeat him
like this-pika!
I have no choice...
Pikachu!
This way!
Pika!
Pikachu got bigger!
Huge! Huge!
How do you like this-pika?!
Game! I have lost-game!
You may pass-game!
Pika!
Now, I must hurry-pika!
Good, Pikachu!
You were great, Bakugames!
Now, the climax is
about to begin-roto!
Get ready-roto!
Leave it to the natural-born
actress, Musabarbara!
Meow!
I will stop you!
Go, Toge-Denji Robo-Police One!
G-Good break...
Take this! Flare Drive!
Bubble Beam!
I have waited for this moment.
Musashi!
That’s gotta be enough, right?!
That’s right, meow! We gotta get out
before they figure out who we are, meow!
No. I will not leave the stage
before the curtain has fallen.
An actress cannot leave the stage before
she has bathed in the applause and cheers of her audience...
...no matter what!
Good grief...
Guess we’ve got no choice but to
indulge Musashi’s dreams ‘til the end, meow...
Musabarbara, you’re up-roto!
I’ll be right there.
Yo, Musashi!
You’re the best in Alola!
The best in the universe!
Hero Liliel! You have done well
to overcome my challenges!
I shall grant your wish!
Thank you, Satoshizma!
O, emissary of the moon,
Musabarbara!
Bestow upon me your power!
Indeed. I am an actress...
The flower of the stage!
I will bloom beautifully
for this moment!
Hero Liliel,
raise your scepter skyward!
Grant me the power of the moon!
Magnificent-roto!
She really is a great actress!
You did it, Musashi!
You’re so cool!
I’m overwhelmed with emotion
right now, meow!
Thank you so—
It can’t be...
Now go, Hero Liliel.
I shall return to the moon.
Thank you, Musabarbara.
Musabarbara...
...flew...
...off...
...roto!
Ah... Alola is so grand...
What even is this feeling?
Everybody!
Alola has been saved!
And thus it was that Alola reclaimed the
power of the earth, and peace fell upon the land!
And they all lived
happily ever after!
Satoshi, you were so cool!
You should have told me
you’d be here!
Lilie, you’ve done so well!
Mother...
Now, it’s time for your
curtain call-roto!
Everyone...
Thank you so much!
Things may not have gone
entirely according to plan...
But all’s well that ends well!
And a good play
is a good play!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thanks for waiting!
It was Rotom who wrote the script!
Satoshi’s Index Rotom has features like
voice sampling and video playback...
It sure has grown a lot,
hasn’t it?
Extending the script on the fly
must have been tough, right Rotom?
What’s up, Rotom?
I’m plotting out the
next play-roto!
My next work will be
a grand sci-fi epic-roto!
For real?! Sounds great!
A masterpiece is born-roto!
You’re supposed to be
cleaning up!
S-Sorry...
Next episode
Acerola, is this how
you want the curtains?
Hmmm... A bit closer together.
Hey, who left a camera here?
Sorry, I’ll move it right away!
Hey, where are the Namakobushi?
Suiren’s gone to catch them.
Sorry for the wait!
I hauled in a ton!
Now we’re good to go!
All right! It’s time for
the haunted house to open!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Ghost Pokémon Outbreak!
A Haunted House for Everyone!!
Happy Pumpjin!
Next time
A Ghost Pokémon Outbreak!
A Haunted House for Everyone!!