Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Good luck!
Pokémon
School
Lilie's house
Ten Carat Hill
-
Mamane's house
Where does Nebby’s Teleport
send me to today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
We went to the Aether Foundation
after being invited there by Mother.
It was a lot of fun,
since everyone was there.
It was quite startling when the runaway Metamon
transformed to look exactly like Snowball,
but I was relieved that we found it.
That being said, Mother keeps
treating me like a baby.
I must get her to stop doing that!
This is how I feel right now.
Sparkly clean!
Pika Pika!
I know, right, Pikachu?
That looks quite comfortable-roto.
There you go...
Nebby, the foam’s just as fluffy as you are.
All right, Pikachu’s done.
Cold!
Now then, next up is...
Hey, Nyabby!
Owww... Okay, I got it.
You’re up next.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Gladio and Silvuddy!
The Confinement Mask!!
I’ll make you sparkly clean,
and you’ll look even cooler!
Stop, stop! Don’t do that!
Despite being a Rock type,
this Lugarugan loves shampoo and water.
Data updated-roto!
Does that feel good, Lugarugan?
Ta-daah!
What is this-roto?
It’s Pikachu. Aren’t I good?
It looks nothing like him-roto.
Well then, how about this?
It’s Nyabby!
It’s no different
from the last one-roto.
Aw, man... Now you’ve done it.
Hey, are you all right, Lugarugan?
Lugarugan,
I’ll have you clean in a second!
He’s worked up to the max-roto!
Hey, cut it out!
I said cut it...
Owww!
That scared me...
But you got a bit too angry.
Nyabby didn’t do it on purpose.
Why did Lugarugan
get so angry-roto?
Well, he’s proud of his mane,
and it got dirty.
You’d be angry too if
your Laki wig got dirty, right?
Understood-roto!
I’m pretty proud of
your evolved form.
Ow...
Stay still. I’ll be done soon.
I’m sure Gladio would be surprised
if I showed you to him.
I wonder how he’s doing.
It used Teleport again-roto.
Ow...
Kaiross?!
I’m very sorry!
Air Slash!
That startled me...
Gladio?!
Thanks, you saved me!
What is that thing? A Pokémon?
Well, now you’ve seen it...
Hey...
Could that be...?!
There, there, there...
Gladio! Please do something
about that thing!
Calm down, Silvuddy.
It’s all right.
Thanks, Pikachu.
Satoshi...
Isn’t that an Ultra Beast?
You know about the Ultra Beasts?
Why is it with you?
It’s a dangerous creature!
It’s not dangerous at all!
Do you even realize
what the Ultra Beasts are?!
Gladio?
I made a promise
that I’d look after it...
...to Solgaleo and Lunala.
Solgaleo and Lunala?!
The Legendary Pokémon?!
Yeah! Or, well,
it was in a dream.
I was just at home,
thinking about you.
And then Nebby brought me here.
The Ultra Beast teleported you?
Yeah.
I wanted you to meet this guy.
It’s neither Midnight Form
nor Midday Form, huh.
Yeah. Cool, isn’t it?
We call it the Dusk Form.
Owww... That hurts, cut it out!
Lugarugan!
Where are we?
Ten Carat Hill. It’s a great place
to avoid being seen by people.
You should go see Lilie
every now and then.
She’s doing well.
The other day,
she managed to touch Pikachu.
She’s taking good care
of Snowball, too.
Big Brother!
Snowball, this is my brother, Gladio.
Oh, that Pokémon.
What’s more, Lilie was the one
who gave Nebby its name.
Nebby...
I can’t believe she
named an Ultra Beast.
Why?
I guess I should tell you.
Lilie became unable
to touch Pokémon...
...because she was
attacked by an Ultra Beast.
I was too scared
to be able to help Lilie.
The one who saved us back then...
...was Silvuddy here.
But the terror she felt then
cast a deep shadow on Lilie’s heart,
and after that, she was
no longer able to touch Pokémon.
She’s never said anything about that.
It must have been so terrifying,
it caused her to suppress the memory.
I will never let Lilie experience such horror again.
I will protect her!
That’s right. I’m different from
how I was back then.
I’ve become a Pokémon Trainer.
I’ve become strong with these guys.
All for the sake of defeating
every last Ultra Beast.
They bring calamities
upon humankind.
They must not be allowed
to exist in this world.
Nebby is no exception.
No way! Nebby is different!
Can you say that for sure?
If Nebby ever shows any signs
of its Ultra Beast nature...
I will bring it down.
Together with this guy.
With Silvuddy?
Silvuddy is a Pokémon who was
made to take down Ultra Beasts.
It was made?!
I can’t give you the details,
but nobody can know about this guy.
So that’s why you’re out here?
You just showed up uninvited
in the middle of our training.
Sorry.
But I’m sure there must be some meaning
behind you showing up here with that Ultra Beast.
What are you?!
W-What? I’m Satoshi from Mas—
Why did Solgaleo and Lunala
entrust you with an Ultra Beast?
Why did Mom accept it?
Why did she think that Ultra Beast
wouldn’t be dangerous in your care?
What was her reasoning?!
And there’s more.
What about that Lugarugan?
What is so special about you?
What sort of effect do you
have on Pokémon?!
Hang on a second!
You’re confusing me
with all these questions!
Oh, I know! How about this?
We could battle!
Battle?
You want to know about me, right?
Then let’s battle!
You can learn about me through a battle!
What bizarre logic.
It’ll make good training
for Silvuddy, too.
Besides, we didn’t get to finish
our battle last time.
Team Rocket got in the way.
You’re right.
Well, Silvuddy?
Do you want to try?
Isn’t that great, Lugarugan?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lugarugan
..                        (Dusk Form)
Type:   Rock
This is strange-roto... Satoshi and the others
don’t seem to be coming back-roto.
There’s a high chance they’re on
a grand adventure like last time-roto.
In this case...
Resolution rate: 100%!
Alolan Detective Rotom’s deductions...
...are never wrong!
The only article remaining
on the crime scene is this brush.
I predict that this will be
a challenging case indeed-roto.
My dear Nyabby,
don’t just sleep!
I want you to work as
my excellent assistant-roto!
He’s not motivated at all-roto.
Aaah!
Today’s the live broadcast of “Alolan Detective Laki:
Viewers’ Choice Clipshow”-roto!
There’s no point to these audience participatory events
if you don’t watch them in real time-roto!
We must make haste-roto,
my dear Nyabby!
Lugarugan, I’m counting on you.
What do you think
about that Lugarugan?
Yes... Its eyes are
even sharper than before.
Very well!
You will let me gauge its strength!
You stand before the sacred beast
bearing the mask of confinement!
Silvuddy! Go!
Gladio! This is Silvuddy’s first battle
against a Pokémon who has a trainer, right?
Yeah.
All right, I’m the first!
Is that really worth celebrating?
Being the first at anything is great!
What a strange guy you are...
All right, let’s go, Lugarugan!
Rock Throw!
Double Attack!
Raise your Attack!
Use Swords Dance!
Be careful! Here it comes!
All is to defeat the Ultra Beasts.
Tear them to shreds
with Break Claw!
Draw them closer!
Attack with Bite!
Lugarugan!
It’s faster than I expected.
Air Slash!
Accelerock!
Not bad.
A good offense is
the best defense!
Go! Use Bite!
Double Attack!
N-Not good! This again!
Hey...
You’re good to go,
huh, Lugarugan?
Use Accele—
Lugarugan!
Looks like that Lugarugan
still has a lot of growing to do.
Wait, you two.
Let’s see how it goes.
Stop, stop! Stop!
Calm down, Lugarugan!
I’ll wash you in a moment!
You haven’t raised it
well enough, I see.
So this is the Dusk Form’s power.
I only just found out
he gets like this...
When his fur gets messed up,
he gets blinded by rage!
Are you all right, Lugarugan?
Aren’t you glad you’re clean again?
I’m sure Nebby
didn’t want you to lose it.
Good, that’s more like it.
All right... There, there...
Should we stop the battle?
Oh, sorry. Let’s keep going!
What just happened
didn’t have anything to do with the fight.
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
Silvuddy, let’s finish this
in one hit!
Swords Dance!
Accelerock!
We’re not done!
Another Accelerock!
Break Claw!
It’s over.
Lugarugan!
Come back.
I see. I understand
who you guys are now.
Right? We’re just us.
This was a good experience
for Silvuddy.
I see.
We both have it rough.
Your Lugarugan and my Silvuddy.
They both have troublesome habits.
It’ll take quite a while before
we can grow to be truly strong.
Right! So let’s battle a lot more
and grow stronger!
See you.
Gladio,
let’s battle again sometime!
Oh, right.
Promise me one thing.
Don’t tell anyone that
you met me and Silvuddy today.
I see.
Especially not Lilie.
Promise me. I’m asking because
I trust you to keep your word.
All right.
Right, let’s go home too.
Wait...
How do we get home from here?!
You’re asleep?!
Wake up!
Please take us back home!
Please, Nebby! I’m begging you!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Ten Carat Hill!
Gladio said the Pokémon with him,
Silvuddy,
was created to defeat Ultra Beasts,
but I’m not sure I get it.
Silvuddy sure was strong though.
My Lugarugan put up a good fight, but still...
How frustrating.
You’re back-roto!
We finally made it...
Where were you-roto?
Ten Carat Hill...
We only made it back
thanks to Lugarugan...
Thanks, Lugarugan...
Next episode
Smile, Ms. Lilie.
Show me a tender smile.
All right. Like this?
Good! You look like an angel! Next!
A photo of you on the beach,
turning around and grinning!
V-Very well.
Oh, how lovely!
What’re you doing, Lilie?
T-This is, well, um...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Strike a Full Power Pose for a Sleepover!
Now, please smile, Ms. Lilie!
Next time
Strike a Full Power Pose
for a Sleepover!
Enough!