Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Paradise Resort
Kaki’s family farm
The TV station
Bebenom’s world
Where do we go today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s time to begin!
Alola Pokémon Quiz!
Time for Group A’s preliminary round!
The first to hit the button gets to answer!
It looks like Māmane is participating in a quiz show on TV today,
and that Satoshi and the others
are here to cheer him on.
All right, question one!
What is Alolan N—
Tsutsukera!
Mr. Kuwashi!
10.9 meters!
Correct!
Thank you.
So quick!
I knew it’d be intense. This show’s filled with people
who take pride in their knowledge on Pokémon.
They’ve gotta be tough.
Hang in there, Māmane!
You’ll get the next point!
Now it’s time for question two!
Which Pokémon’s footprint is this?
Togedemaru!
Mr. Māmane!
Nemush!
Correct!
All right!
Thank you.
That’s it! Keep it up!
Now, Mr. Kuwashi and Mr. Māmane
are both sitting at nine correct answers!
Whoever gets the next one correct
clears the preliminary round!
And here’s the question:
Alolan—
Togedemaru!
Tsutsukera!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A New Series?!
A Tiny Koiking’s Melody
You were so close, Māmane.
What a bummer...
Thank you.
You pushed the button first,
right, Togedemaru?
But you really were a star today!
Māmane, you really stood out,
so tomorrow people might start
asking for your autograph!
W-Well... Yeah!
Now there’s the Māmane
we know-roto!
Oh, my dear Rotom!
How are you?
Long time, no see-roto!
Friend of yours?
But of course! This man is none other than
the producer of Alolan Detective Laki-roto!
How are you?
I’m George Charanpino!
So pleased to meet you!
You make
Alolan Detective Laki?!
Amazing!
By the way, my dear Rotom...
What brings you to Alola TV today?
My friend was participating
in a quiz show-roto!
Oh, I see! I thought for sure...
...that you’d decided you wanted
to be in Alolan Detective Laki again!
But he lost in the preliminaries,
so we’re just about to leave-roto.
I see. That’s a shame.
In that case...
They’re shooting a drama nearby.
Care to come and see?
What?! Yeah, for sure!
Can we really?
Of course you can!
Think we’ll get to meet a star?
I’ll be taking
plenty of photos-roto!
Don’t do anything
too embarrassing.
So cute!
Over there.
What? Who is it?!
Ah! That’s...
Koiking?
I-I-It’s Li’l Koi-roto!
W-Wh-What?!
Li’l Koi? Someone famous?
Satoshi, you don’t know
about Li’l Koi?
Li’l Koi is a Koiking child actor prodigy!
Koiking child actor?
The ongoing TV drama that Li’l Koi stars in,
“A Tiny Koiking’s Melody”...
...is a super high-profile series, and it’s said that
Li’l Koi’s acting has moved all of Alola to tears!
You sure know
a lot about this, Kaki...
My little sister, Hoshi,
is a huge Li’l Koi fan!
Li’l Koi’s acting during
the crying scenes is incredible!
Like the acting during the scene
where he was reunited with his mother...
His adorable high voice there really
tugged at your heartstrings!
And unlike other Koiking,
Li’l Koi doesn’t just flop around when using Splash...
He flops around while spinning-roto!
He became popular because of
how cute he looks when doing that-roto!
He can do that?! Awesome!
I can’t believe I get to watch
Li’l Koi’s acting up close!
You don’t get chances like these often!
Rotom.
Take some pictures. For Hoshi.
You got it-roto!
Stop!
No unauthorized photos!
I’m sorry-roto!
Talk about intense...
She’s Li’l Koi’s manager.
Manager?
The one who looks after Li’l Koi.
He’s got people looking after him?
Li’l Koi.
It’s time to film the scene where you part ways
with your friend, Youngoose. Break a leg!
We’re just about to start filming,
so everyone please be quiet.
Looks like they’re starting!
Listen up, Satoshi!
You’d better burn Li’l Koi’s acting
into your retinas, okay?!
Yeah, I got it...
Well then, let’s go!
Let us hear your beautiful voice, Li’l Koi!
Ready, and... Start!
Blargh!
Cut!
What’s wrong, Li’l Koi?
Let’s try that again!
His body just glowed.
Really?
Sure you didn’t just
sense his superstar aura?
Li’l Koi, let’s hear
your usual, cute voice...
Let’s try one more time.
What’s wrong with Li’l Koi?
Does he have
a cold or something?
Director!
We need a little break!
Let’s go, Li’l Koi!
Oh, w-wait...
Think Li’l Koi’s not feeling well?
Oh, my! I’m afraid
I’ll have to take my leave.
I’ve got a shoot to get to.
Thank you very much!
Mr. George, we’ve got trouble!
Why are you so riled up?
The lead actors from TriDri
just said they can’t make it to the studio!
Why not?
Apparently, their last job was
a shoot in the Sinnoh Region,
but then a Yukinooh and
Yukimenoko started fighting,
and they caused a blizzard that’s
grounded their flight!
We have to film today, or there’s no way
we’ll have the program ready for its air date!
Mr. George, if we don’t do something,
we’ll have to do a rerun of “Alola King!
The Royal Battle to Calm Down Archeos” instead!
What do we do?!
Sounds like there’s trouble-roto.
Yeah.
Good! No worries!
Nothing gets your blood rushing more
than some unexpected trouble!
Moments of crisis...
...present a grand opportunity
to create something new!
All right...
That’s it!
Yeah!
Let’s make a drama with you three
as the main characters!
Us?
Main characters?
What’s that all about?
Well, you see...
The program we were going to film
stars three girls!
And we want these adorable Pokémon
to appear alongside you, too!
But my only acting experience
is being in the School play...
You would be better off
finding someone else...
No, we want you three!
I’d like to try! It sounds fun!
Well then, I’m joining, too.
What about you, Lilie?
It’s your chance
to meet a new you!
V-Very well!
That settles it!
Let’s get right to rehearsing!
I can’t believe they all agreed...
Mr. George sure makes some
pretty bold decisions...
This is far too bold,
even for him-roto!
Lucky them!
I wanna be on TV, too!
Attention!
We’re starting filming again.
Please be quiet.
Is Li’l Koi all right?
He’s fine now!
Aren’t you, Li’l Koi?
Li’l Koi, just do it like
you normally do, okay?
Ready, and... Start!
He glowed!
He definitely glowed!
H-He evolved into Gyarados...
Li’l Koi...
Wait, Li’l Koi!
Let’s chase after him, too!
Yeah!
Li’l Koi, it’s me!
Please, wait!
Guess today’s shoot is canceled.
All right, here we go!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Koiking
Type:   Water
Yes... You’re fantastic!
So beautiful!
Musabarbara, this audition will change
your very acting life, meow!
I’m quite aware, Manager.
So, what sort of work
is this audition for?
A 12-hour drama made to commemorate
the 55th anniversary of Alola TV.
It’s a real high-profile piece, meow!
Amazing!
But...
There sure are a lot of
buff Pokémon here, don’t you think?
Well, it’s a high-profile piece
after all, meow!
Yup. A real high-profile piece!
Number 634, it’s your turn.
Got it!
It’s finally your turn,
Musabarbara, meow.
My Alola Region debut...
Act 1: The Star Arrives!
By the way,
what kind of story is “TriDri”?
The full title is
“The Sparkling Trio is Alola DrinKyun”!
It doesn’t look like it’s
ringing any bells for you, huh...?
“Alola DrinKyun”?
Never heard of it...
They’re a group of three girls who
protect the peace in Alola!
Having a drink enables them
to transform!
Oh, so they’re superheroes?
That’s right.
Here are your scripts.
And here’s one for you.
Now then,
let’s get rehearsing!
Ready, and... Start!
Th-The thrill of pink!
The thrill of blue!
N-No, wait,
it was “twinkle,” not “thrill”!
The radiance of yellow!
Of yellow!
The sparkling trio unites!
Alola DrinKyun!
Good! No worries!
Let’s try that one more time!
Yes!
Didn’t you notice that
he was about to evolve?
I did think his whiskers
had grown longer as of late...
But I didn’t think it was
because he was evolving!
My cute Li’l Koi!
Not good!
They’re filming something over there!
Hi, this is Ana, coming to you
from in front of Alola TV!
It’s time for the afternoon—
Hold it!
Oh, no!
He went inside
the building-roto!
We’re back for
the Alola Pokémon Quiz’s final round!
Mr. Kuwashi only needs
one more correct answer to win!
And here comes the question!
Which Pokémon’s
silhouette is this?
Tsutsukera!
Mr. Kuwashi!
Gyarados!
And the answer is...
Wait, Li’l Koi!
Correct!
Congratulations!
The thrill of pink!
The twinkle of blue!
The radiance of yellow!
The sparkling trio unites!
Alola DrinKyun!
Good! No worries!
You’ve got this scene down perfect!
All right!
Now, let’s move on to the next scene.
Of course!
Wh-What?
Gyarados! So cool!
Suiren!
Are you all right, everyone?
Oh! Li’l Koi!
How could you tell it was Li’l Koi,
even after he’d evolved into Gyarados-roto?
I mean, nobody but Li’l Koi
flops around quite like that!
Amazing!
You’ve gotten so big!
You were this tiny
when I first met you!
So, you’ve evolved!
Good! No worries!
We still have some time left
before we start filming.
Could you all help me out?
It’s starting!
Th-The day has finally come...
I-I’m so nervous!
Me, too.
I can’t wait to see how it turned out.
This is so exciting!
The Sparkling Trio is Alola Drinkyun!
Oh, no! I’ll be late!
What took you so long?
I’m sorry!
We have to get going,
or the teacher will yell at us!
Hurry!
You all did great!
D-Did we really?
You’re naturals!
Glad to hear it!
What?
What is this?
What if someone falls in?
Who could have done this?!
It’s Li’l Koi!
Li’l Koi! Moments of crisis...
...present a grand opportunity
to create something new!
Gyarados Devil!
So, this was your doing?!
Unforgivable!
Everyone, please help us out!
DrinKyun! Let’s gulp!
A sweet aroma fills the air...
A sweet, shocking pink heart!
Tea DrinKyun!
Refreshingness!
The best!
Lightness!
Is that the truth?
The refreshing truth!
A cold, refreshing blue heart!
Soda DrinKyun!
Do you think Pile Juice is sour?
Or sweet?
It’s both!
A yellow heart that
sparkles like the sun!
Juice DrinKyun!
The thrill of pink!
The twinkle of blue!
The radiance of yellow!
The sparkling trio unites!
Alola DrinKyun!
Your transformation scene’s
super cool!
You really think so?
We practiced this part
dozens of times!
Give it up, Gyarados Devil!
Oh! It’s this part!
Here we go!
Yeah!
Land of Alola...
Sea of Alola...
Sky of Alola...
Give us power!
Alola Salute Sunday Sunrise!
The battle is over.
Alola DrinKyun have vanquished
the atrocious Gyarados Devil.
Now, will they make it in time
for their first class?!
That was awesome!
You were so cool!
Really?
The sparkling trio unites!
Alola DrinKyun!
Change brings about
the chance to meet a new you!
Everyone,
let’s keep trying new things!
Why does my Alola Region debut
have to be in this kind of show?!
Because you said in the audition
that you’d be willing to do demanding roles, meow!
Well, why are we in this, too?!
Good! No worries!
Villain star Li’l Koi is born!
What an awful feeling!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
We went to the TV station!
The Atrocious Pokémon Gyarados
is a Water/Flying type.
There are people who swear that any place
Gyarados appears is fated for destruction.
Li’l Koi did a great job of playing the villain!
He will return in “Gyarados Strikes Back”!
Just kidding!
Big news, meow!
The TV station’s asked us to appear
in another program, meow!
We’re getting some lines
this time, right?
Well... They said we did such a good job
at getting beaten up, so...
We’re...
I’m...
...not just some extras!
...a star actress!
Next episode
Oh, how scary! I’m so scared!
What’s wrong, Musashi?
What are you scared of, meow?
My own beauty frightens me!
The day when the whole world
will bow before my beauty draws near!
Yes! Surely it must be so!
Oh, I see...
The same old story, meow...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Beauty and the... Nyarth?!
I am the most beautiful woman alive!
Oh, I see...
Next time!
Beauty and the Nyarth!
The same old story, meow...