Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Hokulani Observatory
Wela Volcano
The Kanto Region
Haina Desert
Where does the School class go today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
A shooting star!
You’re supposed to wish
upon a shooting star, right?
I wish for the Aina Cafeteria
to become famous!
I wish for Hoshi to be healthy!
Oh, and for Bakugames to be healthy, too. That’s all I...
I want to hook a Kaiogre.
I wish to remain friends
with Snowball forever.
I’ll be a Pokémon Master!
Oh and also... Um... Let’s see...
And for Garagara
to be healthy...
It has disappeared
from our view.
What?! Oh, no!
I got plenty of photos-roto!
That wasn’t a shooting star,
but a Meteno.
Meteno?
A Pokémon that lives
in outer space.
Impressive that
you know that, Māmane.
W-Well, yeah...
Actually, the reason we’re sleeping over here
is to observe Meteno.
It’s a Pokémon you don’t get to see often,
so make the most of it!
Yes!
I can’t wait!
Hey!
Kukui! Little Mā!
Big Mu!
I’m glad you’re here,
Little Mā.
Māmane, is this the guy
you were talking about before?
Yup! My cousin, Big Mu!
We’ll be in your care
during our field trip.
I can’t turn down a request
from my best friend.
I’m Mullein.
I work at Hokulani Observatory.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Meteno and Bebenom,
A Promise Faded Into the Starry Sky!
Satoshi and the others have come to
Ula'ula Island’s Hokulani Observatory to observe Meteno.
What kind of Pokémon is Meteno?
It’s so vast and deep!
So these are
the mysteries of the universe!
I wanna see them, too!
Show me the mysteries of the universe!
Satoshi!
Wait for your turn.
Yeah, yeah!
It’s Suiren’s turn next.
Then me, Lilie, and you after that.
Pardon me!
Darn...
You’re not gonna look?
I’ve seen it many times before.
Right, Big Mu?
Little Mā has been coming here
since he was small.
I became friends
with a Meteno once!
Awesome!
That Meteno is over there.
That’s Meteno?
Well, just its shell.
Shell?
Another mystery of the universe!
So does that mean
it was inside this?
Huh? Something moved!
Hey! Bebenom!
That’s an unusual Pokémon!
It’s called Bebenom.
Hey, wait!
You’re a lifesaver...
A Rarecoil!
It’s my Pokémon.
What’s wrong?
Are you all right?
I’m tingling all over...
So pretty!
Snowball, that is
the Kyukon Constellation.
Kyukon?
You’re right!
Then, that’s
the Pikachu Constellation!
And that’s
the Bebenom Constellation!
I’ve never heard of
those constellations.
Huh?
I mean, it looked like them,
so why not?
There’s Rekkuuza!
...Or stars that look like it.
Yeah, it does look like it.
Everyone!
Let’s go see the Meteno!
“Go”?
Can’t we see them from here?
Actually, the Meteno fall towards
Starshower Hill, over here.
It’s started.
Hurry up!
Sure!
Hey, Bebenom!
Awesome!
They’re all Meteno.
Meteno. Shooting Star Pokémon.
Rock/Flying type.
It’s made up of a hard, heavy shell
and the core within it.
It becomes lighter
after its shell breaks.
That’s Meteno’s core?
Correct.
Meteno in outer space
eat the dust floating around them,
and make their shells
out of that dust.
Then they get heavy and fall
to the ground, right?
Correct.
I’ve seen this form in books.
But they’re far more beautiful
in real life!
Earthly stars...
The components of the dust they eat
determines Meteno’s body color.
Someday, I’d like for Hoshi
to see this, too!
They were beautiful
the last time I saw them, too... right?
The Meteno are...
...returning to outer space?
What’s wrong, Bebenom?
It’s still got a shell!
Shouldn’t it be floating?
Think it’s having trouble
getting out?
All right! I’ll get it out!
No!
If you force Meteno’s shell open,
it’ll explode!
Explode?!
Someone might
touch it out here,
so we’d better bring it
to the observatory.
All right, I’ll do it.
Me, too!
This happened back then, too!
Ready, and...
Are you all right?
I... I’m fine...
But what happened after that?
This is nothing!
Carrying Moo-Moo Milk has trained me!
I’m worried...
What’s wrong, Māmane?
Let’s go back.
Oh... Sure.
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Meteno
Type:   Rock/Flying
Looks like the weather’ll be great.
This’ll let us have a nice
Meteno viewing tonight.
I hope they’ll be happy.
Kukui, how much do you want to
teach them about Meteno?
Everything.
They’ll meet all sorts of Pokémon
in the future.
I think it’ll be a good experience for them to learn
about the Pokémon known as Meteno.
Where are the children?
Still sleeping soundly.
What’s wrong?!
W-What?!
What? Is it Bebenom?
What was that?
It came from the lab!
What’s wrong, Bebenom?
The crack’s grown bigger!
It came out!
An orange Meteno, huh.
Oh, that’s right!
The same thing happened
in this room back then, too...
What?
I was wondering
what was going on.
So it’s broken out
of its shell?
It’s shining so bright,
even during the day!
An earthly star!
This is a great photo op-roto!
Bebenom,
move out of the way-roto!
Look at that.
You made Meteno angry.
How impressive!
Is this Meteno?
It’s very well drawn!
Bebenom is quite the artist-roto.
They’ve made up!
Good for you, Bebenom.
I arrived at yet another starting line
Let’s go!
The path keeps going from here, what a relief
Ashimari! Balloon!
Thanks, Ashimari!
Our dreams will go on forever!
Here I go, Satoshi!
When I have you!
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
Sparking Gigavolt Swing!
Because all the time, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
I lost...
You’re not gonna
play with them?
No... I was thinking about
something, you see.
Thinking?
I can’t remember what happened
to that Meteno I met back then.
I see.
They’re practically
inseparable already.
Hey! Time for lunch!
All right!
Let’s go, Bebenom, Meteno.
Thanks for the food!
Delicious!
Will this one go back
to outer space, too?
Probably. Hopefully its friends will come again,
like yesterday.
Tonight will be the peak of
the Meteno showers.
I’m sure you’ll all be amazed
at how many there are.
Really?
Isn’t that nice?
Lots of your friends will be coming!
Will we see a lot of colors?
Yes.
This is so exciting!
Did the Meteno you became friends with
go home with the others, too?
Well...
I don’t actually remember.
Oh.
It’s almost time.
It’s started!
Awesome!
It’s like we’re in the starry sky.
So pretty!
It really is...
Don’t you think so, Snowball?
Another great photo op-roto!
Satoshi, look at this.
What?
This is nothing like
the shell we carried.
You’re right.
Why is it so fragile?
Meteno live by eating
the dust that floats in space.
And then they make their shells
out of that dust.
That much
I already explained, right?
Yeah. Then that shell gets too heavy
and they fall down.
Correct.
When they fall down to the earth,
their shell burns away little by little,
and by the time they reach the ground,
it’s mostly just the core that’s left.
So it’s pretty much just ash?
What about the Meteno that
Bebenom befriended?
It’s rare, but sometimes Meteno
with particularly hard shells fall down.
Big Mu...
I remembered all of it.
I remember where the Meteno
I befriended back then went.
The Meteno are going home!
Meteno that have lost their shells
eventually fade away.
They’re not returning to space?!
The memory from back then
was so sad...
...that I must have
repressed it.
Mr. Mullein,
isn’t there anything we can do?
We only just became friends!
That is the kind of Pokémon
Meteno is.
Bebenom!
Bebenom...
Professor Kukui...
The final duty of those who remain...
...is to remember
the experiences they shared.
Yeah...
Meteno...
We won’t forget.
Rekkuuza!
I got to see it...
The real one!
Amazing!
It’s beautiful!
Did it come for them?
Rekkuuza is a Pokémon
that lives in space, too, after all!
I see!
Satoshi and the others are sure to remember
the time they spent with Meteno.
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The place we all went to
was Hokulani Observatory!
The Shooting Star Pokémon Meteno
is a Rock/Flying type.
It lives in the ozone layer, but hurtles to the ground
when its shell grows too heavy.
If its core stays exposed,
it will soon die off.
It’s a Pokémon that’s
as fleeting as a bubble.
Next episode
Rock-paper-scissors!
Paper!
Pa
Pearshen!
Rock-paper-scissors!
gu
Rock!
Graena!
I’ll win next time!
Rock-paper-scissors!
choki
Scissors!
All right!
chouzetsu rasen rengeki
Super Spiral Combo!
You’re supposed to follow up “Scissors”
with “Choroneko”, remember?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Sand’s Storm! An Ice Hole Double Battle!!
Next time
A Sand’s Storm!
An Ice Hole Double Battle!!