Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Professor Kukui's house
Kaki's house
Suiren's house
-
Mamane's house
At whose house is the sleepover
in today’s episode held-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Is it good, Snowball?
So, what are you doing, James?!
I am not doing anything.
I, James, am nothing but air.
Now, give me a real smile.
...I can’t do that!
Stop the camera.
What is this supposed to mean?!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Strike a Full Power Pose
for a Sleepover!
What are you thinking, Mother?!
Oh my, it seems my baby
is in a bad mood.
I keep telling you, I am not a baby!
Don’t make James do weird stuff!
I humbly apologize.
But I mean,
you can finally touch Pokémon.
I want to see how you
interact with them, you know?
If that’s what you are after,
you should just come visit.
Well, that’s true...
Besides, Mother...
Oh, please excuse me
for a moment.
Hello? This is Lusamine.
About the other day...
Fine!
If your work is that important to you,
then don’t let me distract you from it.
I’ll be going now.
Understood.
All right, done.
Check-up complete-roto.
Thanks. You did well, as always.
Nebby’s gotten really attached
to Professor Burnet.
It’s quite smitten with her.
I’m glad. Please let me get
some more data from you later.
Here, have some sugar stars
as a reward!
Ah, here they are.
Alola!
Oh, you’re all here?
Professor Burnet!
It’s been a while.
What are you doing here?
She came for a regular
check-up on Nebby-roto.
I just finished.
Oh, I know! Why don’t you join us,
Professor Burnet?
What?
We’re having a sleepover.
Everyone’s gonna be staying here tonight.
I agree!
Great idea!
Hey, hey... The professor is busy.
Hang on a second...
Yup, my schedule’s open!
Then, I guess I’ll take you up on that.
All right!
How many years has it been
since my last sleepover?
Well, now that that’s settled,
come on in everyone.
Thank you for having us!
Sorry to get you mixed up in this.
Oh, it’s no problem.
I hope I’m not a bother.
What a big aquarium.
Wow, you have a loft?
That’s my room.
I wanna sleep up there!
Me, too!
Me three.
Seems like fun.
What? The girls, too?
In that case, let’s have a contest to decide
who gets to sleep on the loft!
Contest?
Like what?
Let’s see...
Is something wrong, Nebby?
Probably wants to play hide-and-seek.
It’s been really into that lately.
It teleports off,
like it’s saying “Try to find me!”
Let’s play “Look for Nebby”!
Whoever finds it first wins.
Okay.
Sounds fun!
It’s gone.
Well then, let’s start the game!
Yeah!
I know exactly where Nebby is!
What?! You already figured it out?!
Too bad.
Behold my glorious intuition, honed from
playing hide-and-seek with Hoshi all the time!
All right! I’ll try...
I found it!
It doesn’t count
if you can’t catch it.
What? You should have
said so sooner!
This looks suspicious.
Did you find it, Lilie?
It wasn’t over there.
There!
No, I guess not.
Not here either.
How strange...
Aw, they seem to be
having so much fun.
Isn’t that good?
Nebby!
What is it, Snowball?
It’s like a secret base!
We’re quite high up.
I love the skylight.
Lucky them.
You can come back
another time.
Hey, what should we do next?
Since we’re all here, how about playing
“Full Power Pose, One, Two, Three”?
Great idea!
You’ll be playing too, Professors?
Hm? Is that a problem?
This’ll be so much fun!
Is everybody ready-roto?
Yeah!
I won’t lose, Professor Kukui!
Oh? Well said, Māmane!
All right, counting on you, Rotom.
Roger that!
Leave the instructing to me-roto!
Well then, let the game begin-roto!
Yeah!
Ready, and... Grass! Water! Water!
Grass! Water! Water!
Good-roto! Keep it up-roto!
This’ll be a piece of cake!
Let’s keep it up, Rotom!
You guys joining in, too?
Next-roto.
Ready, and...
Grass! Fire! Grass!
Grass! Water! Grass!
I just copied Ashimari...
Me, too.
All right, Suiren and Māmane
are out-roto!
This is a total breeze for me!
Don’t worry, Ashimari.
We’ll keep going-roto!
Water! Water! Grass!
Grass! Water! Grass!
Grass! Grass! Grass!
Bloom Shine Extra!
All right, Satoshi, you’re out!
When it’s three in a row,
you say the name of the move, remember?
Oh, right.
You messed up, Satoshi.
Well then, now it’s time
to speed up-roto.
Ready, and... Water! Grass! Fire!
Water! Grass! Fire!
Grass! Grass! Fire!
Water! Water! Grass!
Grass! Water! Grass!
They’re so quick...
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Dynamic Full—
Dynamic...
Full Flame!
Kaki, you’re too fired up...
I’m sorry.
Roto...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gonbe
Type:   Normal
That was awful-roto...
I can’t believe you actually
used the Z-Move.
I have no excuse.
And done.
Thank you very much.
Oh, it was no problem.
Well, I guess it’s about time
to make dinner.
You’re a guest,
you shouldn’t! I’ll do it.
I’ll be in your care all day,
so this is the least I can do.
Well, if you insist...
That settles it, then.
In that case, I’ll help out, too!
And me!
Oh, really?
I... I will help out, as well!
Well then, I’ll be
counting on you three.
Yeah!
All right, the rest of you
clean the room.
We can’t really eat with
the room looking like this.
You’re used to this, huh, Mao?
I do it every day.
Me, too!
I’m super used to it!
Yeah, looking good.
How about you, Lilie?
I’m just about to start
cutting vegetables.
Are you okay? When cutting vegetables,
your non-dominant hand should form...
...a Nyabby’s paw, yes?
Oh, you know!
I had forgotten.
Mother taught me long ago.
I see.
All right! I’m done!
Can I put these in now?
Wait ‘til they cool down a bit.
Okay.
All right! Good work, everybody.
We finally finished...
It’s perfect!
I apologize for
the trouble I’ve caused.
And over there...
How about this?
I told you, start with the ones
that have cooled down!
Looks like it’ll take a while yet.
Professor Kukui,
can I watch some TV?
Oh, sure.
All right!
Professor Okido’s “Get Pokémon Haiku!”
is about to start.
Today, I’ll be teaching you the tricks
to making higher level Pokémon haiku!
What are you doing, Rotom?!
This is my time for watching reruns of
“Alolan Detective Laki”-roto!
But you’ve seen it before,
haven’t you?!
Wha-?!
No.
It’s time for a once-in-a-lifetime showdown,
in “Seeking Fishing Adventures in Alola”!
Wha-?!
It’s time for sweat,
tears and guts!
An irreplaceable victory, grasped through
the combined efforts of people and Pokémon!
Magnificent!
In other words, you just want to
watch Poké-Baseball, huh?
I want to see the haiku!
No, I want to see Laki-roto!
No! Fishing Adventures!
Poké-Baseball!
Haiku!
Laki!
Fishing!
Two outs, bases loaded.
The batter is 'Olu'olu!
He’s sure to be
the MVP this season, too.
Gonbe really seems to like
its evolved form, Kabigon.
He hit it!
That’s Kabigon’s
Actually Serious Attack-roto!
Go! Go!
'Olu'olu was so cool!
That was a good match.
Thanks for waiting!
Looks delicious!
What a feast!
These Croquette Sandwiches
are my masterpiece!
Lilie made the soup.
J-Just because Mao
was there to help...
Now, let’s carry it to the table!
Yeah!
Whaaaaaaat?!
We were forced to wait
at the worst possible time...
Seriously... That Gonbe...
Oh, right.
Here, a sugar star!
Satoshi!
Huh? You, too?
No, we have to wait for the professors
to come back from the store.
But...
You were right!
They really are training!
They’re really hard workers.
Lugarugan’s been like that
ever since he was an Iwanko.
Training on their own, huh?
We can’t let them beat us!
That seems pretty nice,
doesn’t it?
I want to try battling, too.
Well, then, shall we?
Let’s continue our training from Kanto.
I see. I’m a little interested myself.
Let’s all do it together!
I’m sure it’ll help us forget
that we’re hungry for a bit!
All right! Let’s do it!
I won’t hold back!
Of course!
Sorry to have caused you trouble.
That’s not true.
If anything, you’re helping.
I hope that’s true.
They were all really happy, too.
They’re all such honest, nice kids.
Yeah.
Thank you for today.
It kinda felt like I’d
gone back to my childhood.
Really? Those happy childhood days
really were great, huh?
Yeah!
It’s ready!
Burnet’s special
Super Speedy Cuisine is done!
I’m sorry to have
kept you waiting.
We were all training together,
so it’s fine!
Training? For battles?
Yeah, just a bit.
Hey... I can’t wait any longer!
Thought as much. So, eat up!
Time to eat!
Wow, this is good!
Delicious!
Crispy on the outside,
chewy on the inside.
I’ve gotta try making this
myself sometime!
There’s plenty more,
so eat as much as you like!
Of course!
Ah, don’t be in such a rush.
More, please!
Me, too!
Sure! Just a second...
Today was so much fun!
Yeah. Though I was on the edge of my seat
for a while, there.
All’s well that ends well, I suppose.
I think my impression of Professor Burnet
might have changed a little.
She’s so cool, yet she’s also nice and reliable.
She’s kinda like a mother.
A mother, huh?
My mom’s a lot scarier than her.
But I really like the food
at your place, Kaki.
Yeah! It’s got that
home-made feel to it!
W-Well, I guess...
Speaking of cooking,
the malasadas at Māmane’s place are great too.
But when you get the same thing every day,
you get sick of it.
I kinda want something
different once in a while.
I know what you mean. Say something tastes good,
and that’s all you ever get.
Good point!
Hey, stop acting so spoiled!
Try to consider the people making the food!
But I still get sick of it!
Hey, I’m turning off the lights!
Okay!
The sound of the waves is nice, isn’t it?
Professor Burnet...
Hearing it just soothes the soul.
The silence brought back
all kinds of memories.
I see...
To tell the truth, I got into a quarrel
with my mother this morning.
It wasn’t anything serious!
I just got a bit irritated.
I mean,
she only thinks about herself.
When did she become like this?
Your mother’s very busy,
so I suppose she must be making you
put up with quite a lot.
But I’m sure she cares about you.
I wonder...
You know how I come and go
at the Aether Foundation?
There, I saw...
Really? Mother?
Yeah.
So I think...
...she actually does want to
be with you and Gladio.
To be with us?
Why don’t you try talking to her
properly next time?
Yes.
Thank you for having us!
No problem!
Be careful on your way back.
See you later!
Yes!
I’ll go with them for a while.
Let’s have another sleepover sometime.
I’d like to try it at
another house next time!
Want to come to my house, then?
Mom’s cooking is great!
Great idea!
Yeah, let’s!
I think she actually does want to
be with you and Gladio.
I’d like to speak to my brother, as well.
What? Where am I?
Brother!
Lilie?! Why are you here?!
I want to talk to you about something!
About Mother...
Silvuddy!
Lilie!
You’re back!
Where’d you go?
Lilie?
What’s wrong?
I met Brother...
Gladio?!
And then I saw a Pokémon
I didn’t know...
No!
Lilie, don’t tell me...
Oh, no...
I...
It’s back... My...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The sleepover was held at
Professor Kukui’s house-roto!
Everyone seemed to be having fun-roto!
The “Full Power Pose, One, Two, Three” game
got everyone really excited-roto!
You should try it, too,
during break time at school-roto!
It gets really fun if you
keep it going for a while-roto!
Grass! Grass! Fire! Roto...
Spicy!
Water! Water! Fyaaah!
Water! Water! Fyaaaa!
Wait, “Fyaaaa”?!
Next episode
Sauboh’s kinda insufferable, isn’t he?
Yeah...
That condescending attitude of his!
“I leave it to you,” he says...
But I get the feeling he doesn’t
actually trust us one bit!
Now, now, keep it in!
As soon as we get that Petitdogas...
We can say goodbye to this
part time job, meow!
Yeah!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
“Lilie and Silvuddy, Awakening Memories”
Don’t miss it, meow.
Next time
Lilie and Silvuddy,
Awakening Memories