The PokéProblem!
I, Māmane will be presenting
today’s problem!
A blackout
Togedemaru running away
Dieting
Moving away
What is the tragedy that befalls me today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi’s classmate Māmane...
...is once again hard at work in Māmane Lab,
the laboratory his dad made for him.
All right, it’s done!
Program, run!
I made a CGI model of you,
and programmed it to show
many different expressions.
I’ll show you.
Angry face. Smiling face.
I think we have some
malasada doughnuts.
Dear, you still haven’t
packed your things?
Well, I figured,
since we still have a week.
That’s no good.
A week passes before you know it.
Hey... Don’t tell me...
we’re moving?!
That’s right?
I thought I told you.
Weren’t you listening?
Wh-Where are we going?
Well...
We’re going kind of far...
What do I do? What do I do?!
Moving means...
...I’ll have to leave everyone
at the Pokémon School, right?
No way, I don’t wanna!
I don’t wanna move!
Oh, I know!
I’ll run a simulation on
myself living here alone.
Cleaning, laundry, cooking...
It’s hopeless!
There’s way too much I’d have to
handle on my own!
What’s more, the odds that any food I cooked
would taste bad are 99.9%!
Odds that I wouldn’t be able to
get up in the mornings on my own are 99.9%!
There’s just no way!
What am I going to do?!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Farewell, Māmane!
Māmane.
Can we come in?
About the move...
You should get your things packed
by the end of the week.
Okay?
Good night, then.
It’s dark! I’m scared!
Thank you, Togedemaru...
I really don’t want
to leave everyone.
You’ll have to leave
your precious Pikachu, too.
You get it? “Good bye.”
You have to say goodbye!
You won’t get to see each other anymore!
Geez... Like this!
Do you understand
how I feel now?
I want to cry, too!
What do I tell the others...?
Alola!
S-Satoshi!
You seem down.
Is something wrong?
What? N-No, nothing...
Does your stomach hurt?
N-No...
Does anyone know
the Pokémon ability Battery?
This ability allows a Pokémon’s moves
to grow stronger.
I guess this week will be my last
in this classroom, too...
All right, can you name a Pokémon
that has this ability...
...Māmane?
Māmane.
Didn’t you hear the question?
What? No...
Well, that’s rare... For you to not be listening
when I’m talking about the Electric type...
I’m sorry.
Doesn’t Professor Kukui
know about the move?
Or does he know,
and is trying to act normally?
I see! That must be it!
All right. I’ll keep it secret
from the others, too.
Today’s P.E. activity will be a baton relay.
The rules are simple.
The Pokémon run first,
and then the trainers. Got it?
Yes!
Well then, let’s do it!
A good start is essential-roto!
Ready...
Togedemaru’s crying.
Māmane,
did something happen?
Huh? No, not much...
You know, it’s the usual thing.
She just loves Pikachu so much,
she can’t help herself!
What’s this?
The best sweets shops,
as hand-picked by me!
Ice cream, pancakes, chocolate,
and malasada doughnuts!
They’re not all that well known,
but as soon as word gets out
they’ll be packed for sure,
so you’d better go soon!
Thanks, Māmane!
My little sister will love this!
But why?
Well, it’s just... I figured it’d be unfair
if I was the only one who knew...
Info like this should be shared!
Thank you!
But this is weird.
Usually, you’d keep
this sorta thing secret.
Yeah.
W-Well, I’ve kinda...
outgrown that, I guess?
Weird.
Did something happen?
We’re here for you
if you need to talk.
Um... Oh, I gotta get home!
Later! Togedemaru, let’s go!
Oh... Māmane!
This is fine.
I’m sure things will just get awkward
if they learn the truth.
So we’ll just act like normal
until the end,
and then I’ll mail them about it
or something after we’re gone...
Huh? When’d you get ahead of me?
Something has happened, right?
N-No, not really...
Something’s bothering you, right?
Please, talk to us.
Don’t be shy!
Be honest with us.
Yeah!
Well, the truth is...
You’re moving?!
Yeah...
When?!
Next week...
To where?!
Somewhere really far away...
apparently.
See? I knew this would happen.
That’s why I didn’t tell you.
Got it! In that case, we’ll just act like normal
until the time comes!
I know! Let’s meet up at Aina Cafeteria
for dinner on Saturday and have a party!
That sounds lovely!
Yup!
No sense in being sappy!
We’ll have a wonderful fun time
with some wonderful food!
Is that okay with you?
Yeah... Thank you...
That settles it!
All right!
Sounds good to me!
Māmane,
do you have time after this?
Huh? Sure.
Come with me for a bit.
This is my first time riding Lizardon!
Hold on tight!
Okay!
It’s Wela Volcano!
Yeah!
We’re flying straight past it!
It’s so intense!
Don’t be surprised just yet!
I’d really rather
stay out of there...
Tough it out for a little bit.
Here we are.
This is my secret spot!
It’s so beautiful!
I don’t really know how,
but apparently the volcano
makes the water turn this color.
I see... That’s incredible!
Really makes me want to analyze it
and see what it’s made of!
Māmane.
Well... Even after you’re gone...
Kaki.
Thank you!
No problem!
See you tomorrow!
Bye bye!
Now, then...
I kinda want to
give them a present, too.
But what would be good?
Māmane!
We’re coming in.
Okay.
Oh... You still haven’t packed?
Hmm... Maybe we can
just leave this room as-is,
and then he can commute here
from the new place.
What? From the new place?
I can do that? Isn’t it far away?
Kind of far, yeah.
I actually wanted to
borrow the house next door,
but we ended up getting stuck
three houses down the street.
I’m sorry, Māmane.
Oh well, we’ll just have to put up with it
for a week until they fix the roof.
Whaaat?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kaki’s Lizardon
Type:   Fire/Flying
Huh?! The moving thing was a lie?!
I-It wasn’t a lie!
But you’re just moving to another house
in the same neighborhood for one week, right?
Yeah...
Are you kidding me?!
So I worried for nothing?!
I hate you.
Me, too!
Same!
Yeah!
Wait, everyone!
That could very well happen...!
What am I going to do?!
Māmane!
Cheer up.
Didn’t we all decide
to stay upbeat?
Indeed.
W-Well... Yeah...
Oh, no...
I have to let them know...
U-Um...
Māmane.
Suiren?
Come with me.
Hi, Laplace!
Get on.
Are we going fishing?
Just wait and see.
We’ve come pretty far.
This is a special spot.
Really?
Right here, at this time,
you can see a miracle.
A miracle?
If you’re lucky, at least.
Looks like you are lucky,
Māmane.
A-A Whaleoh?!
Th-That’s amazing, Suiren!
Māmane.
Please, never forget
the sea of Alola.
Suiren...
What’s wrong?
O-Oh, it’s nothing at all...
How am I supposed to
tell her after that?!
That was your twentieth
“Hmmm” of the day-roto.
I was just thinking...
What would be a good present
to give Māmane?
You can leave that to me-roto!
You got an idea?
Māmane’s passion is programming,
and his partner Pokémon is Togedemaru.
So, what’s needed for
both of those?
Huh? It’s a quiz now?
Hmmm... Something necessary both for
Togedemaru and programming...
Um... Um...
Time’s out!
The answer is electricity-roto!
I see!
So, I was thinking...
I’m not giving him Pikachu!
Not that-roto!
I was thinking of an Electric-type Pokémon
with a most appropriate ability-roto!
This is my last chance.
I have to tell them today.
You remember, right?
Meet us in Aina Cafeteria
at 5 o’clock.
U-Um...
I got somewhere to be.
See ya later!
Me, too.
I have to hurry, too!
As do I.
See you later.
Um...
Listen up everyone,
we got until evening!
We’re gonna find it, for sure!
Give a signal if you find it-roto!
What will you do, Māmane?
You still have time...
You could tell Mao and
have her tell the others...
Māmane! You sure are early!
Oh, no, see, Mao,
the thing is—
Come on!
You’re the star today,
so you just wait here!
Um... Well...
The thing is—
Alola!
Alola.
Alola! You’re all early!
Oh, Hoshi!
When I told her we were holding a party,
she said she wanted to help out.
I’ll do my best!
Māmane, you’re already here?
Y-Yeah...
I’ll hang flowers around the room!
I’m way better at it than my big bro!
Yeah!
I would like to help as well.
Same.
Really? That’s a huge help!
All right! Let’s make the best dinner,
for Māmane’s sake!
Flowers! Flowers!
Where will they bloom?
You wanna help, big bro?
Can I?
Flowers! Flowers! Where—
Iwanko!
Did you find it?
Right! Time to dig!
Hang on!
Is this it?
Definitely-roto!
Ready, and...!
Why, you...!
Satoshi’s late.
We should get started
so the food doesn’t get cold.
Ta-daah!
Thank you for being so patient.
And this is for you,
Togedemaru.
Delicious!
Everything’s delicious!
Glad to hear it!
Likewise.
Yeah.
Then let’s give him
our messages one by one.
Huh...?
But keep it cheerful!
I’ll go first, then.
Māmane, take care of yourself
in your new home.
Take care!
Y-Yeah...
And whenever you look up at the sky,
remember the clear blue skies of Alola!
When I look at the sunset,
I’ll think of you, too.
Well... When I first started
at the School,
you were the first person
to talk to me.
I’m still incredibly grateful for that.
Thank you!
I’m sorry...
I had decided not to cry...
Lilie, um...
Okay, Māmane, now you!
What?!
Oh... Um...
Sorry!
You’re really late, Satoshi!
I was looking for a perfect present.
This is my present for you.
This Pokémon is...!
Denjimushi. Battery Pokémon.
Bug/Electric type.
The evolved form of Agojimushi.
Its body is capable of storing electricity
and supplying it to other Pokémon.
It was pretty hard to find.
Amazing! I’d been wanting
a Denjimushi for a while!
Thought so!
You should catch it!
Yeah! Come on, Togedemaru!
Use Shocking Prickles!
That’s Denjimushi’s Discharge!
All right! She absorbed the electricity
with Lightning Rod!
One more Shocking Prickles!
Go, Monster Ball!
All right!
I got Denjimushi!
Good for you, Māmane!
Yeah! Thank you!
This is from me.
Even after you’re gone...
Please stay the cheerful Māmane
we all know and love.
I’ll never forget you.
If you ever feel like
you’re about to lose,
remember your Alolan spirit!
If you need help,
just give us a call.
Yeah!
We’ll come to help you,
no matter how far away you are!
Everyone...
You don’t have to cry
that much.
We’ll meet again.
No, that’s not it!
I... I had it all wrong!
We’re just moving
a few houses down the street...
And just for one week, too!
I’m sorry... I’m so sorry...!
What a relief.
I mean, that’s great!
That means
this isn’t farewell, right?
And you don’t have to
leave the School, either.
Yeah...
We get to keep being
together as always!
Yeah...
Mao...
Yeah... Thank goodness!
Indeed.
Everyone...
Oh, I hadn’t told you yet,
Togedemaru.
Listen.
We don’t have to go far away.
You won’t have to part
with Pikachu, either.
You get to stay together!
It was all just a misunderstanding!
All right,
everyone say cheese-roto!
The commotion about Māmane moving
has brought everyone closer together.
It really is great to
have friends, isn’t it?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was moving away!
Sorry for all the trouble I caused...
Denjimushi, the Pokémon Satoshi gave me,
is a Bug/Electric type.
Since it can store energy,
it’s the perfect Pokémon for me!
Thank you, Satoshi!
All right! Denjimushi,
now it’s your turn!
Now, run, Denjimushi!
Hmm? What’s wrong?
Denjimushi!
Full speed ahead!
Next episode
Hey, guys! Who do you think of when I say
“a super strong Pokémon Trainer”?
Hmmm... I guess the Island King, Mr. Hala?
My butler, James!
Royal Mask!
Who?
Hey! Guys! I know!
You don’t need to raise your hand.
But okay, Satoshi!
The super strong
Pokémon Trainer is...
...me!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Come Forth! Crimson Glare Lugarugan!!
Next time
Come Forth!
Crimson Glare Lugarugan!!