Alola!
I, Kaki, will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Granbull
Guardie
Windie
Livolt
Which of these Pokémon appears today
as Junsa’s partner?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Kaki’s family’s farm
on Akala Island.
As usual, the Pokémon there
are relaxing without a care in the world.
All right!
That should take care of that.
Big bro!
What’s up, Hoshi?
Garagara’s causing trouble...
Again?
I get that you want to
become stronger, but still...
Do you ever learn?
What are you doing?
Oh, come on!
Be nice to each other!
What a bother...
There really ain’t nuthin’ out ‘ere.
Herderrie!
Calm down, Herderrie.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Protect the Farm!
The Blue Flame Strikes Back!!
There, there, it’s all right.
Can I help you?
Talkin’ ta a kid ain’t gun’
get me nowhere.
What’s going on, Kaki?
You da owner here?
Yes, I’m the president here.
Shibu is my—
I’m president o’ da Rainbow Happy Resort Company.
Name’s Bourgain!
Lemme just get to da point.
I want ya to sell me
dis ‘ere farm!
Out of the blue?!
‘s just da boondocks now, but I can make
a nice relaxin’ spot fer da city folks outta it.
I’ll build a resort hotel out ‘ere
an’ rake in da dough...
while y’all profit from
havin’ sold da place ta me.
Sounds like a good deal, don’t it?
No thanks!
We built this farm with our family and Pokémon,
under the divine protection of Wela Volcano!
We don’t have the slightest
intention of selling it!
She’s absolutely right!
If that’s all you want, then please leave!
Dad! Mom!
Don’t blame me
if ya end up regrettin’ it.
Wha—?!
What’re ya doin’?!
Now, let’s get back to work!
Everybody’s waiting.
Yes, you’re right.
I’ll help!
All right, you can help
give the Dorobanko a bath.
Yay!
Hurry up, big bro!
Can’t believe dey’d go against me...
‘s me. Yeah, stick to da plan.
What’s wrong?
T-This is...!
Dad! Mom! The stream’s...
What?!
But that’s... Well yes, but...
I can’t believe he’d stoop so low...
You’re troubling us.
We’ve been making phone calls
to figure out what was wrong with the stream...
Turns out a company’s bought the land upstream
and dammed the stream.
You don’t mean...?!
The Rainbow Happy Resort Company.
Him?!
What’s bothering Kaki?
Could he have had
a fight with his little sister?
Alola!
Alola-roto!
Oh, Satoshi. Alola!
Alola!
You’ll get dizzy!
What’s up, Kaki?
What?! They even blocked the stream?!
That’s awful.
Have you tried
talking to this company?
Yeah, my dad contacted them
directly, but...
Huh? What I do with my own land’s
my business, ain’t it?
If ya don’t like it,
just sell yer farm ta me already!
Found it.
Looks like that company’s been expanding and
building new resort hotels all over the place lately.
They’re infamous for their dirty tactics.
This is obvious harassment.
They want to make the farm
into a resort hotel...
Awful!
Not gonna happen!
I’ll help in any way I can!
I wouldn’t want your farm’s
ice cream to disappear!
You guys...
Thank you! I’m so moved!
Oh, you’re here to help the farm?
Thank you,
but you don’t have to worry.
We’ve worked it out so that
we’ll get water from the neighbors.
Um, if you need anything,
we’ll be happy to help!
Please let me take care
of your Pokémon!
All right, I accept your help.
You can have all the ice cream you can eat
when you’re done!
Yay!
Oh, Māmane...
Ashimari! Balloon!
Thank you, Ashimari!
Come on, Togedemaru.
Help out a little!
Um...
Come on, everybody, this way!
What are you doing?!
Scram!
Those are our Miltank!
What are you playing at?!
Can’t keep runnin’ da farm now, can ya?
Means da Pokémon are
useless ta ya, too, right?
I knew it was you!
I won’t let you have the farm!
I dunno what yer on about.
Yer fence just happened ta be broken,
so yer Miltank ran off.
Can’t have ya blamin’ me fer it.
Anyway, we have to
bring the Miltank back.
Move!
If ya want my Elecible ta move,
den make it!
Bakugames! Garagara!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Elecible
Type:   Electric
I’m done!
We’re done, too!
Let us take a break.
What? So, ice cream?!
We’re just taking a break!
Hmm? Where’s Kaki?
I thought he’d be here...
What? What’s wrong?
I’ll go look for him!
Me, too!
Bakugames! Flamethrower!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
What are you doing, Garagara?!
You need to cooperate with Bakugames!
Elecible! Thunder Punch!
Garagara!
Garagara! Kaki!
Big bro!
Stay back, Hoshi!
Thunder!
Bakugames!
Baku!
Are you all right?
This is awful-roto!
That’s...
It’s Elecible-roto.
100,000 Volts Pokémon. Electric type.
When it gets excited,
it thumps its chest.
With every thud, thunder roars
and electric sparks shower all around.
Wait, Garagara!
It’s strong! In that case...
Garagara,
you’ll use the Z-Move?
It’s all or nothing. Let’s go!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns like
the mountain of Akala!
What?!
Elecible! Thunder Punch!
Garagara!
Stop it!
Kaki! Satoshi!
What is happening?
Guess dat’s enough fer today.
You’d best sign yer farm
over ta me soon, yeah?
Hold it!
Satoshi!
We have to tend to
Bakugames and Garagara’s wounds!
I’ll go let the family know!
Oh no! The Miltank have run away!
Don’t go that way!
Baku, hang in there! Baku!
I’m glad Bakugames and Garagara
are doing better.
Likewise. It all happened so fast...
Everybody worked hard.
But those guys have to pay for
letting the Miltank out, right?
Yeah!
I see, President Bourgain again?
But we don’t have any proof that
he was the one who let the Miltank get loose...
Who else could it be?!
Anyway, leave that to me.
I am still the president here,
after all.
So cool!
I’m counting on you!
Today was so exhausting...
Farm work is quite demanding, isn’t it?
Gotta sleep...
I’m going to the bathroom.
You don’t have to tell me.
Garagara.
Garagara, listen to me.
Do you know why
we couldn’t pull off the Z-Move today?
It was because I doubted
whether you could pull it off or not.
But I won’t doubt anymore.
I believe in you.
So, Garagara,
please believe in me, too.
I want to burn as fiercely and strongly
as Wela Volcano itself.
I’m sure you understand how I feel.
Thank you.
You’ll work with me, right?
You, too, of course,
Bakugames.
All right, let’s do this!
Kaki...
All right, I’ll train with them!
Wait, Satoshi.
This is something that
Kaki and Garagara...
...have to overcome together,
just the two of them.
For now, just watch over them.
Right!
Oh, I see yer all ‘ere.
Does this mean y’all finally
decided ta hand da farm over ta me?
We’re here to...
Dad, could you leave this to me?
This is the farm my grandpa protected...
It’s our home.
I won’t let anyone take it from us!
All right. I’ll leave it to you.
Hang in there!
Big bro, do your best!
Of course, I’ll do my best!
What’s goin’ on?
Fight me! If I win,
you’ll stop interfering with our farm!
Oh, so it’s a duel ya want?
Fine by me. But dat means dat if ya lose,
ya give up da farm ta me, right?
Let’s go, Garagara!
What, Garagara?
Is he sure about that?
Yeah, they’ll be fine!
Go, Elecible! Thunder Punch!
Dodge, Garagara!
Iron Head!
What?!
Elecible, use Rain Prayer!
The rain puts the Fire/Ghost-type Garagara
at a disadvantage-roto!
Whenever yer ready ta surrender...
It’s obvious dat yer gun’ lose!
Garagara! Flare Drive!
Shadow Bone!
Follow it up with Iron Head!
Elecible!
No matter how strong the rain,
the flame of Wela Volcano
won’t go out!
The flame in our hearts
won’t go out so easily, either!
Garagara! It’s time for a Z-Move!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns like
the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
You did it!
Big bro won!
My son is the best!
You gave me your word.
Stay away from our farm from now on.
I won’t accept dis!
Dis farm’ll be mine,
whatever I gotta do ta make it happen!
Hey!
What?!
I shoulda done dis from da start.
You can’t be...
This isn’t what you promised!
Promised?
Dun remember makin’ no promise.
Don’t lie-roto!
I’ve got it all recorded-roto!
Argh, can it!
Whatever! Wreck it all!
Yeah!
Stop!
Leave the rest to us!
To us!
Mom! Dad!
Our son worked so hard.
Now it’s our turn!
We won’t let you touch our farm again!
Get out!
H-Hoshi... Stop that!
It’s too dangerous!
We’ll help, too!
Yes!
Do it!
Pikachu! Thund—
Ms. Junsa!
President Bourgain of
the Rainbow Happy Resort Company!
I’ve got an arrest order on you for
forgery of land ownership documents!
Furthermore, I can now add trespassing
and destruction of property to those charges!
You’re under arrest!
Their timing is uncanny-roto!
Oh, I reported him.
Great job, darling!
Daddy, you’re the best!
Oh, yeah, Ms. Junsa.
Your Dekagoose isn’t with you today?
Oh? You must have me mistaken
for my big sister on Melemele Island.
I only have one partner,
and that’s Granbull!
Big sister? You’re her sister?
They’re 99% alike-roto!
That means the remaining 1%
is me being cuter, right?
I didn’t say that-roto...
Huh?
Garagara, you did it!
They’re at it again.
Bakugames! Garagara!
You two are my precious partners.
I hope I can keep counting on you!
Only the best of friends
fight like that.
Yeah.
See you.
Thank you!
All right!
The water’s back!
All right, everyone!
Have as much as you want!
Yay! Ice cream!
I’ll have some!
Me, too!
Here, big bro.
Good work!
Thank you, Hoshi!
Huh? Where’s Garagara?
Kaki and Garagara have saved the farm
and mastered their Z-Move.
Their burning hearts are sure to keep strengthening them,
just like Wela Volcano!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
Akala Island’s Junsa’s partner...
...was Granbull!
The Fairy Pokémon Granbull
is a Fairy type.
It has a calm personality
and won’t bite unless it’s angered,
but once it does get angry,
it’s pretty scary!
I sure wouldn’t want to get scolded by
Ms. Junsa and Granbull!
Oh, you’re so pretty!
Next episode
Say, that Shizukumo’s been
following us for a while now.
Yeah, you’re right.
Say, Suiren, that Shizukumo
keeps staring at you.
Yeah. Isn’t it cute?
Say, that Shizukumo...
Maybe... Just maybe...
What?
Maybe it’s in love with you?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Shizukumo Gets Suiren!
Next time
Sure, I don’t mind.
Whaaat?!