Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Kaiogre
Sleeper
Lunala
Kapu-Kokeko
Which one of these Pokémon
does that old geezer Sauboh use today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Sleeping over at Professor Kukui’s house,
I had so much fun with everyone...
Snowball had fun, too,
playing with Pikachu and Nebby...
No!
Oh, no...
Snowball...
I’m... so sorry...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Lilie and Silvuddy,
Awakening Memories
Why did you bring Lilie to me?!
The reason she’s become
unable to touch Pokémon again...
...is that she saw Silvuddy and
remembered something!
It would have been better for her
if she’d never remembered!
I’m sorry, Gladio. But Nebby...
Don’t blame it on Nebby!
Sorry...
Oh, welcome back.
A relative of yours
just came by to visit,
so I let them into your room.
Family?
Welcome home, young master.
Sauboh. I figured it was you.
It’s not like I expected
a warm welcome, but even so...
It’s quite flattering that you reacted
exactly the way I imagined you would.
What do you want?
The wind whispered to me that Little Miss Lilie is
once again unable to touch Pokémon, see...
I’ve come to have you
return Type: Null to me.
The President wants that as well.
Never!
You’ve got some nerve,
considering that you just took it without permission.
You lied about
treating Silvuddy with care,
put restraints on it
and kept it for research,
and you want me to give it back?!
Blacky! Lugarugan!
So you resist me...
Come forth, Houdin! Sleeper!
Lugarugan, use Stone Edge!
Sleeper, use Reflector!
Blacky, use Shadow Ball!
Houdin, use Miracle Eye!
Use Stone Edge and Shadow Ball again!
Sleeper, use Hypnosis!
Houdin, Psychokinesis!
Blacky!
It seems your resistance ends here,
young master.
No, I’m not done!
I cannot allow you
to use that one.
Sleeper, use Hypnosis!
I’ll have you sleep for a little bit,
young master.
Sil... vu...
Lilie.
Cheer up! I know you’ll
be able to touch her again!
Don’t be too hasty.
We’re here for you.
And of course, so is Snowball.
You can realLilie do it!
I can realLilie do it...?
Yeah, now you’re getting it!
You’re better smiling!
Lilie.
Professor Burnet?!
I was worried,
so I came to check on you.
I’m glad. It’s such a relief
to see you smiling.
Hey, Snowball.
Let me try it one more time.
Are you all right?
I want to try.
Lilie’s motivation
is at 100%-roto.
Yes! I know I can realLilie do it!
Come here, Snowball!
Snowball!
Seems it was a bit too much.
Yes...
But well done!
Yeah, you tried hard to
Work Up your courage!
Yes!
Huh? Lilie.
You’re walking home today-roto?
I thought I’d walk home
alongside Snowball...
Just like on that day when
I was first able to touch her.
I see.
Pikachu, Rotom.
Let’s go for a little walk, too.
Agreed-roto!
What did Gladio say about me?
H-How’d you know I met Gladio?!
You met him-roto?!
Yeah...
I just had a feeling you might have.
You just “had a feeling”?
He said he didn’t want you
to meet Silvuddy.
“Why did you bring her to me?!”
Oh, sorry... He got real mad.
I was afraid I’d face his
Fangs of Rage.
That sounds like my brother.
When I met him, I remembered...
Remembered?
Yes.
I remembered
Silvuddy charging at me,
and the intense dread
I felt as it did so.
How did I forget about that?
It was an experience I shouldn’t have
been able to forget even if I wanted to.
Her forgotten memories
have been reinstalled...
Truly fascinating-roto.
Let’s not, Lilie.
Since we’re out on a walk,
we should talk about something more fun.
Oh, I know! Pikachu’s impression
yesterday was just the best!
If you want to see it,
I have it all recorded-roto!
Thank you, Satoshi, Rotom.
I appreciate you trying to cheer me up.
I’ve made up my mind!
About what?
I will try to remember it all!
What?!
I want to know everything
that happened to me.
Lilie...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Sleeper
Type:   Psychic
Huh?
We’ve teleported-roto?
Nebby?
This is...
The beach I often visited with my
mother and brother when I was younger!
There!
How nostalgic!
An orchard?
Back before Mother became so busy,
we were growing vegetables here!
The Pokémon helped out as well.
Where are we-roto?
I know this place!
This is the restaurant in
the hotel I was staying at with Mom!
I was brought here many times, as well.
Now where are we-roto?
Me and my brother’s childhood room.
In our house at Aether Paradise...
This is Mother’s room...
There’s so many pictures of you!
And of Gladio, too!
Your mother is quite
the photo-enthusiast-roto.
Mother...
All right, smile!
How strange.
The memories from when we took this photo
are vividly returning to me.
Our laughter...
Even the sound of the waves...
I get it!
Nebby’s trying to fulfill...
...your wish to remember!
This is the basement laboratory area.
President Lusamine must not be allowed to know
about the incident from four years ago.
Especially not about that Ultra Beast.
Ultra Aura readings?
It’s close!
Little Miss Lilie?!
How did she get here?!
Surely she can’t have remembered?!
I’ve been here before.
How can that be?
Entry into the basement
is strictly forbidden,
so I shouldn’t have ever
come down here...
It’s the brat boy and
the white brat girl, meow!
Petitdogas is with them, too!
Is this our lucky break?
Off we go!
Oh, you guys.
I was looking for you.
Where is Type: Null?
Type: Null?
That name sounds familiar.
I said, where is it?!
Hey, Gladio! Why the scary face?
Sauboh stole it from me!
Sauboh?
I have no idea what
you’re talking about.
You don’t... know anything?
I remember!
Type: Null was the name of
the project Sauboh was working on once, right?
I seem to recall he reported to me that
the project failed, though.
Failed?
It didn’t fail!
Type: Null...
Silvuddy saved me and Lilie!
Saved you?
What do you mean, Gladio?
You must find Little Miss Lilie
and bring her to me, on the double!
The white brat girl? Why?
So that she can forget.
Forget, meow?
Certain memories of her past.
It would be very inconvenient if she recalled them.
Inconvenient if she recalled?
Memories of her past?
With my Sleeper’s help,
it’s quite simple...
...to erase memories.
Erase memories, meow?
Bring her to me, and I’ll throw in
a special bonus for you!
Now, hurry and go!
We refuse!
What?
Erase her memories?
You’ve gotta be kidding me!
Yeah!
Listen up! All the stuff that happens
to people and Pokémon in their daily lives...
Even the little things...
All that stuff piling up is
what makes them who they are!
Yeah!
Take the cake they ate
on their birthday as a kid...
Its shape, color and sweetness,
or the scent of the blown out candles...
All that stuff sticks around somewhere in their mind as memories!
And nothing matters more!
We stand for righteous evil,
not evil evil, meow!
We’re leaving!
I know this place, too.
Who are these guys?!
Are you all right-roto?!
Satoshi!
Lilie!
Where... Where did he hide it?!
I can’t believe Sauboh
opened an Ultra Hole!
You want to meet an Ultra Beast?
It’s been your dream
since you were a kid, right?
The fear she felt when
she was attacked by an Ultra Beast back then...
...made Lilie suppress
her own memories.
And yet you want to meet one...
That’s the kind of person
you are, right?
Gladio!
Did you never find it strange that
she suddenly stopped being able to touch Pokémon?!
Sauboh might have lied
and tried to keep you in the dark...
But as her mother, you should...
I’m sorry...
I’m not the one
you should apologize to.
Emergency!
Somebody help-roto!
How much did you recall?!
Well, it doesn’t matter.
After all,
you’ll forget it again soon.
What do you—
Sleeper, use Hypnosis!
No... I don’t want to forget!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
Sleeper, I retract my last order!
Use Reflector!
Pikachu!
Now that it’s come to this,
I’ll have you all sleep.
Now use Hypnosis, Sleeper!
Thanks, Nebby!
A Teleport, is it?
I anticipated as much.
Then we will answer in turn.
Teleport!
Houdin, use Psychokinesis!
Let me go!
Sleeper, use Psychokinesis to
stop them from moving!
Stop it!
Houdin, use Psychokinesis.
Lilie...!
Lilie!
Are you all right-roto?!
G-Gladio...
Go, Silvuddy!
Type: Null. It was I who
created you and gave you life.
No!
Silvuddy, save Lilie!
Mother!
Where are you?
Lilie!
Big Brother!
Help her, Sauboh!
No!
The one who saved me back then...
Reborn sacred beast, Silvuddy!
Receive this Dark Memory,
and rampage as a demonic beast!
Use Multi-Attack!
Awesome!
Silvuddy became an Evil type-roto!
Lilie! I’m so sorry, Lilie!
I’m sorry... I’m so sorry!
Mother.
Off we go...
Thank you, Mother.
Lilie?
I, too, need to apologize.
I’m sorry, Silvuddy.
I was wrong.
The one who saved me,
both back then and now...
...was you.
Thank you, Silvuddy.
She’s touching it-roto!
I...
Snowball!
Pikachu!
Nebby!
I...
I can touch them!
It is entirely logical
to conclude that I can...
Just like I could
when I was younger!
That’s great, Lilie!
Yes!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
That old geezer Sauboh’s Pokémon
was Sleeper!
The Hypnosis Pokémon Sleeper
is a Psychic type.
It’s an extremely dangerous Pokémon
who puts those it meets to sleep.
It’s truly perfect for
that wretched Sauboh.
What a villain,
wanting to erase people’s memories!
You’ve used Hypnosis on Sonansu,
haven’t you, meow?!
I can’t tell if he’s been
hypnotized or not, meow...
Next episode
I’m itching to touch
all sorts of Pokémon!
You did it, Lilie!
Can you touch Ratta?
Yes! I want to pinch its cheeks!
What about Yatoumori?
I want to twirl its tail around my finger!
What about Betobeton?
I want to pet it!
Awesome! Lilie’s evolved into
a trainer who loves Pokémon!
What was that voice?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Sauboh Strikes Back! Nebby Kidnapped!!
Next time