Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Getting fired from Team Rocket
Being eaten by Yowashi
Getting arrested by Junsa
Hidoide running away
What tragedy befalls Kojiro today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Oh my gosh, this is so cute!
Oh, I just don’t know what to get!
Maybe I’ll just buy all of it!
We’re totally gonna have to
carry her bags today too, meow.
Oh, it’s sparkling! So adorable!
This one’s lovely, too!
What am I to do?
What’s up, Hidoide? You want that?
A Sunnygo horn pendant, huh?
It’s quite pretty.
But, I’m sorry.
I can’t buy it for you today.
Nothing beats shopping
when you’re all stressed out, right?
I don’t care how stressed out you were,
you bought way too much.
What are you talking about?
Shopping is the epitome of living!
The true goal of life!
Our goal is to
get rare Pokémon in Alola...
It’s a Pururill!
Oh, how rare!
That color means it’s female.
What a cute pink!
All right! For starters,
let’s get that one...
Hidoide!
Hey, Hidoide! What are you doing?!
That was our chance to get Pururill!
But you got in my way!
She’s saying “I couldn’t allow another woman
to get close to you,” meow.
W-Well...
Hey, apologize to her!
You can’t even forgive a lady for being jealous?
You’re the worst!
That’s right, meow!
Think about how this must feel for Hidoide,
who’s in love with you, meow!
I guess.
Sorry, Hidoide. I’m not angry anymore.
What’s this? It seems like things are
going to get a bit messy.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Don't Cry, Hidoide!
Hey, you don’t think
that Pokémon is...?
Looks like it’s Hidoide’s first love,
the one she mentioned before, meow.
First love?
The one who looked like Kojiro?
That’s right, meow.
We look alike?
Yeah...
You both seem equally unreliable.
You also seem pretty
similarly indecisive.
That’s what we have in common?!
He healed.
What?!
W-What happened?
We’re in for a bloodbath!
Nyarth, translate!
Guess I’ve got no choice, meow.
I’ll explain it simply, meow.
All right! I’ve been waiting for this!
“The Little Crybaby and Chief!”
Once upon a time, there was a Hidoide
obsessed with love.
One day, Hidoide was out
looking for something, when...
“Oh, no!”
A Dokukurage suddenly attacked!
And that was when... Wham!
Would you believe it?
Another Hidoide appeared and saved her!
“Oh, you are... Chief!”
It was an older Hidoide with whom the little Hidoide
had been smitten for a very long time.
“You’re not out of the woods just yet,
little crybaby.”
“I... I’m not a crybaby...”
At that moment, Dokukurage
started attacking once more...
“Get down, little crybaby!”
“Kyaah!”
Slam!
“Chief!”
“Grrrrrr!”
And then he threw Dokukurage off
to the furthest reaches of the skies!
“U-Um... Thank you very much...”
“Don’t mention it. Anyway,
what were you doing out here?”
“Well you see, I wanted a Sunnygo horn,
as they’re very popular among my friends, and so...
“I see. Then I will find one of those
Sunnygo horns for you, little crybaby!”
“Heart throb!”
But several days later...
The little Hidoide passed by
the rocks where she had met Chief, and...
“Oh? Chief! Wait...”
Unbelievably, Chief was...
...giving a Sunnygo horn
to another Hidoide!
“Waaaaah!”
The little Hidoide
was utterly devastated,
and after that, she did not see
Chief again until today.
The End!
The man’s completely hopeless.
Maybe not, meow.
He’s saying that he just happened to pick up
a Sunnygo horn that another Hidoide dropped, meow.
Really? Sounds like an excuse.
T-That’s...
Huh?
H-Hey, Hidoide...
What’s the big idea?!
This is awful, meow!
It seems Chief thinks Kojiro is
just toying around with Hidoide, meow!
What’s that supposed to mean?!
No way!
He evolved, meow!
What?!
This is, um...
Oh! It’s Dohidoide!
You sure got stung real bad.
Are you all right, meow?
I think I’m all wrong... no?
H-He looks awful, meow!
Huh? Wait, for real?
What do we do? Find a doctor?
Or a Pokémon Center? Hey!
What even is this feeling?
He usually gets better quickly...
Hidoide may have been
holding back on him, meow.
Musashi... Nyarth...
You’re letting Hidoide go, meow?!
Does that mean you’re sick of
having to deal with Hidoide, meow?
Why would you do that?
Chief got her the Sunnygo horn
I couldn’t buy her...
And he even evolved for Hidoide...
Being with a Chief who
cares for her that much...
...would surely make Hidoide
much happier than being with me.
Kojiro...
That was delicious!
What’s wrong, Lugarugan?
That’s...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Dohidoide
Type:   Poison/Water
Professor Kukui, isn’t that Hidoide...?
Yeah, seems she’s the one
that was with Team Rocket.
They might be searching for her.
I knew that when we brought her here.
As soon as she’s feeling better,
we should give her back to them.
But what was Hidoide doing there
on her own-roto?
There, thanks for waiting.
This is Burnet’s special blend
of Pokémon food! Eat up!
Go on and eat, Hidoide.
Gonbe.
That’s not nice...
You’ve all eaten already, right?
Eat up and get better!
Are you all right, Hidoide?
H-Hey!
What am I to do with you?
Where did you go?
You just disappeared all of a sudden...
We were worried!
Sorry it took so long
for me to come get you.
The poison from yesterday
wouldn’t go away, see.
Perfect timing.
Look. He’s waiting for you.
You’re better off
being with Chief.
Now, go.
He even evolved for you.
I know he’ll make you happy.
So go.
Come on, go!
Go!
Please, go!
Chief is waiting for you!
Please, just go with him!
Are you sure about this?
It’s fine.
Now I won’t get poisoned anymore...
And I can catch Pokémon
without her getting in my way.
I won’t have to worry about
any fits of jealous rage.
This is fine... Just fine...
Ow... W-What?
What? Why?
What?
Looks like he’s pretty angry at you,
for making Hidoide cry, meow.
But...
He’s saying his anger won’t subside
until he’s beaten you to a pulp.
You gotta be kidding!
He’s saying “I can’t let a weakling like you
have the little crybaby!”
I know that!
He’s saying “Nobody wants for the little crybaby
to be happy more than me!”
I want Hidoide to be happy, too!
That’s why...
“Then try to take me down and
steal back the little crybaby!”, he says.
Sure! You’re on...
But that means...
“I don’t want to see the little crybaby
cry anymore,” he says.
He’s saying “If you want her to be happy,
then try to stop her tears!”
Guess I have no choice.
Got it. Let’s fight, Dohidoide!
Here goes! Come at me!
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Romanticism”!
You’ll be fine!
The “ke” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Keenness”!
You rock, meow!
The little “c” in “Team Rocket” between the two stands for...
How?!
“‘Course, we’re villains!”
“Come on, come at us!”
“Clearly, Pikachu’s too strong, meow!”
Hidoide...
“What an awful feeling!” we scream as we blast off,
All right!
and beneath us we see a little, tiny earth,
forests, mountains and Pokémon...
They all blend together! What a great feeling!
I’m just getting started!
Wherever we land,
Not good!
He’ll end up like yesterday again, meow!
we’ll have a meal to prepare ourselves for tomorrow
We look up and see the shining moon
We look each other in the eye and laugh together
No way!
The poison, he...!
We’re the invincible Team Rocket!
See that?! This is my evolution!
Tricking crying children into silence...
Team Rocket!
Hey, how long are they
gonna keep this up?
I don’t know either, meow.
But the one thing I can say is...
Yesterday’s foe is today’s ally, meow.
Chief, I promise that
I’ll make Hidoide happy.
There it is again!
Why, you...!
That was close!
Does this mean...?
Yo! You stud!
Shut up! Why are you being
so calm about this?!
Bonds formed by coincidences
are made far stronger thanks to kindness.
Such miraculous chains are formed
whenever a Pokémon and a trainer meet.
Alola...
Huh? Where’s Hidoide?
Seems she’s all right now.
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The tragedy that befell Kojiro
was Hidoide running away!
The no-good Pokémon...
What? That’s not it?
Brutal? Oh, right.
The brutal Pokémon Dohidoide is
Hidoide’s evolved form, and a Poison/Water type.
They say that if you get poisoned by Dohidoide,
you’ll be in intense pain for three days and nights!
Is Kojiro really all right?
Are you sure we
shouldn’t catch him, meow?
Nah, this is fine.
I’m sure Kojiro wouldn’t
survive if we did.
Next episode
Do you want to hear
how Mao and I met?
I do!
It happened back when
I was still an Ametama.
What? Ametama?
Mao saved me from a mean Namazun!
Suiren was an Ametama...?
Keep this secret! If it got out, I’d...
I won’t tell anyone, I swear!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Mao and Suiren, Bittersweet Memories!
Next time
Mao and Suiren,
Bittersweet Memories!
Hey, Suiren!