Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Sonansu
Purin
Mokuroh
Aburibbon
Who’s the Pokémon in today’s episode
who can understand Bebenom’s feelings?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Oh! Satoshi and the others
are training for battle, as usual!
Pikachu, Lightning Speed!
Lugarugan, Rock Throw!
Both Pikachu and Lugarugan
are really fired up!
It’s a clash of moves-roto!
Mokuroh, Razor Leaf!
Nyaheat, Nitro Charge!
Offense and defense with
Razor Leaf and Nitro Charge!
Stellar work, both of you-roto!
Lugarugan! Accelerock!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Bebenom...
When did it learn
Fury Attack-roto?
Stop!
Bebenom!
It’s not your turn right now!
Don’t get in their way!
But your Fury Attack
packed a punch!
What a mess-roto...
Another of Bebenom’s doodles-roto!
You really like Pikachu a lot, huh?
Satoshi!
We’re going shopping!
Come home at Lightning Speed!
Sure!
Everyone, dash! Let’s race to see
who gets home first!
Let’s go! Full speed!
Wait-roto!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
The Shape of Family,
Bebenom's Feelings!
Alola!
Alola, Alola!
It’s an Aburibbon!
Yeah. It’s my partner.
Alola!
What lovely paintings...
You like them?
Aburibbon. Bee Fly Pokémon. Bug/Fairy type.
It rolls up pollen into puffs.
It makes many different varieties,
some used as food and others used in battle.
“Like... Like... Love!”
This one loves drawing!
How can you tell?
Aburibbon told me.
You can understand
what your Pokémon is saying-roto?!
Well... Sort of?
Aburibbon can Synchronize with
the hearts of people and Pokémon.
Oh, my!
It’s said that Aburibbon does this
by using its ability to distinguish flower auras.
We’ve been together for so long,
that I kinda started to understand
what it was sensing, too.
You’re awesome, lady!
I’m the awesome Matsurika!
And you are?
I’m Satoshi! This is Pikachu.
And these are Bebenom,
Gonbe and Rotom.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you, too!
Ms. Matsurika!
Alola!
This is Ms. Matsurika
and Aburibbon.
My friends said they wanted to meet you,
so I brought them!
Alola!
Alola, Alola!
T-This painting... This painting...
This painting...!
...has the soul of Wela in it!
How beautiful!
The ocean...
Ashirène too!
Ashimari’s
fully evolved form-roto.
Isn’t it beautiful?
Isn’t this...?
A night sky full of Meteno!
You could tell?
Yareyutan!
Snow...
This must be a scene
from Lanakila Mountain!
Ms. Matsurika,
what are you painting now?
You mean this?
Is this us?
I’m there, too-roto!
“A Familial Scene”.
Family...
Satoshi’s Alolan family!
My Alolan family!
Bebenom!
Bebenom.
What are they doing?
Miss... Matsurika?
Oh, I’m sorry!
Bebenom’s drawing was just
overflowing with emotion, so...
Emotion?
Aburibbon, please.
Aburibbon can sense the feelings
of people and Pokémon-roto.
Apparently it means
“Like, like, love!”
Is it talking about...
...its Alolan family?
Like... Like...
Love!
That’s it, right?
What’s up, Rotom?
Look at this-roto!
It’s the same drawing!
So its feelings towards Pikachu are...
Like, like, love!
Amazing, Bebenom!
You can draw your feelings?
What?!
Bebenom put its feelings
into drawings?
It’s true.
A fascinating discovery, isn’t it?
Rotom, the data.
Leave it to me-roto!
Ms. Matsurika said that this means
“Like... Like... Love”.
“Like, like, love”!
I feel the romanticism!
I would prefer something a bit more scientifically sound
than mere “romanticism”, however...
In any case, this makes it clear that
Bebenom is highly intelligent.
Satoshi.
Yes!
Keep on observing
Bebenom’s actions carefully,
and contact me
if you find something out.
Ult-Roger!
Oh, we’re at home...
Does it matter?
I’ve been wanting to say it once myself!
Lusamine, let’s try again!
Okay!
Satoshi! Professor Burnet!
Professor Kukui! Pikachu! Rotom!
I’m counting on you!
Ult-Roger!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Aburibbon
Type:   Bug/Fairy
Bebenom!
Where are you-roto?
Found you-roto!
Bebenom...
It’s time for supper.
Isn’t this...
Its Alolan family!
The “Like, like, love” mark
is next to all of us-roto!
Thank you, Bebenom!
This is a great photo op-roto!
Satoshi!
Say “Namakobushi”!
Namakobushi?
Ms. Matsurika was so wonderful.
Yeah! Her paintings were, too!
And Aburibbon!
Bebenom?
Bebenom...
What’s wrong, Bebenom?
What’s this?
I think...
Bebenom’s feelings.
Bebenom’s drawings...
Data updated-roto.
Bebenom...
Bro, don’tcha think
it’s been too peaceful lately?
Peaceful?! As if!
Alola ain’t gonna have no peace while we,
the mighty Team Skull, are here!
But everybody looks happy!
Nemush! What a cutie!
Raichu! What a cutie!
Cuwawa!
Look... Wrap’s gone totally soft
in these peaceful times.
Ain’t this kinda bad?
Yeah...
It might be a bit too peaceful
for Team Skull to accept.
Wait!
Aburibbon!
Is that cute Aburibbon yers?
It’s not “yers”, it’s my partner...
What’s up, Wrap?
Bro, I want this Aburibbon!
My Bro’s super strong!
Ya better hand over that
Aburibbon without a fight!
Yeah! Yeah!
Ya better not defy Team Skull...
For yer own good!
Let’s battle.
But when I say battle...
I mean an art battle!
The subject for this art battle
is your own partner Pokémon.
Well then... Begin!
Yer so cute!
This is gonna be so good!
That pose’s just the best!
My Pokémon’s as cool as ever!
All right, that’s enough!
It’s over already?
I’ve got faith in mine!
Then you go first.
Yer on!
This is Dustdas?!
It’s perfectly fine. Your love for Dustdas
really shines through.
R-Really?
Next...
Wanna see my Li’l Zubat?
Ta-daah!
This is supposed
ta be Zubat?!
I ain’t sure if that’s even
a real Pokémon!
Why?! It’s cute, ain’t it?!
You put your heart and soul into
showing your precious Zubat at its best!
For real?
Man, y’all are such kids!
How do y’all expect to win
with whack drawings like these?!
Let’s show ‘em to each other
at the count of three!
Okay, okay!
One, two, three!
S-She’s good...
B-Bro?
I-Is that...?
Yatoumori’s shocked, too.
Perhaps you should look at your Yatoumori
a bit more carefully...
Don’t mock me!
Anyway, how’d our battle turn into
a drawin’ contest?!
Yeah, yeah!
This is how you do a battle!
I was going to call it a draw since
you showed me some nice drawings, too...
Can it!
Yatoumori! Toxic!
Whaaaaat?!
Well done, Bebenom!
Three-on-one? That’s low!
Can it! Another Toxic!
Zubat, Air Cutter!
Dustdas, Venom Shock!
Oh, fine...
Aburibbon, Pollen Puff!
Zubat!
Pikachu, Iron Tail!
Bebenom, Fury Attack!
It wasn’t just cute...
Remember this, y’all!
It’s Satoshi,
so he’ll probably forget.
Bebenom drew this earlier-roto.
While drawing this,
it seemed to ignore us completely.
It was caught up in its drawing.
Aburibbon.
It seems like it’s having
a lot of fun right now.
What a relief...
But...
I don’t need Aburibbon’s help to understand
how Bebenom felt while drawing this.
How did it feel?
“I’m sad... I’m sad... I’m sad...”
“I’m sad...”?
I knew it...
Why was Bebenom so sad?
Bebenom might be carrying
some kind of heavy burden.
Heavy burden?
Some kind of mission.
I don’t know what it is, though.
Bebenom... I don’t know why you’re sad,
or what sort of mission you might have...
But you have me!
Satoshi’s right-roto!
I’ve seen this before!
It’s the Radiant One-roto!
The legendary being from
the book in Acerola’s library-roto!
Come to think of it,
Bebenom was making a fuss back then, too...
How odd... It’s been a while
since you saw that book, right?
So why did it draw this
all of a sudden?
It really is odd.
I don’t know why...
But it looks like Bebenom
likes, likes, loves the Radiant One!
What sort of ties do Bebenom
and the Radiant One have?
And what is the “mission”
Bebenom must carry out?
The mystery deepens,
as the story continues...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The one who could understand
Bebenom’s feelings...
...was Aburibbon!
The Bee Fly Pokémon Aburibbon
is a Bug/Fairy type.
When the pollen Aburibbon gathers gets wet,
its body gets dirty, so it hates the rain.
It’ll disappear from sight
whenever it’s about to rain.
Bebenom!
Mind finishing up soon?
What are you doing?!
Looks like it likes, likes, loves you, too!
Next episode
Granny, Grandpa, Mommy, Daddy!
It’s finally time fer
“Bling Bling Gold Shoppin’”!
What’s that supposed to be?
Today, I’d like ta introduce th’
golden, high-class Lil’ Bourgain figurine!
Have a look!
Its jaw moves, ya see!
Gross!
Buy it now, and ya get a
mini-mini Lil’ Bourgain, too!
No, thanks...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Leap ‘n’ Climb, Tsundetsunde!
Its jaw moves, ya see!
Next time
Leap 'n' Climb, Tsundetsunde!