Alola!
I will be giving
today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Do your best-roto.
Bubble Beam
Flamethrower
Leafage
Teleport
Which move does
Nebby use today-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Nebby,
the Pokémon which Satoshi found...
I was the one who named it.
Nebby loves sugar stars,
and is incredibly cute.
But it must be said, I was very surprised
when Mother came to visit,
and asked that we entrust Nebby
to the care of the Aether Foundation.
Equally surprising was the fact that
Nebby might be an Ultra Beast.
Nebby is quite
a mysterious Pokémon...
This has me feeling
somewhat concerned today.
Everybody, it’s time for breakfast!
There, there...
Open wide!
Is it good?
Satoshi, are you ready
to go to school?
We’ll be working with clay today.
It’s fine! I left it all there!
Hey, hey...
Don’t forget your lunch box.
Oh, of course!
Thanks for waiting, you guys.
Looks pretty fun.
Play nice with each other, okay?
Lugarugan, Nyabby!
Look after the house while we’re out.
Well then, shall we go?
Yeah!
All right, I’ll do my best today, too!
Don’t forget me-roto!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Nebby Panic!
Sudden Teleportation!!
Come on over, come on over!
Have some Kiteruguma brand Honey Doughnuts, meow!
They’re delicious, meow!
All right, I’m sorry.
I will be more careful next time.
What’s the deal with
bowl-headed four-eyes?!
All she ever does is scold us for stuff that’s
done and over with, like she refuses to let go!
Well, we were summoned and
went all the way to Kanto,
only to leave without meeting her.
If we want to save face, we’ve gotta at least
earn enough money to fund our operations.
Right, the doughnuts
have been baked.
Sure... Can we really save face
by doing this?
We’re not even getting any customers.
It’ll be fine! If we open the stand
right in front of the Pokémon School,
starving children will come here,
lured by the sweet scent of honey!
It’s a brilliant plan!
There’s no way
they’ll come that easily...
Something smells great!
They came! Welcome!
Looks delicious!
The brat boy!
They’re covered with honey!
W-Welcome...
What’s that?!
Hey, Satoshi!
Grabbing junk food this early?
Yeah... I’ll be hungry
well before lunch.
Because you didn’t
eat breakfast-roto!
Some other time.
Darn...
Breakfast is the source of your energy
for the entire day! It’s important-roto.
Being a spoilsport
is not allowed, meow.
Hey, did you see that?
Sure did!
That was a really rare Pokémon!
That purple body and gas-like composition...
Truly, a rare Pokémon among rare Pokémon!
Yes! There can be no doubt!
What is it?
A PetitDogas!
PetitDogas?
What’s that?
Nan nan’su?
Just like Pichu is
Pikachu’s pre-evolution,
that is undoubtedly the
pre-evolution of Dogas, PetitDogas!
I get it! If you’re so sure,
then that must be it, meow!
All right, this is our chance to save face!
Let’s get that PetitDogas!
Yeah!
Did you all bring your clay?
Yes!
Oh, no! I forgot mine!
I’ll share mine.
Thank you...
Wait, what’s that?
Clay!
Today you’ll be sculpting your
partner Pokémon. Got it?
If you watch them carefully while sculpting them,
you might discover something new.
Yes!
Now, who do I sculpt?
Nebby and Mokuroh are asleep, so...
Pikachu, I choose you!
Stand still.
Ashimari, Balloon!
Stop. Stay like that.
Hang in there, Ashimari!
It’s a Denjimushi!
Do the assignment-roto.
Rejected.
It’s finished! It’s Bakugames!
It doesn’t feel stable.
Bakugames, get down!
All right! This’ll work!
Amamaiko,
what pose would you like?
So cute!
If Denjimushi’s a no-go,
I’ll rise to the challenge with Togedemaru!
What’re those?
They’re tools to recreate
Togedemaru’s pride, her thorns.
A super deluxe potter’s wheel
and carbon spatulas!
Wait, aren’t you
gonna sculpt anything?
Nope. Not yet!
It might be better if
I made it a little bit thinner.
What do you think?
This looks more like
Mimikkyu than Pikachu.
Ouch...
All right, let’s try again!
It’s starting to look
more like a Purin.
Less Purin, more...
Togedemaru is more...
Huh?
What happened?
Well, I thought I saw a Purin...
There’s nobody here but Togedemaru.
What pose would be best?
Good grief...
What’s wrong?
Mao disappeared,
and then she came back!
Like “poof”!
What’s wrong, Suiren?
I was in the ocean.
Nebby?
Like the mountain of Akala...
He disappeared!
He’s back!
Ashimari, use Bubble Beam!
What was that?!
I almost fell into the volcano!
Volcano?
Did you see that?
Nebby disappeared alongside him!
Yeah.
That was Teleport-roto.
Teleport?
Teleportation is when you move
from one place to another in an instant-roto.
Awesome!
Kaki, I didn’t know you could do that!
You think I did that?!
That must have been
Nebby’s power.
Nebby’s?
So, where did Nebby go?
Lilie!
Now Lilie’s gonna teleport?!
...Or not?
It’s asleep.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Purin
Type:   Normal/Fairy
You guys’re lucky.
I wanna get taken off somewhere too!
Where were you all taken?
To wherever Purin was.
I ended up with Yareyutan.
I was in the ocean.
I was on the volcano.
By any chance,
when the Teleport happened,
were you all thinking
about those places?
Now that you mention it, I might have thought that
my unfinished Togedemaru sculpture looked like a Purin.
yare yare
Oh yeah. Just as I said “good grief”,
I remembered Yareyutan.
I always find myself
thinking about the ocean.
I was saying
“Like the mountain of Akala”.
In which case, it would be
logical to conclude that...
...Nebby read your thoughts and
teleported to wherever you were thinking.
I get it. Lilie might be right.
It’s still a baby, so it might not know
where it wants to go itself yet.
Perhaps.
Nebby, where do you want to go?
Are you hungry?
All right, open wide!
Sorry, sorry!
It might stop crying if
we make a funny face!
I used to do that all the time
with Ho and Sui!
Counting on you!
Nebby, look over here!
No good, huh?
Then, I’ll try!
What? No good?
You’ll scare it looking like that.
Why?!
What do we do?
I know! In that case...
I will do it.
It worked!
It stopped crying!
They disappeared-roto!
Purin!
They’re not coming back.
Where did it teleport him?
I’m a bit worried.
Surely they must have teleported to
wherever Satoshi was thinking about.
Satoshi would probably just keep
bouncing around to all sorts of places, and never stop...
He can’t do that!
A-Anyway, we can’t just
wait around here, can we?
Yeah.
All right,
let’s all go search for them.
Mokuroh, you help out too!
Lizardon!
We were sleeping?
We gotta get this
cleaned off somewhere.
I know I said I wanted
to get clean, but...
Huh? I’m back home!
Sorry to disturb you two.
So this is Teleport...
Wait, what?!
Hot! I’m gonna fall!
I won’t lose to you,
stupid bowl-headed four-eyes!
Oh, youth. Though it’s come
far too late, meow.
I feel better now.
So, how do we get that PetitDogas?
How about we
ambush them, meow?
We never know when the brat boys will get in our way
if we just wait in front of the School.
Yeah.
It’d be great if they just happened to show up here
on this empty beach, but that’s not very likely, is it?
So, where are we now?
You guys are...!
When you say “You guys are...!”,
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket!
What are you doing here?!
When asked “What are you doing?!”,
we’re not telling.
Hey, brat boy! We’ll be taking that
PetitDogas you have there!
PetitDogas?
That thing you’re carrying!
As if I’d let you have it!
Oh, you wanna fight?
Well, then we’ll just have to take it by force!
I thought of something brilliant.
What?
What, meow?
I getcha, meow!
All right, now that
we’ve settled that...
You’d better fight fair and square,
one on one!
We’ll watch from the sidelines,
so as to not get in the way, meow!
Now, Mimikkyu! Beat them up
to your heart’s content!
Pikachu, be careful!
That thing’s strong!
Stay back, Nebby.
It’s dangerous.
Pikachu, use Electro Ball!
It won’t let you attack easily.
Pay attention, and wait for an opening!
Well? What’s wrong? Bring it on!
That’s it!
Now’s our chance!
I’ve got you now, meow!
Nebby!
Take that!
PetitDogas belongs to us now!
Oh, come on!
How was that “fair and square”?!
Yay! Yay! We tricked you!
Hang on a second!
It’s in times like these
that we must be alert.
This is when it usually shows up.
Yeah, it!
Why? Why?
What’s going on?
What even is this feeling?
Nebby!
I’m so glad you came back!
It must be tired.
Found them! There they are!
Satoshi!
Hey, Satoshi!
Spotted them-roto!
Where were you?
We looked everywhere!
Nebby!
Nebby’s sleeping.
It teleported around a lot.
Like to the top of the volcano,
or into the ocean.
To Yareyutan’s place, or Purin’s place.
Aren’t those...
Yeah, the places it went with all of you.
It might have wanted to go back.
What’s more,
it made it back here on its own.
Nebby’s slowly getting better at
using Teleport-roto. How clever-roto!
We have to tell Professor Kukui.
Yeah. He’s probably desperately
searching for Satoshi in the forest right now.
Oh, no!
Are you awake-roto?
Why are we here?!
T-This might be because I was thinking about
going back to the Pokémon School!
Well, then, couldn’t you
put us in the classroom?!
Somebody,
get us down from here!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting-roto!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Teleport-roto!
Being able to instantly move to any place a person or
Pokémon is thinking about is awesome-roto!
But being teleported is rough-roto.
Since Nebby can use Teleport,
it might be a Psychic type-roto.
Satoshi! Bakugames’s Flamethrower
is amazing-roto!
Don’t just teleport me
without my permission-roto!
Next episode
Sauboh! It seems Lilie is
coming here with her friends!
Then let us go over what we, as hosts,
have to provide them, Wicke.
Yes, Sir!
Cleaning, cooking, reception.
Cake, macarons and biscuits!
Greeting, showing them around,
seeing them off.
Jelly, ice cream and
a chocolate fountain!
Next time, on Pokémon Sun & Moon:
C’mon, Let’s Search for
the Transformed Metamon!
Will this really work out?
Next time
C'mon, Let's Search for
the Transformed Metamon!