Are you all doing well-roto?
I will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Ju'niper
Sauboh
Dodekabashi
Kapu-Bulul
Who trains Mokuroh today-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
In the first round of
the Alola Pokémon League’s final tournament...
Intense, heated battles unfolded,
and eight winners emerged.
For the second round...
Even more intense battles lie in store,
and there’s no telling who’ll win!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Overcome Ju'niper!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Dodge, Mokuroh!
Mokuroh!
Are you all right, Mokuroh?
His lack of progress
concerns me-roto.
He can do it!
Can’t you, Mokuroh?
Oh! There they are!
Alola!
You certainly are up early today.
You weren’t in your room when I woke up,
so I was wondering where you’d gone!
Yeah. Mokuroh woke me up.
Mokuroh?!
Astonishing.
Mokuroh’s been raring to go
ever since last night-roto!
We get to battle
Hau and Ju'niper again.
In this huge arena, at that!
Isn’t this exciting, Mokuroh?
About that...
I know he won
against Fukuthrow last time,
but now that Fukuthrow’s evolved into Ju'niper,
Mokuroh has to be at a disadvantage.
Wouldn’t it be better to battle with Nyaheat,
since he’s a Fire type?
Yeah... Nyaheat would be
at a type advantage.
Yeah.
I’ll go with Mokuroh.
Satoshi?
Do you have some secret plan?
Nope.
But Mokuroh says
he wants to fight.
I trust Mokuroh.
He’ll pull through!
But...
That’s why we’re training.
Right, Mokuroh?
I understand!
May your burning passion
lead you to victory, Mokuroh!
We’re rooting for you...
You’re in today’s
second match, right?
You don’t have much time.
We’ll do what we can!
I’ll help, too-roto!
I would have liked to help,
but my brother...
He’s in the first match,
and you want to go cheer him on, right?
Gotta show your support!
I wanna see Gladio’s battle, too!
But this is more important.
You guys go cheer Gladio on.
I want to gather data,
so I’ll stay here-roto!
Well, we’ll go on ahead, then.
Don’t be late for your match!
I will bring him to the arena
when it’s time-roto!
Hang in there,
Satoshi, Mokuroh.
Yeah!
Now, let the training continue!
You get it, yeah?
You beat me... by accident!
It was a fluke!
You’d better win...
Or else!
I-I get it...
We’re counting on you to
carry out our goal, meow.
Here. Take this,
and go wild out there!
The first match of
the Alola Pokémon League’s second round...
...is Competitor Gladio VS
Competitor Dekojiro.
Competitor Gladio is a skilled trainer
who has fought his way up the ranks with ease!
I look forward to seeing
how he battles today!
You can do it, Big Brother!
He’ll win, for sure.
But he mustn’t
get overconfident.
What sort of battle will this be?
Do your best, Gladio!
Ever the worrywart, I see.
I’m not worried!
Don’t force yourself to hide it.
What mother wouldn’t
be worried about her kid?
It will be quite all right.
I’m certain
Young Master Gladio will win.
He’s very strong, after all.
And his opponent,
Competitor Dekojiro...
We finally got info on him.
It says he’s a ferocious warrior
who’s traveled the world and conquered Gym after Gym!
What?
When did that happen, meow?
He needed a résumé with more of a bite
to really freak out his opponent.
You’re up, Hidoide.
Wait...
This is no time for me to be
wobbling about poisoned.
Listen up, Hidoide.
For Team Rocket’s sake,
we must win this tournament.
...Though, I mean,
that’s true, but also...
I really want to win
and battle Royal Mask!
Will you fight with me
to make my dream a reality, Hidoide?
Thanks!
Oh, there they are!
Go! Take ‘im down!
You’re too excited, meow...
We shall now commence the first match of round two;
Competitor Gladio VS Competitor Dekojiro!
You’d best give up now,
while you have the chance!
Let’s just do this.
Let the battle commence!
Victory goes to he who strikes first!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
Dodge.
Come on! What is he doing?!
He can still win, meow...
Mokuroh! Razor Leaf!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Go, Mokuroh!
Are you all right,
Mokuroh?
He’s asleep-roto...
Don’t sleep, Mokuroh!
How will you win
if this keeps up-roto?
Good question...
He’ll have to learn a new move or something,
or you’ll have no counter strategy-roto...
That’s it!
Mokuroh, let’s learn a new move!
What are you doing-roto?!
Stop-roto!
What’s that?
Tsutsukera?!
And Kerarappa!
Dodekabashi!
So, are these guys...
They’re the Dodekabashi flock
that Mokuroh used to live with-roto!
Knew it! Long time, no see!
Are you here to cheer Mokuroh on?
What?
It’s Feather Dance-roto!
A move that uses feathers
to weaken the opponent’s moves-roto!
Awesome!
If he can learn this move, he might be able to
withstand Ju'niper’s powerful moves-roto!
All right!
We’ll master it, for sure!
Let the training continue!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Tsutsukera
Type:   Normal/Flying
Hidoide!
Hidoide narrowly managed
to stay standing...
But it can’t take much more!
Hey, isn’t this,
like, really bad?
They’re up against
a wall, meow!
Not yet... We can still do this,
right, Hidoide?
Lugarugan! Swords Dance!
Now!
Having weathered
hardships together,
we’ve come all this way!
We’ll show everyone
our full power!
Black Hole Eclipse!
Yeah! Go!
You got this, meow!
He could still pull that off,
even when backed into a corner?
He and his Pokémon must
truly believe in one another.
But our trust is
no less strong than theirs!
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
The rocks are bathed in the Z-Power
of the blue moon’s glow...
...and seal up...
...the crumbling world!
Eat this! World’s End Fall!
What?!
Huh... That’s...
...the same trick the kid pulled!
He canceled out the Z-Move
with one of his own!
Oh, no...
Stone Edge!
Hidoide!
Hidoide is unable to battle!
Accordingly, the victor
is Competitor Gladio!
I knew Young Master Gladio
could do it.
Yes! He’s so amazing!
He won!
Isn’t that great?
That’s great, Lilie!
I’m sorry...
Don’t worry!
He won, after all!
Be happy.
Yes...
Thank you, Snowball.
Satoshi’s match is up next, but...
M-Musashi...
I said you absolutely had to win,
did I not?!
W-Well...
I’m sorry!
I’ll let you off the hook
just this once.
We’ll just think of another way
to conquer the Alola Region, meow.
Team Rocket does not
look back on the past!
We keep moving forward, always!
Everyone...
Let’s keep trying, Hidoide!
I feel like we
almost have it down...
Satoshi! Gladio won-roto!
Really? Great job, Gladio!
This is no time to celebrate-roto!
Next up is match number two... Your match-roto!
That’s right!
Let’s go, Mokuroh!
What?
You look like Ju'niper!
Satoshi, hurry-roto!
Let’s go!
Where are
Satoshi and Mokuroh?
Did they forget?
They might have,
if they got too caught up in their training...
Should we go get him?
It should be fine,
since he’s got Rotom with him...
What’s Satoshi doing?
Satoshi!
Huh? He’s not here.
That’s weird...
It’s almost time for our battle...
He couldn’t have overslept,
could he?
Hurry!
Oh! Hau!
Satoshi!
I made it...
Oh, hey, that cloak
looks really cool!
Satoshi.
I want to become stronger.
I want to be an even greater trainer
than my gramps!
That’s why I’ll win
this battle against you!
I was always...
...aiming to pass
my gramps’s Grand Trial.
But once I did pass it,
I realized...
...that it wasn’t
my ultimate goal.
I won’t lose, either!
I’ll beat you, and everyone,
and win the League!
Now, there’s the Satoshi I know!
Let’s enjoy a full power battle!
Of course! Right, Mokuroh?
Match two’s
competitors Satoshi and Hau...
Please head for the battlefield
at once.
I repeat...
We gotta hurry!
Hurry-roto!
Everyone,
please cheer us on!
We’ll be rooting for you
from the seats-roto!
Thanks!
He really got me nervous...
Oh, kid...
I thought you weren’t coming.
Thank goodness, he made it.
That really was close-roto.
Huh? Mokuroh’s...
He seems to be
wearing something.
It’s the explosive birth
of Ju'nikuroh!
But anyway,
how did the training go?!
It may have paid off...
or not-roto...
What’s that mean?
Um... We will now begin
round two, match two!
Let the match begin!
Let’s show them
how much stronger we’ve gotten!
Ju'niper! Razor Leaf!
Dodge it, Mokuroh!
Seed Bomb!
Leaf Blade!
Well? Ju'niper’s
gotten stronger, yeah?
Yeah! I figured as much!
Guess we just gotta...
...unleash our full power
from the start!
He can’t be...
Already?!
Go, Mokuroh!
This is our full power!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Now, Ju'niper!
Ju'niper dodged
the mighty Z-Move!
It’s so like you
to go right for the Z-Move.
But I’ve researched
all your moves!
Spirit Shackle!
Mokuroh cannot move!
This is quite the pinch!
Now it’s our turn!
Oh, my! It seems Competitor Hau
is following suit!
Lord of the silent forest,
Ju'niper!
Here we go!
Shadow Arrows Strike!
Mokuroh!
Is this the end?!
Mokuroh?
Then what’s that?
He made it out by
shedding his cloak-roto!
Was that...
Was that the art of substitution?!
Man, I really didn’t
see that coming.
But you won’t escape
our next move!
The second match of the second round
in the Alola Pokémon League...
How will
this battle end?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting-roto!
It was Dodekabashi
who trained Mokuroh-roto!
Ju'niper. Arrow Quill Pokémon.
Grass/Ghost type.
Mokuroh’s final evolution.
Its exclusive Z-Move,
Shadow Arrows Strike...
...sends a large number of arrows flying
with awesome power-roto!
Next episode
Mr. Hala! I won’t give Hau special treatment
just ‘cause he’s your grandson!
Naturally!
I have taught him the harshness of battle
ever since he was young.
Here are some photos of that!
Oh, that’s impressive!
Here is his training on Wela Volcano!
How diligent.
This is a vital record of his growth!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Soaring Showdown!
Brave Bird VS God Bird!!
...Could you please photograph it for me?
Next time
A Soaring Showdown!
Brave Bird VS God Bird!!
No, I’m the judge!