Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Mantine
Alolan Persian
Trimmien
Eevee
Who is the Pokémon that
Ashimari saves today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Do you know this Eevee?
This Eevee came to the Alola Region
from across the ocean!
Trimmien! Time to go home!
Wanna have a barbecue
when we get home?
I get it!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Anywhere, to Find You!
Yay! Yay!
Yay! Yay! Yay!
Alola...
Alola! Alola!
Alola! Alola! Alola!
You sure are peppy...
Yeah! Peppy! Peppy!
Because...
He’s coming home!
Home! Home!
Coming home?
Daddy’s coming home!
I see!
He just called.
He’s obtained every single one of
the Pokémon the lab requested!
Whoa!
Including Kaiogre!
Kaiogre?!
No...
I’m just kidding!
Just kidding?!
Oh, we’ll be having a feast tonight!
Are you kidding about that, too?
It’s true!
It’s true?!
I want malasada for dessert!
Masalada! Masalada!
We’ll go buy some. Right, Ashimari?
Thanks, Big Sis!
Thanks, Ashimari!
It looks wonderful on you!
You really think so?
I wonder if it’s a tad plain, though...
Plain?! Oh, it simply pales in comparison to
your natural beauty!
Doesn’t it?
It’s much too plain for me!
Could you show me some others?
Welcome!
I’d like some malasadas.
Would you like them sweet,
sour, or dry?
Ho and Sui want them sweet...
And then, um...
Which would you like, Ashi...
Huh? Ashimari?
Ashimari!
Where are you, Ashimari?
She’s gone...
What an appetite-roto!
Eat up!
You, too.
Thank you, Ms. Moani.
Don’t mention it! It’s always wonderful to see
Little Nyabi and his friends doing well!
Suiren!
Satoshi!
What’s up?
Ashimari’s...
Perrie!
Where are you, Perrie?
Ashimari’s gone missing?!
Oh, no!
We’ll help you look!
Thank you, Mao.
Excuse me,
but would you let me off here?
It’s Lilie-roto!
Is something the matter?
Where is Ashimari?
Well...
Hey, Kaki!
Got it.
I’ll contact you if I find her.
Thank you.
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Mokuroh...
You’ll help search, too, Mokuroh?
What’s up, y’all?
Somethin’ happen?
What’s that thing?
Cute Eevee!
Soft and fluffy cute Eevee!
I’m takin’ ya home with me!
Can I, Bro?
Wrap!
Havin’ an Eevee around
would hurt Bro real bad, yo!
How come?
Just look at this precious li’l baby!
Havin’ that thing around’ll make ‘im think of
that friggin’ stud Ilima all the time!
Stud...
Look at that!
That guy has an Eevee with him!
You’re right! It’s so cute!
Hey, isn’t that Eevee’s trainer cool?
So cool!
An adorable Eevee
with a cool trainer...
The contrast’s irresistible!
Oh, no...
Bro?
Okay! Eevee’ll be mine!
No! The cute Eevee
goes home with me!
He’s mine!
No, mine!
Mine!
Mine, I say!
Hey, I said he’s mine!
Mine!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I wanna be popular!
I’ll get Pokémon!
I don’t care!
Name: Zubat
Type:   Poison/Flying
Please!
I’ll raise ‘im!
Gimme a chance!
I wanna raise ‘im!
U-Um...
Hah! Faked ya out!
He’s mine!
Give it up!
I’ll play ya for ‘im!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Are you all right, Ashimari?
And...
...Eevee?
Are you lost?
It’s a wild Eevee-roto!
Oh, my!
Looks like they’re friends
with that Eevee.
Yeah!
Such good friends.
Hey, y’all!
Yer gonna hand that Eevee over to us!
The cute Eevee’s mine!
No, he’s mine!
I said, he’s mine!
Bro... Wrap...
Mine!
What part of “mine” don’t ya get?!
That’s my line!
He’s mine! Mine, I say!
Will ya drop it already?!
No, you!
I’m yer Bro, remember?!
Just let me have this one!
Why should I hafta
let you have ‘im?!
Bro...
Act like a grown-up!
Don’tcha think this has gone on
for long enough?
Ain’t you a grown-up, too?!
No, I’m not!
Let me have ‘im!
No, he’s mine!
We’re not giving him to either of you!
What?!
Couldn’t you tell that
you were bothering Eevee?!
If you can’t treat a Pokémon right,
then you don’t deserve to catch it!
Can it! ‘Kay,
we’ll just catch ‘im by force!
Yeah!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Ashimari...
All right!
Let’s protect him together!
Your Eevee friend!
Eevee?
Yatoumori! Flame Burst!
Dustdas! Sludge Bomb!
Zubat! Supersonic Waves!
Ashimari! Aqua Jet!
Th-This move... It’s Surf-roto!
Ashimari has learned Surf-roto!
What’s this?!
Eevee...
Eevee and us’re...
...totally incompatible!
Bye bye, cute Eevee...
Wh-What?
That was Desperate Tackle-roto!
This guy and Ashimari?
Yup. It’s Ashimari’s Eevee friend!
You did great, both of you.
Ashimari and Eevee
really do get along great!
Hey, Suiren, you should catch him!
Great idea!
I’m sure Eevee wants to
be with you, too!
I completely agree!
She’s catching him, huh?
How exciting!
Catch him...
You love the sea, don’t you...?
Sandy.
Sandy?
That’s his name.
You named him already?
You’re getting ahead of yourself.
Come on...
You got the order wrong, Suiren!
Catch him! Catch him!
Will you be with us?
I got Sandy!
Feast! Feast!
Sandy! Sandy!
Oh, my...
Feast! Feast!
Sandy! Sandy!
I’m home!
Daddy!
Welcome home!
Gah!
Sandy.
Sandy?
I just caught him earlier today.
So cute! So cute!
He’s an Eevee who
loves the sea!
The sea...
Loves the sea...
Oh, perhaps...
Out at sea, I saw...
...an Eevee riding a Mantine!
Yeah!
That might have been Sandy!
Right, Ashimari?
Sit down, Sandy.
Done!
Yup. It turned out great!
Does that feel better?
Looks great on you!
With the addition of the Eevee
who came to Alola from across the sea,
Suiren’s family has gotten livelier.
We’re happy for you,
Suiren, Ashimari... and Sandy.
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting!
The Pokémon that Ashimari saved
was Eevee!
The Evolution Pokémon Eevee
is a Normal type.
What should I evolve Sandy into?
I’m thinking of evolving him
into a Bug type!
Just kidding!
Yay! Yay!
Next episode
Hey, Rotom.
I saw a yellow, spiky Pokémon!
That was a Spear-roto!
No, it was using Electric moves.
I got it-roto!
It was a Dentula-roto!
No...
It seemed super strong!
Thunder?
Oh! Raikou-roto!
No, that’s not it, either...
What was that Pokémon?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Lightning that Slices the Wind!
Its Name is Zeraora!!
I got it! It was Koduck-roto!
Next time
The Lightning that Slices the Wind!
Its Name is Zeraora!!
The only thing right is the color...