Burnet here! V! V!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Suikun
Entei
Zoroark
Raikou
Which Pokémon
is Gladio looking for in today’s episode?
Blue: Suikun?
Red: Entei?
Green: Zoroark?
Or Yellow: Raikou?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Poni Island,
home to Island Queen Hāpu'u.
Golugh!
100,000 Horsepower!
It seems Hāpu'u is
in the middle of a battle.
Here it comes, Golugh!
Luster Cannon!
Ultimate Dragon Burn!
That was a most fine battle!
I, the Island Queen of Poni Island,
declare that you have cleared my Grand Trial.
You did a splendid job, Golugh.
I am most grateful.
Was mine your final Grand Trial?
Yeah.
Will you enter...
...the Alola Pokémon League?
But before that,
there’s something I have to do.
I see...
It is believed that Magearna’s true self
is the Soul Heart, located in her chest.
Some documents say it’s powered by Pokémon souls,
but that hasn’t been proven.
But I can’t give up now.
It’s all for my little princess, Lilie.
For me...
Father was trying everything he could think of
to activate Magearna on his own.
Making full use of modern science,
to try and replicate
the accomplishments of ancient science...
Snowball!
I’m sorry.
I was engrossed in my studies.
Ms. Lilie!
Yes!
Your friends are here to see you.
I see!
I’m going to practice Z-Moves
together with Mao and Suiren today!
Master Satoshi and the boys
are here as well.
They are?
Alola, everyone!
Alola!
We asked them to cheer us on.
Let’s make those Z-Moves work!
The Alola Pokémon League
is right around the corner!
Let me train with you, too!
Let us give it our all!
But first...
There is a Pokémon
I’d like you all to meet.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Gladio and Lilie!
Chasing the Father’s Illusion!!
Let me introduce you.
This is Magearna.
Magearna! I’ve never seen
this Pokémon before-roto!
Father got her for me
back when I was still a baby.
I see.
It seems Magearna is an artificial Pokémon
that was created by scientists...
...over 500 years ago.
It’s said to synchronize its consciousness with others,
allowing it to understand their feelings.
Data on Magearna updated-roto!
Is Magearna asleep?
The truth is, Magearna has never moved,
not since Father met her.
Father worked hard
to try and get her to move, but...
Hey, Lilie...
Can I touch her?
Naturally!
Magearna, I’m Satoshi.
Nice to meet you!
I wanna introduce myself, too!
I’m Mao.
It’s nice to meet you!
I’m Suiren. Pleasure.
I’m Māmane.
Kaki.
What is this-roto?
Well, you see, I should very much like
to be friends with Magearna,
so I’ve been studying
Father’s Magearna journal.
I see!
That’s awesome, Lilie!
I’m rooting for you!
Me, too!
Same here!
Thank you so much!
To awaken Magearna...
And to master the Z-Move...
Until I can see Father again,
I will put my full power
into these goals!
It’s finally coming true...
The dream I’ve had since childhood,
that’s been burning in my heart
like a Magma Storm...
My dream to form
an Alolan Pokémon League!
Yeaaaaah!
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Would you like some of the most delicious
Honey Doughnuts in all of Alola, meow?!
In commemoration of
Manalo Stadium’s opening,
we’ve started our sales today,
before anyone else anywhere!
You can get an early taste of
the Manalo Doughnuts, here and nowhere else!
I’ll have three
Manalo Doughnuts, please!
Of course!
I want five!
Coming right up!
Here!
Here, meow!
Thank you very much!
We hope to see you again, meow!
Good...
Very good!
Operation: “Take Advantage of Manalo Stadium’s Opening
to Rake In the Cash” is a massive success, meow!
Team Rocket aims not only
for victory in the League...
But also to conquer
the Alolan economy!
What a great feeling!
I really look forward to seeing
the birth of Alola’s first-ever Champion.
Oh? I thought for sure
you would be participating.
No, I find watching more enjoyable
than participating.
Where’s Professor Kukui?
Pretty sure he’s at the arena.
Already?!
He’s been like an excited little boy lately,
saying “My childhood dream will come true at last!”
I feel romanticism in the air!
I’m counting on you, Blacky.
Not it, huh...?
Zoroark?
Yeah!
I’ll find it and catch it!
I’ll tell it that Dad is alive,
so that we can find him together!
Thank you, Gladio.
It had been bothering me
for so long...
I would be so happy
if it came back to us.
Try again,
and start from the pose!
Right!
Let’s go, Amajo!
That was great!
You’re making clear progress!
You’re almost there!
Of course!
Let’s do our best!
I will perfect this move!
Fleeting Bubble Aria!
Us too, then!
Kuwagannon! EM Cannon!
Kuwagannon’s EM Cannon
was amazing!
Ashirène was incredible, too!
You’ve got Fleeting Bubble Aria
down perfectly!
That’s wonderful!
It’ll help my Z-Move, too.
When I do feel the Z-Power,
I’m not sure how to
share it with Snowball.
It’s easy!
When you feel it heating up
like fwoosh,
you let your power
burst out like zap...
And then Pikachu goes
fwoosh and zap, too...
Right, Pikachu?
“Fwoosh”? “Zap”?
That’s right! Fwoosh and zap!
Miss, it is starting!
Coming!
It’s Professor Kukui!
I’m incredibly honored to be able to unveil
the Alola League venue, Manalo Stadium, to all of you today!
The Alola League is a tournament open for all,
the likes of which could only be held in Alola.
Everybody, please come and participate
with hearts burning like a Sacred Flame!
Of course we will!
Right, guys?!
Absolutely! There is but one goal...
Victory!
It will be mine!
No, mine!
No, it’ll be mine!
Mine! Mine!
Mine! Mine! Mine!
It can only be mine!
And for the Alola Pokémon League’s first-ever Champion,
who will be crowned here...
We’ve prepared a special exhibition battle
for after the tournament ends!
Special?
Exhibition?
Battle?
They will be facing...
Royal Mask?!
And Gaogaen!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Zoroark
Type:   Evil
Being able to battle
the League’s first-ever Champion...
...is a great honor for me!
W-Wh-What?!
What a brilliant idea!
A special exhibition battle
with Royal Mask?!
All together, now, everyone...
Enjoy the Alola Pokémon League!
Enjoy!
I will be the Champion!
No, me!
The Champion will be me!
Me!
It’ll be me!
Here they go again...
I will focus on mastering my Z-Move!
Great!
I will take some time off work!
I need to train
in order to win the League!
Didn’t you just say you’d rather
watch the battles than participate?
Why, I said no such thing!
Musashi! Nyarth! Sonansu!
What?
I will win the Alola Pokémon League,
no matter what!
Kojiro’s on fire, meow!
Wh-Why?!
Evil Pulse!
Shadow Ball!
Blacky!
We’re here to find Zoroark.
I wonder if I can
get out more Z-Power?
But I can’t give up now.
It’s all for my little princess, Lilie.
Lend me strength, Father.
Lilie!
Amazing!
Snow silently fluttering down
from the heavens...
Countless glimmering crystals of ice...
O, freezing Z that covers the land...
Along with my heated soul,
return now once more to the heavens!
Raging Geofreeze!
Snowball!
Thank you!
You did wonderfully!
Congratulations, Lilie!
That was so cool!
Thank you all!
Satoshi!
I did it!
Fwoosh and zap!
Sure did! That was
a great fwoosh and zap!
You’ve graduated from
your provisional Z-Ring license!
We’d better go
tell Mr. Hala about this!
Indeed!
Blacky! Evil Pulse!
Zoroark?!
Well done, Gladio.
You went to tell Mommy
that Lilie was crying?
Yup! I made sure Mommy knew!
Is this... Zoroark’s illusion?
There, there, Lilie, don’t cry.
Don’t cry, Lilie!
Is our little princess
in a bad mood?
Here, Lilie... Poke, poke!
Nyah nyah... Bah!
She smiled! Such a good girl...
It’s our little princess’s smile!
Let me see the princess’s smile, too!
Here. You too, Gladio.
You’re Dad’s...
I wanted to see you.
Zoroark... Dad is alive.
I want you to help me
look for him.
Gladio has met Zoroark.
Lilie has mastered her Z-Move.
Their wish to meet
their father, Mohn, again...
...steadily pushes them forward.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting! V!
The Pokémon Gladio was looking for...
...was Zoroark!
The Illusion Fox Pokémon Zoroark
is an Evil type.
It has the power to disguise itself
as other Pokémon.
It’s said to protect its lair
with illusory scenery.
I can’t believe you found it,
Gladio!
Now, come forth!
You’ll be partners from now on.
Next episode
I’ll win!
No, I will!
I won’t lose, either!
Satoshi and the others
are really fired up!
It is the opening of
the Pokémon League, after all.
Well, then...
Ready, and...
Rock, paper, scissors!
Rock, paper, scissors?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Curtain Rises!
The Alola Pokémon League!!
All right! I won!
Time to eat!
Oh, a malasada.
I see...
Next time
The Curtain Rises!
The Alola Pokémon League!!