Alola!
I will be giving today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Agoyon
Ariados
Kapu-Rehire
Lunala
One of Bebenom’s kind
appears in today’s episode-roto.
Who is it-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
We Ultra Guardians rushed in to save Lunala,
who was in trouble.
We managed to save Lunala, but UB: Black
possessed Solgaleo and left through the Ultra Hole.
We promised that we’d use our full power
to save Solgaleo.
And then...
...using our full power!
Yeah!
Lunala...
Lunala is...!
Calm down, Lunala!
It must want to
go help Solgaleo.
Probably.
Then we’ll do the same!
Yeah, let’s go.
Yeah!
Of course!
Wait just a minute...
You’re planning on accompanying Lunala
to the world beyond the Ultra Hole?
Yes.
It’s too dangerous.
But back when we went to rescue you,
we got home safely.
True, it went well that time...
But we don’t know the sort of world
that Ultra Hole connects to!
It will be fine.
Please!
All right.
We’ll do whatever we can
to support you!
Yes!
All right, let’s go!
Yeah!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
A Prism of Light and Darkness,
Its Name is Necrozma!
If we can get Lunala and hand it over to Sakaki
before that bowl-headed four-eyes does...
His respect for us will skyrocket!
And then we’ll get to
order that bowl-headed four-eyes around!
It’s Lunala, meow!
We’re not giving up!
Let’s go after it, meow!
And while we’re at it,
we’ll gather some info!
Let’s go, too.
Yes.
I’ll prepare a helicopter.
Wait...
Ms. Lusamine, I’ll go.
What?
We’ve been inundated
with unexpected trouble since yesterday.
And for all we know,
Team Rocket could strike again.
But...
Professor Kukui is right.
President, please remain here.
We need someone to
gather information and give orders.
Please don’t worry.
I will go with him.
Sauboh... All right.
Burnet, I leave this to you.
Be careful.
Well, then...
Come along, Kukui.
I will be the team leader.
It’s open.
Are you all ready?
Yeah!
We’re off, Ms. Lusamine.
Make sure you come home safe
after rescuing Solgaleo.
Ult-Roger!
Our connection with the Ultra Guardians
has been broken.
Could we at least
communicate by audio?
I’ll see what I can do.
We will reach our destination
momentarily.
I’ve been waiting for this chance.
We will go through the Ultra—
What happened?!
We’ve taken a hit from 9 o’clock!
It doesn’t matter. Go!
No, it wouldn’t be safe to enter the Ultra Hole
while the hull’s damaged!
Fall back!
And put out the fire!
Hard turn to port!
Get that fire out!
Multipe heat signatures on
the mountain ahead!
Putting it on screen!
Well done, Warrgle.
Hey, you listening?
“Matori Matrix”, was it?
We won’t let you get in
the Ultra Guardians’ way!
You insolent little...!
Warrgle! Rock Slide!
Houdin! Shadow Ball!
And Sleeper, you use Psychokinesis!
Gozu, crush the enemy!
You needn’t tell me!
Prepare counterattack!
Where are we?
What’s up, Bebenom?
Satoshi,
it’s gonna leave us behind!
Let’s hurry!
Watch out-roto!
Lizardon, Flamethrower!
Bebenom?
Over here, too!
They’re here as well.
Is that...
A Bebenom nest?
Wait! We’re not your enemies!
We’re just here to save Solgaleo!
Bebenom!
That one’s huge!
No data! No data!
It kinda looks like Bebenom.
It’s got the same
color and shape.
Is it... one of its kind?
Let’s go!
Wait, Satoshi!
If we don’t get going,
we’ll lose sight of Lunala.
But we gotta help that big one!
Well? Do you think
you can figure it out?
It won’t be easy to decipher.
There’s gotta be some hint on that mural about
the relationship between the Radiant One and UB: Black.
Yeah.
If only we could work that out,
it might help us rescue Solgaleo...
There doesn’t seem to be
anything physically wrong, but...
...it seems pretty tired.
Have some Obon Berries.
Eat.
Here!
Well?
Is it good?
Please get better.
Thank you,
ones without stingers.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Bebenom
Type:   Poison
Thank you,
ones without stingers.
W-What? Who was that?
It was I.
Telepathy?
You said you had come to
rescue Solgaleo, correct?
Yeah.
UB: Black possessed Solgaleo
and fled here.
UB: Black...
Do you mean Necrozma?
Necrozma?
I have a request.
Please leave Necrozma be.
We have need of
Necrozma’s power.
But that would mean
leaving Solgaleo...
Why?
Please explain your reasons.
Then allow me to show you
what happened in this world.
Amazing!
Is this telepathy, too?
There’s so much green!
Could this be...?
It is this world, as it once was.
The world we live in was filled with
the light that Necrozma rained down on us.
That’s Necrozma?
Looks like the painting
of the Radiant One.
So, the Bebenom
call the Radiant One Necrozma...
However...
It was not just the light of hope
that rained down upon us.
A meteor!
If this had hit you, then...
Kaboom!
UB: Black!
That means...
...that the Radiant One,
having lost its light, became...
UB: Black...
So both Bebenom’s drawing
and the image on the mural...
...were showing the Radiant One,
who had lost its light-roto!
Necrozma protected
this world, but...
Wounded and having lost its light,
it entered a long slumber.
In time, the plants withered,
and the lands were desolated.
We were forced to
rely on what little light we had,
and live huddled together like this.
I had no choice but to search for
a new place where everyone could live...
But I am old, and I no longer
have the strength to do so.
It’s Satoshi’s Bebenom-roto!
This one set out on its own.
And so you came to Alola?
I see... Alola seems like
a nice place.
Yeah, it’s the best!
Just when we had given up on this world,
and placed our hopes on a new land,
a chance appeared.
Lunala! Solgaleo!
In order to absorb these two lights
and revitalize itself,
Necrozma awoke
from its slumber.
Light? Radiance?
That “light” must be
their Ultra Aura-roto!
This story sounds kinda familiar...
Yes.
It resembles the legend of
the Radiant One.
Lilie, could you
tell us that story again?
The Radiant One appeared on Earth,
and filled the world with its overflowing light.
The light was filled with a mysterious power,
and from it our Alola Region was born.
However, after the Radiant One
had depleted all its light,
it turned black,
and entered a long, deep slumber.
Then the emissaries of the sun and moon appeared,
and shared their light with it.
Awakened from its slumber,
the Radiant One shone once more,
and flew off to
the ends of the sky.
So Necrozma didn’t attack Solgaleo and Lunala
for just no reason.
So you wanted to
revitalize Necrozma...
...and have it
restore this world?
Exactly.
But that would mean
losing Solgaleo forever.
That’s right!
What would happen to Solgaleo?
It would stay possessed, right?
If we save Solgaleo, then...
...Bebenom’s world stays like it is.
Silvuddy!
Gladio!
Air Slash!
Another Air—
Wait, Gladio!
If we leave Necrozma
to its own devices,
it’ll mean losing both
Solgaleo and Lunala!
Well...
The darkness might fall
over Alola eventually, too!
Are you okay with that?!
No, I’m not.
But if we drive Necrozma away,
then there’s no hope for Bebenom’s world.
So I...
will save everything!
Everything?!
Big brother.
I agree with
Satoshi’s perspective.
As do I.
Me, too.
And me.
I do, too.
And me-roto!
Well then, what do we do?
Necrozma wants Ultra Aura...
That’s why it’s trying to
possess Solgaleo and Lunala...
It’s basically starving...
Sharing!
Of course!
Together, we can weather...
...any storMaggyo!
Mankey! Mantine!
Alola, Manalo, right?
What are you talking about?
Alola means “To share”.
Manalo means
“You and I live together”!
Share... What?
Something like power.
That’s right! Z-Power!
Z-Power is closely linked
to Ultra Aura...
Professor Burnet said so-roto!
So basically, we’ll share our Z-Power
with Necrozma...
...and live together with it!
Once Necrozma’s all full
from our Z-Power,
it might release Solgaleo!
That’s it!
Let’s do it!
Gladio!
Got it!
So here you are...
We won’t let you
go through the Ultra Hole!
Give it up!
You underestimate us.
We will remove them!
Wait!
I’ll do it.
Let’s go!
Bossgodra?!
The fun’s only just beginning!
That’s...
Evolution that
transcends evolution...
Mega Evolution!
Heavy Bomber!
Warrgle!
Houdin! Sleeper!
Unthinkable...
In just one hit?!
Talk about sloppy.
But what do we do?
It looks like the mega rare thing possessed Solgaleo
and went through the Ultra Hole.
As did Lunala
and the brats, meow.
Well, that just means that
they’re all inside that Ultra Hole, yeah?
So we can
catch’ em easily, yeah?
So, we’re going through
the Ultra Hole, too?!
Well, that’s too scary, yeah?
We might not be able
to get back, yeah?
Then, what do we do, meow?
We just catch ‘em all
the moment the brats come back, yeah?
Yeah! We’ll champion the evils
of truth and love, yeah?!
Yeah! We’re the lovely,
charming villains, meow!
I got it, Lusamine!
You’ve deciphered it?
Yes!
UB: Black is the Radiant One,
who’s lost its light!
What do you mean?
Let me read it.
“The Radiant One, having expended all of its light,
was consumed by darkness.
“Then darkness began to
spread in Alola once more.
“The people then decided to take the light
that had been shared with them...
“...and give some of it back
to the Radiant One.”
They would share it?
“The emissaries of
the sun and moon appeared,
“and offered their prayers
with the Pokémon and people.
“Their prayers reached
the Radiant One,
“who regained its light.
“Alola became
a beautiful world once more.”
So there was another tale hidden
in the legend my father told me?
Yes. It wasn’t just the emissaries of the sun and moon
who shared their light with the Radiant One...
The people and Pokémon did, too!
We’ve got to find some way to bring this information
to Satoshi and the others!
Necrozma, we’re gonna give you
plenty of Z-Power to eat!
Lunala!
Get away from Necrozma!
Huh? You’re not
using Lugarugan?
Don’t think I’ll always be
the same as I was.
We’ve matured, too.
I see.
Right! Let’s go, Pikachu!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Super Aqua Tornado!
Ultra Dash Attack!
Satoshi and the others have
bathed Necrozma in their four moves.
Will they be able
to save Solgaleo?!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The one of Bebenom’s kind
was Agoyon-roto!
Agoyon, whom we met in Bebenom’s world,
is a Poison/Dragon type.
It was the leader
of the Bebenom-roto!
And what’s more,
it can talk and show images using telepathy...
It’s an awesome Ultra Beast-roto!
Thank you...
How considerate of you.
A Granbull Mountain!
You get me!
Next episode
The emissary of the sun
is consumed by darkness...
The efforts of the moon’s emissary and
the innocent children proves fruitless...
The world is faced with darkness!
In this crisis, Musashi, Kojiro
and Nyarth make a stand...
The radiant legend of the three saviors...
...reaches its conclusion!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Connect to the Future! The Legend of the Radiant One!!
Next time
Connect to the Future!
The Legend of the Radiant One!!