This is awesome!
Right, Pikachu?
This is Melemele Island,
one of several islands that make up the Alola Region.
Satoshi and Pikachu are
vacationing on this island.
Right... Let’s do this, Samehada!
That freaked me out...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Alola!
A New Island With New Pokémon!!
How did you like Alola’s famous
Pokémon Jet Ski?
It was super fun!
Good to hear!
Come back any time!
Sure!
Thank you, Samehada.
You’re not beating me!
Sorry!
Blue seas... White clouds...
and...
delicious Pile Juice...
This is so calming!
Mom, I’m back!
Welcome back, Satoshi.
That was great!
I dove into the sea with Samehada,
and there were so many Pokémon there
that I’d never seen before!
Glad to hear you had fun.
All thanks to Bari-chan winning tickets for an Alola vacation
in the shopping district lottery!
Hooray!
Professor,
please look after these.
Of course.
Leave it to me.
We’re here!
All right, time to get changed
and head out.
Head out?
To go see
Professor Okido’s cousin.
Oh, that’s right!
Your timing couldn’t be better!
I wasn’t sure how to get this to my cousin,
who lives in the Alola Region.
An egg, huh?
Say, what Pokémon is it?
That’ll be a surprise for
when the egg hatches!
Darn...
We’ll be sure to give it to him.
I’ve never ridden
a Pokémon taxi before!
Here in Alola, we can go anywhere
with the help of Pokémon!
They’re called Ride Pokémon.
If you want to cross the land,
you use Land Ride.
Flying through the sky
is called Sky Ride.
If you wanna go out at sea,
you can use a Sea Ride Pokémon.
Oh, so the Samehada I rode earlier
was a Sea Ride Pokémon, huh?
Oh, you’ve already experienced it, sir?
Say, where are we
dropping off the egg?
At a place called
the Pokémon School.
Pokémon School?
Sounds fun, doesn’t it?
Yeah!
Oh, those fruits look delicious!
Maybe I should buy some as souvenirs.
Everything they sell at the marketplace
is fresh and delicious!
All right, that settles it!
There’s just so much
to choose from...
It’s a Pokémon! So cool!
What kind of Pokémon are you?
Owwww!
All right!
Let’s catch it, Pikachu!
What do you think about...
Hm?
Hold it!
Where are you?!
Where’d it go?!
Ow!
Huh?
Where are we?
Aw, man... We’re totally lost.
Um... Where were we supposed to
deliver the egg to, again?
Another Pokémon?
There it is!
It’s waving at us!
It’s so cute!
Wh-What?!
What was that thing?
Isn’t that a...
A Lizardon! That must be
a Sky Ride Pokémon!
All right, let’s chase it, Pikachu!
Even more Pokémon
I’ve never seen before!
Watch out!
Stop! Stop, Kentauros!
Are you all right?
I’m just fine!
I’m used to Kentauros.
I’ve caught some myself.
Wait... Are you scared of Pokémon?
Certainly not! I love Pokémon...
...as a subject
to learn about, that is...
Sorry about that! You just sprung out
from the forest without warning.
I couldn’t stop in time.
Lilie can’t touch Pokémon, you see.
I can touch them!
It’s entirely logical to conclude that,
were I to put my mind to it...
It’s all right. You’ll be able to touch them
in due time, Lilie.
That’s right.
It’s you! The girl who was
fishing in the ocean!
Oh, the boy with the Hagigishiri...
You know him, Suiren?
I’m Satoshi!
I’m from Masara Town in Kanto!
This guy’s my partner, Pikachu.
Nice to meet ya!
So, where am I?
This is the Pokémon School.
That’s right, the Pokémon School!
So this is the place...
I got it! You’re lost, aren’t you?
Well, yeah...
I’ll give you a tour.
A tour?
Come this way!
You don’t have to pull me...
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pikachu
Type:   Electric
What’s that?!
Awesome!
So awesome!
All right!
Oh... Pass!
What is this place?!
I told you,
it’s the Pokémon School.
It’s a place where Pokémon and students
study and learn together.
I see.
Principal,
I’ve brought a new student!
New student?! N-No, that’s not...
Oh, my! You made it here
on your own?
Mom?!
I shouldn’t have doubted you.
Alola, Satoshi! Welcome to
the Pokémon School, greetingSolrock!
Professor Okido?!
I get that a lot.
I am Professor Okido’s cousin,
Nariya Okido!
He’s the principal of this school.
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
young oNuckrar!
“Nuckrar”...?
Principal Okido makes
Pokémon puns all the time.
People and Pokémon
living together and having fun...
...is most superBanguirus!
So I chased Lizardon
and happened to end up here.
Oh, so you’re not a new student?
Sorry. I just didn’t have
time to explain.
I’m the one who should apologize.
I have a tendency to
jump to conclusions.
Hey, Yukinari, it’s me.
The egg made it here just fine.
Oh, Nariya!
I see, so it made it there.
Thank you, Hanako!
You’re quite welcome.
Say, Principal, can I show Satoshi
around the campus?
Go on!
Porygon! Yabukuron!
Let’s go, Satoshi!
Yeah!
This is our classroom.
Feels great!
We don’t just learn in here.
Classes take place all over the campus, like on the field
where I was riding Kentauros earlier, or by the pond.
You two!
Alola!
Professor Kukui!
Professor?
He’s our teacher.
Professor, this is Satoshi.
Principal Okido told me.
Satoshi, Pikachu.
The Pokémon School is a great place.
You might only be here for today,
but enjoy your stay!
Of course!
That’s...
Yer gonna pay dearly
fer makin’ us stop our bikes!
Yeah, you said it, Bro!
Team Skull ain’t
toleratin’ no disturbances!
Yeah, that’s right!
I don’t recall blocking your way.
And you’re the ones
disturbing people here.
What was that?!
Ya talkin’ back at me?!
I dare ya to say that again!
Who are those guys?
They’re Team Skull.
They’re a nasty bunch who say all kinds of crazy things
and force you to battle them.
I might be willin’ to let ya go,
if ya can beat us in a Pokémon Battle...
But if ya lose...
...we’ll be takin’ yer Lizardon!
You’ll come to regret that.
Regret what?
C’mon, Yatoumori!
Youngoose!
Zubat!
C’mon, get that Lizardon o’ yers
ready to fight!
Hold it!
Satoshi?!
Who’re ya supposed ta be?!
Three on one isn’t fair!
And what’cha gonna do ‘bout it?
I’ll fight, too!
I’ll help you, um...
I’m Kaki.
But I don’t need your help.
Watch out, Satoshi!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
I choose you!
Don’t push yourself.
Come out, Bakugames!
So cool!
That one’s called Bakugames?
He’s a dual-type Pokémon.
A Fire/Dragon type.
He’s my partner.
Get ‘em!
Yatoumori, Venom Shock!
Youngoose, Bite!
Zubat, Leech Life!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
It’s quick!
What was that?
The spikes on Bakugames’s shell
will explode if stimulated.
Go! Use Flame Burst!
Pikachu, dodge it and
use 100,000 Volts!
All right!
Leave the rest to me.
Let’s go, Bakugames!
No way...
He’s...
...usin’ that move?!
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
W-We’ll get ya fer this!
You said it, Bro!
Ya shoulda told us
ya can use that move!
Yeah!
Kaki, what was that?
That was a Z-Move.
Z-Move?
Yeah.
I knew you could do it, Kaki!
But Satoshi,
you were great, too!
It was nothing...
Z-Moves are a special type of move
passed down for generations in the Alola Region.
There are four islands in this region,
and all four have their own
Guardian Deity Pokémon.
Only those who have participated in a ritual known as
the Island Pilgrimage, and have cleared certain Trials...
...may use Z-Moves.
Guardian Deity Pokémon?
The Island Pilgrimage? Z-Moves?!
That battle had the impact
of a Megaton Punch!
Satoshi, it looks like you like battling.
Am I correct?
Yes! I’m aiming to be
a Pokémon Master!
I see.
What’s that Pokémon?
Pokémon?
Where?
I don’t see any Pokémon...
But it was there, I swear!
That was definitely a Pokémon!
It was yellow, and on its head there was an orange, um...
What do you call it again...
Like a head comb...
That sounds like...
Kapu-Kokeko?
You saw Kapu-Kokeko,
the Guardian Deity of Melemele Island?!
Guardian Deity?
That was it?
Delicious!
Did something fun happen?
Well, you’re tired in an energetic way.
Wasn’t that...?!
Satoshi?! Pika-chan?!
There!
The island’s Guardian Deity...
Kapu-Kokeko...
Hey, why’d you
only show yourself to me?
Did you want to...
tell me something?
Isn’t this...?
It looks like the thing
Kaki had on his wrist...
Hey!
Professor Kukui’s house
is incredible!
He’s even got a training room
in the basement!
I’m glad to see you’re both
full of energy!
Thank you, Mom.
When I said I wanted to stay on this island,
you said yes right away!
Of course I did.
I am your mother, after all.
I had a feeling you might say that, too.
I gotta go!
The Pokémon School starts today!
Yes, you’d better get going.
Talk to you later!
Have fun!
All right, let’s race there, Pikachu!
Why’d you run off without me?!
Hey, wait!
Satoshi and Pikachu obtained a Z-Ring
from the island’s Guardian Deity, Kapu-Kokeko.
The curtain now rises
on a new adventure...
...here in the Alola Region!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Next episode
Mao, about Kapu-Kokeko...
The Guardian Deity Pokémon?
Yeah, that!
Try saying it three times fast!
Kapu-Kokeko, Kapu-Kokeko,
Kapu-Kokeko!
You can say it...
Well, of course I can!
How about you?
Try saying it three times!
Kapu-Kokeko, Kapu-Koke...
Don’t play with the name of
your sacred Guardian Deity Pokémon!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
Enter the Guardian Deity Kapu-Kokeko!
Let’s Put Our Z-Move to the Test!!
Next time
Enter the Guardian Deity Kapu-Kokeko!
Let’s Put Our Z-Move to the Test!!