Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Bug-Z
A year’s supply of malasadas
Kuwagannon merchandise
Silver medal
I participate in a certain
competition in today’s episode.
What do I get in it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Ta-daaah!
What’s that?! It’s super cool!
Isn’t it?
What Kuwagannon is wearing
is called VR Armor...
...with a camera
attached to the headpiece.
The footage from that camera gets
projected into my VR Goggles!
Meaning you get to see the same things
Kuwagannon sees while flying-roto?
Yup! And then I use this microphone to
give commands to Kuwagannon.
I’m planning to use these to participate in
the upcoming Kuwagannon Race!
Really? Sounds fun!
Kuwagannon Race?
Is that something like the Denjimushi Race
you were in a while back?
It’s a much bigger, grander race
than the Denjimushi Race was!
There’ll be plenty of skilled
Kuwagannon Racers participating!
The Rehire Cup’s
Kuwagannon Race...
The first prize is a Bug-Z!
You can get a Bug-Z?!
That’s amazing!
Yeah! I don’t have a Z-Ring yet,
but I really want that crystal,
for when I do get to use Z-Moves!
Are we gonna form
a three-man team again?
No, everyone fights on their own this time,
so it’ll just be me and Kuwagannon.
Please come cheer us on!
Of course we’re gonna!
I’ll make food for everyone!
Me, too!
Yeah!
Very well...
If we are to cheer you on,
you must aim for victory,
and nothing less!
Of course!
Let’s win this, Kuwagannon!
You’re too excited-roto!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Superspeed Kuwagannon!
Māmane Awakened!!
That being said, Māmane started
training after school,
in order to win
the Kuwagannon Race!
Viewing conditions, perfect.
Kuwagannon, are you ready?
Slowly! Slowly!
All right... For starters,
fly over to Togedemaru!
Yeah, perfect!
Hey!
Come this way next!
Now dash over to Kaki!
Huh? Wait...
What’s wrong, Kuwagannon?!
Show some restraint, Kuwagannon!
Matching up tomorrow’s
weather forecast with past data...
Maybe I should look up
more data on the sea, too.
We’re gonna win tomorrow, for sure!
Awesome! I didn’t think
the place would be this big!
Māmane,
you’re not nervous, are you?
No sweat at all! I’ve planned
for every single possible situation!
Perhaps, but staying up all night
is bad for you...
Whoa! It’s really him!
What?
That’s Mr. De Rosa!
He was the champion last time!
There are plenty of other tough
Kuwagannon Racers participating, too, so...
...I’ve gotta be sure
not to get too starstruck!
If you’re this scared already,
then it’s easy to see how this’ll go!
It’s Hayate with
the Red Denjimushi-roto!
What are you doing here?
I’m here to win, of course!
With my Kuwagannon!
A white Kuwagannon!
After we last met, I stayed on Poni Island
and went through intense training.
And then my Kuwagannon evolved
from a Red Meteor...
...into a White Comet!
Bro worked his butt off
to evolve Denjimushi, yo!
Bro is now completely
unrivaled, dude!
My eternal rival!
Today is the day my grudge
with you is resolved!
Sure! I’ll show you the power
of my Kuwagannon!
Looks like the brat boys are
joining this race, too.
I see. We’ll just have to
nab theirs, too, then.
After all, this is Operation:
“Give Sakaki an Elegant Vehicle Present”!
We’re gan’na get
all those Kuwagangan!
It’s “Kuwagannon,” though...
We’ll go on ahead and get ready.
Do your job right, okay?!
Sure!
Leave it to us, meow!
It’s finally time for the 34th Rehire Cup’s
Kuwagannon Race to begin!
Now, let us hear
a few opening words...
...from Poni Island’s Island Queen,
Ms. Hāpu'u!
Hāpu'u!
Ahem!
I look forward to seeing a heated race
from everyone here! That is all!
Thank you very much!
Now, to continue,
let me explain the race course!
The race will begin here,
on this special venue,
and then they’ll enter
the ocean course.
Following that, they must pass through
various checkpoints in the forest, cave and beach,
and then circle back around
to this special venue,
where whoever crosses the finish line first
will be the winner!
That’s a real marathon
of a course...
It’ll be fine!
Māmane and Kuwagannon
can do this!
Yeah!
For this competition, we’ve prepared a special system
to strengthen the sense of unity...
...between the trainers
and their Kuwagannon!
These devices will sync up
with Kuwagannon’s movements,
giving the trainers the sensation of
personally riding their Kuwagannon!
All ready! How about you?
Okay, meow!
Leave the controlling to me!
We’ll corner the Kuwagannon from behind,
just as planned.
Don’t mess up the finisher!
I got it, meow!
It’s a simple job! I just have to press the button
at the right time, and they’ll all be ours, meow!
Well then, prepare to start,
everyone!
Here we go!
Stand by!
Kuwagannon!
And they’re off!
Go, Kuwagannon!
They’re off to a great start!
Hit the gas, Māmane!
Go, go!
The defending champion
De Rosa’s Kuwagannon takes the lead!
Wait!
Stay in this position for now.
It’s all right. Trust me!
This course sends the racers
from one side to the other.
Who can cut their distance
with sharp turns?
This is the competitors’ chance
to show off their techniques!
Oh, my! Competitor Kojirton Nyanya
showcases an amazing technique!
We’re gonna keep speeding up!
What?!
There’s been an accident!
The front runners are in complete disarray!
Kuwagannon, use String Shot!
I knew there’d be
a gust of wind right then!
Let’s keep going!
Good job, Māmane!
Competitor Māmane kept a cool head,
and jumped to the head of the pack!
If there’s anyone here
I must defeat, it’s you!
There you are, White Comet!
Sorry to keep you waiting,
my rival!
The real battle...
...starts now!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kuwagannon
Type:   Bug/Electric
The race enters its middle stage...
They must now make it through the forest course!
Competitors Māmane and Hayate
are in fierce competition for the first place!
The other competitors are closing in on them as well...
This will be intense!
To the right, Kuwagannon!
Now, left!
Don’t lose, White Comet!
Up! Down! Left!
Right! Left!
Competitors Māmane and Hayate
demonstrate superb techniques!
Awesome!
He’s perfectly in sync
with Kuwagannon-roto!
Mr. Hayate is impressive, too!
I can feel his tenacity!
Don’t give up, Bro!
His training’s paid off, dude!
Here comes the hardest part:
The cave course!
Now!
Oh? What could have happened?
Another accident?
What?
Calm down! Just keep a careful eye
on your surroundings, and you’ll be fine!
This won’t be enough to stop us!
Where did my rival go?
It’s dark... I’m scared...
I’m scared of the dark!
What’s going on?!
Nobody told me about this!
Absolutely no problem!
The other Kuwagangan are
gonna reach the spot any second now!
Roger that! They’re called
Kuwagannon, though.
I’m good to go, too, meow!
Kuwagannon...
You’re doing that for me?
Thank you, Kuwagannon.
But I’m fine now.
You’re working so hard...
So I have to do my part, too!
I thought I’d have to
overcome my fears eventually...
Because my dream is
to be an astronaut!
Fly, Kuwagannon!
I don’t see Māmane anywhere...
Did he drop out at some point?
Flawless victory!
What is this?!
Kuwagannon, you have to escape!
Whoa, now! We’re not
letting you get away, meow!
Thank you!
I’m starting to get used to this,
so you can speed up now.
What’s that?
All right!
Runaway spotted!
Nyarth, catch them!
Got it, meow!
Stop!
Hayate, are you all right?
Māmane!
Get out of there, quickly!
Of course...
Run, Kuwagannon!
How dare you, meow!
Don’t give up, Kuwagannon!
Will you just drop it, meow?!
You’re finished, meow!
Wh-What?!
I will not let these creeps
get in the way of our showdown!
Kuwagannon! Charge Beam!
Now!
Our present for Sakaki!
This can’t be happening!
What?
What are you doing here?
But that means...
I knew it!
What even is this feeling?
What’s going on?
Here they come!
Māmane!
Bro!
Well then, let’s go!
Yeah!
Three...
Two...
One...
Go!
What could have happened?
All competitors started back up
at the same time!
Every competitor has entered
the beach course simultaneously!
Competitors Māmane and Hayate
are competing for the first place!
Hang in there, Kuwagannon!
We’re gonna win for sure!
Neither side is yielding!
It’s a clash of will!
What a match!
Go!
They’re finally turning
the last corner!
The finish line of glory awaits them
around this curve!
Will the winner be Competitor Māmane?!
Or will it be Competitor Hayate?!
Go, Māmane!
The winner is Competitor Māmane!
Kuwagannon!
Owwww...
That hurts, Kuwagannon!
You did it, Māmane!
Congratulations!
That was amazing, Māmane!
I was so moved!
Māmane!
I lost...
But next time, I’ll win!
I...
...won’t lose, either!
A passionate handshake
of friendship!
Magnificent! That truly was
a magnificent race!
Now then, let’s meet again
in the next race!
You got the Bug-Z!
Now you’ll just need the Z-Ring!
Yeah... But I’m not sure if I can meet
the Island King’s standards...
You can do it, I’m sure!
Thank you, everyone!
I have been waiting for you, Māmane.
Hāpu'u?
The other competitors informed me of
the deeds you and Kuwagannon performed.
I understand you battled
to save everyone, yes?
In recognition of your valiance,
I will present you with this.
A Z-Ring!
Thank you, Hāpu'u!
Certainly!
May you continue
working diligently.
You did it, Māmane!
Now you can use Z-Moves!
Congratulations!
Yeah, congratulations!
This is my Z-Ring!
Māmane won the heated battle
with his rival.
And now he’s got his own Z-Ring!
Isn’t that great?
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
What I got was the Bug-Z!
Kuwagannon can carry Denjimushi with their legs
and get electricity from them. Did you know?
The Kuwagannon Race today
was so much fun!
Let’s do our best next time,
too, Kuwagannon!
Now...
Kuwagannon...
Absolute... Predatory...
Next episode
In a barren field
Groudon was enjoying some
Delicious berries
Really, really?
Just kidding!
Just kidding?!
Proud Rekkuuza was
Dancing a graceful dance with
Odoridori
Really, really?
Just kidding!
Just kidding?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Suiren Hooks a Kaiogre?!
Just kidding about that, too?!
Just kidding!
We knew you were kidding!
Just kidding about the kidding!
What?! We’re confused...
Next time
Suiren Hooks a Kaiogre?!