Alola!
I, Kaki, will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem!
Malasada Doughnuts
Alola Pancakes
Mitsuhoney Honey
Ice Cream
What is my farm’s speciality?
Watch the episode, then answer!
Having cleared Island King Hala’s
Grand Trial...
...and obtained the Electric- and
Normal-type Z-Crystals,
Satoshi is now taking advantage of a day when School’s off
to get some training done.
All right, Pikachu!
Let’s do this!
Hang on. Why not try it
with Mokuroh instead?
Mokuroh knows the Normal-type move
Tackle, doesn’t he?
Since you have the Normal-type Crystal,
Mokuroh should be able to use that Z-Move, too.
Really?! I’ll try it, then!
Come out, Mokuroh!
Mokuroh,
let’s give the Z-Move a try!
Right! Let’s go!
Good!
The Z-Power’s building up!
Go! This is our full power!
Ultra Dash Attack!
That’s some power!
Right? Z-Moves are
a real Trump Card!
Yeah, it’s awesome!
Come back, Mokuroh!
Are you okay, Mokuroh?
Using a Z-Move is
immensely exhausting-roto.
One shot is all you can do right now,
but the more you train,
the more you should be able to
mitigate that power drain.
Hang in there.
Okay!
Take a nap, Mokuroh.
Oh, it’s Kaki and Lizardon!
Alola!
Whoa, there’s so much!
Is this Moomoo Milk?
Yeah. Completely fresh.
You sure are up early, Kaki.
Doing chores today, too?
Yes.
Chores?
Kaki lives on a farm.
Kaki helps out by delivering dairy products
and collecting the empty bottles.
Whoa, you sure are diligent...
It’s really no big deal.
Say, farms have loads of Miltank
and Pokémon like that, yeah?
Yeah. We have stuff like
Dorobanko and Kentauros, too.
I really wanna see them!
The ice cream they make on
Kaki’s farm is exquisite.
For real? I want some!
Professor Kukui,
can I go visit Kaki?
Now? What about your
Z-Move training?
Of course I’ll keep it up!
Kaki can use Z-Moves, too, right?
Battling him would
count as training, too!
You are... something else.
Kaki’s in the middle of deliveries.
Oh... Then, I’ll help him!
It’ll go faster
if we do it together!
Professor, I don’t mind.
If you say so...
All right. But do help him
with his chores, too.
All right!
So we can battle afterwards.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Satoshi Visits Kaki!
Pelipper, huh?
It’s really fast.
It dashes through the sky
at Lightning Speed.
Nice to meet you, Pelipper.
Let’s go!
Satoshi! Don’t cause trouble
for Kaki’s family, okay?
I won’t!
I do deliveries
before going to the School.
You wake up crazy early!
I like flying through the Alolan sky
as the sun rises.
Doesn’t the morning air feel nice?
It’s really refreshing!
After Melemele Island,
we go to Akala Island.
That’s the third Ride Pokémon.
Two more, and I win.
I am so bored!
That’s Akala Island.
That’s where you live, right?
Right.
It’s your first time here, isn’t it?
Yup!
That’s why I’m super excited!
Kaki! What’s that?
Oh, that’s Wela Volcano.
It’s on fire!
Kaki! Alola!
Alola, Haru.
Alola!
I’m Satoshi!
Thank you very much!
It’s a Pikachu! So cute!
Can I pet it?
Sure.
It’s my first time!
Are you ready for tomorrow?
Yup! I’ve got the design
all worked out.
Here!
Hey, it’s Mokuroh!
That’s a great drawing-roto!
Tomorrow’s my mom’s birthday.
So I’m gonna make her this cake,
together with Dad.
Don’t be late! Come here
first thing in the morning!
I can’t make the cake without
your farm’s fresh Moomoo Milk!
Don’t worry!
Have I ever been late?
A farm!
Is that your house?
Yeah!
Thanks, Pelipper!
You can rest now.
It smells of farm!
Oh! I see Dorobanko-roto!
Huh? Where?!
It’s eating dirt!
Dorobanko. Donkey Pokémon.
Ground type.
It has a stubborn,
individualistic disposition.
Eating dirt, making mud, and playing in the mire
all form part of its daily routine.
I see!
The dirt is the source of
Dorobanko’s power.
That’s so cool!
What’s up?
Oh, that’s right, Satoshi.
Don’t get too close to Dorobanko,
or it’ll hurl mud at you.
It already did...
Man, I’m all muddy...
Go on, wipe yourself off!
Um... Thank you very much.
That’s my mom.
How do you like our Pokémon?
They all look real lively,
don’t they?
The dirt and grass here are great,
after all.
Dirt and grass?
It’s peak quality farm grass,
nurtured by Wela Volcano and Alola’s nature.
Pokémon who eat it
all grow up healthy and happy!
The milk we get from these Pokémon
is highly nutritious.
You want something to eat?
Yes! I’d like some of
your famous ice cream, please!
Sure thing.
Dear! Bring over some ice cream!
It’s huge!
Here you go.
This is my father.
He may not look it,
but he’s the president of this farm.
Good day. I’m the presid—
Thank you very much!
Delicious!
Kaki... It looks like your friend
only cares about the ice cream...
Sorry, that’s just the way he is.
Cheer up-roto!
I will take your card-roto!
My name is Shibu.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
I see...
Taking picture-roto!
Recorded-roto!
W-What?!
What’s up?
Watch out!
Hoshi, are you all right?!
I’m fine!
There was nothing to worry about!
I want to help out!
I can do it for you.
Don’t put yourself in danger!
Leave it all to your big bro!
Oh, come on!
I can do it myself!
What do you think of
this big brother of mine?
He’s super overprotective, right?
Huh? Um...
I guess... he might be?
So, who are you?
My adorable little sister, Hoshi.
Be nice to her.
Geez! Now what am I
supposed to do?!
Want some ice cream?
What a cute Pikachu!
Is there anything
we can help with?
I just can’t sit still
after seeing all your Pokémon!
Oh, is that so?
Well then, maybe you can help!
Watch real carefully.
We have to wash them once a day.
Like this.
You need a proper rhythm
while washing them.
Some fall asleep while standing up
because it feels so nice.
That does look comfortable!
Okay, do what big bro does.
All right!
I’m gonna clean you real good!
Stand still.
Whoa! Your fur sure is hard.
This is easy!
Huh? Oh, come on! What?
It’s stuck...
He’s stopped-roto.
That’s weird...
Oh, right, Satoshi!
Don’t stand behind the Dorobanko...
They’ll kick you...
Thought so!
I’m done!
You’re only done with the first one.
We can’t move on to the next task
until we’ve washed all of them.
All of them?!
Counting! Counting!
There are sixty of them-roto!
Sixty...?!
Pocket Monsters!
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Bakugames
Type:   Fire/Dragon
Why is there so much?
You can never have enough hay.
When we bring in the Pokémon in the evenings,
they stay here until dawn.
We have to stock up plenty of food and water,
so that they can eat whenever they need.
You still need practice.
Yeah.
Well done, Pikachu!
You’re a natural!
Then once we’ve
seen them all go in...
...We’ll be done?
No. Now we have to check
that nobody’s sick.
You can tell from
how much hay and water is left.
I see...
It’s finally dinner!
I’m famished!
Wait.
What?
We have to pray to Wela Volcano
before we eat.
Pray?
Thank it for
watching over us again today.
Now, all together.
I am so tired!
You’re not gonna battle-roto?
I can’t move a muscle...
Kaki?
Very good, Bakugames!
Sorry, did I wake you?
What are you doing?
At day, I help out at the farm.
At night, I refine my Pokémon’s moves.
As a bearer of a Z-Ring...
As one who lives with the Pokémon...
That’s my daily routine.
This Z-Ring is a memento
from my grandfather.
Your grandfather’s the Island King?
He was.
This guy was his partner.
Bakugames and I challenged
the Island Queen, Ms. Lychee.
I took on the Grand Trial in order to earn the right
to bear the Z-Ring Grandfather left for me.
We triumphed over her,
and that right was granted to us.
When I was younger,
Grandfather would often say...
We are being kept alive
by the fires.
Flames...
...can sometimes be terrifying things,
capable of laying all to waste.
But they have also served as a light,
bringing civilization to humankind.
Kaki.
You ought not to pursue the flames of destruction.
Follow instead the lead of Wela Volcano.
Strive to be a wielder of
the life-nourishing flames!
I want to perfect the Fire-type Z-Move,
for Grandfather’s sake, as well.
I will become the flame of Alola!
Or... something like that.
All right...
I guess it’s time to sleep.
Kaki.
I’ve become a Z-Move user, too.
I want to perfect my moves!
Let’s battle!
Aren’t you tired?
We’re waking up early.
We have to be at Haru’s place with the milk
first thing in the morning.
I hope I can get up...
Hurry up, Satoshi.
Sure.
Hoshi, be careful!
You could really hurt yourself
if that fell on your feet!
I’ll do it!
No!
Counting on you again today,
Pelipper.
Get it there safe, okay?
Say hi to Haru’s father for me!
Be careful, big bro!
Of course!
Now, let’s get going, Satoshi!
S-Sure...
This view is awesome, Kaki!
It’s like the sun
is revitalizing you, right?
What’s this?
Dive down! We’ll have to take a detour,
or we won’t be able to breathe!
Pelipper, go down!
That freaked me out...
Can we still make it?
Yeah, it’s fine.
It’s still 30 minutes before
he said he’d be here.
He might come early!
What’s wrong, Pelipper?
Satoshi!
Pelipper, are you all right?
That was Dragon Rage-roto.
It needs care.
I’ll do it. You go to Haru.
But...
Found ya!
You guys!
We’re the proud Team Skull,
who’ll scare even cryin’ kids to tears!
Time to get back at ya for the other day,
stinkin’ Z-Move user!
We’re gonna make ya cry today!
Move it! I have no time
to deal with idiots like you!
If ya really wanna pass,
then drop yer load!
We can’t do that!
Quit the tough guy act,
ya friggin’ extra!
I really can’t stand
them friggin’ Z-Moves!
Get ‘im, guys!
Yer on!
Venom Shock!
Dodge it, everyone!
Kaki!
It’s fine. They just cut the belt.
Hey! You said you
hated Z-Moves, didn’t you?
What of it?
Well then, try this one!
A Z-Ring?!
Right!
Go, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
This ain’t over!
That kid can use Z-Moves, too?!
We’ll get back at ya next time!
Quick! We gotta get Pelipper
to the Pokémon Center!
Well done, Satoshi.
Thanks!
Well, Haru?
There he is!
Here you go, Haru.
I’m sorry I’m late.
I thought you weren’t coming!
There was a traffic jam.
In the sky?
Yeah, kinda.
Well, to make up for being late,
can you do something for me?
Do something? What?
Can you two battle each other?
Let me see a battle
after we’ve had cake!
Kaki! I came here because
I wanted to battle you!
Very well! I won’t hold back.
Kaki and his Z-Ring...
Satoshi has gotten to know another one
of his classmates.
His adventure in Alola
will go on and on!
But what about Team Rocket?
I mean, it’s boring,
but this is still kind of...
...a great feeling.
We should probably get some
work done soon, meow...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Sorry I kept you waiting.
The answer to the PokéProblem
was ice cream!
It’s made from
first-rate material, after all!
The ice cream made from our Miltank’s Moomoo Milk
is rich and full of nutrients!
It’s super delicious!
It’s a really famous, popular treat
on Akala Island!
Hoshi, help me cook the pizza.
Sure!
I’ll do it for you!
What if you get a burn?!
I can do it myself!
Bakugames! Counting on you!
Geez! You’re a fire hazard!
Next episode
It’s the beach!
Hey, this is still part of
the extracurricular lesson!
Kaki, let’s have a swimming race!
You think you can beat me?
Let’s play something we can all do!
I guess it’s time to unleash my secret weapon:
This special water gun!
I wanna play beach volleyball, too.
That sounds wonderful! Let’s do it!
Hey! Class is still in session!
They’ve totally forgotten,
haven’t they?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
A Hidoidestructive
Extracurricular Lesson?!
A Hidoidestructive Extracurricular Lesson?!