Shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Here’s the PokéProblem!
Do you know?
Bourgain Stadium
Lanakila Mountain
Aether Paradise
Manalo Stadium
The Alola Pokémon League
opens its doors today, but where?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I see it!
What? Where?!
So that’s...
...Manalo Stadium?
So cool!
Massive!
I can’t believe they built
an entire island!
Their craftsmanship
is awesome-roto!
Mother said the entire Aether Foundation
worked on constructing it.
You changed into your
“I Can RealLilie Do It” form?
Indeed! This is
the Pokémon League, after all!
It looks as good as ever!
Thank you very much.
All right, here we go!
To the Pokémon League!
Yeah!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Curtain Rises!
The Alola Pokémon League!!
It’s finally time for
the Alola Pokémon League.
Satoshi and his friends have arrived at
the League venue, Manalo Stadium.
Professor Kukui!
There you are!
Professor, Professor!
Can I use the battlefield?
Calm down, Satoshi.
We haven’t even signed up yet.
Huh?
Signups start in the evening.
You can go see the battlefield,
but no battling there yet. Sorry.
Huh?
Try to be patient, Satoshi.
I get how you feel, though...
Namely, psyched up.
It might be fun to explore the island
while you wait for signups to start.
Right, Lilie?
Indeed.
Manalo Stadium consists of
more than just the battlefield.
There is the Pokémon Center,
of course,
but there’s also a shopping mall,
relaxation facilities, restaurants and diners...
There’s a wide variety of places to go.
Sounds fun!
I’d love to show you around, but...
Professor Kukui!
Could you help us out?
Be right there!
I’ve got my hands full, see...
Don’t worry.
We can go on our own.
Sorry about this. Later!
Good luck!
So, what are we going to do?
I wanna see the battlefield!
Satoshi!
Do you even know where it is-roto?
I want a look, too!
Wait! Me, too!
That was fast.
As always,
they know just what they want.
Should we go have a look
at the shopping mall?
Of course!
All right...
You can tell it’s
the grand opening.
It’s not just League participants!
There’s loads of spectators, too, meow!
Our early batch sold well, too...
With this massive crowd...
The Manalo Doughnuts will
sell like crazy, for sure!
We’ll be rich, meow!
Let’s give it our all, gang!
Hey, have you forgotten?
We’re here to win the Alola League,
and conquer the Alola Region!
I know that!
But securing funds
is an important job, too.
We’ll win the League, sell loads of doughnuts
and rake in the cash!
Kill two Poppo
with one stone, meow!
What’s up?
Nuikoguma?!
But that means...
Nuikoguma, let’s go!
We’ll be fine!
We’ve taken preventative measures.
She won’t get here
that easily, meow...
Ta-daah!
To show our gratitude for everything you do,
we’ve dug you a hot spring!
Have a nice, long rest, meow!
She’ll be stuck in Hot Spring Heaven
for a while, meow.
All right!
And even if she gets tired of the hot spring,
we have a backup plan, meow!
Nothing to worry about, then.
Awesome!
What a magnificent stadium-roto!
We’ll be able to have some
intense all-out battles here!
Right, Bakugames?
I’m gonna win
the Alola Pokémon League!
I won’t hold back.
Don’t forget me, either!
Of course not!
I knew you’d be here!
Satoshi!
Hau!
You’ll be in the League, too?
Of course!
You’re as lively as ever,
young Satoshi.
Mr. Hala!
Um...
Mr. Hala is Hau’s grandpa!
I see!
Alola! I’m Kaki!
I’m Māmane!
I’m Hau!
Pleasure to meet you!
A Z-Ring!
I finally cleared
my gramps’s Grand Trial!
I see! Great job!
Your Island Pilgrimage
has only just begun.
You have only taken your first step!
I know!
That’s not the only surprise I have!
Come out!
Ju'niper!
Ju'niper. Arrow Feather Pokémon.
Grass/Ghost type.
It nocks and fires arrow feathers
kept hidden within its wings.
Its aim is sharp enough
to pierce a pebble a hundred meters away.
Fukuthrow’s evolved!
Yeah! We’ve trained hard
since last time!
All so that we wouldn’t lose
to your Mokuroh!
So cool!
Mokuroh, wake up!
There’s a new Pokémon there, too!
It’s called Meltan.
C’mon, Mokuroh!
Fukuthrow’s evolved into Ju'niper!
Mokuroh’s the same as ever...
He might not look any different,
but Mokuroh’s gotten a lot stronger!
I can’t wait to battle you!
Gramps, is it okay if
I explore the area with Satoshi?
But of course!
Right! Let’s go!
Yeah!
Right, you too!
There’s all sorts of stores here!
Just looking around is fun!
What do you like, Snowball?
There’s too much to see
in just one day.
The Pile Juice beckons me!
Shall we take a break?
Yeah!
Excuse me!
I’d like to make an order.
Welcome!
Mao, it’s you!
Big Brother?!
Is this your Pokémon, too?
It’s Xiemi...
But what are you doing here?
Well, I heard Alola was holding its first-ever
Pokémon League, so I came to check...
They were looking for people
to work the food stands,
so I saw that as my chance,
and signed up for it!
Well, you could have told me!
How about you?
What brings you here?
We’re all participating in the League!
I see! Hang in there!
I’ll close the store and come cheer you on
during your matches!
Oh, Big Brother...
You get it, right?
We gonna smash
this stinkin’ Alola League!
Ya sure, Bro?
Shouldn’t we tell Mr. Guzma?
Sure we won’t get yelled at?
Doin’ it in secret is best!
Mr. Guzma can’t stand
that creep, Kukui!
He told ‘im he was gonna smash
the League he was holdin’, yeah?
He shouldn’t hafta bother...
So we’ll just do it for ‘im!
Think that’ll make
Mr. Guzma happy?
Absolutely!
Yer the best, Bro!
But how do we wreck it?
Huh? Well, um...
Just go do stuff!
I hate hot guys...
Huh, yer good.
Give ‘im a beard, too.
What are you doing?!
Yikes!
Scram!
I swear...
Is something wrong,
Ms. Junsa?
Look at this.
Who would do this?
There have been people throwing garbage around
and picking fights with trainers, too.
Be careful.
Bye.
How awful...
Everyone’s been looking forward
to the League.
Unforgivable.
Yeah. If we find them,
we’ll stop them!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ratta
..               (Alolan Form)
Type:   Evil/Normal
Here you go.
Would you like
a Royal Honey Drink with that?
Here.
Yo, dudes!
Scram, yer in our way!
No cutting in line, please!
These guys look
awfully familiar, meow.
We don’t want them
making a scene, yeah?
Well, we gotta get rid of them.
Will you kindly line up over there?
Why ya sellin’ doughnuts here?
What was that?!
I’ll let you know we have a permit!
Who cares ‘bout that?!
Oh, this simply will not do...
You’re disrupting our business!
We must ask that you leave, meow!
We will remove you by force!
Ya wanna fight?!
W-We’ll get ya fer this...
That wasn’t even enough to
warm me up for the League.
They were no match for us!
Dang it! We’ll get ya fer this!
Oh, dear... Why do losers always say
the exact same thing every time?
They’re so predictable.
Scram! Get lost!
This place belongs to
Team Skull!
Stay outta our way!
Stop!
Team Skull!
What are you doing here?!
The Pokémon School kids...
What do we do, Bro?
Mr. Guzma hates
these kids’ guts, too!
If we crush ‘em...
Mr. Guzma’ll be real happy!
Guzma?
That guy?
This is perfect.
We’ll wreck y’all so bad,
ya can’t be in the League!
Think again! Bakugames!
Pikachu!
Mokuroh!
Kuwagannon!
Me, too! Ju'niper!
Get ‘em!
Sludge Bomb!
Bakugames!
Flamethrower!
Yatoumori! Scratch!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Mokuroh! Seed Bomb!
Yatoumori!
Zubat! Bite!
Dodge, Ju'niper!
Leaf Cutter!
You’re all dazzling-roto!
We didn’t get to do anything...
Why are you doing this?!
That’s right! Everyone’s been
excited for the League!
Yer the only ones who’re excited!
Yeah!
The League should just burn!
What?!
Hey!
What are you doing?
Mr. Guzma!
Y-You’re here early, Sir...
Don’t do anything without
running it by us first!
O-Oh, you see, we just wanted to save Mr. Guzma
the trouble of wrecking the League on his own...
And then you got your butts
handed to you.
Seems you’ve been
entertaining my brothers for me.
Could be fun to destroy you all
right here, right now.
There they are!
Lilie! Everyone!
We heard there was trouble here.
We were worried, so we came.
Guzma, why are you here?
You told me to enter the League earlier,
didn’t you?
So here I am, as you asked.
Mr. Guzma!
Yer enterin’ the League?
My entry will be accepted, yeah?
That’s right.
Now you’ve said it!
I’ll make you regret that!
I will dominate this
dream arena of yours!
I can’t wait to see if you’ll still be able to
talk about your precious dreams when that happens!
When I’m Champion,
I’ll make sure you’ll never hold another League!
Your dream will crumble!
Guzma...
I can’t wait.
Oh, Boss! Please, wait!
I can’t believe Guzma is
participating in the League.
Why is he so obsessed
with Professor Kukui?
Long ago, both Guzma and Kukui
were my apprentices.
But Guzma would always
defy my teachings...
Until finally, one day...
That high-and-mighty
“I’ll follow the righteous path” attitude of yours...
...really gets on my nerves!
I’ve had enough of your “Trials” and
“Offer gratitude to the nature of Alola” drivel!
Guzma...
Useless, all of it!
I don’t need no
Z-Moves or Z-Rings!
I’ll become strong
my own way!
Guzma!
I see...
I should have taught him better...
I failed to save his heart.
Gramps...
It wasn’t your fault.
If only I’d tried harder
to talk him out of it...
I don’t want to lose to him.
Satoshi?
Everyone I’ve met here in Alola
has been so nice...
It’s been so much fun!
I’ve been really looking forward to
competing with you all in the Pokémon League.
And Professor Kukui’s been working so hard
to make this a League everyone can enjoy!
That guy doesn’t get any of that!
Satoshi...
So I refuse to let him beat me!
Well said, Satoshi!
You’re exactly right!
Th-Thanks...
We won’t let that guy
destroy the League!
Indeed.
We won’t lose.
We’ll give it our all!
Yeah!
Me, too!
Thank you, everyone.
It’s the eve of the Alola League!
Eat up, have fun,
and show us some heated battles
in tomorrow’s League!
Looks great!
We’re all signed up for the League.
Yeah!
Time to eat!
Come out, everyone!
Us, too!
Yeah!
You two, too!
Eat up, Snowball.
It’s delicious!
Yeah!
Ah, it’s a Nasshi!
Oh, you’re all here!
All rightta! Koratta! Meloetta!
Principal Okido?!
Have you come to cheer us on?
Not at all!
I’m participating as well!
I’d hate to miss a festival
as grand as this!
Everyone,
try to get faRoentorar!
Later!
What a weird guy...
Well... Yeah...
It’s Ilima.
He’s participating, too?
Popular as ever, I see...
I’ll go say hi, too.
Are you all right?
Try again tomorrow.
Ow...
Satoshi.
Gladio!
Big Brother!
Glad you’re doing well, Lilie.
Thank you!
You’re participating, right?
Yeah. I’m going to win this!
I wouldn’t be so sure about that!
Right, Pikachu?
I’m here, too, remember?
And me!
I shall not fail!
What was that?
A mystery.
It’s the first-ever
Alola Pokémon League!
Now, then, I’ll let our
special guest, Royal Mask...
...explain the rules of
the preliminary round!
Sorry to have
kept you waiting, everyone!
There he is!
The League’s
preliminary round will be...
...a free-for-all between
every single competitor,
where only the last 16 standing
will advance to the final tournament!
A Battle Royal!
What?!
The Alola Pokémon League
is finally starting.
It seems like it will be off to
a chaotic start.
How will it turn out?!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Did you get it?
The venue for the Alola Pokémon League is
Manalo Stadium! Remember that!
Manalo Stadium has
not only a Pokémon Center,
but also a shopping center and
lodging facilities!
The Alola League is finally starting!
Battles on a whole other level,
fought on the stadium of dreams!
Please look forward to it!
Next episode
All right! It’s a hotel!
An actual hotel!
Competitors get to stay in
their own rooms, huh?
The bed is so soft...
There’s got loads of fruits
to welcome us!
And a round,
bubbly bathtub, meow!
What generosity!
We’ll get through the preliminaries,
no problem!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Brawl! Battle Royal 151!!
I can’t sleep...
We’re so used to sleeping on leaves...
Next time
Brawl!
Battle Royal 151!!