Alola! Mao here!
I’ll be giving out today’s PokéProblem.
Tractor
Airplane
Ride Pokémon
Cruiser
What vehicle do we use
to get to Akala Island today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Akala-Akala-Akala-Akala-Akala-
Akala-Akala Island!
Satoshi!
I know the extracurricular classes start today,
but you’re too excited about it-roto!
Rotom?
What kind of Pokémon
can I meet on Akala Island?
Hold on-roto.
I’ll do a search-roto.
Calm down, Kentauros!
Keep holding it in place,
Lizardon!
Are you all right?
I’m not so sure...
What’s going on over there?
Kentauros got startled
by Lizardon landing.
It got really worked up about it...
It’s a Lugarugan!
A Midday Form one-roto!
Alola!
Don’t be so upset.
There, there. Good.
Yeah. That’s it!
Awesome...
So cool!
Who is she?
I don’t think she’s
part of the School staff...
Who is this woman with the Lugarugan,
who calmed down the raging Kentauros?
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Enter Lychee!
Laugh and Cry, Island Queen!!
Lizardon,
you did well holding it down.
You’re as dignified as ever.
Ms. Lychee!
Alola, Kaki!
Look how much you’ve grown
in the short while since we last met!
You’re really cool!
You know her, Kaki?
Yeah!
This is the Island Queen
of Akala Island, Lychee!
The Island Queen?!
All right, class...
Today is the day we set off for our
extracurricular lessons on Akala Island...
Yeah, I’ll do it!
I’ll do the Grand Trial!
Satoshi, you’re getting
ahead of yourself.
But you know...
Satoshi...
There he goes...
Alola!
I’m Lychee, the Island Queen
of Akala Island!
I’ll be your guide for this
extracurricular lesson. Let’s get along!
First, as a way of saying hello...
Nothing to see,
nothing to see.
Here you go.
You never cease to impress!
Beautiful!
Gorgeous!
It looks like the deep sea.
What is this made of?
What do you think, Pikachu?
I guess jewelry might not be
that good a present for the boys...
No, that’s not true at all,
Lychee!
Really? Well, the thing is...
You see... Look here.
I also run a shop of
hand-crafted items.
A Z-Ring!
This is a Rock Z-Crystal
attached to it.
A Rock-type one? That’s so cool!
Are you taking on
the Island Pilgrimage?
Yes! I want to face
your Grand Trial!
Maybe you will, depending on
how this trip goes.
All right! Now I’m excited!
Now, grab your stuff
and bring your Pokémon!
Akala Island, let’s...
Gong...
Alola, Principal!
It’s been far too long!
Since you’re here, wouldn’t getting to know
the students’ Pokémon be fuNutrey?
“Be fuNutrey”?
That’s great!
Oh, my! Wow...
This is amazing!
They all have a good look
in their eyes.
They’re all really loved,
aren’t they?
There you go...
Smells like the sun!
Yeah, right? Sometimes I
can’t help but smell them, too!
How strange-roto.
They’re not tense
in the slightest-roto.
You’re right!
In fact, they look incredibly happy!
It’s almost like Ms. Lychee’s
a Pokémon, too!
Huh? Nyabby!
Come here...
Ms. Lychee, be careful!
He can be hostile to people he doesn’t...
It’s all right.
Come here.
Let’s be friends.
He’s being affectionate!
Guess she’s not an Island Queen
for nothing!
Well...
Ms. Lychee is special,
even among the Island Queens.
She surprised me
during my Grand Trial.
I’d never seen Bakugames drop his guard
around a stranger before that.
There must be something special about Ms. Lychee
that causes Pokémon to open their hearts to her.
You want to become
this cool too, right?
Aren’t you glad you got
a cute little admirer, Lugarugan?
You really are cute!
Please, tell me more about them!
I want to get to know
all of them better!
Then I’ll start with Iwanko!
So much happened before
Satoshi caught you... Nyabby...
I’m so glad you came to Satoshi...
Ms. Lychee, if you’d like...
Oh, my... Thank you.
She’s all over the place...
Laughing, crying, blowing her nose...
Your Pokémon truly are lucky.
They’re blessed with
great partners!
Please never forget the stories you told me,
nor how those experiences felt at the time.
They’re treasures that
will last a lifetime!
You’ve gotten quite a bit tougher
since the Grand Trial.
You’re starting to look like Kaki!
Um, I’m not so sure...
That tickles!
All right. In return for telling me
about your Pokémon,
I’ll tell you about Akala Island!
Starting recording-roto!
Akala Island has been nurtured by
Wela Volcano’s sacred flames.
It instills both gratitude
and fear in its people.
So, do you all know what Pokémon
is known to be Akala’s Guardian Deity?
Kapu-Tetefu!
Oh, good! You know!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Kentauros
Type:   Normal
Kapu-Tetefu,
Akala’s Guardian Deity,
is known to scatter its
glittering scales from time to time.
It’s said that whoever touches those scales
will be immediately revitalized.
Oh, yeah. So that’s why...
You know what I think?
I think Kapu-Tetefu is
the God of life!
Its light heals wounds and
gives strength to living beings.
Do you think I can
meet it again?
Of course!
If you want to meet it, you will!
It would make me so happy
if you were to feel Kapu-Tetefu’s breath,
and contemplate what
life truly is during this trip.
Us and our Pokémon...
Different lives coming in touch with each other...
I want you to experience that special feeling
that can only be born between partners.
Though it might be a bit much to ask.
Right then, story time’s over!
Now it’s time.
Grab your things and
bring your Pokémon!
Akala Island, let’s go!
Now! All aboard, everybody!
I’m fine, I’m fine...
She’s all over the place... Telling serious stories,
laughing, falling on her face...
She’s so cool!
How?
See ya later!
Have a nice treKoiking!
Ah, this feels great!
Going the sea route is nice, too.
Right, Lizardon?
Wow, it’s Kaki!
You’re right!
It’s the Akala Island tour guide.
They’ve got a feature on Kaki’s house.
What’s with your face?
You were way too nervous!
So what if I was?!
Look how relaxed they are.
Yeah.
I can’t wait to see what kind of
Water Pokémon live on Akala Island!
And I can’t wait to try the food!
I’m sure they have
lots of rare ingredients!
Hey, something jumped.
Where, where? I wanna see!
I don’t see anything...
I can’t detect anything either-roto.
Sounds like they found something.
Roger that. Let’s take a detour.
Turning port side!
If you’re interested,
then we’ll have to take a look!
You’re so understanding,
Ms. Lychee!
There!
It’s Hakuryu-roto!
Whoa...
For real?
Oh, my!
Wow...
Did the Hakuryu do this?
The extracurricular lesson
has already begun.
Let’s get to know
some Pokémon from the sea.
Keikouo...
Menokurage!
Neolant...
Lovecus!
Sunnygo...
Shellder!
And there’s a Lugia!
Where? Where?! A Lugia?!
Oh, come on,
the boys actually believe you!
Of course there’s no Lugia!
Indeed.
You know a lot
about Water Pokémon!
I love them!
Wonder if there’s any others...
Oh, no!
Lychee!
The water’s great!
Come on in, everybody!
It’s beautiful!
Pikachu? Wanna go?
What’s that?
Let’s find out.
What are they doing?
I’m curious, too.
Let’s follow them!
It’s a Whaleko!
It’s stuck in the rocks!
Satoshi?
Is something wrong-roto?
A Whaleko’s stuck in the rocks!
That’s awful-roto!
I’ll alert the others-roto!
Please do!
Satoshi, I’ll pull Whaleko,
so you push from the other side!
Gotcha!
Lychee!
Rotom told us what’s happening!
We’ll help, too!
A Hagigishiri’s responsible!
Hagigishiri?!
This area might be
Hagigishiri’s territory.
We’ll be in serious trouble
if we get hit by its psycho-power.
Satoshi! Pikachu!
Get back on the boat right away!
Hagigishiri. Tooth-Gnashing Pokémon.
Water/Psychic type.
When it unleashes its psycho-power
from the protuberance on its head,
an extremely grating sound
echoes through the area.
It’ll drown
if we don’t do something!
Lugarugan, help me.
But Lugarugan’s a Rock type!
It’s not good with water-roto!
Just watch this.
Lugarugan, go!
It leapt?!
Awesome!
Impossible-roto...
The water didn’t scare it at all.
So cool!
Where’s Whaleko?
No!
The psycho-power’s keeping it
from moving! It needs help!
Warning! Warning! That’s the sign that
it’s activating its psycho-power-roto!
Lugarugan! Rock Slide!
She did it!
I’m sorry we made you angry.
Let’s help Whaleko!
I’ll help!
Me too!
Ashimari, let’s go with them!
Whaleko is severely weakened-roto!
I’ll get some medicine!
We’re popping the balloon!
Whaleko will sink right away,
so everyone help hold it up!
Got it!
Ashimari!
Pop the balloon!
Heave... ho!
You’re going to be fine. Trust us.
We want to help you.
Ms. Lychee! Here’s the medicine!
Throw it!
Copy what I do.
Thank goodness.
Whaleko, you did great.
Be careful the next time
you see Hagigishiri!
You really are amazing!
Well, you know...
I am the Island Queen, after all!
What’s wrong?!
M-My leg! My leg!
She’s all over the place...
Helping out, getting a leg cramp...
She’s so cool!
Alola!
Geez.
If you’re going to be late,
please let me know.
Sorry we made you worry.
Huh? Ms. Joy,
when did you move here?
I think you have me confused
with the Joy from Melemele Island.
She’s my older sister.
S-Sister?
Are you twins-roto?
You two are over 99% alike-roto!
Ms. Joy,
these six from the Pokémon School
will be staying here with you.
Thanks for having us!
Of course! Please enjoy your
extracurricular lessons on Akala Island!
All right! Now put your things away in your rooms,
then it’s dinner time!
Yeah! I’m starving!
Me, too!
The extracurricular lessons on Akala Island
are about to begin.
What kind of experiences will the students have
with Island Queen Lychee?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was a cruiser!
Lychee’s Midday Form Lugarugan
is a Rock type.
Apparently it’s the evolution of an Iwanko
who took in plenty of energy from the sun!
Its defining characteristic is its ability to move
at godlike speed. It’s amazing!
Ms. Lychee and Lugarugan
are both so cool!
Ms. Joy! Ms. Lychee’s in trouble!
Oh, no! What’s wrong?!
Can’t breathe...
She’s all over the place...
Eating and drinking heartily,
choking on her food...
Next episode
Let’s do our best, Mooland!
Nobody can beat me
when it comes to Ride Pokémon!
Fight me, Kaki!
Bring it on!
Ready...
Go!
Hey! We’re not racing,
we’re hunting for treasure!
They’re gone...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Treasure Spotted! Mooland Search!!
Um, must I ride one as well?
Next time
Treasure Spotted!
Mooland Search!!