Alola!
Here’s your PokéProblem, meow!
Matadogas
Solgaleo
Lunala
Dogas
PetitDogas evolves
in today’s episode, meow!
What does it become, meow?
Get the answer at the
end of the episode, meow!
Alo-
I want to rescue Mother, who was taken away
by an Ultra Beast,  no matter what it takes.
I went off with my brother...
...to find a way to open the Ultra Hole.
We made it through
ruins covered with traps,
and battled Jararanga.
All of it was new
to Snowball and me.
With great effort, we finally made it
to the Altar of the Sunne.
Then, the others all came along.
They had been looking for us!
I was so glad that they all felt
they couldn’t leave me alone.
But I didn’t expect Kapu-Kokeko
and the other Guardian Deities to appear...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Altar of the Sunne!
Solgaleo Descends!!
Kapu-Kokeko! Kapu-Tetefu!
Kapu-Bulul and Kapu-Rehire, too!
Why are they here?
Melemele, Akala, Ula'ula, Poni...
I can’t believe all four of Alola’s
Island Guardian Deities have gathered here!
Shocking.
Yeah...
What’s going on?
I don’t know.
Kapu-Kokeko.
Lilie’s mom was taken away
by an Ultra Beast.
So we want to save her,
no matter what it takes!
We want to ask Solgaleo to help us
open the Ultra Hole!
Can we meet Solgaleo here,
at the Altar of the Sunne?
Electro Field, Psycho Field...
The four Fields are intermixing-roto!
It’s just like
what I saw in my dream!
Solgaleo and...
...Lunala!
The Pokémon spoken of
in Alolan legends...
So cool!
It’s my first time seeing them.
Intense!
What’s that?
Nebby?
Satoshi!
Pikachu and I are there, too-roto!
What is it, Pikachu?
Pikachu!
Satoshi! Satoshi!
Kapu-Kokeko!
What’s that?
All of the Kapu were there back then!
Solgaleo, Lunala and
the Alolan Guardian Deities...
...entrusted you with Nebby.
Entrusted me with it?
What’s wrong, Mokuroh?
Look what’s happened to Nebby.
It’s not even making any noise.
It’s just floating around.
Get a move on!
I want to go rescue Mom!
Every second counts!
I have no time to just sit still here!
Big brother.
Let’s wait. Have faith in
the Alolan Guardian Deities.
She’s right! It’ll work out.
Yes, this is Kukui.
What?! Understood.
For now, hide someplace safe.
I’ll be right there.
Professor!
Where are you going?
It was from Burnet.
Apparently she’s heading here,
so I’ll go meet her.
I’ll be right back.
Okay!
Counting on you, partner.
Those jangly Jarako just
would not let us leave!
Running over here was
the right choice.
The brats are at the top,
for sure, meow!
We will get PetitDogas!
Those jangly things have nothing on us
when it comes to persistence!
Not good... I’m losing my grip...
Hang in there, meow!
The goal’s right up there, meow!
And there we... go!
Goal...
What’s with those floating cup thingies?
Unbelievable! It appears they’re considered
Guardian Deities here in the Alola Region!
Apparently they’re called Kapu-Kokeko, Kapu-Tetefu,
Kapu-Bulul and Kapu-Rehire, or something.
Well then, what’s that
badge-looking thing there?
That one isn’t listed in here.
I wonder if Nebby’s asleep?
Sleep well, grow well!
I wonder what kind of dream it’s having.
I’m sure it’s dreaming about
playing with us!
Maybe.
Not “maybe”, it’s gotta be!
I 100% agree with
Mao and Māmane’s evaluation-roto!
What?!
Big news, meow! It seems that tiny one
is PetitDogas, meow!
Huh?! Hey, didn’t you say that when PetitDogas evolved,
it would become a Dogas?
That must mean... that in Alola, it has another stage
before evolving into Dogas, I guess?
That’s a SemiDogas!
SemiDogas?
Let’s get that PetitDogas,
or as it’s now known, SemiDogas, meow!
While we’re at it,
why not get those cups, too?
They’re “Kapu”, not “cups”...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Cosmovum
Type:   Psychic
This doesn’t look good...
Burnet!
You’re not hurt, are you?
No.
Warrgle! Brave Bird!
All right!
Good, Warrgle, that’s how it’s done!
If we offer SemiDogas up to Sakaki,
he’ll be so pleased with us, meow!
Especially if we throw in the full set of cups, too...
What a great feeling!
I told you, they’re Kapu.
All right, let’s go...
Um, hold on...
What even is this feeling?
What’s up, Pikachu?
Oh, come on!
What are you doing?!
We missed our chance at
getting SemiDogas!
W-What, you wanna fight?
I-I’m sorry...
My spine...
I can feel it cracking!
I got it, I got it already!
What?
The Altar of the Sunne is...
Will Solgaleo come?
What’s this?
Nebby...
Solgaleo!
...became Solgaleo?
You gotta be kidding...
T-This is a major discovery-roto!
After evolving twice, Nebby becomes Solgaleo,
the Legendary Pokémon of Alola-roto!
Updated-roto!
It evolved into some really cool thing.
I-I’m pretty sure that’s...
Solgaleo, a Legendary Pokémon
who’s famous in Alola...
What? Then what happened to
Dogas’s Alolan form?
Yeah, yeah! Where’d it go?
W-Well...
Where is the Dogas
we were supposed to get?
W-Well...
Was it all a mistake, meow?
Were you completely wrong
about PetitDogas and SemiDogas, meow?
Was that it?
W-Well...
I was mistaken! I’m sorry!
Huh?
You’re so cool, Nebby.
You really are!
You’ve become so impressive!
What a shock! Who’d have thought
you’d evolve into Solgaleo?
I got to meet
the Legendary Pokémon!
My...
My feelings are...
...roaring as fiercely as
a Dynamic Full Flame!
May I touch you?
So warm...
I can feel the power of the sun.
Thank you.
Oh, I know!
Want some, Nebby...
I mean, Solgaleo?
Guess it won’t
eat them anymore...
It really is Nebby!
Solgaleo.
We want you to take us to the
other side of the Ultra Hole.
Will you please help us rescue Mother?
Please.
A Z-Crystal?
You’re telling me to use a Z-Move?
What’s wrong?
It won’t fit.
What are they doing-roto?!
It looks kinda fun!
Yeah, really fun!
My Ring evolved!
All right! Thanks, Kapu-Kokeko!
Can we make it now?
To the other side of the Ultra Hole, where Mom is?
Solgaleo’s telling us to get on its back!
Everyone, return your Pokémon
to their Monster Balls.
Oh, of course!
Come back, Amamaiko!
You, too, Snowball.
It’s true!
You really are warm like the sun!
I can’t believe it!
I get to ride the
Legendary Pokémon, Solgaleo!
It’s so exciting.
Yeah.
Lilie.
That outfit looks really good on you!
It’s perfect!
It’s my “I Can RealLilie Do It” form!
Are you all ready?
Yeah.
Yes.
It’s time.
All ready-roto!
Solgaleo!
Oh, the Z-Move.
This is...
...our...
...full power!
Sunshine Smasher
What, what?! A hole?!
In the sky?! What?!
The brats are...
What are they trying to do?
Is that...?!
They’re going through the Ultra Hole...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting, meow!
Can you believe it? PetitDogas
evolved into Solgaleo, meow!
It started out so small, but became so big after evolving...
What an amazing shock!
And then it went into that hole in the sky
with the brats on its back...
Maybe there’s treasure
on the other side?
There might be
plenty of rare Pokémon, too!
Hey, you can leap up there, too, right?
Next episode
Go, Solgaleo!
It might not be the best time to say this,
but we should have brought snacks!
Yeah. What a blunder.
I have some.
Really? Great thinking, Suiren!
This isn’t a game, you know!
Then you don’t get any.
I’ll have some!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Hurry Up! Operation: Rescue Lusamine!!
Next time
Hurry Up!
Operation: Rescue Lusamine!!
Pleaaaase!