It’s time to begin, everyone!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Victory for Lucario
A draw
Victory for Agoyon
It doesn’t end
How will today’s battle between
Lucario and Agoyon end?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The exhibition match between...
...the Alola Pokémon League’s first Champion Satoshi
and Kukui, a.k.a. Royal Mask.
This 6v6 full battle...
...turned into an intense clash with
frequent switch-outs.
Professor Kukui kept up
a powerful offense,
but Satoshi and his Pokémon
fought back with intense resolve.
Both sides now have three Pokémon left.
The battle now enters a showdown between
Satoshi’s Agoyon and Professor Kukui’s Lucario.
Here we go! Cross Scissor!
Infight!
Go!
Lucario leaps up!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Conclusion!
Gaogaen VS Nyaheat!!
Agoyon’s Cross Scissor attack
missed its mark!
Lucario’s Infight
seems to have dealt damage!
Are you okay, Agoyon?!
That’s the spirit!
It’s responding loud and clear
to Satoshi’s voice.
Satoshi has built a friendship with it
ever since it was a Bebenom.
Agoyon is now battling
for Satoshi’s sake.
This is friendship!
Friendship indeed!
Friendship gives rise to
heated battles!
Don’t let your guard down.
You managed to land the first hit,
but this is still a foe we know little about.
Let’s go! Sludge Bomb!
Charge in!
Oh, no! That’s right!
Dragon Pulse!
Poison-type moves have
no effect on Steel types!
Sludge Bomb will not work
on Lucario!
100,000 Volts!
Infight!
Cross Scissor!
Agoyon lands Cross Scissor this time!
Right! Good going, Agoyon!
That was a quick reaction-roto!
Keep it up!
It’s gotten into the rhythm of battling!
Seems they’re evenly matched.
Yes.
Divine Speed!
Use Cross Scissor!
Go!
Divine Speed is fearsome!
Lucario is even faster
than the soaring Agoyon!
Agoyon!
I couldn’t see it at all!
Lucario’s movements are
impeccably precise!
Offense... Defense... Speed...
They’re perfectly balanced-roto!
Agoyon, please stand up!
Agoyon is back!
You can still go on, right?
Glad to see it!
They can see through
our movements...
In that case...
I’m sure you’ll use...
Dragon Pulse!
It’s a Dragon Pulse clash!
Such power!
Go, Agoyon!
Here they come, Lucario!
Infight!
Cross Scissor!
Lucario stopped Agoyon again!
It’s read its opponent perfectly!
Dragon Pulse!
Dragon Pulse makes impact!
Lucario is unable to battle!
Lucario is eliminated!
Agoyon wins its battle debut!
All right! You did it!
You look just like Bebenom
when you do that!
They won! Incredible!
Agoyon’s battle data
has been updated-roto!
A huge victory for Goyo-chan!
Return, Lucario.
Didn’t expect that!
You copied what I did
to beat Melmetal, yeah?
Well, if I just battled normally,
there’s no way I could’ve
landed a hit on your Lucario!
A sharp wit to adapt
to the situation at hand...
And your Pokémon answering in turn...
You guys really are incredible!
Agoyon, take a break.
Oh? He won’t keep going with Agoyon?
You did great in your first battle!
A Fire Pledge, huh, Satoshi?
Go!
Gaogaen and Nyaheat
face off once more!
The time has finally come!
How will Nyaheat fight,
now that he’s powered up?
I can feel the tension in the air!
Isn’t this exciting, Garagara?
Hang in there, Nyaheat!
Ever since their first clash, it’s like there’s been
invisible sparks flying between these two!
Let the battle begin!
Nyaheat, don’t be hasty.
Watch Gaogaen’s movements carefully!
Nitro Charge!
DD Lariat!
They have made their move!
Will the winner be Gaogaen or Nyaheat?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lucario
Type:   Fighting/Steel
Nyaheat is so quick!
Fire Fang!
Throat Chop!
It really is tough!
Were they using this first round
to size each other up, perhaps?
Satoshi!
I could really feel Nyaheat’s power!
This is just the beginning!
We’re gonna keep impressing you!
I can hardly wait!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
Use Great Blaze!
You were that strong?!
Go!
Gaogaen wins the showdown between
Great Blaze and Build Up!
But the flames are intense!
Nitro Charge!
So fast! Nyaheat blurs into
nothing but a red flash!
Nyabi-chan seems
rather obsessed with Gao-chan.
Ever since they first met,
Gaogaen’s been like a massive wall
for Nyaheat to overcome.
He’s challenged it several times,
but never won.
Satoshi tends to partner up with
a lot of highly competitive Pokémon.
They flock to him.
Fire Fang!
What?!
Oh, my!
Gaogaen grabbed Nyaheat!
It’s got a firm grip
and won’t let go!
He won’t get out of
that grasp easily!
Him raising his speed
won’t help here!
Let’s see you fight back
from there!
Things seem hopeless for Nyaheat!
Throat Chop!
Nyaheat!
Awesome!
That’s right, Nyaheat!
We can still go on!
Blaze up, Gaogaen!
Go, Nyaheat! Use Revenge!
Revenge hits its mark!
Gaogaen’s down on one knee!
How’s that, Gaogaen?!
That was intense!
I didn’t know Revenge
was that strong!
Its power is greater than ever-roto!
Can Gaogaen recover from this?!
Gaogaen and Nyaheat’s flames
flare up to full power!
This build-up of flames...
Now’s the time to end this!
Let’s go, Nyaheat!
Let’s go, Gaogaen!
What is this?!
A face-off between two Z-Moves?!
This is our full power!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the field ablaze
with the ultimate flames!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Both fighters use Dynamic Full Flame!
Their Z-Moves clash and turn into a massive fireball
that consumes the battlefield!
Nyaheat! Let’s finish this!
Revenge!
Let’s go, Gaogaen!
Use Throat Chop!
Gaogaen is unable to battle!
Down! Gaogaen is down!
All right, Nyaheat, you did it!
He evolved!
I can’t believe it!
Amazing! Following its victory,
Nyaheat evolved!
Amazing, Gaogaen!
Keep it up for the last one!
Gaogaen... You’re...
Gaogaen is unable to battle!
The battle reached
a shocking conclusion!
After grasping victory and evolving,
Competitor Satoshi’s Gaogaen
goes down, as well!
No way...
Is this even possible?
Gaogaen, you were really cool.
I won’t let your effort go to waste!
Listen to this applause!
Competitor Satoshi and Nyaheat— No, the evolved Gaogaen
are being showered with applause for their performance!
Return, Gaogaen.
That was a great fight!
Satoshi! This still isn’t over!
Of course not!
We’ll clash at full power ‘til the very end!
Let us resume the battle!
Both sides, send out your Pokémon!
Kapu-Kokeko!
It’s Kapu-Kokeko!
What is it doing here?
Surely it cannot be enraged?!
This is unbelievable!
Kapu-Kokeko has appeared
on Manalo Stadium!
H-Hey, what’s...
You mean you want to battle us?
Hey, hey... Are you serious,
Kapu-Kokeko?!
It seems young Satoshi
is exactly right.
Kapu-Kokeko wishes to battle by your side
against young Satoshi and his Pokémon!
Kapu-Kokeko!
We don’t mind! Let’s do this!
This just got really interesting!
Let’s do it!
How about all of you?
Do you want to see Kapu-Kokeko battle?!
That’s just incredible!
Yeah! I gotta see this!
I’ve never even read
about a battle like this!
This exhibition match is the best!
We’ll cheer them on at full power!
A team-up between Kukui
and Kapu-Kokeko! This’ll be intense!
Who would have thought an Alolan Guardian Deity
would battle under the command of a trainer?
This is spectacular!
Counting on you, Kapu-Kokeko!
Oh, sorry, Pikachu!
Let me fight with this guy first!
Competitor Satoshi rises
to the challenge with Agoyon!
An Ultra Beast VS an Alolan legend!
This will be a marvelous showdown!
I feel romanticism in the air!
It’s giving me chills!
Electro Field, huh?
Kapu-Kokeko! Let’s battle!
The exhibition match
has taken an unexpected turn!
How will Satoshi face Kapu-Kokeko?
Next time:
The conclusion!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting!
The battle between Lucario and Agoyon
ended in victory for Agoyon!
The Aura Pokémon Lucario
is a Fighting/Steel type.
They say it can sense the feelings of people and Pokémon
from a kilometer away! Incredible!
But Agoyon sure was strong!
Let’s see...
Kapu-Kokeko’s moves are...
Wonderful! This sort of surprise
lights a fire in my announcer soul!
Now, then...
Next episode
You really have made it far, Satoshi!
It’s all thanks to you!
The bond between teacher and student...
Between Alolan parent and child... It brings a tear to my eye!
Here’s your coat!
Yeah, it’s all clean!
Here’s your shoes!
Yeah! They’re shining!
Well done, Satoshi!
What are you even talking about?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Alola’s Mightiest Z! Kapu-Kokeko VS Pikachu!!
Next time
Alola’s Mightiest Z!
Kapu-Kokeko VS Pikachu!!