Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Gantle
Nuikoguma
Elfoon
Meguroco
Which of these Pokémon keeps
clinging to me in today’s episode?
Blue: Gantle?
Red: Nuikoguma?
Green: Elfoon?
Or Yellow: Meguroco?
The answer’ll be at the end!
Everyone’s got appetite to spare!
That’s a sign that they’re healthy-roto!
Satoshi, too-roto!
Huh?
What’s wrong?
Lunches?
For Professor Burnet and Gonbe?
Did they forget them-roto?
Yeah.
I’ll deliver them!
Where’s Professor Burnet working today?
Aether Paradise.
It’s a bit far, isn’t it?
I know!
Let’s order a Ride Pokémon!
All right!
You’d better get going soon,
Professor Kukui,
or you’ll be late for
the Pokémon Battle Research Conference-roto.
Oh, right.
Thank you.
You can count on me!
Bye!
Right! Let’s get ready!
Satoshi! Pikachu!
What’s this?
Lilie’s come over in a jet...
What could she want?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Team Rocket and Nuikoguma!
Ms. Lusamine wants to see me?
Indeed. She has been hard at work
since the Manalo Festival,
wishing to record everything
that happened there.
She said it was an important event,
sure to leave a mark on Alolan history.
Which is why we have come to pick you up today,
Young Master Satoshi.
She wishes to hear
your side of the story.
I’m very sorry. Mother always
makes these requests on such short notice.
Perfect timing!
We were about to make a delivery
to Aether Paradise, anyway!
Oh, my!
And if she wants data on Necrozma,
I can provide her with it-roto!
I’ve recorded plenty-roto!
Thank you, Rotom!
I can see it!
We’re back,
Pokémon of Aether Paradise!
This time, we will nab every Pokémon
in the Conservation Area! Nothing will stand in our way!
Then we’ll present them all
to Sakaki, meow!
What a great feeling!
Not good!
Does that mean...?
It would seem that
we are kindred spirits.
This window’s cloudy!
Well, that’s no good at all!
Pardon me...
You four seem rather familiar...
Familiar?
Couldn’t be...
Nope, meow...
Is that so?
What are your names?
Um...
What department do you work in?
Oh, these four?
Chief Wicke...
They’re new here. I hired them just the other day
to look after the Pokémon Conservation Area.
Yes! We’re in charge
of the Conservation Area!
Indeed!
Today, they’ve been appointed with cleaning Area C,
and with counting up all the Pokémon.
I see.
Work hard!
All right, now list the Pokémon’s
numbers on this form.
We’ll do our best, Chief!
Um... Meguroco...
One, two, three, four,
five, six... Seven.
Usokki...
One, two, three, four... Five.
As for the Gantle...
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven... Eight.
Okay, they’re all here.
Just the thought of
all of these becoming Sakaki’s...
What a great feeling!
Now, next up are the Purin.
P—
Purin?!
Thank goodness...
That Purin isn’t here.
This place is huge!
I really need some assistance.
Gimme a hand, Hidoide!
No, stop that already!
T-Time t’ do sum cleanin’,
Hiroide...
What’s that? You say the Conservation Area is
a really comfortable place to live?
Hmm? You’re about ready to be
sent back into the wild, meow?
Oh, I see!
Good for you, meow!
If we get them, then all these Elfoon
will go to Sakaki...
If they get to live with Sakaki, then...
You’ll all become even happier, meow!
Isn’t that great, meow?
You’ll be so happy, meow!
Happy! Happy!
Here you go, Professor Burnet.
Thank you, Satoshi!
I just realized I’d forgotten these,
and it was such a shock!
Okay, Pikachu.
Let’s eat together later.
Rotom, could you
give me the data right away?
No problem-roto!
Copying data... Copying data...
Copying...
Copying complete-roto!
Thank you, Rotom!
You’re welcome-roto!
Say, since it’s been a while, would you like to go
see the Pokémon in the Conservation Area again?
Sure! I’d love to!
I wonder how the Metamon
that transformed into Snowball is doing.
Lovely! So many Pokémon
for us to catch!
Coming here was the right choice!
Well then, shall we get started?
Ready to go, meow!
Team Rocket’s
once-in-a-lifetime super gig!
Let’s do it!
Here we go, meow...
Hey, Metamon!
The brat boy?!
Pikachu, too?!
Of all days to show up...
They had to come on
the day of our super gig!
What do we do?
We have no choice but
to wait until they leave.
Well then, let’s go somewhere
else for now, meow.
Hmmm?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moo...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nuikoguma
Type:   Normal/Fighting
I hope they’re all here today.
One, two, three, four... Five.
Everything seems to be okay.
Is that Pikachu?
What will we do
if it runs off again?
It’s back to normal!
That one’s grown quite a bit.
Yes. It’s calmed down,
and has stopped causing trouble.
We’re thinking it might be ready
to graduate soon.
Right, Metamon?
“Graduate”?
Here at Aether Paradise,
when we return Pokémon in our care to the wild,
we call it graduation.
I see. Graduation, huh?
Congratulations!
But it is a bit of a shame that
I won’t get to see it here anymore.
There are several others...
...who are almost ready
to graduate.
We are so out of luck!
Now, now... As soon as
the brat boy and his friends leave...
Then we’ll get to enact the plan
immediately, meow!
What’s with you?
President Lusamine!
Chief!
It’s awful!
What’s wrong?
I just looked at the Pokémon headcount,
and there’s one that’s unaccounted for!
What?!
Who’s missing?
It’s Nuikoguma!
Oh, no!
That’s the one who’s
graduating next week, right?
Let’s split up and look for it!
Y-Yes, good idea.
Let’s help look!
Yes!
Rotom,
what’s a Nuikoguma?
I got you covered-roto!
Nuikoguma. Flailing Pokémon.
Normal/Fighting type.
Despite its adorable appearance,
it doesn’t like being touched by strangers,
and will flail around
dangerously in response.
Huh?! That’s really bad!
Don’t worry.
It’s a calm Pokémon.
It’s never caused us any trouble at all.
I first met it...
...one time when I was
patrolling on my own.
Where are you?
A young Nuikoguma
had gotten its leg stuck under a fallen tree,
and couldn’t get out.
Oh, no!
It’s all right!
I’ll save you, I promise!
You need medical assistance!
Ever since then,
I’ve been acting as its guardian!
I can’t believe
it would disappear!
Nuikoguma!
Come out!
Nuikoguma, dearie?
Good, it’s not in the water.
Searching... Searching...
Why is it following us?!
No idea...
It’s quick
for being so small, meow.
Hey, you! You want something?
Huh?!
I think maybe
it wants you to catch it.
Get it, Musashi!
R-Really? Well, if that’s what it wants,
then here goes!
You’re mine!
Huh?
Sheesh!
What is your problem?!
Attention,
everyone in Aether Paradise!
The Nuikoguma in
the Conservation Area has disappeared!
If any of you finds it,
or knows where it might be, please...
A missing Nuikoguma?
It’s gotta be this one, meow!
Not good, meow!
What? What’s not good?
If they think that
we stole this one...
Figuring out how to catch all the Pokémon
will be the least of our problems!
Hey, get off me, you!
Get off me, I said!
Get! Off! Me!
There!
It’s Nuikoguma-roto!
Now we just gotta...
Run, meow!
Hey, wait for me!
This way, meow!
You!
Wait!
Oh, there’s Nuikoguma.
Why are you running?!
They must be thieves-roto!
Hold it!
Give Nuikoguma back!
Now this is a surprise.
I didn’t expect you
to be Pokémon thieves.
We’re not thieves, meow!
If you weren’t thieves,
then what reason would there be for you to run?
He’s right... We probably would have
been better off not running...
We could have just said “Hello, we found Nuikoguma”
and handed it over, couldn’t we...
Our habits as righteous evildoers
made us default to running away, meow...
We might as well
go with it now!
Yeah!
Stop!
When told “Stop!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Integrity and innocence,
generous and selfless!
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Clear skies and a clear heart!
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
Cleared of all charges,
justice prevails!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
What?!
You were Team Rocket
all along?!
Give Nuikoguma back-roto!
I would if I could!
The thing just won’t let go,
you see.
If you won’t return it, then...
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Not good, meow!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Wh-What?
What?
“Mama”?!
No way!
“Mama”...
So that’s your mother?
I’m so happy for you!
What even is this feeling?
What a surprise!
Kiteruguma and Nuikoguma were mother and child!
But what will happen
with Team Rocket now?
Take care of yourself,
Nuikoguma...
What’s this?
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon that kept clinging to me
was Nuikoguma!
The Flailing Pokémon Nuikoguma
is a Normal/Fighting type.
I can’t believe that Kiteruguma
was that Nuikoguma’s mother!
Is Kiteruguma laughing?
She’s laughing, meow.
Huh? That’s her laughing?
Next episode
There’s this boy named Hau...
I see. And?
And he’s got a Pokémon
with an “R” in its name.
Is it a Numacraw?
No! I’m pretty sure
it did have a “W” in it, though!
Then it’s gotta be Fiarrow!
No, wrong!
Then... Break Claw!
That’s a move, not a Pokémon!
What are the two of you
doing-roto?
W-Well...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Artisan Fukuthrow!!!
The Sleeping MokurohZZZ
Next time
The Artisan Fukuthrow!!!
The Sleeping MokurohZZZ
Fukuthrow! That’s the one!