Alola! It’s me, Kukui!
I’ll be giving out today’s PokéProblem.
Poké-Soccer
Poké-Rugby
Poké-Baseball
Poké-Ping Pong
What sport is played in
today’s special lesson?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Professor Kukui’s house,
where Satoshi and his Pokémon are freeloading.
They seem to be glued to the TV.
I wonder what they’re watching...
Gyarados hit it!
The ball crashes into the fence
with immense force!
Awesome! This is getting
really exciting!
All right! We’ve got two outs
and a runner on first...
and here comes batter
number four, 'Olu'olu!
The final win for the Koikings to clinch the season
hangs on what 'Olu'olu does with that bat!
And 'Olu'olu
hits the ball dead-on!
The ball flies far above
Nasshi’s outstretched neck!
It’s an out-of-the-park
walk-off home run!
That’s so awesome!
I wanna play Poké-Baseball, too!
And the Pro League Poké-Baseball
season champs are the Koikings!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Hot-Blooded Poké-Baseball!
Aim for a Tide-Turning Home Run!!
Alola!
Alola, Professor Kukui!
So did everybody watch
the Poké-Baseball game?
Yeah!
He hit the ball like, bam! Ran like, whoosh!
Then slid like, screech!
It was amazing! Right, Pikachu?
'Olu'olu’s play
guaranteed their victory.
He’s from Alola, right?
Not just that, I hear he’s
from Melemele Island!
Really? You sure
know a lot about him!
Could you be a fan?
W-Well... Yeah...
Give us the details, Māmane!
It seems like it would be fun
if we, too, could play.
Actually, today’s class is
all about Poké-Baseball!
Really?!
But I don’t quite know the rules.
Me neither!
Are you going to teach us,
Professor Kukui?
No. I’ve called in a special coach
who would be absolutely perfect for Poké-Baseball.
Coach?
Alola!
It’s the Koikings’s...
'Olu'olu!
I-In the flesh?!
Who? Who?!
I... I want his autograph!
And behind him, isn’t that...
It was from this very Pokémon School
that he graduateDugtrio.
I’m 'Olu'olu from the Koikings.
The pleasure’s miNuckrar!
Was his teacher the Principal?
Maybe...
'Olu'olu is usually very busy with
Pro League Poké-Baseball,
but he had some free time today.
Professor Kukui told me he had students
who were interested in Poké-Baseball, you see.
Professor Kukui?
So, today’s special lesson will be
Poké-Baseball with 'Olu'olu!
Poké-Baseball!
This is gonna be great!
Thank you for waiting-roto!
'Olu'olu has taught the students well,
and now it’s time to play ball-roto!
First off, introducing the defending
home team, Team Kaki-roto!
I’ll pour every last bit of
my strength into this mound!
Batting third
Pitcher
Kaki
Pitcher: Kaki!
Batting fourth
Catcher
Bakugames
Catcher: Bakugames!
Here I go, Amamaiko!
Batting first, third base
Mao
Third base: Mao!
Batting fifth, first base
Amamaiko
First base: Amamaiko!
Snowball, here it comes!
Batting sixth, right fielder
Lilie
Right fielder: Lilie!
Batting second, left fielder
Snowball
Left fielder: Snowball!
Unlike a Pro League game,
today’s competition will use three bases,
with each team consisting of
three trainers and three Pokémon-roto.
And here providing commentary: Principal Okido,
Professor Kukui, and 'Olu'olu-roto!
This is a triangle base game,
so no second base to step oNeolant.
Since there’s six students, I adjusted the rules
a biTamatama, Tamatama, Tamatama!
Moving on-roto...
Introducing Team Satoshi-roto!
All right...
Let’s go for a homerun!
Batting first, catcher, Satoshi
Batting first, Satoshi!
Batting second, pitcher
Pikachu
Batting second, Pikachu!
Batting third, first base
Ashimari
Batting third,
Ashimari!
Batting fourth, third base
Suiren
Batting fourth
Suiren!
Batting fifth,
Māmane!
Batting fifth, right field
Māmane
Batting sixth, Togedemaru!
Batting sixth, left field
Togedemaru
Watch me,
Mokuroh! Iwanko! Nyabby!
Oh, so the umpire is Strike!
Pleasure to meet you.
Here it comes, Satoshi!
Bring it on!
He can’t be...
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
Go! This is my full power!
Sparking Gigavolt Swing!
A whiff...
Satoshi!
Keep a closer eye on the ball!
I know, I know!
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
That was a terrible throw-roto!
Well, it is a Strike.
Definitely a Strike.
All right. I’ll just
have to hit everything!
Let’s see now. What kind of pitch
will the pitcher, Pikachu, show us-roto?!
Pikachu! Show them
your full power!
Come at me!
I will rise to any challenge!
Oh, my! Could this be...
Oh no! I got jammed?!
Where will it fall?! Where?!
To the right! No, to the left!
Which way?!
Amazing! He got it!
Well... yeah...
Bring it...
Ashimari, Balloon!
And you’re out-roto!
Nice play-roto!
What a spectacular team!
Now, Amamaiko! Make it fly!
Jump, Togedemaru!
Nice catch-roto!
Let’s see if you can hit this!
I can catch it...
I read about this in a book!
Looking at its angle of descent,
I can definitely catch it!
But... I’m scared!
Thanks so much, Snowball!
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
Leave it to me...
This is our chance!
Bakugames, block him!
No way...
Blooper recorded-roto!
Now for the last inning!
Team Satoshi started out on offense,
but one more out
and the game is over!
They’re one point behind,
with runner Ashimari on first and Suiren at bat!
Can they make a
one-hit comeback-roto?!
Here I come, Suiren!
This will end the game!
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
Secret Art:
Single-Hook Fishing-Style!
All right!
It’s an out-of-the-park
home run-roto!
Poké-Baseball is so much fun!
There’s still...
the bottom of the ninth inning...
'Olu'olu is such a man.
I didn’t expect you to be
interested in Poké-Baseball.
Poké-Baseball? Who cares?
I’m interested in 'Olu'olu.
Whatever, we’ve gotta get some Pok—
Why, you...!
Who was it, meow?!
Who threw this b—
'Olu'olu!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kabigon
Type:   Normal
Team Satoshi wins, 4-3!
I lost...
Too bad, Kaki.
But that was a good match!
Hey!
Catch this, meow!
Oh, it’s the out-of-the-park
home run ball!
Thanks a lot!
When told “Thanks a lot”...
Let us tell you our names!
Playing to win, pitching at full power...
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Clearing the bases, wrecking all runners...
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
Loading the bases in a losing match...
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh yeah!
Team Rocket!
What are you doing here?!
“What are you doing here?!”
Isn’t it obvious?
Yeah, meow!
We’re gonna get your Pi—
We’re gonna get
'Olu'olu’s autograph!
What?
Lies!
I’m not lying!
You’re after our Pokémon again,
aren’t you?!
Not today!
We’re not falling for that!
Besides, I want his autograph too!
I’m getting it!
Why don’t you settle this
with a Poké-Baseball game?
'Olu'olu!
I will give the winners my autograph.
However, Kabigon and I
will play, too...
...on Team Pokémon School.
Oh, you’re such a card!
Nothing’s better than a
reasonable, handsome man!
I don’t care if you’re a pro.
If it’s a match you want, you’ll get it, meow!
Right! We accept your challenge!
Now, it’s time for a Poké-Baseball match
with Team Rocket...
...with 'Olu'olu’s autograph on the line!
Who will win-roto?!
Hang in there!
Go get them!
The word “Defeat” does not exist
in Team Rocket’s vocabulary.
The only entry is “Victory”!
But there’s a
professional on their team.
Don’t worry. It’s obvious they have
a slow amateur on their team as well.
Kabigon, right?
See how unmotivated it is?
Looks like it thinks it’ll be an easy win
because 'Olu'olu’s on their team,
so all we gotta do is target it.
Good point.
We can do this, meow.
We’re Team...
...Rocket!
Now, come at me!
'Olu'olu’s autograph will be mine!
All right! Do it, Pikachu!
Not yet!
She hit it!
By sheer dumb luck, meow!
Kabigon!
It’s headed your way!
Just what I was aiming for!
I’ve got it!
See? Just as planned!
Flawless victory!
Musashi, celebrate later!
Run now, meow!
I have to run?
Wrong way!
Run towards the first base!
Oh, come on...
It’s all for 'Olu'olu’s autograph!
Can I do it in time?!
First!
Out!
You didn’t run soon enough!
What are you doing, meow?!
Well, duh.
I don’t know the rules.
Again?!
I got it, I got it!
Nice cover, 'Olu'olu-roto!
Kabigon, we’re changing,
so get back to your base!
We’re counting on you, Pikachu!
Now, with Team School on offense,
Team Rocket’s pitcher
is Mimikkyu-roto!
Get ‘em! Throw!
I’ve never seen Mimikkyu
so charged up before.
This just might work, meow.
Don’t tell me Mimikkyu was actually
aiming for Pikachu there...
Are you okay, Pikachu?
That’s against the rules,
Team Rocket!
Oh, fine... Changing pitchers!
Strike! Batter out!
You got me...
Mimikkyu’s off the mound,
and Nyarth’s on!
His surprisingly nice pitches are
completely shutting out Team School-roto!
Team Rocket has a one-run lead going into
the bottom of the ninth and final inning.
This will be Team School’s
final offense-roto!
One batter left!
I can’t believe he can throw
those fast balls with his paws...
A clever Nyarth
conceals its claws, meow!
My intense training, wearing power training casts through
rainy days and windy days alike in order to get Pikachu...
...has come in handy at an
unexpected time, meow!
The batter is 'Olu'olu-roto!
I feel like I can’t lose
to anyone, meow!
What?!
What are you doing?!
Get a grip!
It’s nothing. I was just letting the pro
have a brief moment in the sun, meow...
Besides, the next batter is
someone I can definitely strike out, meow!
Now, can they pull off
a tide-turning inning-roto?
'Olu'olu’s partner
Kabigon is up!
What do you think,
Principal Okido?
I’d been wanting to see Kabigon’s true skill,
so this will be quite excitIwanko.
I can’t really feel
any drive from it...
I hope it’s okay...
Kabigon is the Sleeping Pokémon,
so it doesn’t
move around very much.
Hang in there!
Kabigon!
Give us a home run!
There’s no point in
talking to Kabigon, meow!
Check this, meow!
Demonic Meow League Ball, meow!
Let me explain!
The Meow League Ball...
...is Nyarth’s unbeatable breaking ball
that always strikes out the batter,
which Nyarth attained after
countless long hours of top-secret training!
Hidoide, it’s all on you!
Over here!
What are you doing, meow?!
Not yet...
If we can strike out the batter,
the game’s ours, meow!
Kabigon, run!
Run!
Please run!
Come on! Please, run!
Let’s get serious, Kabigon!
No way!
Burn! Sweat, tears, and guts!
Run, Kabigon!
Actually Serious Attack!
W-Wha?
I won’t let you step on
the home plate, meow!
Safe!
All right!
Well done, partner!
Game set! Team School wins!
I’m picking up the dirt stained
with my sweat and tears, meow.
I can’t believe I won’t get
'Olu'olu’s autograph...
What’s this?
The autograph I promised!
But we lost the game!
Thank you for a great game!
This is my way of thanking you!
'Olu'olu! Thank—
What even is this feeling?
What even is this feeling?!
Thanks to all of you!
This really reminded me of back when
I first started playing Poké-Baseball.
It was a practice session
that filled me with joYoguirus!
Oh, 'Olu'olu, you’re always
such a graceful playeRunpappa!
Today we brought you a double-header:
One game between the Pokémon School students,
and one between the students
and Team Rocket,
coming to you live from
Pokémon School Stadium-roto!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was Poké-Baseball!
It was so much fun!
'Olu'olu’s Kabigon, who played a crucial role
in the match, is a Normal type.
True to its classification as the Sleeping Pokémon,
it’s always sleeping, except when it’s eating.
Kabigon’s exclusive Z-Move,
Actually Serious Attack, is immensely powerful.
Who knew it could be used
in Poké-Baseball like that?
Kabigon! You can get serious
during practice too, you know!
Next episode
Satoshi! Wanna go camping with us?
Oh, yeah, I’ll go!
When it comes to camping...
You gotta have curry!
You gotta have a campfire!
Can you get up in time?
We leave early!
It’s fine. I just won’t sleep.
Really?
You really won’t sleep?
I really won’t sleep!
You really, really, really won’t sleep?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Musht You Sleep in
the Nemush Forest, Too?
Next time
Musht You Sleep in
the Nemush Forest, Too?
I said... I won’t... shleep...