Alola!
I will be giving today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Somebody’s big brother
shows up in today’s episode,
Lilie
Kaki
Mao
-
Mamane
but whose brother is it-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Hey!
Looks like we’ve got a guest...
We goin’ for it, Bro?
Yeah.
Hold it, you.
Ya ignorin’ me?!
Yer pretty full o’ yerself,
ignorin’ our Bro!
Leave that Blacky with us,
Mr. Full o’ Yerself!
Ya just gave me a glare, didn’tcha?
When two trainers make eye contact,
it’s battle time!
Come out, Yatoumori!
Yer up, Dustdas!
Countin’ on ya, Zubat!
Come forth, crimson glare.
Lugarugan!
Lugarugan?
Looks like this guy’s real strong!
Blacky’s real good,
but so is Lugarugan!
Let’s do this, Yatoumori.
Use Venom Shock!
Zubat, use Leech Life!
Dustdas, use Sludge Bomb!
Stone Edge.
Yer tough...
With just one attack?!
What just happened?!
Return!
We’re gettin’ outta here,
full throttle!
We’ll get ya for this!
Blacky, let’s go.
Did you see that Luganga?
Oh, yeah... Lugarugan, you mean.
I could feel a serious
killing intent from it, meow...
Like, it was both scary
and cool, wasn’t it?
That Luganga would be perfect
for our evil justice!
Yeah. But anyway,
who was that trainer?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Come Forth!
Crimson Glare Lugarugan!!
Alola!
It seems Satoshi and the others are doing
some early morning Pokémon Battling practice, as usual.
Here it comes, Iwanko.
Dodge it!
Mokuroh! Leafage!
Iwanko! Rock Throw!
When did Mokuroh manage...
Be careful, Iwanko!
Take a break, Iwanko.
Next up, it’s Nyabby vs. Mokuroh!
Wow! You’re really fired up,
huh, Iwanko?
Okay, Mokuroh, you take a break.
Here we go! Iwanko, use Tackle!
Nyabby! Scratch!
Nyabby, Fire Fang!
Use Rock Throw, Iwanko!
All right, that’s enough for now.
You both fought well.
Nyabby, those were some awesome flames!
And Iwanko, I could really feel
how determined you were!
Iwanko’s Rock Throw
is getting stronger-roto!
Morning training’s done!
Time for Pokémon School!
So cute!
Are they playing Caterpie?
Snowball seems to be having fun, too.
Hey, did you hear?
They say there’s this really strong Pokémon Trainer
who’s been showing up on the island lately.
A strong Pokémon Trainer?
I heard that! Some customers were
talking about it earlier.
What kind of guy is it?
They called him
the Mysterious Lugarugan User.
Apparently he’s got
a Midnight Form Lugarugan with him.
Midnight Form Lugarugan?
Midnight Form?
Lugarugan has two forms;
Midnight and Midday-roto.
Apparently he’s got a Blacky, too.
Wow! I really wanna
battle this trainer!
Kamex!
What power!
Don’t flinch, Kamex!
You can still win!
Hey, Rotom, what were we
supposed to buy again?
The professor asked for
a bag of Alolan coffee beans,
some fresh Pile Juice,
a box of Gokurin-brand zipper-lock bags,
and some Pearshen-brand short pasta.
What’s that?
Let’s have a look-roto!
Kamex! Rocket Headbutt!
Counter!
W-We got completely trashed...
Kamex’s weight is estimated to be 100 kilos!
Yet Lugarugan took it out in one hit!
Awesome!
Data updated-roto!
Lugarugan and Blacky...
Satoshi, there’s a 99.95% chance that this trainer
is the Mysterious Lugarugan User-roto.
Really?!
Satoshi!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
That battle was so awesome!
If you don’t mind,
could you battle—
Big Brother!
Lilie?
I could never have guessed that you were
the Pokémon Trainer everyone was talking about!
You’re kidding, right?
So that guy and Lilie
are siblings-roto?!
You can touch Pokémon now?
Her name is Snowball.
Snowball, this is my brother, Gladio.
Master Gladio, since she was an egg,
Snowball has been in Ms. Lilie’s care.
She is the first Pokémon
she ever caught.
I see. Take good care of her.
Master Gladio! It’s been so long
since you’ve been home,
so I was hoping you’d come with us
back to the mansion.
No thank you, James.
See you, Lilie.
Big Brother!
Wait a minute!
I was hoping we could have a battle!
My goal is to be a Pokémon Master,
so I wanna battle lots of awesome
trainers in the Alola Region!
That’s a Z-Ring?
I got it from Kapu-Kokeko.
From Kapu-Kokeko?
Right.
Satoshi has battled with Kapu-Kokeko.
Battled with it?
I’ll consider it.
I’m staying at
Professor Kukui’s house.
It’s down by the coast!
I’ll be waiting for you!
You see, my brother left home
a little over six months ago.
He just left one day, saying he
wanted to train by himself.
What kind of training-roto?
“I want to think about my life and future,
while improving my battling skills.”
That’s what he said.
That’s pretty cool!
But...
Lilie?
When I saw him today, he seemed like
a completely different person from the kind brother I knew.
It feels like only yesterday...
...that Young Master Gladio brought
Eevee back home with him.
James! James!
What have we here?
I found it hurt and crying
in the tall grass.
Please help it...
Oh, this is terrible.
Young Master Gladio,
you did well!
I suggest immediate first aid,
and then we’ll take it to Ms. Joy.
Will it get better?
It will, right?
It’s all right.
I’m sure it will get better.
I never knew...
You were but a small child at the time,
so I highly doubt you would remember any of it.
But there’s no doubt that Master Gladio
is a very generous person at heart.
Oh yeah, when he saw Snowball,
he said...
I see. Take good care of her.
“Take good care of her”...
Your brother’s a good guy!
Thank you so much,
Satoshi, James!
They took out Kamex
in a single punch, huh?
That really is cool!
I guess Iwanko’s become a fan
of that Lugarugan, hasn’t he?
Well, it was really cool.
Hey, cut it out! That hurts!
What was that for, Pikachu?!
What’s this?
All right!
Wh-What’s happened-roto?!
What’s happened-roto?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lugarugan
.                      (Midnight Form)
Type:   Rock
All right, let’s work hard and
get us some Pokémon!
I don’t see why we’d have to go out
this early in the morning...
What choice do we have?
We don’t want Kiteruguma
to find us.
We’re better off if we leave
while it’s still sleeping.
Isn’t that...
The superbly skilled
blonde brat trainer, meow!
What’s he doing here?
No idea. I have no idea, but... look!
It’s the Alolan sunrise!
Pretty...
So beautiful, it pains my heart.
It’s so refreshing, it feels like it’s
polishing my Charm, meow!
Gladio!
Thanks for the letter.
I’m going to test your skills,
to see why Kapu-Kokeko took an interest in you.
The brat boy!
Why is he here?
Do they know each other, meow?
Then let’s go!
Iwanko, I choose you!
Come forth, crimson glare.
Lugarugan!
You’ll be fighting your idol,
Lugarugan.
Let’s do our best, Iwanko!
All right! A chance to get the evil justice Luganga
and the brat boy’s Pikachu!
We’re super lucky, meow! Maybe it’s because
we paid our respects to the Alolan sunrise, meow!
Or maybe it’s because we’re
such model citizens?
Iwanko, Bite!
Rock Throw!
Stone Edge!
Dodge it, Iwanko!
Crunch!
Iwanko!
That’s the spirit!
Who are you?!
When asked “Who are you?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
It’s Team Rocket again-roto!
Give Pikachu and Lugarugan back!
What villain would actually
oblige that request?
Well then...
Farewell!
Wait!
Way to go, Iwanko!
Now use Bite!
There’s a pest
dangling behind us, meow!
Quite the impressive little runt.
Is this really the time
to be impressed?
Indeed not!
Blacky, use Evil Pulse!
Iwanko!
Hey, they got away!
What was I supposed to do?
Uh-oh...
Okay, Pikachu...
Leave this to us.
Here we go.
The rocks are bathed in the Z-Power
of the blue moon’s glow...
...and seal up...
...the crumbling world!
Eat this! World’s End Fall!
What is this?!
Looks pretty bad!
Figures...
What an awful feel-
Gladio, I wanna try using
the Rock-type Z-Move, too!
You have a Rock-Z?
Nope!
Then you should challenge
the Grand Trial of Akala’s Island Queen.
All right! I definitely will!
Right, Pikachu, Iwanko?
Then let’s continue the battle.
Big Brother!
Lilie!
Oh no-roto!
It’s time to go to
the Pokémon School-roto!
It’s really that late?!
What a shame. We’ll have to
save the battle for later.
It’s hard for me to fight
in front of my sister.
Okay, sure. Some other time.
Your Iwanko has a good look in its eyes.
They look just like my Lugarugan’s.
You think so? Thanks!
Satoshi has a new rival: Gladio!
When will they get to
continue their battle?
And who will emerge victorious?
Satoshi! Where is my brother?
Gladio left already.
Sheesh! I was set on having him
come visit me today!
Right, Snowball?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Lilie-roto!
Gladio’s Midnight Form
Lugarugan is a Rock type.
When Iwanko evolves after taking
in the energy of the moon,
it becomes the Midnight Form-roto!
Its special technique is to provoke
the enemy to attack it,
only to give them a Counter
for their trouble-roto!
Satoshi, we’ll be late!
Let’s get in the car!
I’m good. Everyone,
let’s do some training!
Let’s run to the School
at full power!
You’re guaranteed to be late-roto!
I’ll be hitching a ride
in Lilie’s car-roto!
Oh, of course...
Next episode
Satoshi! Can you hit my ball?!
Here I go!
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
I will hit it! This is my full power!
Sparking Gigavolt Swing!
This truly is a clash of passionate spirits,
embodied in a single ball-roto!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Hot-Blooded Poké-Baseball!
Next time
Aim for a Tide-Turning Homerun!!