Alola!
Here’s the PokéProblem!
Good luck once again!
10,000
Volts
100,000
1,000,000
Volts
10,000,000
What Z-Move does Pikachu use
to save Lilie’s mom today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Riding on Solgaleo, we made it through the Ultra Hole,
but what awaited us there...
...was Mother, who was
all but unrecognizable.
What’s more, the Ultra Beast
set Mother’s Pokémon loose in order to defeat us.
I tried to make Pixie remember...
...the days we spent together
and how we used to be good friends.
My feelings reached her,
and Pixie came back to me.
But how do we save Mother?
Go, Solgaleo!
No! Stay away!
What’s that?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Shine, Z-Power Ring!
Super Full Power 10,000,000 Volts!!
What is this?
It smells that bad?
It’s poison! This is bad! Awful!
You sure are strong...
It must be because of
the Ultra Beast’s power.
But don’t think you’ve won.
Sacred beast, Silvuddy!
Receive this Fire Memory,
and blaze up as a fire beast!
Multi-Attack!
You guys...
Silvuddy, use Break Claw!
Good going, Blacky!
Silvuddy, use Air Slash!
Lugarugan, let’s go!
The rocks are bathed in the Z-Power
of the blue moon’s glow...
and seal up the crumbling world!
Eat this!
World’s End Fall!
Well done.
We can’t attack
with Mokuroh there-roto!
Come on, snap out of it, Mokuroh!
What do we do, Rotom?
Thinking... Thinking... Thinking...
I know!
If Amamaiko gives off an even sweeter scent
than Dredear does,
Mokuroh might come back!
Māmane, you’re a genius!
We’ll give it a try!
Amamaiko, use Sweet Scent!
Good!
Mokuroh is reacting-roto!
Keep it up!
Come here, Mokuroh!
What?
You want me to lift you up?
There you go!
Fatal Moku Shot
Amazing!
What sort of
combination move was that?
Fatal Moku Shot.
Sounds great! We’ll use that name!
New move registered-roto.
Warning! It’s assuming the stance
to fire a Solar Beam-roto!
Nyabby!
Thank you for saving us!
In that case...
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Denjimushi! Discharge!
All right!
Ashimari, let’s go, too!
Reach...
...beyond the horizon!
Super Aqua Tornado!
We did it!
We all won together!
We’re the best team ever!
Brilliant work-roto!
What’s wrong, Nyabby?
No way!
Dodge!
Why?!
But I thought we beat them!
This can’t be-roto!
Stone Edge!
I see. So unless we defeat
that thing,
there will be no end
to this battle, huh?
Blacky, Lugarugan!
I leave Absol to you!
I will go to Mom!
She doesn’t want to let us
get close, huh.
Lilie’s mom! Lilie and Gladio
will be here any moment!
Go away! I hate you!
Thanks, Solgaleo.
Stay away!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Pikachu, you attack and draw
that thing’s attention!
Then I’ll pull Lilie’s mom out
while it’s distracted!
100,000 Volts!
Electric Ball!
I’m fine, Pikachu! Try again!
Satoshi!
Lilie! Gladio!
Again...?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pikachu
Type:   Electric
I hate you!
Thank you, Solgaleo.
Lilie, is Pixie all right?
It remembered me.
Satoshi! Unless we
defeat that monster,
Mom’s Pokémon will
just keep recovering.
If we don’t stop her soon,
the others fighting below will be in danger!
What?!
Solgaleo,
you’re going to help them?
I’m counting on you, Solgaleo!
Lugarugan, you go, too!
You take care of yourself, too.
Mother, I’ll be right there!
Lilie, don’t step in that!
I’ll be fine, Satoshi.
Pixie, take me to Mother.
Awesome!
This is Pixie’s ability,
Magic Guard.
It renders the poison
completely harmless to us!
We’ll go, too!
Become a steel beast, Silvuddy!
If I make Silvuddy into a Steel type,
it won’t take any damage from Poison!
Lilie, Gladio!
I trained Silvuddy to
take down Ultra Beasts.
The time has come
to use that power!
Again?
You’re running?!
Only because
you keep following me!
What is she planning to do?
Mother...
Lilie?!
Stay away!
Please don’t run!
Lilie!
There’s something I
want to tell her!
Won’t you please leave it to me?
We act the second I suspect
she’s in danger.
Right.
Mother... I hate you!
It’s stopped...
You always treat me like a baby...
But right now, you’re far more of
a spoiled baby than I’ve ever been!
That’s why you were taken
over by an Ultra Beast!
This thing you’ve become...
is not my real Mother!
She carried out her Ultra Beast
research for such a long time...
She’s an incredibly strong person.
And you... You’re nothing but a marionette
who can’t even move on her own.
Please come out!
You should be able
to get out on your own!
It’s entirely logical
to conclude that you can!
Lilie...
Mother...
Mother!
Mom!
Oh, no!
It got bigger!
What a monster!
It’s completely consumed her!
The Ultra Beast doesn’t
want to let Mom go.
What? Why?
Just like how Mom
wanted to know it,
that thing might be trying to learn about Mom...
Or rather... about humans.
Gladio, let’s both use
our Z-Moves together.
That might stop the Ultra Beast!
I used World’s End Fall on Absol.
Satoshi!
We’ll draw its attention.
Use your Z-Move
to stop it from moving!
Got it.
Lilie, in the meantime...
I will rescue Mother!
Pikachu, let’s do this!
Air Slash!
Now!
Yeah!
Pikachu, let’s hit it full-on
with our full power!
What’s this?!
A new Z-Crystal?
Fire, Satoshi!
Satoshi!
All right!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Pikachu!
10,000,000 Volts!
Mother!
Wake up!
Mother, please wake up!
We did it!
Thanks!
Wait, you two!
What happened?
Satoshi and the others must’ve...
Mom, can you stand?
Yes.
You really are strong.
Just as I thought.
I feel like I was living in a nightmare...
But your voice reached me, Lilie.
I’m sorry.
Thank you, Lilie, Gladio.
Hey, Satoshi!
Lilie!
Everybody! We did it!
Everybody, thank you so much!
Mother is fine!
You did it, Lilie!
Satoshi, I saw an incredible
discharge of electricity-roto!
What happened-roto?
That was our new Z-Move,
10,000,000 Volts!
10,000,000?!
What’s that-roto?!
Tell me the details-roto!
It’s detected an Ultra Hole materializing!
Here they come.
Fixing the spatial phase...
Maintaining the Ultra Hole wavelength!
They’re back?
Please let this work!
Please be safe, all of you!
It worked!
We’re back, Professor!
Lusamine!
It’s all thanks to these children.
You did well!
Well of course. We’re...
...the best team ever,
after all!
That hole was really pretty,
wasn’t it?
One of Alola’s mysteries, meow.
I’m so glad everyone’s all right...
Kiteruguma, you wanted us
to see this, meow?
Well, the sun’s setting.
I guess it’s time to go home.
Yeah, I’m hungry, meow.
What even is this feeling?
The Ultra Hole...
It’s gone.
Look at this!
You brought it with you?!
Oh, my!
It’s a memento of our adventure!
You say that, but...
Māmane, that thing will
get you possessed...
...by an Ultra Beast.
What?!
Just kidding.
Come on!
I panicked for real there!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
Pikachu’s Z-Move
was 10,000,000 Volts!
The Z-Move Pikachu used
sure was amazing!
Since my Electric-Z just changed all of a sudden,
I shouted “10,000,000 Volts!” without thinking.
How did we manage
to use that Z-Move?
I dunno, but I hope I can do it again.
Oh, right.
Mokuroh learned a new move!
Really, Mokuroh?!
Fatal Moku Shot
Next episode
Lilie didn’t come today either.
I know!
Let’s all write her a letter!
Great idea!
I agree!
Um... Dear Lilie.
I hope your mother—
I hope she’ll get better soon!
I’m taking notes for all our classes,
so you don’t have to worry about that!
But it’s really lonely without you!
We’re all waiting
for you to come back!
Write your own letters!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Thank You, Solgaleo!
Our Nebby!!
Thank You, Solgaleo! Our Nebby!!