Alola! V! V!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Melemele Island
Akala Island
Ula'ula Island
Poni Island
Which island are the Ultra Guardians
operating on today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi has cleared
his third Grand Trial.
He’s back on Melemele Island,
and tonight he’s at a fireworks festival
with his friends. Boom!
Ashimari!
There’s Nyabby, too!
So cute!
Next up is
the final, big fireworks!
That was wonderful.
A memory for life.
Fireworks are the best!
Awesome!
It’s the fireworks’ evolved form!
It still wasn’t over?
No, this is weird...
There’s still more?
Could this be... an encore?
What’s that?
Is somebody there?
It’s like a magic trick.
Awesome!
That startled me.
I thought my heart
was gonna stop...
Mine is still pounding.
So awesome!
I’ve never seen anything like this!
It’s like a walking fireworks.
Truly fascinating-roto.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Clash of the Ultra Beasts!
Operation Boom Boom Crackle!!
Aw, it’s gone.
That fireworks-man yesterday
sure was cool!
What do you think that was?
A Pokémon?
If so, could it be an Ultra Beast?
Ultra Guardians!
Get to the base, right now!
Another Ultra Beast’s
appeared?
Yeah. Please hurry!
Ultra Guardians, Alola!
Alola!
Burnet told me about
what happened last night.
It’s the fireworks-man!
That’s right.
This fireworks-man-like creature...
Our research has confirmed it
to be an Ultra Beast.
Really?!
We discovered an Ultra Hole reaction
near the coastline.
We’re working as fast as we can right now
to pinpoint its exact location.
It really was a Pokémon.
An Ultra Beast, at that.
Quite a showy Ultra Beast,
don’t you think?
We’ve named this Ultra Beast
Zugadon.
Zugadon?
Rotom, please update your data.
Roger that-roto!
Zugadon. Fireworks Pokémon.
Fire/Ghost type.
It startles its foes by
making its own head explode,
and absorbs their surprised reactions
to energize itself.
So it kept startling us...
...to absorb energy?
What a strange one.
Dark! Scary! Dark! Scary!
Thank you, Togedemaru.
Is there a backup
power source anywhere?
What was that?
I’d really rather avoid
this kind of trouble.
Everyone, we’ve found the spot.
There’s a strong Ultra Aura in the southern part
of Melemele Island’s Route 3, by the power lines.
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Pikachu, do you feel something?
Huh? Togedemaru, too.
Could it be Zugadon?
We’ll know once we get there.
Let’s hurry!
Yeah!
What is that?
It’s not Zugadon!
But they said they’d detected
a strong Ultra Aura.
So that’s an Ultra Beast, too?
Is it attacking?
It’s crackling!
We can’t get close!
It’ll be tough
to Ultra-get it like this.
What is it doing?
It appears to be
absorbing electricity.
So the crackling from before might have been
it yelling at us not to disturb while it was eating.
We just confirmed the situation.
I didn’t expect this...
Another Ultra Beast has appeared
at the same time as Zugadon.
It seems Zugadon’s explosions last night
opened another Ultra Hole,
and this one came through.
The electricity in the surrounding area
is draining rapidly.
We believe the Ultra Beast
is absorbing it.
Wicke, send a message to
stop supplying power to that area immediately.
Understood.
The electric current has stopped!
All right! Let’s Ultra-get it!
It’s mad that
the electricity stopped!
It’s an annoyed crackle!
Māmane! Let’s draw its attention
using Pikachu and the others’ electric moves!
All right!
We’ll prepare to Ultra-get it!
Yes!
Let’s all throw at the same time!
One of us is sure to get it!
Bebenom, get back!
You need electricity to draw its attention!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Denjimushi! Discharge!
Here it comes!
Togedemaru!
Over here!
Here’s the electricity you love so much!
All right! Now!
Could this be...?
Don’t tell me...?
From yesterday...?
Zugadon...
It’s even fiercer
than yesterday...
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Zugadon
Type:   Fire/Ghost
What are they doing?
Boom Boom Crackle!
A Boom Boom Crackle
showdown, huh!
What’s that supposed to mean?
It is true, though,
that they seem to be competing with each other.
Can’t we take this chance
to Ultra-get them?
Everyone,
take out your Ultra Balls.
Yeah!
Go!
Ultra Ball!
There!
What?!
It’s not working!
All their booming and crackling...
...is repelling the Balls!
I doubt that they will stop
any time soon...
Awesome!
Beautiful!
It’s like space.
Hey, this is no time to
be watching the fireworks!
This is pretty bad, isn’t it?
Yeah.
Sorry for the late analysis.
Here’s a follow-up.
The new Ultra Beast’s name
is Denjumoku.
Denjumoku?
The Glowing Pokémon Denjumoku is,
as you can probably see, an Electric type.
It absorbs electricity and uses it
to fire powerful shockwaves.
Be careful.
Mother,
why is this happening?
They’re engaged in a full power
performance battle.
Zugadon and Denjumoku...
...have presumably never met anyone else
with performance skills that match their own.
So they’re rivals?
Of course neither of them
would want to lose.
If their performance
keeps escalating,
there’s no telling
what could happen.
We must send them back to their own world
as quickly as possible.
Agreed.
But the air pressure is
repelling our Ultra Balls!
Oh!
I have a brilliant idea!
What?
Fight their performance with
our own performance!
We’ll launch even bigger
fireworks ourselves!
Fireworks... is it?
How?
With help from
Pikachu and the others!
If we combine everybody’s moves,
we can make some really flashy fireworks!
I see! If we show them a performance
flashier than their own...
...we might draw their attention!
And while they’re distracted,
we’ll use this one’s Z-Move to make them flinch!
Lugarugan! I choose you!
Counting on you,
Bakugames!
Let’s do it, Amamaiko!
Let’s do our best, Ashimari.
Snowball, I trust you!
Let’s go!
Super Special Pokémon Fireworks!
Yeah!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Denjimushi! Discharge!
Bubble Beam!
Amamaiko! Magical Leaf!
Lizardon! Bakugames!
Flamethrower!
Gaburias!
Flygon!
Tyltalis!
Great Blaze!
Snowball, use Powder Snow
as a finishing touch!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
Impressive, everybody!
Well done!
I knew you could do it.
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Amazing!
Sparkly Twirl!
I gripped my small palms tight
Great... Shine brighter!
The Pokémon fireworks
are in full bloom!
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
How do you like that,
Zugadon, Denjumoku?
This is our full power
performance!
It’s even more impressive
than yours, isn’t it?
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
Now, let’s go! Lugarugan!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
This is our...
I choose you!
...full power!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Radial Edgestorm!
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
I’m still on the way, I don’t know what’s ahead
If I’m honest, it’s scary
My precious friends, my precious time
We did it!
It worked!
Such power!
It’s all passing by, all fading away
Can I make it someday,
I’ll finish it in a single throw!
to the distant goal from my dreams?
As will I!
Amamaiko!
I want to stick with you and laugh with you
All right!
Denjumoku!
Zugadon!
We Ultra-got you!
You did well, everyone.
Those children have become
quite dependable.
Indeed. That was an impressive solution
to this crisis.
The Ultra Guardians have
successfully completed another mission.
But there’s no telling when
another Ultra Beast will appear.
You will protect Alola’s peace.
Fight on, Ultra Guardians!
However...
The mission was not yet over...
What?!
Well basically...
Event venues from all over
Melemele Island have requested...
Well... That you do that
Pokémon performance again.
Can we do it again?
Do you remember
the order and all that?
We were caught up
in the moment...
What do we do?
It’s a chance to get rich!
What?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Ultra Guardians operated...
...on Melemele Island!
The Fireworks Pokémon Zugadon
is a Fire/Ghost type.
The Glowing Pokémon Denjumoku
is an Electric type.
It was quite troublesome to have
two Ultra Beasts appear at once...
The Ultra Guardians
really saved us this time!
Amazing, Snowball!
I have to keep it up, as well!
I know I can realLilie do it someday!
Next episode
seiza
Today’s lesson is on constellations.
Sitting on your knees?!
I know of the
Kyukon Constellation!
Did you know there’s
a Denjimushi Constellation?
I wonder if there’s
an Amamaiko Constellation?
Ah! Rekkuuza!
Huh?! Where?!
What have you
been doing all this time, Kaki?
Well, sir, I’m sitting on my knees!
seiza
My legs are killing me, though!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Meteno and Bebenom,
A Promise Faded Into the Starry Sky!
Kaki, not that kind of “seiza“.
Next time
Meteno and Bebenom,
A Promise Faded Into the Starry Sky!
My legs!