Alola!
I, Māmane, am in charge of
presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Iwanko
Nyabby
Alolan Digda
Togedemaru
Who’s today’s featured Pokémon
who looks up to Dugtrio?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Awesome!
The place is packed with excitement.
This is my first concert ever!
Stay close to your big bro, okay?
Here we are!
Alola!
Alo— Huh?!
What’s going on?!
Oh, these? They’re just wigs.
You gotta have them if you’re going
to a DugLeo concert!
DugLeo?
The band performing today?
Yup! Dugtrio with DJ Leo...
DugLeo for short!
Those are wigs?
They’re not wigs-roto!
Dugtrio: Alolan Form.
Mole Pokémon.
Ground/Steel type.
These Pokémon are cherished in Alola,
where they are called emissaries of
the goddess of the land and her siblings.
Their shining gold whiskers
provide them with protection.
What?! They’re whiskers?!
Incidentally, its pre-evolution Digda
looks like this-roto.
Huh...
Digda just has three whiskers?
Look at this!
The one with long hair is Jessica!
The one with the bob cut is Ashley,
and the one with the perm is Michael!
And then this guy is DJ Leo!
I see! Everyone’s cosplaying as
their favorite Dugtrio, huh?
I’m on Team Michael!
Huh? Since when?!
Well, I got hooked pretty recently.
You guys should join us, too!
All right!
Me, too!
I won’t.
Come on, Kaki!
You just gotta go with the flow, Kaki!
Big bro... I’m joining in the fun,
but you won’t?
I’ll do it...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Here’s a Real Shocker!
A Dugtrio Split-Up?!
You all look great!
Really? You flatter me...
By the way, Rotom,
isn’t that costume...?
Resolution rate: 100%!
Alolan Detective Rotom’s deductions
never miss the mark!
You missed the point
of the wigs, though...
Well, so what? It’s all for fun!
That’s right-roto! Fun-roto!
I’ll dress how I want-roto!
I don’t want you
criticizing my choices-roto!
What was that?!
Hey, hey...
Come on over!
Would you like some wigs
for some fabulous cosplays?
We’ve got all kinds of wigs;
stylish, cute and everything in between!
Buy three for a 50% discount,
only today, meow!
Hey, Nyarth! Didn’t you say we could
“kill two Poppo with one stone”...
...by selling wigs and
scouting out the headliners?
We’ll only be killing one Poppo
if we can’t sell any wigs!
Maybe they only want blond wigs
like I thought, meow...
Then why didn’t you set it up
like that in the first place?!
You were the one saying that
selling a wide variety would be better, meow!
Oh, look, a shooting star!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, audience!
Alola!
Feel the shouts of the earth’s divas
and her brother!
Receive Alola’s love and prayers!
Brought to you now by...
DugLeo!
One more!
Okay! It’s showtime!
That Dugtrio is pretty cool, yeah?
Yeah! With that one, we could make a killing,
and our operational budget would skyrocket!
Continue scouting, meow!
Yeah!
That was the best, yo!
Both DJ Leo and Dugtrio
were so cool!
Aren’t you glad we came?
I waved my arms way too much...
My joints are gonna hurt tomorrow.
I’ve decided!
I’ll be a DJ when I grow up!
What’d you think, Kaki?
What’s up, big...
Huh?!
I... I...
I cannot hold back this
torrent of emotions!
Their marvelous melodies
praising the nature of Alola...
...made dreams, hopes and the like
pour on my heart like waves,
washing it completely clean!
This will be my second most
precious possession, after my Z-Ring!
You liked it that much-roto?
My wig!
Hold it!
There’s been a crime-roto!
Iwanko, catch it!
Great job, Iwanko!
Thank goodness-roto.
Why, if it isn’t a Digda!
Why’d it run off
with Rotom’s wig?
It got away!
Hey, now...
This place is off-limits to outsiders.
DJ Leo!
We’re sorry.
There’s a perfectly good reason why...
Huh?
Could you be... Kukui?
Um... Yes, I am... What of it?
I knew it! It’s me, Leo!
Go on, take a seat.
Friends of Kukui
are always welcome!
Thank you for having us.
So you’re the Professor’s
childhood friend, DJ Leo?
Yes!
Amazing!
But you really have changed.
I didn’t recognize you at all
during the concert.
I don’t blame you.
Nobody’s more surprised
about my change than me.
My life changed
when I met Dugtrio.
I was pursuing a career in music,
wanting to put my gratitude towards Alola into song.
But I was lost... Both in my musical direction,
and literally lost in the forest.
What’s this voice?
It was as if they had put the blessings
of the earth itself into song.
We became fast friends,
started playing together,
and so DugLeo, or more specifically,
DJ Leo, was born!
I see.
The Digda from before!
It seems to really love Dugtrio.
Yeah.
Digda is singing!
Amazing!
I see. If that’s what Dugtrio wants,
I’m all okay with it!
What’s going on?
This Digda just became
Dugtrio’s apprentice!
Wow...
Was that why it wanted Rotom’s wig?
I get it!
Rotom Index Feature
Expansion: On!
Obtained voice sampling
feature-roto!
I must thank DJ Leo!
What?
Now you match Dugtrio!
That’s mine-roto!
Now, now...
I’ll buy you another one.
Then I can let it go-roto.
You must be happy, Digda.
Thank you for today, Leo.
It was really fun!
You’re welcome!
The pleasure was all mine!
Good luck with
the concert tomorrow!
I will come see it, I promise!
Thank you. I’ll be waiting.
See you later,
Digda and Dugtrio.
Now let’s start the lesson
to prepare for tomorrow!
Very good! One more!
Hey, hey! What’s wrong,
everyone? One more!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
You have to stop fighting!
Oh, no...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Dugtrio
..                  (Alolan Form)
Type:   Ground/Steel
It seems they’ve gotten into a fight
about who’ll sing in the middle, meow.
A battle for the center stage, eh?
We can nab Dugtrio!
Now get the chance!
Now come on, everyone!
Make peace!
Hello there!
How do you do?
Who are you?
We’re from a famous music agency.
I’m the manager.
I’m the producer.
Yo! DJ Charm speaking, me-yo!
What does a famous music agency
want with me?
Oh, come on! Isn’t it obvious?
We’re here talent scouting!
Our agency would very
much like to hire your Dugtrio!
What?! What are you saying?!
Dugtrio and I are...
Yo! Come with me, and... yo!
I’ll make sure, yo! All three of you, yo!
Get equal, yo! Time in the spotlight, yo!
Dug, dug, dig it, yo!
That settles it, yo!
Don’t worry.
We’ll treat your Dugtrio well!
Wait just one moment!
We’re supposed to perform tomorrow...
Now, if you’ll excuse us...
Dugtrio!
How can this be...?
DugLeo’s disbanded?!
You’re kidding!
What will become of tonight’s concert?
The sudden news of their disbanding...
got all of Alola consumed by sadness.
And that includes me!
Now back to our
regularly scheduled programming!
It’s just been one night...
What could have happened?
They left with some people from
a famous music agency?!
It’s my fault...
I knew they all wanted to be
in the middle while singing...
That’s why they...
Leo...
I wanted to stand on stage again,
as part of DugLeo...
Well then, you gotta let them know
how you feel!
What? But how?
Let’s go see Dugtrio!
But the only info we have is that
they went to “a famous music agency”...
In that case...
Remember this scent, Iwanko.
Find Dugtrio!
Let’s go!
Wait-roto!
They’re around here?
Charm, charm, yo, yo, yo!
Our friendship dazzles the stage!
DJ Charm bursts on to the stage,
gonna put all other acts to shame-me-me-me-Menokurage!
Clean your ears, heads up, listen close!
It’s the birth of DugCharm, yo!
Thank you!
Yay! Good going, DJ Charm!
”What happened to all three of us
getting equal spotlight?”
All three of you get equal billing
as my backup choir, yo!
Give it up, me-yo!
You don’t have time to slack off!
The four of you will
perform on stage together,
and make us tons and tons of cash
to fund our operations!
That’s enough!
Team Rocket!
So it was you all along!
Well, yeah. What of it?
Dugtrio!
Please, give them back!
Not a chance!
In fact, now we’re gonna
get Pikachu, too!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
Iwanko! Bite!
Mimikkyu!
Use Shadow Ball on Pikachu!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Hold it!
We’ve kidnapped, or rather, Pokénapped
a precious hostage, me-yo!
That’s right! So if you care at all
what happens to these guys, then...
Hey, you!
What have you done?!
Get them, Mimikkyu!
You go, too, Hidoide!
That’s Dugtrio’s ability,
Curly Hair!
Now, Leo!
Have them use Tri-Attack!
All right, Dugtrio...
Tri-Attack!
Awesome!
And then use Iron Head!
Dugtrio, finish them off
with Tri-Attack!
Show them the earth divas’ groove!
What? What?!
Huh?
What even is this feeling?
Satoshi, thank you for
helping Dugtrio!
And you, too.
Jessica, Michael, Ashley.
Will you sing with me again?
All right! Now we’ll get to see
DugLeo’s cool concerts again!
But what will you do about
the “who gets center stage” issue?
Oh, I have an idea for that.
Thank you for coming today to see DugLeo,
or as we’re now known;
Dugtrio & Digda with DJ Leo...
DigDugLeo for short!
We’ve reached the last song,
but let’s keep living it up ‘til it’s over!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah! This is DigDug!
Yo, yo, yo!
Amazing! Look at Dugtrio!
They’re spinning around!
Now all three of them
get center stage!
Good job, Leo!
The Tri-Attack inspired you, right?
Leo, Leo!
DigDugLeo has reached new heights
thanks to the addition of Digda!
The groove they play...
...will echo throughout Alola
forevermore!
Thank you!
, Yo!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Alolan Digda!
DigDugLeo was the best, yo!
Alolan Dugtrio is
a Ground/Steel type.
Fallen pieces of their golden hair-like whiskers
are considered sacred.
So they say a curse will fall upon you
if you try to take any away from Alola!
We’ve reached the last song,
but let’s keep living it up ‘til it’s over!
Next episode
I wonder what Satoshi is up to...
He’s so lucky, getting to study
and practice battling with Pokémon.
Bari-chan, I choose you!
Go! Super Ultra Gigantic Hyper Peak!
Blazing, Grinding, Sparking Beam!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Alola! The First Visitation Day!!
Next time
Alola!
The First Visitation Day!!