Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Mantine
Samehada
Laplace
Namakobushi
Which Ride Pokémon
do we ride today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s another peaceful day
at the Pokémon School.
Satoshi and the others are
getting ready to go home.
Holidays start tomorrow!
What are we gonna do?
There’ll be an amazing fireworks show
here on Melemele Island!
Let’s all go see it together!
I have an announcement!
Actually, we’ve got visitors today!
Alola!
It’s been a while, you guys!
Have you been doing well?
Kasumi!
Takeshi!
Alola!
Didn’t expect that, did you?
The surprise was a success!
So cute!
You must be Sandy!
I’ve been dying to meet you!
How do you know about Sandy?
Ever since we went to Kanto,
Kasumi and I have been writing to each other.
So, we came to hang out
while you were on break.
Then what about Hanada Gym?
I left my sisters in charge.
We’ve had so many
challengers as of late.
I need a break
every now and then, you know?
I wanted to see the
Pokémon Centers in Alola.
It really shows that you’re a Pokémon Doctor!
You’re so passionate about your research!
I’m still just a
doctor in training, though.
That said, we’re planning to
have loads of fun while we’re here!
Please take us to all the cool stuff
there is to see in Alola, guys!
Of course! Especially after you
took such good care of us in Kanto!
There are so many places
I want to show you!
I’ll gladly show you around!
All right!
I’m getting hyped up!
Me, too!
I’m counting on you all.
Well then,
let’s go sightseeing in Alola!
Yeah!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Alola, Alola!
Takeshi and Kasumi!!
Alo—
Ms. Joy!
My name is Takeshi,
and I’m a Pokémon Doctor in training!
I was born to meet—
Ow! Owwww!
Yeah, yeah,
let’s leave it at that.
Ow ow ow ow ow!
Oh, excuse us.
He’s just here for a tour.
Ms. Joy!
Something’s wrong with my Youngoose...
It hasn’t eaten anything all day!
Don’t worry...
Let me have a look.
It has a jaw injury?
He saw where the problem was
right away...
I’ll take your Pokémon for
a little while, then.
Please do!
Let’s go, Cuwawa, Happinus.
Um, do you mind if I help?
Can I count on you,
Mr. Doctor-in-Training?
Absolutely!
...So that’s that.
I’ll see you all later.
Sure. Hang in there!
Knock their socks off!
It’s so mild, meow!
It’s melting on my tongue!
It’s about time for
our briefing with HQ!
Um, HQ, do you copy?
This is the Alolan division,
calling for our regular checkup.
Why are you here?
Where’s Matori, meow?
“Everyone’s busy?”
“You probably haven’t done much anyway,
so I might as well take your report myself”?!
How’d you figure that, meow?!
Well, it’s true that nothing’s
really changed on our end.
That’s not true!
Doughnut sales are up since last month, right?
That’s right, meow!
Our latest products have been really well received!
Tell that to Sakaki, will—
Listen until I’m done, meow!
Talk about rude... Well, at least we didn’t have to
listen to another lecture from the bowl-headed four-eyes,
so it’s not all bad!
Why do you look so pensive?
The Alolan Nyarth is right...
We haven’t had any
noteworthy results lately.
It’s possible that the guys back at HQ
are starting to forget we’re even here.
Judging from how they treat us,
they don’t seem to care much, meow...
Huh? So what’s that mean?
Before long, we’ll be forgotten
and tossed aside...
In time, we won’t have our
righteous evil or anything...
We’ll just be some
Honey Doughnut vendors.
Don’t say such scary stuff!
I don’t like it any more than you!
Then there’s only
one thing for us to do!
Nyarth?
We’d better get
some explosive results,
and show some smashing efforts
to the guys over at HQ, meow!
So cute!
What’s this? A Raichu?
It’s an Alolan Raichu.
It’s our mascot Pokémon.
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
Here’s your Raichu Electric Float!
Thank you, darling!
By the way,
those two are newlyweds.
I see!
We’ll keep working hard,
and so will Raichu!
Now, enjoy your meal!
Time to eat!
This jam is great!
Isn’t it? It’s made using
the best Alolan fruits!
They’re all so sparkly and huge!
They’ve all received
plenty of blessings from the sun!
Oh, dear...
Hey, Koduck!
What are you doing?!
I’m sorry! I’m so sorry!
Don’t worry about it.
Go ahead,
take whatever you want.
Thank you!
I’m having this!
Here, Togedemaru, this is for you.
I want this one!
Delicious!
Heart Scale earrings!
They’ve got Pearl necklaces, too!
This is our favorite store.
I can see why!
These pink things
look like Sunnygo!
Do you like them?
Yup!
Come out, my steady,
Sunnygo!
Look at these accessories, Sunnygo!
Aren’t they adorable?
Hmm? What’s wrong?
These are made from
real Sunnygo branches.
Just kidding.
Girls sure do love to shop...
Yeah.
Hey, what’s that?
That’s Mantine Surf!
Mantine Surf?
It’s a type of Pokémon Ride-roto.
You can travel around on Mantine’s back,
and ride atop the waves-roto!
Awesome!
You can ride Mantine?
I want to try, too!
Me, too!
Then let’s all go surfing together!
Wanna go to Treasure Island, then?
Treasure Island?
Over there, see?
I went there with Pikachu once.
It was an uninhabited island.
It was super pretty and fun!
An uninhabited island!
It sounds incredibly adventurous!
I’ll show you around!
It’s settled, then!
Let’s go Mantine Surfing
and explore the uninhabited island!
Can you believe it?
We’ve run into the brat boys.
They’ve even got
the OG brat girl with them!
But that sounded real good.
This is our chance to nab
all the Mantine that they’ll be riding on, meow!
I see! And then if we get Pikachu
and offer him up to Sakaki, too...
Our reputation will get
an explosive, mega massive boost!
We’ll be shining like stars
in the organization!
Sounds great! We’ll do it!
Then we’ll use our
newly completed invention...
...to make sure
this plan succeeds, meow!
Mantine, you’re great!
This is nothing-roto!
The real fun in Mantine Surf
comes from jumping-roto!
Jumping!
Sandy?
Amazing!
Sandy, is that Mantine
a friend of yours?
All right! Let’s try, too!
We’ll jump our way
to Treasure Island!
Let’s go, Garagara!
Huntail Spiral!
Sandy! Ashimari!
Go!
Ashirène Twist!
I challenge you, Satoshi!
Bring it on!
Starmie 720!
Koiking Splash!
You’re all doing wonderfully!
This is great!
Yahoo!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Mantine
Type:   Water/Flying
Almost done...
And that’s it. You did well.
How wonderful!
Oh, it was nothing...
This fur coat and your noble stance...
You’re positively enchanting!
That?!
So this is Treasure Island!
You can all stay here and play!
My friends are up ahead!
C’mon, this way!
Oh, Satoshi...
Abuly! Aburibbon! Butterfree!
And Cuwawa, too!
What do you think, Kasumi?
...What?
Bugs bug me!
Oh, dear...
What are you searching for?
Well, last time I was here,
I met some...
There they are!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
It’s a flock of Nasshi!
Hey! Long time, no see!
Those were
the friends he mentioned?!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
We’re so high up!
This is pretty shaky!
We need to hold on tight.
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
Nasshi!
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Feels great!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Let’s go!
Now swim, future hero, and cross the vast waves
How do you like that?!
There!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
You got me!
It’s your adventure which only you can picture
Ashimari!
Use a gentle Bubble Beam!
I know you’ll be all right!
Pathetic and lame...
Obstinate and weak...
But in your eyes,
a single flame is blooming
What’s up?
Nothing. I was just thinking
that this is nice.
You mean the sea?
Well, Alola itself, I guess.
Just being here is
so incredibly relaxing.
Good to hear.
Well, then...
Time to head back, I guess!
What?
Are the mountains enraged?!
It came from where the Mantine are!
You kept scuttling about.
Cornering you was a real pain!
But it was worth it!
We caught every single Mantine, meow!
Hey! What are you doing?!
When asked
“Hey! What are you doing?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket!
You’re causing trouble
here in Alola, too?!
Doesn’t matter where we are!
We’ll go anywhere for Sakaki!
Our plan is flawless!
First we gotta take
these Mantine and...
Next up is our main goal, Pikachu!
As if! Pikachu, 100,000 Volts!
Let’s go, too!
Garagara, Bone Boomerang!
You think we're playing around?
What an insult!
This Nyarth Robo Giga Mk.03...
...is a cut above all our old robots!
We’ve used the data from all our previous failures
to strengthen its defenses to the max, meow!
You’d better just surrender
while you still can!
Sandy!
You did your best, Sandy.
We’ll try, too!
We’re gonna save the Mantine!
Yeah!
Then leave it to the world’s greatest beauty,
the tomboyish mermaid!
Go, my steady!
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
What are you doing, meow?!
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
Satoshi! Now!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Sandy, Desperate Tackle!
Ashimari, Aqua Jet!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
We’ve got a trump card we can use
even if we can’t move, meow!
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
Team Rocket Punch!
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
Amajo, Tropical Kick!
There’s no way to know for sure
Garagara, Iron Head!
If things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
All right!
Go!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
Amajo! Magical Leaf!
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Our perfect plan!
How could you do that?!
Our future’s on the line here!
Be quiet!
You’re meessing with
my hard-earned vacation!
Feel my wrath!
Strongly, valiantly, beautifully!
My blue sweetheart!
Someone was singing that “Your dreams will someday come true”
Mega Evolution!
Just like how buds will eventually blossom into flowers,
You gotta be kidding!
dreams will eventually come true
Mega Evolution?!
That’s cheating!
We can’t have you doing that in Alola!
There’s no way to know for sure
This is our full power!
if things will always work out
Sparking Gigavolt!
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Dynamic...
...Full Flame!
Super Aqua Tornado!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
A heaping pile of moves!
It’s a finishing move festival, meow!
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Look! It’s holding strong!
It’s resisting all of these moves!
It’s our latest model, after all!
This’ll finish you!
Gyarados, Hydro Pump!
Hey, it didn’t work!
We made it pretty far, though.
Curse you! This is not
the last you’ll see of us, meow!
Well then, all together now...
Ready, and...
What an awful feeling!
Alola sure is nice.
This makes me want to know
more about the place.
Doesn’t it? There’s still loads of places
I wanna show you.
Takeshi!
Oh, you’re back!
Nice timing!
But why’d you put up a tent?
Since we’re all together,
we gotta do this, right?
Oh, I get it!
You might be
onto something.
Well then, time for a meal!
Hey! Koduck!
Kasumi and Takeshi have
enjoyed a day in Alola.
But their fun time with Satoshi
has only just begun!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting!
We went riding on Mantine!
The Kite Pokémon Mantine
is a Water/Flying type.
If it builds up enough speed swimming, it can fly over
100 meters out of the water from the surface of the ocean.
It’s true!
You were really good
at Mantine Surf, Sandy!
Oh, he’s such a kid...
This is just like him!
Next episode
It was a miracle that happened
one night on a midsummer’s island...
Under the veil of night, I met...
...a yukata-clad goddess.
Before I knew it, the woman illuminated by the
countless moonlit flowers had me spellbound.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Fireworks, the Yukata and the L—
Ow ow ow ow!
Wrong!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Rock-Smashing Passionate Heart! Lychee and Takeshi!!
Next time
A Rock-Smashing Passionate Heart!
Lychee and Takeshi!!