Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Hiker A
Hiker B
Hiker C
Alolan Gorogna
Today’s episode features
Alolan Gorone’s evolved form. Who is it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Ultra Guardians
have assembled-roto!
Alola!
I have a request for all of you today.
A request?
We want you to
investigate Akala Island.
You don’t mean there’s
an Ultra Beast on Akala Island, do you?
No, that’s not it.
You see, there’s a powerful magnetic reaction
centered all around Wela Volcano,
and it’s affecting our
Ultra Aura detectors.
Magnetic reaction...
You mean like between two magnets?
Indeed.
There were just trace amounts
near the crater and the mines at first,
but for some reason,
it’s spread across all of the volcano.
You’re right!
It’s almost reached Ohana Town!
If nothing is done, it will affect
the Ultra Guardians’ activities as well.
That’s why I want you to investigate
this magnetic anomaly.
Understood!
Thank you. Now then...
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Wela Volcano, the Gorone,
the Gorogna and the Hikers!
The Ultra Guardians...
Their mission today is
to investigate Wela Volcano.
What could be the cause
of this magnetic anomaly?
We can’t pinpoint the origin
from the sky.
We’ll have to investigate on foot!
Okay!
So... How do we even investigate
this magnetic anomaly thing?
Seriously?
I borrowed a sensor!
Me, too! Look!
You can use this to find it?
Indeed. We have two sensors,
so it seems more sensible to split into two groups.
You’re right. Satoshi, Māmane and I
will investigate around the mine.
Got it.
Then we’ll look around here.
All right, set off!
We should hurry on ahead, too!
Indeed.
That way!
Recorded!
Let’s have a look...
Oh, hi there!
What was that?
I feel like I’ve seen them before...
Garagara’s really fired up-roto.
This is his homeland, after all.
Garagara!
Don’t get too far ahead!
What?
What’s up, Garagara?
The sensor’s reacting!
What?!
Over here!
Ishitsubute! And Gorone, too!
Gorone: Alolan Form.
Rock Pokémon. Rock/Electric type.
They often get into a scrap over who gets to
eat the largest rocks. Ishitsubute’s evolved form.
Alolan Gorone have
some crazy eyebrows!
That’s a cluster of iron sand-roto.
The ones with the larger, thicker eyebrows
have more authority-roto!
Really...
Look at these magnetic reactions!
They’re abnormally high!
Indeed. Gorone are said to
radiate strong magnetism-roto.
There being so many in one place
would cause a magnetic anomaly, I guess.
But what are they all
doing over there?
What’s this, Pikachu?
Spark Stones!
Spark Stones?
They’re stones found in this area
that are infused with electricity.
Apparently they store up electricity while
hardening under the pressure of the magma.
I did hear that Gorone and Ishitsubute
love eating them, but...
You mean that the magnetic anomaly was caused by
Gorone and Ishitsubute gathering here to eat Spark Stones?
That’s gotta be it! The same thing must be
happening all over Wela Volcano!
What’s wrong, Kaki?
I’ve never seen Gorone or Ishitsubute
gathering around here.
They normally live underground,
like in the mines and such.
They can get plenty of
Spark Stones down there.
So why would they—
Hey, those are Gorone!
What?
Go, Kaiross!
Good! Chase them all away!
Yes! There are Spark Stones here!
Really?
Man, it’s tiny...
We won’t find anything good here.
We should go to the mine, after all!
Yeah.
Hold it!
What do you want?!
Can’t you tell?
We’re digging for Spark Stones.
The Gorone and Ishitsubute
were here first!
It’s not like they belong to them.
What?!
They’re stones that formed
naturally on Wela Volcano.
Which means they
belong to everyone.
Unacceptable!
Will you stop yapping?!
Kaiross! Shut him up!
Use Thrash!
Garagara! Flare Drive!
Kaiross!
We’ll get you for this!
It’s fine now.
They said something about
going to the mines, right?
They might try to
pull the same trick again.
I’ve got a bad feeling about this...
Let’s hurry after them!
Awesome!
These mines are the best!
I’ve got loads, too!
Okay, let’s gather ‘em up!
Yeah!
Hey! This spot looks promising,
doesn’t it?
Those guys are digging for
Spark Stones, too?
Completely unacceptable!
But what do they want to do
with the Gorone’s food?
Sell it!
If you want to know about
Wela Volcano, then leave it to us!
You know something?
There’s been
a Spark Stone boom recently!
Spark Stone necklaces!
Their shocking electricity
will fill you with energy!
But they’re expensive,
aren’t they?
Right now, you can get a ring
with your bracelet for no extra cost!
Wow! That’s fantastic!
And so that’s why rock hunters
searching for Spark Stones...
...started coming to
the Wela Volcano mines.
What?!
They drove the Gorone and Ishitsubute
from their homes and up to the surface for that?!
Utterly unacceptable!
What happened?
I-It wasn’t me!
The road is blocked.
Was there a cave-in?
There’s people in there!
We have to save them!
It’s those rock hunters
getting what they deserve!
Why do they have to cause me
even more trouble?!
No good, huh?
Leave this to me.
Metang!
Metang, clear away that rock!
Awesome!
Great attack, Metang!
Hot!
This makes me want
some ice cream...
This heat might make me
shut down-roto...
The heat from the magma’s
amassed in here.
What is it, Satoshi?
Ready, and...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gorone
..                  (Alolan Form)
Type:   Rock/Electric
Hey, wake up! I said wake up!
What happened?
It was that thing!
It made stuff go boom!
It was like a zapping,
crackling boom!
Speak in words
we can all understand!
We were picking up
Spark Stones.
Then it came flying at us
with a boom!
Flying?
A zapping, crackling boom!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
I-It’s that thing!
It’s back!
A zapping, crackling boom!
Run!
Satoshi, look!
Gorogna?
Gorogna: Alolan Form.
Megaton Pokémon. Rock/Electric type.
It fires rocks charged with electricity.
The things that look like eyebrows and a beard
are actually clusters of iron sand.
It’s too dangerous-roto!
It’s crazy angry!
If we don’t stop it,
this whole place will collapse!
Garagara!
Togedemaru!
Pikachu!
It’s out of ammo right now!
This is our chance!
All right...
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Pikachu!
Togedemaru!
Hang in there!
Metang!
Metang! Fight!
Metang needs to keep it close,
or more Ishitsubute will fly at us!
Fight it at close range!
Hang in there!
Hooray, hooray, Metang!
Go, go, Metang!
Push, push, Metang!
Huh?
Metang...
...has eyebrows?
What’s going on?
The Gorone treat their iron sand eyebrows
as a strength barometer-roto.
So the one with the most splendid eyebrows
is suited to be their leader?!
Now it’s on its head!
Metang is the winner!
All right!
That was a heated battle,
fit for Wela Volcano!
A heated friendship has been born
between those who faced each other in battle-roto!
The magnetic anomaly was caused by Gorone,
who had been driven out of the mines by rock hunters,
gathering up around
the Spark Stones outside.
I see! In that case, I’ll ask to have
the patrols around Wela Volcano strengthened!
Well done, Ultra Guardians!
Patrols, huh?
It might be too much work
for Ms. Junsa alone.
If you want someone to
patrol Wela Volcano...
Then leave it to us!
Leave it to us!
The men who know...
...every nook and cranny
of Wela Volcano!
Their names are...
The...
Hi...
...kers!
What?!
What’s going on?!
I get it. The Hikers could very well
be perfect for this job.
Assemble, Hikers!
The Hikers...
...have assembled...
...to protect Wela Volcano!
I’m counting on you, Hikers!
That’s...
The Gorogna from before!
It’s saying it wants us...
...to catch it!
They got Gorogna!
Gorogna!
Our Pokémon!
A new friend for you, Boobur!
Now Wela Volcano is
back to normal.
The Gorone and Ishitsubute
can eat Spark Stones again, too!
Isn’t that nice?
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thanks for waiting!
The evolved form of Alolan Gorone
was Alolan Gorogna!
The Megaton Pokémon Gorogna’s
Alolan form is a Rock/Electric type.
The electricity-charged rocks it launches from
the protrusions on its back are immensely powerful!
From now on, please keep Wela Volcano safe
alongside the Hikers!
Um...
Oh, hi there!
Say...
You wouldn’t happen to be...
...lost, would you?
Next episode
Beginning roll call!
Our Team Rocket army
is pretty understaffed...
In that case,
we’d better go get tons of Pokémon!
Now get the chance!
Shh! We gotta head out
without Kiteruguma knowing, meow!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Team Rocket and Nuikoguma.
We’ve been found, meow!
Next time
Team Rocket and Nuikoguma!