Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Ashirène
Gaogaen
Ju'niper
Kairiky
Today’s episode features Royal Mask.
Who is his partner Pokémon?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Ever since the Royal Dome
opened its doors,
Royal Mask and Gaogaen are the first
to attain 19 successive victories!
Will this Battle Royal
give them their 20th?!
Battle Royal?
It’s a traditional sport in Alola.
A free-for-all battle
between four opponents-roto.
Really? Sounds fun!
Who can stop this invincible duo’s
winning streak?!
The bell signaling the start of
a fierce battle rings... now!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Burn with Passion, Nyabby!
Down with Gaogaen!!
Now, Kairiky goes in for the first attack!
Next up, Ju'niper and Ashirène
also take aim at Gaogaen!
Ju'niper evolves from Mokuroh,
Ashirène from Ashimari,
and Gaogaen evolves
from Nyabby-roto.
Awesome!
It’s a super deluxe battle!
Kairiky! Bullet Punch!
Ashirène! Fleeting Bubble Aria!
Ju'niper! Shadow Stitch!
Gaogaen shows off
its fearsome toughness!
Its opponents’ moves
didn’t even make it flinch!
So strong!
Gaogaen, let’s go!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the ring ablaze
with the flames of victory!
Hyper Dark Crusher!
It’s over! Gaogaen is the winner!
It’s their 20th successive victory!
Gaogaen is the best!
I’m home!
Welcome home!
Huh? Kukui isn’t back yet?
To all the trainers watching at home!
Tomorrow, you’ll be given a special chance
to challenge me and Gaogaen!
What?! All right, we gotta try this!
He’s so cool, isn’t he?
You know him?!
I love Royal Mask!
We’re looking forward to
a heated battle!
Well then, everybody...
Enjoy!
This is the Royal Dome?
It’s huge!
Hey, Satoshi!
Over here!
Guys!
Welcome!
Welcomeow!
Would you like some
Kiteruguma brand Honey Doughnuts?
We’re not selling anything today...
Nothing at all, meow...
Excuse me!
Is there anyone here
who can be the MC?
Our regular MC is sick,
so we need a substi—
Us! We have plenty of MC experience!
Just for today, we’ll work at
an ever-so-slight discounted price!
Ta-daah!
There it is!
Enjoy!
You look just like him!
What’s that?
You don’t know about Royal Mask?!
He wears a mask just like this.
He’s super cool!
I’ve been a fan of his all my life!
His Gaogaen is amazingly strong!
We’re gonna battle them today,
for sure!
Why does he wear a mask, I wonder?
Is he really that set on
not letting people see his face?
Maybe he’s just shy?
His true identity is a mystery...
That’s what makes him so great!
Dear audience members,
we’re sorry to have kept you waiting!
Today is a special day
at the Royal Dome!
A Battle Royal between
Royal Mask and all of you!
Then let’s call on him!
The man they call the Battle Royal evangelist!
Royal Mask!
Enjoy!
Everybody!
Do you want to battle me?
Yeah!
Well then, let me introduce my partner...
The hottest burning flame in all of Alola:
Gaogaen! Come on!
There it is!
The unmatched brawler, Gaogaen!
Witness Royal Mask’s
burning soul, right here!
Gaogaen. Heel Pokémon.
Fire/Evil type.
Nyabby’s final evolution.
It has an organ on its navel that spews fire,
and its waist is covered in flames.
This is called its Fire Belt.
Fire Belt? Awesome!
Any trainers who want to battle Royal Mask,
raise your hands!
Here! Here!
Pick me! Here! Here!
They’ve trained hard...
They’re not to be taken lightly.
That’s them! That’s really them!
Hey, Nyabby!
Oh, what’s this?
This little one is...
The honch—
Why, hello there, little Nyabby!
Sorry!
The brat b—
Nyabby! You shouldn’t be down here yet!
Let’s get back!
Th-This is quite the event!
Nyabby’s stormed into the ring!
What’s wrong?
Are you interested in Gaogaen,
little Nyabby?
Um...
I think he’s wanted to battle Gaogaen
ever since he saw it on TV.
Well, this is quite the honor!
Very well! Step up onto the ring!
You will be the challengers
in our first round!
Are you sure?!
All right! Nyabby,
this is all thanks to you!
Did you come here on your own?
No, I came with my friends!
Then call your friends here, too.
We need two more to have a Battle Royal.
Well then, let us introduce
the three challenger Pokémon!
Nyabby the go-getter!
Garagara the distinguished!
And Denjimushi! All aboard!
Oh, and it looks like a cute little Royal Mask
is among the challengers, too!
I feel kinda nervous...
Tonight’s announcer is
yours truly: Fire Kojiero.
Freezer Moosa and Thunder Nyatare
will be providing the play-by-play.
Well then, let’s explain the rules.
Sure, meow!
Battle Royal is a traditional Pokémon Battle style
with a long history in Alola.
Four Pokémon Battle at once,
and the last one standing wins, meow!
This really gets you fired up, huh?
All of you, come at me!
Let’s do this, Nyabby!
Use Scratch!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
Denjimushi! Discharge!
It didn’t even feel the three’s attacks!
It’s so strong! I want it!
They failed!
Even when it was three on one!
Those really are the hottest
burning flame in all of Alola!
Go! Shadow Bone!
Shadow Bone was deflected!
What a great sound that made!
I will show you all my special move!
DD Lariat!
Here it comes!
Gaogaen’s DD Lariat!
Oh, my! It’s spinning around!
A-Awesome...
Thank you for the DD Lariat...
What’s this? Nyabby withstood
the finishing move, DD Lariat!
All right! Well done, Nyabby!
You’re angry?
Oh? So you figured out that
we were holding back?
What’s this? Some sort of trouble?
That’s right, this is a battle.
There’s no point unless you go all out!
Right, Nyabby?
So you’re going all out, Gaogaen?
In that case, I’ll go into serious mode myself!
Go, go, Nyabby!
We’re all here for you!
Nyabby! Nyabby! Nyabby!
Wow! The Royal Dome is filled with
cheers for Nyabby!
Nyabby’s the star today!
Wow, the tension keeps rising!
Nyabby!
Everybody’s cheering for you!
Let’s do this!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
It got bigger?!
Nyabby, use Fire Fang!
Grab him, Gaogaen!
Nyabby!
Nyabby, why did you
want Gaogaen to go all out?
Are you trying to become stronger
by battling an opponent far above your level?
Hell Thrust!
Nyabby!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gaogaen
Type:   Fire/Evil
Nyabby must be frustrated.
It was over in a single blow, after all.
That Hell Thrust had been
powered up by Build Up-roto.
But he did his best.
He just picked the wrong opponent.
That was Gaogaen going all out!
One loss, and he’s acting like
it’s the end of the world...
I wish he’d learn something from us!
Honcho, you can win, meow!
I believe in you, meow!
Anyway, we got plenty of cash
outta this, so...
Let’s go home.
Nyabby’s primal instincts might
have been stimulated.
Primal instincts?
Another way to put it would be that
his wild side awakened...
...after meeting
his fully evolved form, Gaogaen.
Hey, Nyabby!
Let’s challenge Gaogaen again!
We just have to make your flames
burn even hotter than Gaogaen’s!
I see!
A new move!
These might be movements
for Nitro Charge-roto!
Nitro Charge, huh?
Nitro Charge is a move that
increases the user’s speed every time it’s used-roto.
If he can pull that off,
he won’t get caught by Gaogaen anymore-roto!
So that’s what you meant, Lugarugan?
All right! Let’s all do
some special training!
Let’s go learn Nitro Charge!
Just standing around waiting
won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl
all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing,
naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere,
it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on
and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you!
(For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you!
(Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint
with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage
will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul,
give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Not yet! One more try!
Let’s go! Use Nitro Charge!
So close! We’re almost there!
This is less of a Nitro Charge and...
more of a Simmer Charge with low-heat flames, I guess...
No way...
Hard at work, I see!
Enjoy!
What?!
Royal Mask?!
Why?!
Well, I was out jogging, you see!
I happened to spot you,
so I came to see what was up!
Well?
Would you like a rematch?
Gaogaen VS Nyabby!
What?
All right! Let’s do it, Nyabby!
Are you sure-roto?
You haven’t perfected Nitro Charge yet-roto!
We just gotta do it!
After all, Royal Mask is right here!
Please!
Come at me!
Time for a super serious
all-out battle!
Let’s go, Nyabby! Fire Fang!
Counter with Hell Thrust!
Already?!
Hang in there, Nyabby!
Don’t lose, Nyabby!
Use Ember!
No use!
Cross Chop!
Nitro Charge!
It’s still just a Simmer Charge!
Another Nitro Charge!
The flames are bigger than before!
It’s an Medium Simmer Charge!
Stop him!
You still need work.
I know!
Me... Nyabby...
Lugarugan... Mokuroh... Even Pikachu...
We still need to work harder...
But we’re gonna keep on
getting stronger!
Isn’t that right, everybody?
So, Nyabby, don’t lose!
You’ll get stronger!
Show them your serious flames!
Here it comes!
No way!
You evolved?!
This is...!
Nyaheat. Fire Cat Pokémon. Fire type.
Nyabby’s evolved form.
The sack of flames on its neck rings like a bell
whenever this Pokémon spits fire.
Awesome, Nyaheat!
Now it’s getting interesting...
DD Lariat!
Let’s go, Nyaheat!
Nitro Charge!
It worked!
A High-Heat Simmer Charge!
Um, it’s called Nitro Charge.
We’re not done! Nitro Charge!
H-He’s fast!
Gaogaen, grab him!
Amazing! He dodged it!
He keeps getting faster and faster!
Go!
DD Lariat!
How’s that?!
So hot! You’re on fire,
Satoshi! Nyaheat!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
Hell Thrust!
Nyaheat! Nitro Charge!
Nyaheat!
Hang in there, Nyaheat!
You were so cool, Nyaheat.
Your flames have gotten way stronger!
Well done, Gaogaen.
That’s why you’re my partner!
I guess you’re right,
little Nyaheat.
Starting today,
you and Gaogaen are rivals!
When we meet again
at the Royal Dome,
we’ll enjoy it to the fullest!
You’re so lucky, Satoshi.
I wish I could meet Royal Mask, too.
Don’t you, Kukui?
Huh?!
Oh, yeah, I guess...
Nyabby has evolved into Nyaheat.
Who could Royal Mask, who offered such
passionate yells of encouragement, really be?!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
Royal Mask’s partner was Gaogaen!
Nyabby’s final evolution, the Heel Pokémon Gaogaen,
is a Fire/Evil type.
But man, Royal Mask’s Gaogaen
was crazy strong!
Nyabby evolved and fought hard,
but he couldn’t win...
What’s this?!
N-No, you see, that’s...
Professor, you have a mask too,
just like Māmane!
Y-Yeah, that’s it!
Next episode
Who’s this Pokémon?
I know! It’s Nagetsukesaru!
Well then, what are
its defining traits? Satoshi!
Correct! I’m impressed
that you knew that!
Huh?
Really?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Satoshi and Nagetsukesaru!
A Touchdown of Friendship!!
Hey, this is bizarre, right?
Yeah!
How can they be having a conversation?!
Next time
Satoshi and Nagetsukesaru!
A Touchdown of Friendship!!
Yeah!