Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Lilie running away from home
Kaki’s birthday
Professor Kukui’s wedding
Mamane moving
-
Which of these is the surprise
that happens today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It feels like quite a long time has passed...
...since the day when we went to the Ultra Beasts’ world
beyond the Ultra Hole and rescued Mother.
Mother went through a horrible ordeal,
but she’s recovered surprisingly quickly.
Snowball, we’re finally going back
to the Pokémon School tomorrow.
Are you excited?
As am I.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Thank You, Solgaleo!
Our Nebby!!
Solgaleo!
Solgaleo?
I didn’t get to say thank you...
Pikachu...
Where do you think
Solgaleo is now?
I wonder if it went
through the Ultra Hole...
Or if it’s all on its own,
somewhere in Alola.
Welcome back, Lilie!
I simply couldn’t wait to see you all,
so I rushed over here.
I wanted to see you, too.
How’s your mother?
She’s all better.
Thank you for asking.
All right!
Your mother sure is strong!
Lilie.
Satoshi, Pikachu!
Thank you, Satoshi, Pikachu.
I don’t know if we could have
saved Mother without you.
Suiren, Mao, Māmane, Kaki.
And all of you...
Really, thank you so much!
Wait, Lilie,
you don’t have to thank us!
That’s right!
We help each other out
when things get rough, right?
That’s right, Lilie!
You can count on us again any time!
You do have some pretty great lines
now and again, Satoshi.
They’re growing up well,
using the Stored Power of their friendship.
Alola!
“You can count on us again
any time”, huh...
Satoshi is so cool!
Isn’t he?
I wish I could have seen
their faces back then.
Me, too.
I thought I would have liked for
you to see their faces, too.
Really...
We think alike, don’t we?
I guess we do.
In that case, can you tell what
I’m thinking right now?
I guess it’d be hard to.
No, I can tell!
Really?
Yeah!
Then answer me.
Well...
You don’t know.
Um...
Why don’t you just accept defeat,
my dear Kukui?
No, not yet!
What I’m thinking right now is that—
W-W-Wai—
I choose you!
I guess... I’ve caught you?
Sheesh, Mokuroh...
If you’re gonna sleep,
then don’t fall.
If you’re gonna fall,
then sleep somewhere lower.
I keep telling you, don’t I?
Oh, Professor. Mokuroh fell...
Satoshi, we have
something to tell you.
To tell me?
We wanted you to be
the first to know.
You, Pikachu, Nyabby, Rotom...
Lugarugan, Gonbe
and Mokuroh, too.
You’re getting married?!
The odds of you two becoming happy
by getting married...
Calculating... Calculating...
That isn’t the sort of thing you can answer
with calculations, Rotom.
Married...
The two of you, Professors?!
Awesome! That’s great,
Professor Kukui, Professor Burnet!
Thanks.
Thank you.
They’re getting married?!
How lovely!
B-But that means...
Professor Burnet becomes
Professor Kukui’s wife...
Professor Kukui becomes
Professor Burnet’s wife...
And, and—
Calm down, Māmane.
You just said there’d be two wives.
So, Satoshi, when’s the ceremony
being held?
A wedding ceremony!
A wedding dress!
Exchanging rings!
Tossing the bouquet!
Sounds like they’re
not having a ceremony.
What?! What a shock...
They won’t pledge to
the flames of Wela?
Flames of Wela?
People pledge to the flames
when they get married on Akala Island?
I don’t know if it’s an Akala Island tradition
or if it’s just in my family.
I know!
Hey, let’s all give them a present!
Do you mean we give them a ceremony?
As a surprise!
Sounds great!
I’m in!
I wonder how they’ll react.
The Professor is coming-roto!
Alo...
Something the matter?
Not really...
Y-Yeah, not really...
Not really... Professor.
Not really.
Not... really...
I... see...
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Solgaleo
Type:   Steel/Psychic
We’ll need a list of guests to invite,
a program, welcome cards...
I like this.
That settles that, then.
What about these?
They gotta be white!
Preparations are going well!
The Principal was okay with it!
He said he’ll gladly
serve as the witness!
Kukui is getting married?!
To Professor Burnet?!
Well then, I’ll gladly serve
as their witness!
This is cause to celebratEevee!
Buoysel! Xerneas!
Being the best witness I can be
will be my endeavoRokon!
How about you guys?
Ms. Lychee said
she’ll gladly be there!
You’re giving them a surprise
wedding ceremony as a present?!
That’s wonderful!
A wedding, huh? I see, I see...
I’d like to give them
some sort of present, too.
I suppose a hand-crafted accessory
would be the best...
Or perhaps...
Ms. Lychee!
Are you all right?
I’m just fine! I’ve decided!
I’ll go with that!
She’s all over the place...
Shouting, worrying, tripping, and laughing...
I’m all done, too!
The menu for the day is perfect!
Right?
Of course! I’ll give it my all
for the Professor and his bride!
We’re counting on it!
So, for the wedding cake...
Wedding cake...
I’ve settled on Noa’s
special Alola pancakes!
Now we’ll just have to wait
for the main event!
Hey, Satoshi. Professor Kukui and Professor Burnet
still haven’t caught on, have they?
I don’t think so.
The wedding’s tomorrow, huh.
It’s kinda hard to believe,
right, Pikachu?
You’re not listening...
The Alolan sky sure is beautiful!
I’d have loved to
share this with Solgaleo.
Satoshi.
Gladio!
Great timing! Professor Kukui is
getting married tomorrow.
You should—
I’m just about to
head off on a journey.
Huh?
I intend to face the
Island Pilgrimage.
To challenge the
Trials and Grand Trials.
The Z-Move you and Pikachu used...
10,000,000 Volts!
I can’t just sit quiet after seeing that!
Gladio...
Congratulate Professor Kukui and
Professor Burnet for me.
See you later.
I’ll do the Island Pilgrimage, too!
Next time we meet,
let’s battle again!
Professor Kukui, wake up!
Come on!
What’s up?
School’s off today...
Nothing wrong with sleeping in...
Sheesh... Well, in that case...
Mokuroh!
Wake him up with Peck!
Owww!
All right, I’ll get up!
Mokuroh?! You’re awake?!
What’s going on?
Mokuroh’s not the only one
who’s awake.
Hurry, hurry!
I got it...
Ta-daah!
Alola surprise!
Congratulations, Professor Kukui!
Burnet! You...
The most surprising part
is still coming up, Kukui.
Is this... for us?!
That’s right. A surprise present ceremony
from your adorable little students!
Professor Burnet’s attendant is Gonbe?
Well then, I’ll do the same.
Come on!
So cool!
The Professor’s partner...
...was Warrgle?!
I didn’t know!
Me neither!
Or me!
Data updated-roto!
We are gathered here today to celebrate
the union of Kukui and Burnet!
What’s up, Hidoide?
Looks like somebody’s
getting married, meow.
What, a wedding? Not interested.
Hey, let’s go.
Come on, Hidoide.
Um, the two of them met under
the same Alolan blue sky we can all sEevee.
They care deeply
for one anotheRishan!
As they affirm their undying love,
we wish them lucKametete...
...on this day, when they are
to be weDeathkan!
You may now exchange rings.
As I, Nariya Okido am your witness,
I now pronounce you wife
and grooMassuguma!
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Thank you, everybody!
You may now kiss the bride.
Now, don’t be shy—
Gonbe?!
I’m truly, truly sorry!
Sauboh will be starting from scratch
as Wicke’s subordinate.
When I think of what I did to
Little Miss Lilie and Young Master Gladio...
This is more than I deserve!
I’m so very, very grateful.
Raise your head, Sauboh.
Yeah.
Thank you so much
for your kind words!
Satoshi, everybody.
There’s actually something we’d like to ask of you.
If another Ultra Beast should appear,
we’d like you to cooperate with us.
Mother?
On the other side of the Ultra Hole,
you battled Utsuroid...
That experience is invaluable.
What is “Utsuroid”?
We’ve decided to
give the Ultra Beasts names.
It makes things easier for us,
in several ways.
Utsuroid! Data updated-roto!
Sauboh, show them the documents
on the Ultra Guardians.
Yes, chief!
Have a look at this.
“Ultra Guardians”?
We want you all to join
the Ultra Guardians,
and, whenever Ultra Beasts appear,
we want you to help us capture them.
Capture? What do you mean?
The Alola Region has become more susceptible
to the emergence of Ultra Holes.
We figured that many of the Ultra Beasts
we’ve seen so far...
...have wandered into
our world by accident.
If they do stray into our world,
we’ll return them to their own.
We thought that would be
the best solution.
We want you all to help us with that.
Please, Satoshi. Everyone.
The Ultra Guardians’ activities
are sure to help keep Alola safe.
Keep Alola safe, huh...
I’ll help out!
Me, too!
And me!
I’ll cooperate too!
I agree with them!
I...
I’ll cooperate!
The way you keep going, with a positive outlook,
even after going through a terrible ordeal...
I love it!
Here I go!
Finally, she’s tossing the bouquet.
So exciting!
Legend has it that whoever catches the bouquet
will be the next one to get married, yes?
Here it comes!
All right! I got the bouquet!
Solgaleo!
Thank you, Solgaleo!
Thank you!
Will we meet again?
I’m sure you will.
The Legendary Pokémon Solgaleo
is our own Nebby, after all!
Nebby...
Yeah, you’re right!
We’ll meet again, right?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The happy surprise was
Professor Kukui’s wedding!
The wedding between
Professor Kukui and Professor Burnet!
I’m so glad we managed
to surprise them!
Ever since the sleepover, we girls have been saying
that the two are perfect for each other!
That was unexpected...
But we should be thankful to them.
Anyway, “I choose you”?
What a great line.
I’m glad to be with you.
Likewise.
Next episode
Hey, let’s go out for some karaoke!
Great idea!
Karaoke? What is that?
You sing your favorite songs
with passion!
Choir singing, is it? I love that!
Not quite,
but close enough, I guess.
I won’t lose!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Strong Sleeper: Nekkoala’s Secret!
Next time
A Strong Sleeper:
Nekkoala’s Secret!