Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Akala Island
Ula'ula Island
Poni Island
Aether Paradise
Where does everybody go
in today’s episode?
Blue: Akala Island?
Red: Ula'ula Island?
Green: Poni Island?
Or Yellow: Aether Paradise?
Get the answer at the end!
Your aid is most appreciated,
Golugh.
Here you are, Odoridori.
I wish to show my gratitude for your encouragement.
Does it taste good?
Surely it must!
I have grown these vegetables,
and I am most proud of them!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Research Projects on Poni Island!
Find the Island King!!
This is Poni Island.
What’s this? Satoshi and the others have just arrived,
yet they already seem to be up to something.
Alola! Welcome to Poni Island!
Alola!
My students will be in your care
for the next few days.
You can leave it to me.
Um, Ms. Joy... Is Melemele Island’s Joy
your younger sister?
No, I’m the youngest
of the four of us.
She’s once again over 99% identical
to the other two-roto!
I’m told I’m the cutest
of all my sisters!
You all remember what you’ve
come to Poni Island for, don’t you?
Personal research projects!
Exactly.
Well then, why don’t you all announce
what you decided to work on before coming here?
Sure!
All right!
Māmane, you go first.
I want to evolve Denjimushi!
I heard I can do that on Poni Island!
I suppose you’re heading for
Vast Poni Canyon, then!
Vital information received!
Denjimushi!
Let’s do our best together!
I will polish my skills
in the vast wilderness of Poni Island...
...to overcome the person I am n—
Garagara’s so eager-roto!
I’ll get Poni Radishes to
make a new dish for the cafeteria!
What are Poni Radishes-roto?
They’re incredibly long radishes
native to this island!
They say they’re hard to harvest
without breaking them.
Poni Radishes!
Data updated-roto!
I’m meeting Master!
We made a promise by letter!
Master? You mean I'a
from the seafolk?
You’ve been writing to each other?
Yup.
Don’t you want to see Master
and Oshamari again soon?
What’s wrong, Lilie?
Oh, pardon me!
It’s been a while since I was at
the Poni Island harbor...
It just made me remember certain things,
and I must have spaced out...
The last time we were here was
when we went to rescue Ms. Lusamine, right?
I don’t remember
the place at all!
We didn’t exactly get a chance
to enjoy the sights.
In that sense, this could be seen as
our first real experience with Poni Island.
Yes! I want to observe and learn
a lot about the Pokémon here!
That sounds great!
I wanna get started on my research project, too!
What did you choose
to work on?
I’m taking the Grand Trial
on Poni Island!
I’ve cleared Melemele Island, Akala Island
and Ula'ula Island’s Grand Trials,
so this’ll be my fourth one!
I’m gonna clear it, for sure!
Huh? What’s up, everyone?
Um, Satoshi,
I hate to break it to you,
but you can’t
take a Grand Trial here.
There is no Island King
on Poni Island right now.
You didn’t know?
They’ve been talking about it
all the time lately on TV!
“I, the Island King of Poni Island,
“am starting to feel that
my body’s at its limit,
“so while I recognize that
this is selfish of me, I am retiring.”
...So he said.
No way...
I’m afraid you’ll have to
find another theme.
I’ve decided!
Already?
If there’s no Island King here...
Then I’ll just take on a Grand Trial
directly from Kapu-Rehire!
Directly?! I’ve never heard
of anyone doing that!
Don’t go too overboard.
I’ll be fine!
You can just go back home
and wait for me!
He’s right!
Huh?
We’ll be fine on our own!
It’s a personal research project,
after all!
That’s right!
H-Hey, you don’t have to push!
Got it! I’ll go back
to Melemele Island,
and wait for your reports!
All right!
Let’s go explore Poni Island!
Yeah!
You have very lively students,
don’t you?
I’m really proud of them.
Satoshi, are you all right?
Awesome! I guess this is what
they call a “picturesque view”?
Recording! Recording-roto!
Satoshi,
you’re getting too hyped up.
But I mean, we’re exploring!
Not to mention,
I wanna find Kapu-Rehire!
Rushing won’t help you
find it any faster...
Isn’t that Pokémon...?
It’s Golugh-roto!
Huh, so they have Golugh
in Alola, too?
Golugh. Golem Pokémon.
Ground/Ghost type.
It flies across the sky
at Mach speeds.
Removing the seal on its chest
makes its internal energy go out of control.
What is it doing?
It seems to be working
in the field-roto.
That’s one crazy long vegetable...
That could be a Poni Radish!
The thing you’re looking for?
Yeah!
Ms. Joy wasn’t kidding,
that does look hard!
Guess that makes that Golugh
the Poni Radish-plucking master!
Stay out!
Golugh spoke!
Would you be
the Poni Radish thief?
No!
Golugh,
vanquish him with Luster Cannon!
Thanks, Amajo...
Are you all right, Satoshi?!
Vile Poni Radish thief,
I shall punish you!
Hey, wait! I’m not a thief!
I care not for your excuses!
Go, Golugh!
What’s her problem?
Pikachu!
Pikachu, is it?
Golugh, teach them a lesson!
Satoshi!
Pikachu’s at a disadvantage
against Golugh-roto!
I know.
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Your Lightning Speed will have
no effect on Golugh!
Follow it up with
Iron Tail!
I see... You misled me with Lightning Speed,
so you could land a hit with Iron Tail.
You are rather skilled
for a vile radish thief.
She’s so calm...
Who could she be?
Pikachu!
Lightning Speed, then Iron Tail!
What?!
Pikachu!
Good!
Golugh, show them
every bit of your might!
High Horsepower!
Pikachu!
Are you all right?
Pikachu is unable to battle-roto!
Surely now you understand what happens
when you attempt to steal my radishes.
Never come near
this place again!
Satoshi, let’s hurry
to the Pokémon Center!
Yeah.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Golugh
Type:   Ground/Ghost
Thank you for waiting!
We’ve restored your Pikachu
to full health.
I’m glad you’re better,
Pikachu.
Thank you, Ms. Joy!
You’re quite welcome.
But her Golugh sure was tough.
Yeah. She had a Banbadoro, too,
so she might be a Ground-type user.
Oh, could you be
talking about Hāpu'u?
You know her?
Yes. She lives alone
in the radish fields up the hill.
Doesn’t she have any family?
Her parents live close by.
But Hāpu'u refuses to
leave that spot.
Does it hold some strong
sentimental value for her?
That field is where she used to live
together with Mr. Sofu'u.
Mr. Sofu'u?!
The same Mr. Sofu'u who was
my grandfather’s best friend,
and the Island King
before the last one?!
Yes. I understand Mr. Sofu'u
cared deeply for his granddaughter Hāpu'u,
and taught her everything from
growing vegetables to battling with Pokémon.
Her grandfather was the Island King?
So she got her strength
from the old Island King?
Yes, but not only that.
Hāpu'u really hates to lose.
There’s nobody around here her age,
so she’s only ever had grownups
to battle with.
In the beginning,
she’d lose more often than not,
but she kept on challenging them
again and again, until she won.
I get it now.
What’s wrong, Mao?
I guess we shouldn’t have
gone into the field,
but was it really worth
getting that angry about?
She called us “radish thieves”,
didn’t she?
I didn’t steal anything!
Oh, that’s right. Hāpu'u said that someone was
stealing her precious Poni Radishes,
so she’d started keeping watch
around the area.
So she thought Satoshi was the thief?
I told you,
I didn’t steal anything!
By the way,
how do those Poni Radishes taste?
Oh, of course! I still have a few of
the ones I bought a while back left!
Happinus.
These are Poni Radishes.
Are they edible
for Pokémon, as well?
Of course.
Thanks for the food!
It’s...
So...
Spi...
...cy!
You don’t think it’s spicy,
Garagara?!
I’m fine, too. It’s delicious.
It’s an acquired taste,
but you get really hooked on it!
But the Poni Radishes grown at Hāpu'u’s field
are particularly great.
They’re mellow without losing the spiciness,
and really easy to eat!
That’s amazing!
I want some!
Challenging Golugh
with a Pikachu...
That boy had quite the backbone.
All right, Denjimushi and I
are gonna go train!
I’ll come with you.
Thank you, Kaki!
I actually wasn’t sure if I
could do it on my own...
I’m thinking of taking a walk
around the area.
Well in that case, wanna go
check out the market with me?
Suiren, what are you gonna do?
I’ll try to fish up something spectacular
before Master’s ship comes in!
I see! And you, Satoshi?
I’ll go look for Kapu-Rehire!
The training seems fun-roto...
The market sounds fun, too-roto...
Fishing for something spectacular
intrigues me, too-roto...
But with all that said...
Kapu-Rehire intrigues me
the most-roto!
All right, let’s go!
Wait-roto!
It is oddly quiet...
Banbadoro, Golugh,
it is time to go patrolling.
Satoshi,
where are you going-roto?
Kapu-Rehire looks like
it’s a Water type, right?
So it’s probably in the sea.
Kapu-Rehire. Land God Pokémon.
Water/Fairy type.
The guardian deity of Poni,
it can control water.
People say it can create pure water
that will wash away any uncleanness.
It doesn’t show itself
to people very often.
See?
Look, there’s the beach!
Kapu-Rehire! Where are you?
Kapu-Rehire! Let’s battle!
Aren’t those... um...
Odoridori, Mai-Mai Style.
Dancing Pokémon. Ghost/Flying type.
It dances an elegant,
attractive dance.
That was so easy!
Knew ya could do it, Bro!
We got a real haul now,
don’t we?
What we gon’ do with these?
Ain’t it obvious?
We gonna make ‘em dance!
Dance at the entrance to our
Team Skull Paradise, or SkuPara for short!
That’ll make Big Sis happy, too!
SkuPara’s awesome!
Simmer down!
Stop that!
Can’t you tell they don’t like it?!
Y-Yer that kid
from the Pokémon School!
What’cha doin’ here?!
What are you doing here?!
We came to this island
to create SkuPara!
Big Sis told us ta come here!
So leave us alone, will ya?
What are you even talking about?!
Just let them go!
Nope, not happenin’!
If ya got a problem with it, then we can fix that!
Yatoumori!
Zubat!
Dustdas!
I won’t lose to you! Pikachu!
What is that?
That is...
Hold it!
Hāpu'u!
Those are, indeed,
my Poni Radishes.
Moreover, they have been
reduced to such a pitiful state...
No, it wasn’t me!
If so, then why are you here?!
Because Team Skull
were capturing Odoridori!
What?!
They have them in that bag-roto!
I see. This explains all.
It would appear that you
require punishment!
What’s that, kiddo?
Ya wanna fight?!
Banbadoro!
D-Don’t get cocky just
‘cause yer Pokémon’s big!
We’ll show ya just how terrifyin’
Team Skull can be!
Hāpu'u, this is my battle!
Leave it to—
I require no aid!
I am perfectly capable of
punishing this filth on my own!
Ya sure know how to run yer mouth!
Don’t take us for wimps!
Well, bring it, then!
Go, Yatoumori!
Flame Burst!
Zubat! Supersonic Waves!
Dustdas! Venom Shock!
Gotcha!
It took ‘em all like it was nothin’!
What’s this mean?!
Banbadoro’s Defense rises
with every attack it takes-roto!
I-I ain’t never heard
nothin’ like that!
Now it is our turn!
Banbadoro, High Horsepower!
What was that?
She’s kinda... too tough...
One hit...
Roto...
Well?
If you have learned your lesson,
then leave this island!
You numskulls!
Big Sis!
“Big Sis”?
You’re not following my orders at all.
What’re you all playing out here for?
W-We’re not!
We wanted to make the Odoridori
dance for SkuPara!
Quit spouting nonsense,
will you?
We’re done checking out this place.
Let’s get going back.
Oh, wait! Hold on!
Cut us some slack, Big Sis!
You! Halt!
It’s all right now.
Satoshi.
You are no thief, are you...?
Forgive me!
It’s fine.
But never mind that!
Let’s have another battle!
I refuse!
Why?
That has nothing to do with this.
Oh, come on...
Let us return home, Golugh.
I won’t give up, you hear?!
Looks delicious!
Eat up so you can keep doing your best
on your research projects tomorrow!
Dinner time!
Satoshi has met
the strange girl, Hāpu'u.
The research projects
on Poni Island...
...are sure to lead to many more
adventures yet!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you very much for waiting!
The place the Pokémon School children
visited was Poni Island!
Hāpu'u’s Golugh is the Golem Pokémon,
and a Ground/Ghost type.
Some say that ancient people invented Golugh to serve as a laborer.
It’s a faithful companion
to Hāpu'u!
Oh yeah, Suiren.
Did you catch anything good?
Sure did! A Jilanth!
A Jilanth?!
Alternate-color, at that!
Awesome!
Look! A fish print!
We can’t tell if it’s
alternate-color or not from that...
Next episode
What are you?
A sea monster of some sort?
I am the Index Rotom-roto!
Index... Rotom?
Show me your true form!
Stop it-roto! That tickles-roto!
Most suspicious...
Surely you must be the radish thief!
No-roto!
Wait! Wait, Hāpu'u!
There you are,
the radish thieves’ boss!
I am not the thieves’ boss!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
You will face my judgment!
Lugarugan Showdown! Satoshi VS Gladio!!
You’ve got the wrong guy!
Next time
Lugarugan Showdown!
Satoshi VS Gladio!!
The radish thieves’ boss!
I am not the—