Namakobushi!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem, meow!
Tiny Mushroom
Matoma Berry
Grass-Z
Sunnygo Horn
What does the green brat girl get today?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode, meow!
Delicious!
I can feel the mellow sauce spreading,
with an amazing, creamy texture!
What’s this made of?
Just a slight helping of Big Mushrooms
as a secret ingredient!
Really? Quite the rare ingredient.
What’s this?
My own special dish.
Give it a try, Ms. Lychee!
All right, then...
It’s both crunchy and fluffy at once!
What is this? Mochi?
Ta-dough!
Presenting the Fluffy Radish!
It’s made from this!
Wow!
You made something this sweet
from that spicy Poni Radish?
You really know your stuff!
I want to make Aina Cafeteria
the best in all of Alola,
so I’m creating all kinds
of different dishes.
You sure are passionate.
Mao! We’re out of Big Mushrooms.
Could you go get some from Master?
Of course!
Oh, I know.
I’ll bring some Poni Radishes
for Master, too!
“Master”?
That’s right!
Master Yareyutan!
He lives out in the forest!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Mao's Struggle!
The Pokémon Café in the Forest!!
This is Yareyutan’s café,
located in the forest on Melemele Island.
It looks like some
unusual customers are here today.
What’s the deal with
bowl-headed four-eyes?!
She finds something to complain about
no matter what we do!
They sure have it easy back at HQ...
All they have to do is bark orders.
Is “Produce results!”, like,
the only thing she can say?!
Is it too much to ask that they
trust our judgment a bit more?
You’re being too loud, meow!
This is supposed to be a quiet place, meow!
Quit pretending to be
a good boy, Nyarth!
Yeah!
How can we not
complain about this?!
We’re gonna be loud today!
Yeah!
We’ll let it all out!
Um... Ms. Kiteruguma?
You’re here early...
We haven’t even done...
I-I was behaving nicely, meow...
I’m a good boy, meow...
What even is this feeling?
Master, another drink, meow.
It’s finally quiet, meow...
Now I can finally begin my
calming moment of revitalization, meow...
Alola!
Master, do you have any
Big Mushrooms?
I brought some Poni Radish
to share with you!
Here comes another
noisy one, meow...
Team Rocket’s Nyarth!
Be quiet, meow.
I’m off work today, meow.
I simply long for the soothing taste of
Master’s delicious Pile Juice, meow.
Sure your friends aren’t going to show up
to make trouble later?
That’s it! That’s the one I want!
Nagetsukesaru?
Why so surprised, meow?
I didn’t know this place
had Pokémon customers, too.
I’m a Pokémon, too, meow.
Oh, right.
Alola!
Mao!
I came to give back
the frying pan I borrowed...
Welcome, Satoshi!
It’s Ms. Lychee-roto!
Why are you here?
Mao is away doing chores,
so I’m filling in for...
Are you all right?
Just fine, just fine...
I’m not fine at all-roto...
You worry me...
All right! I’ll help, too!
All these customers must be
hard to deal with...
Then quit bothering us
and go home, meow.
I’ll help you!
Here you are.
Coming up!
Enjoy!
Thank you very much!
So, about the Big Mushrooms...
Now it’s Dekagoose.
It’s Junsa’s Dekagoose, meow.
Ms. Junsa’s?
Is it off work today?
Dekagoose always orders
the same thing, meow.
What?
He’s telling you to
give it a try, meow.
Me?
You shouldn’t bother, meow.
It’s too much for you, meow.
All right, I’ll give it a try!
What?!
Dekagoose...
What does Dekagoose like?
Oh, that’s it!
And what would “that” be, meow?
Here you are!
Some delicious Moomoo Milk!
Was I wrong?
Thank goodness!
Oh, my!
How’d you know, meow?!
Thank you very much!
You just got lucky, meow.
What?
Where are you going, meow?
Amazing!
Did you grow all of these?
I didn’t even know
this place existed, meow!
You want me to pick
the ripe berries?
Okay! You got it!
Let’s do this!
What is Master thinking, meow?
Alola! Here’s the Moomoo Milk
you asked for!
Huh? Satoshi? What are you doing?
Kaki! You came at
just the right time!
Just the right time?
What?!
Alola, Kaki...
I see...
Yeah, this one’s definitely good.
Xiemi, don’t eat them.
Anyone could find and pluck
the ripe berries, meow...
That was a mega spicy
Matoma Berry, meow...
Amajo?
What’s wrong?
A herd of Onidrill, meow!
Could they be
after the berries, meow?
Master!
We’ve got trouble, meow!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Onidrill
Type:   Normal/Flying
Hurry, meow! The Onidrill are
going to ruin the orchard, meow!
Master, what are you doing, meow?
Hurry, meow!
Master,
we have some Onidrill customers.
They gave me this!
Oh, my!
What do Onidrill like?
This, maybe?
No?
How about this, then?
I see. Well, this, then!
Okay! Okay!
If they like
Belbue Berries, then...
There! A Duri Berry!
A Belduri Punch!
Enjoy!
They’re really happy, meow.
Why did you mix Belbue Berries
and Duri Berries, meow?
Lilie taught me...
...that Pokémon who like Belbue Berries
also like Duri Berries.
Fresh Green Bamboo Salad!
Here you are!
A pair drink made from sap!
Master’s special
Flower Nectar Spring!
What?! Forest Grampa?!
Welcome!
Wait just a moment!
Here’s your special
Bittersweet Drink!
I’m so glad!
The Pokémon love the stuff
the green brat girl makes, meow...
What a crowd...
Yeah.
Here you are!
Oh, perfect timing!
Please, help us!
Here you go.
W-We are sorry to have
kept you waiting!
Where’d Mao go?
She’s doing some chores
at Yareyutan’s.
We’ve got ten more orders
for Pile Juice-roto!
Ten more?!
I’ve gotta pick up the pace!
Thank you, everyone.
Another ten for Pile Juice-roto!
Mao... Please come home!
Master, another, meow.
Here you are.
You made this, meow?
Yup.
I’m sure it’s no good, meow.
I-It’s delicious, meow!
That’s great to hear.
Welcome...
What?
What?!
Kapu-Kokeko?!
I didn’t know Kapu-Kokeko
visited this place, meow!
You want me...
to make something for Kapu-Kokeko?
No, no, no, I couldn’t possibly!
Amajo... Xiemi...
Okay! I’ll do my best!
Oh oh! Let's go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
What is she making, meow?
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
Please, Cortoise.
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Glug...
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
I still feel like something’s missing...
One more time, please!
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
That might be it.
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
Now, to finish it off!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
It’s done! Thank you for waiting!
This is the Aina Cafeteria’s Mao’s
fully powered dish!
Fluffy Radish Burger!
Looks delicious, meow!
Fluffy Radish made from Poni Radish...
...with extra radish
simmered to the melting point...
Then a slice of fruity Pile Berry...
Topping made from nuts and
a Momon Berry, and then...
A generous pouring of honey
to finish off this daring dish!
A dish sure to stimulate
my stomach, meow...
Eat up.
It’s all gone, meow!
Well? Was it good?
A Z-Crystal?!
It’s gone...
Was this for me?
That Crystal is proof that Kapu-Kokeko
approved of your cooking, meow.
Kapu-Kokeko approved of me?!
All right! I’ve decided!
I’ll make Aina Cafeteria
be just like this place...
A cafeteria where Pokémon
can come and eat, too!
If you’ll serve that Fluffy Radish Burger,
I might want to drop by myself, too, meow.
Oh, I’d completely forgotten!
Thank you!
What?
Isn’t this...?
I’m home! Sorry I took so long!
Mao, welcome back...
What’s wrong, everyone?
There were so many customers...
It was crazy...
You all helped?
Yeah, and because of that,
we narrowly avoided disaster.
I’m sorry...
Here are the Big Mushrooms.
Things were crazy for me, too.
All sorts of Pokémon came
visiting Master Yareyutan’s café...
Really?
Yup! And then,
because I helped out...
I got this!
A Grass-Z?!
And isn’t that a Z-Ring?!
But it looks a bit broken...
Let me have it.
You helping out...
...must have been
Yareyutan’s Trial for you.
Really?
All right, it’s perfect!
Here you go.
I got my own Z-Ring!
That means all of us have
our own Z-Rings, yes?
Now that you mention it...
You did it, Mao!
This really fires me up!
Me, too!
Yeah!
Mao has cleared Yareyutan’s Trial.
Now, at last, everyone has
a Z-Ring of their own.
Next up, it’s time to train
for the Pokémon League!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting, meow!
The green brat girl got
a Grass-Z, meow!
Onidrill is a Normal/Flying type, meow.
It’s a tough Pokémon that can fly all day
while carrying heavy loads, meow!
I must say though, I had no idea
they liked Belbue Berries...
Feels great, meow...
More... Do that some more, meow...
Next episode
It’s time for today’s advice corner!
Hmmm, here we have a message from
pen name “Cool Bespectacled Beauty”...
“I’m troubled by my incompetent subordinates.
Is there any way to get them motivated?”
You should just
fire those mouth-breathers!
That’s right, meow!
N-Now, isn’t that a bit harsh?
Not at all! No point in hiring
those wage thieves!
There! Problem solved!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
You’re Being Watched!
Team Rocket’s Alolan Forms!!
Next time
You're Being Watched!
Team Rocket's Alolan Forms!!
Their real name is...