Alola!
It’s me, Lilie.
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Lusamine
Wicke
Burnet
Lychee
My mother shall make an appearance
in today’s episode.
Which one of these is she?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I just have to go over there?
Got it.
All right, let’s go, Pikachu!
Where am I?!
Solgaleo... Lunala...
I got it, Solgaleo. I promise, Lunala!
No!
I can’t let you outside,
where anyone could see you!
Please,
try to understand!
Yes, good.
Could it be... an Ultra Beast?!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Satoshi and Nebby!
A Mysterious Meeting!!
Satoshi, wake up-roto!
Hurry and get up,
wash your face, eat breakfast,
and go to the Pokémon School-roto!
Pikachu, you wake up, too-roto!
And you, Mokuroh-roto!
I got it, Solgaleo...
He’s still talking in his sleep-roto...
Nyabby, it’s your turn-roto!
Owwww!
Oh? As usual, Professor Kukui’s house
is quite lively in the early hours.
Morning...
Don’t “Morning” me-roto!
You were supposed to be out of bed
two minutes and thirty seconds ago-roto!
Hurry up and get changed-roto!
Sheesh... Couldn’t you wake me up
a little more gently?
If you’d actually wake up from that,
I wouldn’t have to go through all this trouble-roto!
Huh? I feel like...
I might have just had
a really awesome dream...
I promise.
Promise? Well, whatever.
What is it, Professor?
Oh, it’s nothing. I was just entranced
with you all Stockpiling nutrition.
Excuse me for a second...
It’s time for the news-roto.
The Index Rotom does not Stockpile nutrition,
but information-roto!
The Alola Lady Award is presented to the lady who
shines the brightest in all of Alola!
And this year’s winner
is Professor Burnet!
Burnet?!
Someone you know?
She’s a fellow researcher.
This is the fifteenth time
the Alola Lady Award has been handed out.
The prize is given out yearly,
with nominees from a wide variety of fields,
but this is the first time
an active professor has won the award.
The Professor’s skill within her field,
and her sociable personality...
were what clinched
her victory this year, it seems.
V! V!
What an interesting person!
Yeah, she’s something else.
An excellent researcher, too.
She’s right at home in the spotlight.
What is Professor Burnet researching-roto?
Ultra Holes.
Ultra Holes?
Oh, I’ll explain some other time.
The Altar of the Sunne.
The solemn atmosphere here
always overwhelms me.
Don’t you feel the same way, Lusamine?
That’s because this is the place where,
in the distant past, the Guardian Deities of Alola...
...fought an intense battle
with the Ultra Beasts.
Thanks to these ruins,
I was able to picture the legendary battle
which my father told me about when I was a child,
and how it might have played out in real life.
Yes, even today,
I still dream that someday I will meet an Ultra Beast,
even if it’s just once.
I feel romanticism in the air!
The true meaning behind these
sun and moon-shaped objects...
...still hasn’t been
properly deciphered, has it?
Professor Burnet!
Was it true, when last night you said you were getting
strong Ultra Aura readings from this place?
Yes.
It was a very sudden spike,
so I told Lusamine about it.
The current levels
appear to be quite low.
Perhaps that sudden spike
was not caused by an Ultra Beast,
but rather, by your
equipment malfunctioning?
That’s quite
an illogical proposition, Sauboh.
You didn’t reach that conclusion
due to careful consideration as a scientist,
but rather, out of jealousy
towards Professor Burnet!
All right, let’s keep investigating.
Agreed!
This is quite exciting.
Just the mere thought of
getting to meet an Ultra Beast...
I feel romanticism in the air!
“Romanticism in the air”?
Give me a break!
I feel nothing but
disappointment in the air.
How very disappointing...
What is it, Pikachu?
Hey, Pikachu!
Where are you going-roto?!
Hey, wait!
Satoshi!
Satoshi! Satoshi!
What’s going on, Pikachu?
Kapu-Kokeko!
What’s that?
A Pokémon?
Is it sleeping?
It’s light.
Promise...
The promise!
I promised that
I’d definitely find this thing!
Promise?
When, where, and to who-roto?
Last night... In a dream...
Um... to someone.
Does not compute. Does not compute.
Does not compute.
I wonder if it’s dreaming?
I wonder what this Pokémon is called.
You can leave that to me-roto!
This is odd-roto! I have no data on its name,
typing, nor any defining traits-roto!
What?!
Alola!
Where’s Satoshi?
He’s not here yet.
That’s strange.
He left home before I did.
Did he get distracted?
That is possible.
Maybe he’s just trying to
get a Pokémon somewhere?
That could be!
A Groudon could have suddenly
popped out from the ground...
No way.
Professor Kukui!
We met a Pokémon I have no data on-roto!
It’s the one I saw in my dream last night!
I promised someone in my dream that
I’d find this thing and look after it!
And then... And then... Geez,
why do we always forget what we dream?!
Now now, just calm down, Satoshi.
So, where is this Pokémon?
It’s in my bag!
It’s floating...
But it’s still sleeping-roto.
It’s so cute!
It does not seem to be
in any of my books.
Do you recognize it, Principal Okido?
I’ve never seen this Pokémon before either.
It’s quite mysteriouSymboler!
What if it’s a new Pokémon species?
If it is, then Satoshi would be
the one who discovered it!
For real?!
Let’s all investigate this Pokémon carefully.
It sure does sleep a lot.
It’s laughing! So cute!
It’s like a baby!
Nebby...
Nebby?
Oh, its body sparkles,
much like stars,
and yet it’s all puffy and floaty
like a cloud, right?
So it’s like a nebula,
a cloud of stars!
“Nebby” from “Nebula”, huh?
Sounds great!
That’ll be its name!
It’s not a bad name.
I prefer “Purple Sweet Cotton Candy”, myself.
It really is a great name, Lilie!
It suits it perfectly!
That settles it.
Nebby!
Its voice is like getting hit
by Supersonic Waves-roto!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Cosmog
Type:   Psychic
D-Don’t cry, Nebby!
Look, upsie-daisy! Upsie-daisy!
Upsie-daisy!
I leave it to you, Kaki!
Later!
“Leave it to” me?! Hey!
Don’t cry, my little child!
If you cry, the mountain of Akala will cry too!
Back when Hoshi was a baby,
that song would make her stop crying...
Help!
What?! Um...
Good baby, good baby.
Come on, don’t cry...
We’re all friends here! It’s all right!
It cries and laughs...
It really is just like a baby.
Now that Nebby’s in a better mood, let’s try to figure out what it eats.
You can’t really look after it
without knowing that, after all.
Yes!
Anything here you want to eat, Nebby?
How about this?
It’s soft, has a mild taste, and nutritionally speaking,
I think it should be perfect for a baby Pokémon.
I see. Well?
Well then, how’s this?
Sugar candy!
It seems to be interested!
Let’s see...
How is it?
It ate it-roto!
Sugar candies do look
like stars, after all.
It’s the perfect food for Nebby!
It’s quite a relief that you found
something it would eaTamanta!
We’d better start stocking up some
at home, too, right Satoshi?
On the way home, I’ll show you the supermarket
where they sell these sugar stars.
Thanks!
Lusamine! I’m getting
an Ultra Aura response!
On Melemele Island?!
I haven’t been to Melemele in quite a while!
The value only changed a little bit,
but it’s worth checking out.
I feel romanticism in the air!
Good grief...
Thank you, Māmane.
Don’t mention it. See you tomorrow!
Later!
Have a nice day!
Bye!
See you at the Pokémon School-roto!
What’s that?
Welcome back.
I’m home!
We’ve got some guests here.
They say they want to see you.
You, Nebby, and Lilie too.
Me, too?
Mother!
Lilie!
Mother?! That’s Lilie’s mom?!
Long time, no see!
Have you been a good girl?
A “good girl”? Well...
You’re not being a bother
to James, I hope?
You’re embarrassing me, Mother!
Oh, you’re such a shy kid!
I can’t believe you were still a baby
just the other day!
It was not “just the other day”!
Lilie... You can touch Pokémon now!
Such a good girl!
I said you’re embarrassing me!
Lilie has raised Snowball
since she was an egg-roto.
Since she was an egg?!
My little baby...
I am not a baby!
Sheesh! Mother, you never
consider how I feel!
You just push your own feelings onto me!
That’s not what I...
Even that time with Pippi!
Pippi?
There was that time when you evolved Pippi into Pixie
with a Moon Stone while I was not there, remember?
What? Oh, yes...
I wanted to raise it as a Pippi,
but you didn’t care!
But it was my Pokémon.
Besides, your reason for
wanting it to stay a Pippi...
Because it’s cuter that way!
That was illogical!
As far as I am concerned,
that was an entirely logical conclusion!
Lilie sure is a lot more energetic
when she’s with her mom...
Yeah.
And they look just like each other-roto!
Like their hair color, or...
Or how straightforward they are.
P-Professor Burnet?!
So you’ve Forme-Changed into a Pokémon Index.
I’m honored that you know me.
I saw you in the news this morning-roto!
Let me introduce you.
This is Professor Burnet.
She’s involved with the research
of the Aether Foundation,
the organization that Lilie’s mother,
Lusamine, runs.
I’m Lusamine.
It’s a pleasure to meet you, Satoshi.
These two are Wicke and Sauboh.
They’re employees at the Foundation.
Alola! My name is Wicke, and I’m in charge of
looking after the Pokémon in our care.
It’s nice to meet you.
I’m Sauboh, chief of
the research department.
To get straight to the point,
could you let me meet Nebby?
What a sweet little baby!
This one really is an Ultra Beast.
Ultra Beast?
Could you look at this?
It’s Kapu-Kokeko!
A long time ago,
strange creatures from another world...
...fought a fierce battle against
Alola’s Guardian Deities.
Have you heard the legend?
I’ve read about it!
These days, those creatures from the other world
are called Ultra Beasts, correct?
You’ve studied hard, Lilie!
I’m so glad I enrolled you
into the Pokémon School!
You most certainly did not.
I said I wanted to enroll!
Is that so?
Geez!
So Nebby really is one of those Ultra Beasts?
There’s a high chance.
Anything connected to the other world or the Ultra Beasts
is enveloped in what we call Ultra Aura.
In our laboratory, we are constantly
measuring the levels of Ultra Aura...
Wicke.
Sure!
Last night, exceptionally high
levels of Ultra Aura...
...were measured in the vicinity of
the Altar of the Sunne on Poni Island.
And just a few hours ago...
That’s the place!
Satoshi?
What’s the place-roto?
In the dream I had last night, I was there!
And then Solgaleo and Lunala...
these two really cool Pokémon came out of the sky!
And then Nebby came out of the light!
Solgaleo...
Lunala...
President!
The names of the Ultra Beasts who
are spoken of as legends...
They made contact with Satoshi?
It is no more than a dream. Nonsense.
Satoshi!
Please leave Nebby in the care
of the Aether Foundation.
The Aether Foundation...
has both the facilities and the knowledge
to take good care of Pokémon.
You can safely leave it to us.
But...
But?
I made a promise.
I promised Solgaleo and Lunala
that I’d look after Nebby.
So I’ll be the one to take care of it.
An Ultra Beast is much too heavy a burden
for you children, Satoshi.
Sauboh.
Mother.
Satoshi has received both a Z-Ring and
a Z-Crystal from Kapu-Kokeko.
He is an incredibly strong trainer.
From Kapu-Kokeko?
The Guardian Deity of Melemele Island?!
Is that true, Professor Kukui?
Yeah. Satoshi is an incredibly
promising Pokémon Trainer.
He’s already cleared
both Melemele and Akala Island’s Grand Trials.
Then I’ll trust you, Satoshi.
President Lusamine!
I, too, would like to know why Solgaleo and Lunala
entrusted you with this child.
Mother...
But if you have any trouble,
please give me a call.
All right?
Yeah!
It fell asleep again.
It’s got a cute sleeping face.
Good grief... Now we’ve got
another sleepyhead in the house-roto.
And so it was that Nebby, who might be an Ultra Beast,
joined Satoshi and his friends.
What is its true identity?
The answer will have to wait
until Nebby wakes up!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was my mother, Lusamine!
Nebby is a mysterious Pokémon.
Professor Burnet said it might be an Ultra Beast,
but is that really true?
Next episode
Come on over, come on over, meow!
We’ve got an order for a Kiteruguma-brand Honey Doughnuts
drink set with mega cream, nuts, and extra molasses glaze, Alola!
One Kiteruguma-brand Honey Doughnuts drink set with
mega cream, nuts, and extra molasses glaze, coming up, Alola!
Thanks for waiting! Here’s your Kiteruguma-brand Honey Doughnuts
drink set with mega cream, nuts, and extra molasses glaze, Alola!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
“Nebby Panic! Sudden Teleportation!!”
Next time
Nebby Panic!
Sudden Teleportation!!
Alola!