Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Yamirami
Mimikins
Alolan
Persian
Waruvial
Which of these is the final Pokémon
Mr. Kuchinashi sends out today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Is he here?
I knew he wouldn’t be.
You actually act like an Island King
on Grand Trial days.
The lazy Kuchinashi
is nowhere to be found!
Oh, please. I just want the hassle
to be over with as fast as possible.
Going to the Altar
is always a pain...
But I guess it’s not too bad
every once in a while.
All right! Let’s go!
They’re raring to go-roto!
At last, today is the day of
the Ula'ula Island Grand Trial.
Satoshi will challenge
the Island King Kuchinashi!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Kuchinashi's Grand Trial!
Lugarugan Awakens!!
I’ll be the judge.
Satoshi, do your best!
Thanks, Acerola.
All right, let’s get started.
The Island Pilgrimage ritual,
the Grand Trial, is about to begin.
A righteous heart harbors malice,
and a malicious heart harbors righteousness.
May the two blend together
and bring forth further evolution.
If you want to clear the Ula'ula Island Grand Trial,
I’ll need you to take out three of my Pokémon...
But you must do it using
only one Pokémon.
What?! Just one?!
Three on one?!
He has to win thrice in a row?!
That’s unfair-roto!
Not happy with it?
Well, feel free to give up.
Uncle Kuchinashi said a proper Grand Trial
entails overcoming a great challenge.
This’ll be a pretty intense battle.
Are you okay with that?
I accept your challenge!
What a bother...
I thought you’d leave after hearing
it was three on one...
I wanna let Lugarugan get revenge!
Lugarugan’s really motivated, too!
Motivated?
Sure you’re not just projecting
your feelings onto it, kid?
I’m not!
Right, Lugarugan?
But are you prepared?
Prepared to battle at full power,
I mean.
Of course we are!
Guess I have no choice, then.
Let’s do this.
Waruvial!
The opponent Lugarugan
lost against last time-roto!
They’re trying to make him flinch
with Intimidate again-roto!
Seems you’ve grown a bit.
Pikachu, you guys watch
from the back.
We’re rooting for you-roto!
Well, then... The challenger is
Satoshi from Masara Town!
His opponent is
Ula'ula’s Island King, Kuchinashi!
Let the three-on-one
Grand Trial battle begin!
Grand Trial
We’ll be making the first move.
Waruvial! Mud-Slap!
Dodge it!
Sand Hell!
Use Mud-Slap!
Such power-roto!
The results of his training
with Kapu-Bulul are showing!
All right, keep it up!
We’ll win today, for sure!
Then why don’t you show me
a battle worthy of such a boast?
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
Accele...
Waruvial... Counter!
No, Rock Throw!
Another Rock Throw!
Try as you may,
it’s pointless.
Use Bite or Accelerock and
you’ll fall prey to our Counter.
You’re avoiding close-range combat
because you’re afraid, aren’t you?
In that case,
we’ll bring the fight to you.
Use Crunch!
Dodge!
Rock Throw!
What a boring battle.
You’re that scared of Counter?
Guess I had you all wrong.
I didn’t expect you or your Lugarugan
to be this gutless, kid.
Pokémon battles are all about putting our moves
up against each other at full power, yeah?
And you said you were prepared
to do that, right?
Lugarugan...
You wanna fight, huh?
All right! Accelerock!
Counter!
What?!
So fast!
His speed nullified
the Counter-roto!
Let’s finish this! Rock Throw!
Waruvial!
Waruvial is unable to battle!
Lugarugan wins!
You did it, Lugarugan!
Satoshi and Lugarugan
win round one-roto!
Nice work.
So you can do it!
I wasn’t talking to you, kid.
I was talking to Lugarugan.
Still, thank you!
What?
You just said that Pokémon battles are about
putting our moves up against each other at full power.
You motivated me
to keep fighting!
Man, I should’ve
kept my big mouth shut...
They say that lies can be
a tool, you know?
I just wanted to lure you into a Counter.
Didn’t matter how I did it.
Uncle Kuchinashi,
send out your next Pokémon!
Sure.
Let’s go!
So our next opponent is Yamirami!
Yamirami. Darkness Pokémon.
Dark/Ghost type.
When its gemstone eyes begin
to glow with a sinister shine,
it’s feared that it will
steal people’s spirits away.
Begin!
Use Shadow Ball!
Rock Throw!
Shadow Sneak!
Lugarugan!
Attack with Bite!
Shadow Claw!
Use Accelerock!
Mean Look!
He’s been frozen in place
by Mean Look-roto!
What?!
Well then, use Rock Throw!
Rock Throw isn’t working either-roto...
Attack with a flurry
of Shadow Claws!
Lugarugan!
Lugarugan, hang in there!
Use Bite!
Think that’ll reach us?
Now use a flurry
of Shadow Sneaks!
No, Lugarugan! Calm down!
Flurry of Shadow Claws!
Lugarugan! Calm down and
dodge the Shadow Claws!
Take a good look, kid.
Your Lugarugan is
narrowly keeping its vital organs out of harm’s way.
Isn’t it actually stronger when
it’s angry and red-eyed?
But when he’s angry,
he stops listening to me...
You sure about that?
Whatever. Yamirami!
Finish it off with Shadow Claw!
I can’t use Bite or Rock Throw...
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
What?!
Great work!
Yamirami is unable to battle!
Lugarugan wins!
All right! Good job, Lugarugan!
Good grief...
So it’s learned Stone Edge?
That’s two wins
for Satoshi and Lugarugan!
If they win one more match,
they’ll have cleared the Grand Trial-roto!
But...
Lugarugan, are you all right?
Kapu-Bulul?
Isn’t this...
An energy-restoring
Obon Berry-roto?!
Uncle Kuchinashi,
can he use it?
Can’t really defy
the Guardian Deity...
Sheesh... Does that meddlesome Kapu-Bulul
wanna mess up my Grand Trial?
Lugarugan.
Well then, Uncle.
Send out your third!
The plan was to end it
without having to use this one, but...
Looks like it’s
time for it to shine!
So the final opponent is
an Alolan Persian!
It’s as big as
a Totem Pokémon-roto.
I’ll win this Grand Trial!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Persian
.                    (Alolan form)
Type:   Dark
If Satoshi wins this battle,
he’ll have cleared the Grand Trial-roto!
Well then, begin!
Persian, use Power Gem!
Lugarugan, hang in there!
All right! Use Stone Edge!
All right!
You’ve trained it well, kid.
But your Lugarugan could have done that
even without you here.
Actually, wouldn’t it be better off
without you?
Without me?!
Yeah. Your Lugarugan would be stronger,
and be able to keep getting stronger, too.
Why would you say that?!
I’m just stating facts.
A Pokémon has to choose
its trainer carefully, too.
Are you saying
I’m not good enough?!
Yup.
Satoshi, calm down-roto...
Lugarugan has been with me
since he was an Iwanko.
We’ve worked so hard together since then.
Even when he evolved, we...
You don’t get it, do you? Your so-called “friendship”
with your Lugarugan is holding it back.
What do you mean,
“so-called”?!
There, you see?
That short fuse of yours is the absolute worst!
You’re a perfect example of
a worthless trainer.
Why, you...!
Good, good...
Now, Persian. Evil Pulse!
Lugarugan!
He was so distracted
by the Island King...
...that he didn’t
give a command on time-roto!
Don’t lose, Lugarugan!
So it shook off the Evil Pulse
with the power of its rage.
Accelerock!
Evil Pulse!
What’s wrong?
Just shake it off again!
You should be strong enough
to do that!
Evil Pulse!
Why does he keep
using the same move?
Have a look!
Its eyes look real good, don’t they?
Lugarugan!
Not good!
This is terrible-roto!
Lugarugan will go into an
uncontrollable fit of rage-roto!
So you were trying to
make him angry?
If I do that,
it’ll stop obeying you, right?
Having you two self-destruct would be
the best possible outcome for me.
I won’t let you!
Calm down!
You gotta calm down, Lugarugan!
It won’t listen to commands
from a worthless trainer.
I’m not a worthless trainer!
I’m Lugarugan’s partner!
Its worthless partner,
who wants to be its “best friend”...
No!
Persian. Crossroad Kill.
Lugarugan!
You two sure are
perfect partners!
That wasn’t fair!
Do you really think a Dark-type Pokémon user
cares about being “fair”?
They’re a perfect target, Persian.
Dish out some more pain!
Calm down, Lugarugan!
Ow...
Lugarugan?
Lugarugan,
what’s wrong-roto?
Can’t you recognize
Satoshi-roto?!
Lugarugan...
You could hear me?
Your eyes didn’t turn red...
...because you were
blinded by rage.
You were raising
your power...
You’d already learned
to control yourself!
I’m sorry I didn’t notice.
I was a total idiot,
letting Mr. Kuchinashi’s insults get to me.
Your tackle
snapped me out of it.
Owww...
Lugarugan has learned to keep control,
even when his eyes turn red.
Data updated-roto.
All right,
let’s continue the battle!
Back on your feet, huh?
Too bad you can’t win a Grand Trial
simply by getting back up.
Hit them with a flurry
of Crossroad Killes!
End it with the next one!
Lugarugan!
That move was...
Counter-roto!
You learned Counter?!
Interesting.
Didn’t think I’d have to use this.
A Z-Move?!
May the full power of darkness
consume you.
Black Hole Eclipse.
Fight Z-Move with Z-Move!
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
This is our...
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
...full power!
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
World’s End Fall!
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
What?!
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
They canceled out his Z-Move
with their own-roto!
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
Use Accelerock! Go!
There’s no way to know for sure
If things will always work out
Persian is unable to battle!
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Which means this battle goes to
Satoshi and Lugarugan, for winning all three matches!
We won!
Amazing-roto!
You cleared the Grand Trial-roto!
Well done.
Mr. Kuchinashi, sir.
Well, what can I say?
Grand Trial complete, I guess.
Thank you so much!
You did it, Satoshi!
Lugarugan,
you were great, too!
As proof of your victory,
I’ll give you a Dark-Z...
...is what I was thinking,
but you’re not really a “Dark” kinda guy, kid.
Take this instead.
What’s this?
A Lugarugan-Z.
Lugarugan-Z?
An item that’ll let you use
Lugarugan’s exclusive Z-Move.
Awesome!
Take it.
I got a Lugarugan-Z!
What’s that sound?
Kapu-Bulul!
You were watching
our Grand Trial?
Thank you, Kapu-Bulul!
Satoshi! Come hang out on
Ula'ula Island again sometime!
Sure! You should come visit
our Pokémon School sometime, too, Acerola!
Yeah!
That kid sure had some spunk.
Uncle Kuchinashi!
If you were here, you could have at least said bye!
Not really my style,
now is it?
You were so cool today!
It looked like you really
enjoyed that battle.
I couldn’t afford to slack off there, could I?
Took everything I had.
I know, right?
Let’s get even stronger...
...and clear the next
Grand Trial, too!
Satoshi and the others have cleared
their third Grand Trial with flying colors.
Now that they have the Lugarugan-Z,
what sort of battle will they show us next time?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The final Pokémon
Mr. Kuchinashi sent out...
...was Alolan Persian!
The Classy Cat Pokémon Persian’s
Alolan form is a Dark type.
Kuchinashi’s Persian’s Z-Move
was pretty amazing, but...
thanks to Lugarugan’s hard work,
we were able to clear the Grand Trial!
Thanks, Lugarugan!
Come to think of it,
what is Lugarugan’s Z-Move called?
It’s called Radial Edgestorm,
and the pose looks like this-roto!
Huh? Like this?
Like this-roto!
Like this?
Next episode
Ultra Aura detected at Point 806 on
Melemele Island’s southeastern beach!
An Ultra Hole has materialized!
We’re getting an
Ultra Beast reading!
Here it comes...
An Ultra Beast...
Exchange information
with the Alola Police!
Evacuate nearby civilians!
The Ultra Beast has
appeared at Point 806!
It’s an emergency!
A second Ultra Beast has appeared at Point 796!
All right!
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Clash of the Ultra Beasts!
Operation Boom Boom Crackle!!
Next time
Clash of the Ultra Beasts!
Operation Boom Boom Crackle!!