Alola! V! V!
Snip snip snip!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Lunala
Kiteruguma
Necrozma
Solgaleo
Is the Pokémon we call
the Radiant One...
Blue: Lunala?
Red: Kiteruguma?
Green: Necrozma?
Or Yellow: Solgaleo?
Get the answer at the end!
We went through the Ultra Hole together with Lunala,
and arrived in the world Bebenom lived in.
There, we learned that UB: Black,
or Necrozma, has to regain its power,
or else this world is doomed.
So we decided to use our Z-Power
to restore Necrozma.
Then we’ll be able to save
both the Bebenom and Solgaleo!
Heavy Bomber!
Warrgle!
Houdin! Sleeper!
Unthinkable...
In just one hit?!
Warrgle, are you all right?!
The enemy won’t give us time
to worry about the defeated.
Prepare to fight!
He’s right.
Sauboh, what’s your
next Pokémon?
Don’t have one.
What?!
It’s started...
Connect to the Future!
The Legend of the Radiant One!!
It’s absorbing the Z-Power-roto!
All right!
Now if it’ll just let go of Solgaleo...
What’s happening?!
The worst possible
outcome-roto!
Necrozma is still possessing Solgaleo,
and now it’s powered up-roto!
What?!
Satoshi, what do we do?
Think it didn’t get enough to eat?
We have to think of another plan!
Now that it’s come to this...
I can’t think of anything!
At last, the time has come for
Alola’s traditional Manalo Festival...
When all light is lost and
darkness governs the world...
Deep in our hearts,
we all long for the power...
...of radiance!
Gozu, how long are you going
to play around? Get back here!
You all go without me.
I’ll come after you
once I’ve finished off these two.
Yes, Sir!
The eclipse heralds the era
of the Matori Matrix!
If you would oppose us,
then crumble into the darkness!
Bossgodra! Heavy Bomber!
Sauboh, please keep this a secret
from Satoshi and the other kids!
Let’s go, Gaogaen!
DD Lariat!
I see, so you
had another one.
Luster Cannon!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the ring ablaze
with the flames of victory!
Hyper Dark Crusher!
What?!
“Set the ring ablaze”...?
Could you be...?!
Royal Mask?!
Then let’s do this
together!
Enjoy!
I’ll get you for this!
Now they’re trying
to charge straight into the Ultra Hole!
Indeed!
What’s going on?!
That’s what
I should be asking!
There’s something
in front of us!
What is that?
Kapu-Kokeko!
The rudder isn’t working!
Our thrusters’ power
has dropped by 30%!
What do we do?!
Make up your mind, Matori!
Retreat!
Is everyone all right?
Sure...
Yeah...
We’re fine.
All right, I know!
For real?!
What are we gonna do?
No idea!
But you just said you knew!
I have no idea what we
should do, but I know...
...that we’ll never,
ever give up!
What’s that about?
Still...
Satoshi is right.
Yeah!
Yup!
We have Lunala with us!
Yeah, and these guys!
You come out, too!
And you, Denjimushi!
Blacky! Lugarugan!
What is that?
What is Kapu-Kokeko doing?
It looks like the pose the Island Kings make
to give their thanks during the Manalo Festival.
Is it for the Radiant One...?
All right! We finally have a visual link
to Satoshi and the others!
Thank you, Wicke!
Everybody, can you hear us?
Mother!
We can hear you!
What’s going on
over there right now?
We’re in the world where
the Bebenom live.
And we’ve learned something...
UB: Black,
who possessed Solgaleo...
...is in fact the Radiant One who has lost its light,
as was described in the legend!
I knew it...
It’s exactly as
the mural said.
The Bebenom call the Radiant One
Necrozma.
We tried to use our Z-Power
to restore Necrozma, but it failed!
It wouldn’t let go of Solgaleo!
That must mean we need power from
a lot more people and Pokémon.
A lot more?
We figured out some things about the legend
after deciphering the mural.
Long ago, when the Radiant One
had lost its light,
Solgaleo, Lunala, and all the people and Pokémon
shared their light with it.
The people...
...and Pokémon?
I see... So we need everyone’s power,
not just the Z-Moves.
But how do we
send our power?
I know!
Kapu-Kokeko is probably sending Z-Power
through the Ultra Hole to the Radiant One!
So we just have to do
what it’s doing!
Got it!
Let’s all try!
Everyone in Alola...
All of us here...
The Pokémon and...
..the people...
...will work together...
..and send power!
Yeah!
I’ll have the Island Kings and Queens
assist us as well.
Very well, I understand.
I thank you on behalf of
all the Island Kings, Ms. Lusamine.
People of Alola,
please heed my words!
Alola’s Guardian Deity Kapu-Kokeko
is currently sending power to the Ultra Hole.
Kapu-Kokeko!
As a matter of fact, the Radiant One is on
the other side of the Ultra Hole, and it has lost its light!
According to
the ancient legends of this land,
it was the Radiant One who
filled the world with a mysterious light,
and created the Alola Region!
That very same Radiant One has expended all its light,
and turned pitch black.
If we wish to save the Radiant One,
the power of everyone in Alola is needed!
Send it some power with me...
...along with the prayers of gratitude that have been
traditionally passed on during the Manalo Festival!
That is what will save Solgaleo,
Lunala, and the Radiant One!
Give the Radiant One...
...all of Alola’s...
...power...
Give the Radiant One your power!
Some weird pose seems to
be trending, meow...
Do we have to do that, too?
I don’t wanna!
My arms are gonna get tired!
Huh?
Whaaat?!
What even is this feeling?
You want us to do it, too?
I don’t get it, but if we do that,
the brats will come home sooner,
and we’ll get to snatch
their Pokémon sooner, meow!
I see!
Let’s champion the evils
of truth and love!
We did it!
It let go!
Now all that’s left is for Necrozma
to regain its light...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Necrozma
Type:   Psychic
O, Radiant One! In accordance with
the Manalo Festival’s rituals...
Accept our...
...full power!
Gladio!
Big brother!
Silvuddy!
Air Slash!
A Z-Crystal?
Solgaleo!
Eat this.
You mean you want me
to use a Z-Move?
Are you all right, Solgaleo?
Satoshi!
Can you pull off a Z-Move?!
I’ll try!
Solgaleo!
Lend me your power again!
Let’s do it together!
Yeah!
Let’s give it our all, Solgaleo!
Mystic eyes of the moon,
illuminate the demonic realm of darkness!
Sunshine Smasher!
Moonlight Blaster!
Ms. Lusamine!
We’ve saved Solgaleo!
The Radiant One has
returned to its original form, too!
Awesome!
Yes!
There’s so much green!
So much light, too!
It’s beautiful!
Now this world
will be all right!
Yeah...
Aren’t you glad, Bebenom?
Everyone, this is bad!
The Ultra Hole has
suddenly started to close!
What?!
We gotta hurry back!
Bebenom says that
it is staying here.
Huh?!
And that it will join forces with us
to protect this land.
That’s for the best.
Your home has
returned to normal, after all...
Satoshi, there’s no time...
I know!
So long, Bebenom...
Let’s meet again someday!
Take care of yourself!
Farewell-roto...
Let’s go.
Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection-start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection-don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
I’m still on the way, I don’t know what’s ahead
If I’m honest, it’s scary
My precious friends, my precious time
It’s all passing by, all fading away
Can I make it someday,
to the distant goal from my dreams?
Satoshi and Pikachu...
“I like, like, love you!”, it’s saying!
I want to stick with you and laugh with you
I like, like, love you, too!
Future Connection-I’m glad to have met you
Oh oh!
Let’s head into the unknown tomorrow together!
All right!
It’s our long-awaited chance for a double catch;
Solgaleo and Lunala, meow!
Future Connection-start afresh and anew today
W-W-Wait!
Oh oh!
What even is this feeling?
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection-don’t worry about tiny doubts
The Radiant One!
Oh oh!
Because all the time, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Manalo...
We will live together!
‘sup...
D-Don’t tell me
it’s happened again?!
Nah... I just have a cold...
Then let’s do
the morning greeting over!
Give it all you’ve got...
and shout it out loud:
Alola!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Radiant One was
Green: Necrozma!
At first, Necrozma was ferocious enough to
possess Solgaleo and Lunala...
But now I see it was because it was
trying to absorb Z-Power.
It’s fantastic that the Radiant One was able
to regain its original form!
A lot happened...
But in the end, the Manalo Festival
came to a successful end.
Thank you so much,
Radiant One!
Good grief...
What a bother
that festival turned out to be...
Next episode
Satoshi, you can talk
to Pikachu?! Amazing!
Let me try, too!
I don’t know this guy...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
It’s a Pikaoutbreak!
The Pikachu Valley!!
Next time
It's a Pikaoutbreak!
The Pikachu Valley!!