Alola!
I will be giving
today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Dark Ball
Ultra Ball
Safari Ball
Master Ball
What is the Ball made to catch Ultra Beasts,
that is featured today-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Next, time to film Scene 28!
Okay!
Are you ready? It’s finally time
to shoot the climactic scene.
Scene 28, cut 1, take 1!
Action!
The culprit is the only one who
could have exploited Odoridori’s Teeter Dance.
In other words, it is you!
Hm?
What’s that?
Yeah, what could it be?
What is that?!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Move Out!
Our Ultra Guardians!!
It’s another beautiful day
at the Pokémon School.
As you can see, different environments
can have big effects on Pokémon.
Of course, you can say the same for
all living things, us humans included.
Nekkoala sure is ringing the bell
an awful lot today.
This has never happened before, right?
What could have gotten into it?
My dear Ultra Guardians.
There’s an emergency,
and your help was requesteDarkrai!
Emergency?
Ms. Lusamine contacted you,
did she?
It seems a new Ultra Beast
has been spotted.
Meaning, Ultra Guardians,
it’s your turn at last!
Ultra Guardians?
You mean the thing Lilie’s mom said
she wanted us to help out with?
Now, get out there,
and show no feaRokon!
All right, everybody!
Let’s go!
What?!
Are you surprised?
The Aether Foundation and Pokémon School
worked together to install this passagewaYorterrie!
When?!
Everyone, assume your positions!
Positions?
I’m first!
I’m second!
Looks fun!
Wait for me, everybody!
Awesome!
Where does this lead-roto?
This is pretty fun!
Mother would like
this sort of contraption...
Really?
She has quite the
pronounced childlike side...
Pixie!
Alola, Ultra Guardians!
Alola!
A-Alola...
Mother, what is Pixie doing here?
Pixie will be providing assistance
as a fellow Ultra Guardian.
Have a look at this.
It’s Laki-roto!
This is the report of an
Ultra Beast sighting we’ve received.
The culprit... is you!
Rotom, focus on
what’s in the background.
That’s an Ultra Beast, too?
We’ve named this Ultra Beast
Massivoon.
Massivoon?
Awesome!
What power!
Its muscles are bulging...
So cool!
President Lusamine! If the Aether Foundation
has any data on this Ultra Beast,
then I would like
to download it-roto!
Of course, Rotom.
You are an important member
of the Ultra Guardians too, after all.
Thank you-roto!
Rotom, connect your own terminal
to that panel over there, and download the data.
Roger-roto!
Ultra Beast data updated-roto!
Massivoon. Swollen Pokémon.
Pokémon?
After extensive research,
we’ve decided to define the Ultra Beasts as Pokémon.
Ultra Beast = Pokémon.
Understood-roto!
Massivoon. Swollen Pokémon.
Bug/Fighting type.
It is strong enough to pulverize a dump truck
with a single punch.
It seems Massivoon emerged from an Ultra Hole
that opened by chance over Melemele Meadow.
Its destructive actions...
...presumably stem from its confusion
at stumbling into an unknown world.
We’re counting on you,
Ultra Guardians.
Capture Massivoon
and protect the peace in Alola.
Capture...
Catch it in a ball, you mean?
It’s just a temporary capture,
in order to send it back to the world it came from.
Pixie, bring them the equipment.
What’re these?
These are Ultra Balls. We developed them
for use exclusively against Ultra Beasts.
They’re based off Monster Balls,
so it’ll be easier to catch your opponents with them
after battling them and wearing them down.
This Ultra Beast is quite powerful,
so please take care, everyone.
There are so many
Full Restores and Max Potions!
Berries, too!
Thank you!
Since you have experience
battling Utsuroid,
I have faith that you’ll be able
to complete this mission.
Thank you!
Please contact us immediately
if something goes wrong.
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Yes!
In times like these,
please respond with “Ult-Roger!”
Oh, Mother...
Cool!
Well then, let’s try again.
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Gaburias, I choose you!
I’m counting on you, Metang!
Let’s do this, Flygon!
Let’s do our best, Hakuryu!
Tyltalis, please!
I didn’t expect you to be here.
Let’s do this!
Hakuryu...
The sky looks like the sea.
Vast and blue...
Doesn’t it feel nice
to fly through the sky, Snowball?
Don’t we look
really cool right now?
Yeah!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Massivoon
Type:   Bug/Fighting
We’ve got so many, meow!
Where did Kiteruguma go, meow?
I don’t see Musashi or
Kojiro either, meow.
Who is that thing with
the massive stinger, meow?
It’s holding its ground against Kiteruguma...
What unbelievable strength, meow!
Oh, my!
I can’t understand
a word it’s saying, meow...
I’m so tired...
Oh, Nyarth.
Well, did you get any?
Musashi, stay away, meow!
Kiteruguma!
We’ve gathered plenty of berries!
Kojiro, you stay away too, meow!
W-Wait!
W-What’s this all about?!
This is better, meow.
It’s safer to stay away from
things we don’t understand, meow.
What even is this feeling?
We just got a tip that Massivoon
is attacking a Kabigon.
Fly straight to
the prairie near Mahalo Trail!
Ult-Roger!
I’ll guide you there-roto!
There!
Hey, stop!
Wait!
Are you all right, Kabigon?
I’ll spray you with
a Full Restore.
Here!
Here, here, here, here!
Eat up!
Massivoon is a
pretty interesting guy, huh.
Don’t let your guard down-roto!
Yeah.
Anyway, we gotta catch it, right?
Massivoon! I’m gonna capture you,
so we can bring you back to your own world!
With that outta the way,
let’s battle!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Lightning Speed!
Pikachu!
Are you all right, Pikachu?!
Dodge it with Lightning Speed!
Now! 100,000 Volts!
I-It’s fast!
Satoshi!
Kaki!
I’ll back you up!
What? What do you want?!
Seems kinda fun!
Pikachu, you try too!
Satoshi...
Kaki...
Pikachu...
Massivoon...
Sheesh... Satoshi, Kaki!
How long are you gonna keep playing around?
This is the perfect chance!
Throw an Ultra Ball-roto!
Oh, of course!
Yeah...
Go, Ultra Ball!
It went in unexpectedly easily-roto!
B-But...
Don’t come out!
Please!
We did it!
Massivoon...
I ultra-got you!
Burnet.
Yes.
Seems it was around here.
If an Ultra Hole has opened somewhere before,
it’s a lot easier to open it again.
All set!
All right! Now...
It’s much more
impressive up close!
I’m sure it understands
that it can go home.
Now, go back to
your own world, Massivoon.
Massivoon!
It’s gone...
You know... I think I’ll miss it.
Massivoon was an interesting guy.
Thank you, Ultra Guardians.
Your first mission was a rousing success!
Ult-Roger!
The Ultra Guardians successfully sent
the lost Massivoon back to its own world.
But there’s no telling when
another Ultra Beast will appear.
Fight on, Ultra Guardians!
To be continued!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting-roto!
The Ball used to get the Ultra Beast
was the Ultra Ball-roto!
The Swollen Pokémon Massivoon
is a Bug/Fighting type.
It shows off its body, but whether that display
is a boast or a threat remains unclear-roto.
We still need more data on
the Ultra Beasts’ biology-roto!
Next episode
I’m thirsty, meow.
Have a Pile Juice, Alola special!
I’m hungry too, meow.
Have our special
Chef’s Surprise Alolan Pancakes!
Can’t you massage my shoulders, meow?
Good, meow...
That hits the spot, meow...
This comfort feels like a dream, meow...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Dark Nyarth is an Alolan Nyarth?!
Will you wake up already, Nyarth?!
Next time
The Dark Nyarth is an Alolan Nyarth?!
It was a dream, meow?!