Alola!
I, the Island King Hala,
will give today’s PokéProblem.
Akala Island
The shopping mall
The Altar of the Sunne
The Kanto Region
Satoshi and the others head for
a certain place in today’s episode.
Where is it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
In an attempt to protect
me and my brother,
Mother was captured
by an Ultra Beast!
Mother...
Mother!
Lilie!
Are you okay, Lilie?
Mother...
She was taken away...
Sauboh!
Why did you use the machine
without telling me?!
I-It’s...
all President Lusamine’s fault!
I’m not to blame!
I...
I will go rescue Mother!
Lilie!
Then, I’ll...
Satoshi.
Sorry for getting you
mixed up in this.
But from here on out,
this is a family matter.
Gladio...
Professor Burnet!
What?
Can the Ultra Hole be opened again?
Not possible.
It’ll take time to repair the machine.
And even if we did fix it, there’s no guarantee
that we could stabilize the Ultra Hole it would open.
You’ll have to find another way.
Another way? Like?!
I can’t think of any right now.
Oh, no...
Who knows what might happen
to Mother before we...
We’ll try to find a way.
So... I think it would be better if
you went back to land for now.
But...
There’s nothing you can
do right now.
Get some rest, to make sure
you’re ready when you’re needed, Lilie.
Nebby!
Satoshi, what’s that?
It’s Nebby.
It suddenly shrank like this...
It’s not moving at all-roto!
A sign of evolution?
No, it’s nothing.
I’m not sure what’s going on,
so just keep an eye on it for now.
All right.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
I Can RealLilie Do It!
A Determined Runaway Act!!
I wonder if your mom might have known something
about why Nebby ended up like this, Lilie.
Yes... She was the one who
entrusted you with it, so surely she would...
Oh, I’m sorry!
We’ll save your mom for sure!
Right, Gladio?
Is there no way to
open the Ultra Hole?
Well then, Master Satoshi,
please take care on your way home.
Thank you, Mr. James.
See you later, Lilie, Gladio!
Lilie?
Yes?
See you tomorrow
at the Pokémon School!
Oh, yes.
Snowball.
Be good.
James, I’m sorry...
Lilie, I’m coming in.
S-Say that before entering!
I was just getting ready
to go to bed!
I see. Well, then I have to ask
what’s with the outfit you’re wearing.
Th-These are...
...my pajamas!
You’re going to look for a way
to open the Ultra Hole, aren’t you?
N-No!
Do you have any ideas
on where to go?
I do.
But it’s a really dangerous place.
So I’ll be going on my own.
On your own?!
That’s right.
I just came to let you know.
No!
You aren’t the only one
who cares about Mother.
I’ll go with you.
Fine.
But you have way too much luggage.
What?
Bring only what you can fit in that.
All right!
Mother... I swear I’ll save you!
That’s Nebby?!
Yeah...
It’s strange.
Ever since it became like this
at Aether Paradise,
it hasn’t moved at all-roto.
Maybe it ate too many sugar stars
and ended up becoming one itself?
Obviously not.
I’m sorry...
Satoshi, what happened over there?
Well, you see...
Lilie’s mother was kidnapped?!
An Ultra Beast...
Hey, hey, you gotta be kidding!
Are you sure you shouldn’t
tell Ms. Junsa about this?
Is Lilie all right?
Now that you mention it, she did seem kinda out of it
when we parted ways yesterday.
And she’s not here.
She’s late-roto.
Professor Kukui?
And Mr. James!
She’s not here, huh?
Is something wrong?
Young Miss Lilie and Young Master Gladio
have disappeared from the mansion.
Disappeared?!
They ran away?
No way!
They must have gone
to save Lilie’s mom!
But she’s on the other side
of the Ultra Hole, isn’t she?
Then where did they go?
They’d have to open
an Ultra Hole first, right?
But if they don’t know
how to open it...
Yeah, right? There’s just too much
we don’t know.
A clue...
Young Master Gladio might
have known something.
It’s possible, since he knows
a lot about the Altar.
So, what do we do?
Let’s try asking the Island King.
The Island King...
You mean Mr. Hala?
Yeah.
We turn to our Island King
in times of need.
All right! Let’s go visit Mr. Hala!
I’ll go, too!
I’m going, too-roto!
I hope he knows something...
I see...
In short, you worry about those two
who went off to find an Ultra Hole.
So, what was this Ultra Hole like?
A hole just suddenly appeared
out of nowhere,
then an Ultra Beast came out of it...
...and took Lilie’s mom with it!
A hole from nowhere...
Was it like the sky itself
splitting apart?
Yeah, exactly!
How’d you know?
There is a legend that has been passed down
from one Island King to the next.
A legend?
Indeed.
The legend of Solgaleo.
Solgaleo?
I saw it in a dream!
A dream?
In that dream, Solgaleo and Lunala
told me to take care of Nebby!
What?!
I climbed to the top of a long, long stairway,
and there were symbols of the sun and moon...
A long stairway... The sun and moon...
And Solgaleo and Lunala.
The first thing that comes to mind
is the Altar of the Sunne.
I think Wicke mentioned
something like that!
Long ago, there was a battle at the Altar of the Sunne,
between the Guardian Deities of Alola and the Ultra Beasts.
As the legend goes, Solgaleo appeared,
splitting the sky.
Splitting the sky?
Just like the Ultra Holes...
Does that mean we might be able to
open an Ultra Hole with Solgaleo’s help?
I wonder if that’s where
Lilie and Gladio went, too?
That’s gotta be it.
Well then, we should go to
the Altar of the Sunne, too!
Yeah!
If you wish to go to the Altar of the Sunne,
it sits on Poni Island.
Poni Island?
The Altar of the Sunne
lies beyond here, yes?
That’s right. And this is the place...
...where the Legendary Pokémon,
Solgaleo, is said to appear.
There’s no turning back now.
I know.
I’m prepared to do whatever it takes
to get Mother back.
It’s not just you.
I’m with you, too.
Yes!
Let’s go!
Mr. James, this boat...
I asked Ms. Wicke to provide it.
With this, you should be able to catch up
to the young master and lady.
Thank you so much.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Hariteyama
Type:   Fighting
Statues of Mokuroh,
Nyabby and Ashimari...
I get it. It appears we must push these
Pokémon statues to their corresponding type.
Lilie, what are you doing?
What do you mean, “What”?
Surely we must solve this puzzle
for the door to open?
That door?
If anything, moving the statues
would mean trouble.
What do you mean?
Step aside.
Silvuddy, move that statue.
Get it? Be careful not to touch
anything suspicious around here.
Y-Yes...
We can’t cross like this, I see.
I know! I read about this in a book!
Surely, there is an invisible bridge here!
Sprinkle, sprinkle, sprinkle...
What are you doing?
What?
Isn’t there an invisible bridge here?
No. Get on.
Leap, Silvuddy!
There’s no puzzle here.
It looks like there was a bridge here once,
but that it’s fallen down now.
How do you know so much
about this place?
It was in the Foundation’s documents.
The documents from the time
Mom and Professor Burnet came here.
You know everything, don’t you?
I know nothing.
Or rather... I’d forgotten.
And even now, I’m no help at all.
Am I simply slowing you down?
If you are, will you stay here?
No.
In that case, keep looking ahead.
You won’t... can’t change
anything by turning back.
Mom won’t come back either.
I understand.
Let’s go.
There’s nothing here.
Look at that.
The Altar of the Sunne
is past there, yes?
Wait, Lilie!
Those are Jarako and Jarango!
Doesn’t look like they’ll
let us pass that easily.
Silvuddy!
We have to get through here,
or we won’t be able to save Mother.
Snowball!
What’s that?!
Are you all right?
Yes. But what...
Stand back.
That body covered in hard scales...
It’s Jararanga, a Pokémon that has both
the Dragon and Fighting types!
But it’s far bigger than the size
I saw listed in books!
From what I can tell, it seems to be
the Totem of the Altar.
Very well. Let’s show it...
...the power of
the sacred beast, Silvuddy!
Lilie. You and Snowball
take care of Jarako and Jarango!
All right!
Advance, Silvuddy!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Now! Use Break Claw!
They’re hard!
Dodge it, Silvuddy!
What a bother.
Big Brother, can you change Silvuddy
into a Fairy type?
Fairy? Oh, of course.
If we’re up against a Dragon type...
Silvuddy, receive
the Fairy Memory and—
Big Brother!
Where’s the Memory?
What?
Snowball and I will make a path.
Lilie...
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Again, Snowball!
This time, aim at the ground!
Now, Big Brother!
All right! Let’s go, Silvuddy!
This is our path to victory!
Make it in time!
Silvuddy!
Big Brother!
The armor of a fairy clad in light
will not be pierced by a dragon’s claws!
Big Brother!
Here it comes!
And the fairy’s blade
will shatter the dragon’s scales!
Silvuddy, use Multi-Attack!
Well done, Silvuddy!
You’re amazing, Big Brother!
No, you saved us.
Let’s hurry onward.
Yes!
What’s wrong, Silvuddy?
Big Brother!
What?!
Hey!
We made it!
Satoshi?!
I’m so glad you’re safe!
Good job, Satoshi!
Why are you all here?
Isn’t it obvious?
We wanted to save your mom!
Didn’t I tell you that
this was a family matter?
Big Brother!
Gladio. Alola’s all about
sharing stuff, right?
In that case, we might as well
share in your family matter, too!
We’ll all be happy about the good things,
and help each other out when things get rough.
That’s the best!
But this is...
Big Brother, it might not be entirely logical
for me to conclude this, but...
I want to go with all of them.
I feel like that’ll help us save Mother!
No, I know we can save her together!
Lilie...
All right, then.
Counting on all of you.
Let’s look for Solgaleo!
So we can save Lilie’s mom!
Yeah!
So this is the Altar of the Sunne.
Solgaleo, where are you?
Satoshi, look!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Long time, no see!
That’s Kapu-Tetefu!
More are coming!
The Guardian Deities of Alola are all here-roto!
This is huge-roto!
What does this mean?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for being patient!
Satoshi and the others headed for
the Altar of the Sunne, huh.
Long ago, at the Altar of the Sunne,
a battle unfolded between
the Guardian Deities of Alola and the Ultra Beasts.
It truly was an intense struggle.
Legends say it went on for days,
nay, months, nay, years!
Did Satoshi and the others
meet Solgaleo?
O, Kapu-Kokeko.
Please watch over the children.
Next episode
Try and say the names of
the Alolan Guardian Deities fast!
Kapu-Kokeko Kapu-Tetefu
Kapu-Bulul Kapu-Rehire.
Lilie, I knew you could do it! I’ll try, too!
Kapu-Kokeko Kapu-Tetefu
Kapu-Bulul Kapu-Rehire!
Perfect.
Now it’s Satoshi’s turn!
Right! Kapu-Kokefu... Kapu-Kokefu...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Altar of the Sunne! Solgaleo Descends!!
Next time
The Altar of the Sunne!
Solgaleo Descends!!
Don’t play with the the sacred Guardian Deities’ names!