Alola!
I’ll be presenting
today’s PokéProblem to you.
Yamikarasu
The brat boy
Mokuroh
Nyarth
Which of these jerks was it who
stole my precious malasada today?
The answer’ll be
at the end of the episode!
Satoshi got the Rock-Z
on Akala Island.
Today, he’s once again headed for
the Pokémon School in high spirits,
together with Pikachu and
the recently evolved Lugarugan.
Lugarugan, let’s test
the Rock Z-Move together!
I’d like to see it too-roto.
Alola, Satoshi!
Mao, Alola!
Alola-roto!
Alola, Kaki!
Alola!
You’re early this morning.
Since I got the Rock-Z from Ms. Lychee,
I’ve been itching to try it out.
Then, wanna give it a try right now?
Pikachu!
The plan was a success, meow!
Wasn’t that shockingly easy?
Paying our respects to the Alolan sunrise
was well worth it!
Team Rocket!
No use!
In that case, I’ll test
the Rock Z-Move right here!
Lugarugan!
That’s a Luganga?
It’s actually called Lugarugan, meow.
Did it really look like that?
See? It’s different from
the one listed in the Index!
You’re right, meow.
Meaning it’s mega rare, right?
That’s perfect!
We’ll nab that too while we’re at it!
Go, Mimikkyu!
Hey, Mimikkyu!
Mimikkyu is only interested
in Pikachu, after all.
Let’s go!
Lugarugan!
This is our...
...full power!
World’s End Fall!
What’s wrong, Lugarugan?!
The Z-Move...
...failed, meow!
Now get the chance!
We can now—
...taste this move instead?
Let’s go, Bakugames!
Dynamic Full Flame!
That was our first appearance
in a while, too.
Guess we really need to be careful
about those Z-Moves, meow.
They’re really annoying.
Huh? Isn’t Kiteruguma a bit late?
Could this be...
Kiteruguma’s turned into...
...Kiterugone?!
Ouch!
Wait...
Pikachu?!
It’s a Mega Massive Evolution!
Oh.
Isn’t this the shopping mall?
Kojiro! Nyarth! Where are you?
Sonansu! Mimikkyu!
Mimikkyu! Oh, good, you’re...
...not fine!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Mimikkyu’s Disguise!
What’s inside Mimikkyu...
...is an entrance to
a terrifying world, meow.
If you happen to see what’s inside,
you might never be able to
come back to us, meow!
That’s what Nyarth told me...
But how am I gonna
not see it now?!
W-Well anyway,
get inside your Ball.
You can’t go anywhere
in that state, right?
Hey, why won’t you go in?
I can’t look for Kojiro
and the others like this!
This is bad...
Look! Malasada doughnuts!
I’ll go buy you one,
so get back in your Ball!
Pardon me!
Welcome.
Two malasadas, please.
Thank you for waiting.
Thank you very much!
Likewise!
H-Hey, hang on! Those are my...
My malasadas!
Ah! Wait!
Oh, geez... Wait.
Now I won’t have to see
what’s under your disguise.
Still, they sure did a number
on this thing.
It’s a rag.
Why not just throw it away?
Oh, I know!
Let’s get you a new cover!
Want me to pick one out for you?
You hate Pikachu, don’t you?
Then why not just
wear something else?
Yeah, that’s a great idea!
Yup. Let’s do that!
Let’s do just that!
Hey, Musashi!
Mimikkyu,
where are you, meow?
Musashi!
If you’re there, answer me!
M-Mimikkyu!
Looks like they’re not here, meow.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, when we were in the air,
I saw a large shopping mall
over in that direction, meow.
Shopping mall?
If Musashi actually landed there...
Musashi... Shopping...
This is awful!
If we don’t find her quickly...
All the money we saved up
from working part-time...
...will be gone!
Welcome!
I haven’t gone shopping in so long!
Time to flaunt my skill!
What are you looking for today?
I’m not shopping for myself.
Oh my gosh! This is adorable!
It’s a very popular item,
and we only have one left in stock.
I’ll buy it! No, wait. Like I said,
I’m not buying things for myself today.
We only have one left of these, too!
And they have to be specially ordered!
I’ll buy it!
Oh, dear! I wasn’t planning
on buying all this!
It suits you wonderfully!
Doesn’t it? I knew that!
Now, come here, you.
It’s your turn next.
Let’s do a warm-up first...
Cute ribbons!
And then next,
we have a casual bucket!
And next, a frilly pochette!
Next! A nostalgic straw hat!
Let’s keep it up!
Next, we have...
Hey wait! What?
H-H-Hang on!
Mimikkyu, wait!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Yamikarasu
Type:   Evil/Flying
World’s End Fall!
Failed again, huh?
Don’t worry,
Satoshi! Lugarugan!
I’m sure you’ll pull it off soon!
Thank you.
But I wonder,
why does it keep failing?
You got the pose right-roto.
I read about this in a book.
For Z-Moves, the trust between
a Pokémon and its trainer is important.
Then there shouldn’t be a problem.
Yeah.
What could it be?
It’s all right, Lugarugan.
It’s not your fault.
Actually...
The reason you’re failing
might very well be Lugarugan.
Professor... What do you mean?
Lugarugan’s working so hard!
That hard work might just be the reason
why the Z-Move keeps failing.
When Lugarugan evolved,
he gained power far beyond what he had before.
But Lugarugan doesn’t have the experience points
to control that power quite yet.
Do you mean something like...
...him trying too hard, exhausting his power
before he gets to attack?
That might be it.
How about taking another look at
the Rock-type move you’re using as the foundation?
So that you can make
Lugarugan’s power your own.
All right!
I’ll give it a go, Professor!
Then I guess it’s time
to train, right, Satoshi?
Yeah!
I’ll help you practice
whenever you want!
Me, too!
In that case, this afternoon’s class
will be practicing your moves!
Really?
You’re itching to start training
right now, aren’t you?
All right, Lugarugan!
Let’s get right to training!
Sheesh... What would you like?
I’m all worn out thanks to you!
Let’s actually take a break and
have some malasadas now.
You’re so stubborn!
Welcome!
Two malasadas, please.
I spent too much!
Actually, just one.
Very well.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Ah! It’s Pikachu!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
I love Pikachu!
Me, too!
I’ll fix it for you. Give it to me.
I don’t really get it,
but it seems looking like Pikachu
is important to you.
One more time!
Lugarugan, use Rock Throw!
Block it!
What’s wrong, Lugarugan?
Are you tired?
Don’t get carried away, you two.
We’ve almost got it, though.
Ashimari! Aqua Jet!
Amamaiko, you’re good!
You can do this sort of thing
with Aqua Jet, too?
I guess this is what you’d call
a winning idea?
It’s done.
I think I sewed it up pretty well,
don’t you?
Truly, I’m amazing!
Don’t tear it again, you hear?
Oh, that’s right.
The malasada from before!
Yeah, of course.
I only have one, so you get half.
Hey, what gives?!
Not that!
Oh, for crying out loud...
What are you doing, Mimikkyu!
We’ve gotta take it back!
Hey, you!
That belongs to Mimikkyu!
Give it back!
And don’t eat the malasada, either!
Got it!
Hey! Give it back!
Give it back! Give it back!
Got it!
We finally reached
the shopping mall, meow...
We sure got lost pretty badly.
Wait, where’s Sonansu?
Did we get separated, meow?
Sonansu’s kinda
Sonanscrewed. Get it?
How stupid, meow.
Musashi would have
exploded with laughter!
What was that?!
I’m sure Musashi
must have laughed, meow!
That can’t be...
Oh no!
This is...
Mega Massive Pikachu?
Its shed skin?
Ow...
Why did this happen?
She really did explode, meow.
What, meow?
Here, I got your treasure back.
And the malasada!
The larger bit’s mine.
We already ate the malasada!
If that bothers you,
just try and get back at us!
Serves you right!
Hey, you came to get back at us
a bit too fast, don’t you think?!
Mimikkyu!
I’ve seen this tunnel before, meow...
Why am I walking
through here again, meow?
I’m not sure if I should
keep going or not, meow...
It’s the exit, meow!
I’m sure heaven awaits me
on the other side, meow!
Now that’s the Mimikkyu
I know and love!
Oh, that was Mimikkyu?
Nyarth, what’s wrong?
Something’s coming!
Dodge it!
Mimikkyu! Wood Hammer!
Mimikkyu’s actually
following her commands!
Take that! You’re about a million years away
from beating the great Musashi!
Hey, Musashi! Mimikkyu!
Oh?
Kojiro, what brings you here?
What’s that supposed to mean?
Hey, why are you sleeping, Nyarth?
Wake up!
Nyarth, wake up, I say!
What? Would you please not disturb
my moment of bliss, meow...?
Nyarth! Wake up!
He’s awake.
Who am this place?
What is I?
Snap out of it! We’re going after
the brat boy, right now!
What? Now?
Right now...
Mimikkyu and I are invincible!
Let’s go, Mimikkyu!
What’s happening, meow?
You came at me twice in a day?
You’re pretty motivated today.
We’re the mighty Team Rocket,
unrivaled on both heaven and earth!
When we’ve set our sights on our prey,
we’ll come as many times a day as it takes!
Right, Kojiro? Nyarth?
...They’re not even here?
Musashi! Mimikkyu!
Give it your all, meow!
We’ll give it our all
in cheering for you, too!
Sheesh...
In any case, it’s time for a rematch!
This time, I’ll beat you!
There’s no way Satoshi can lose!
Yeah! We’ll show you
the results of our training!
Lugarugan, use Rock Throw!
Go, go!
Hang in there!
Mimikkyu! Wood Hammer!
Hey, Mimikkyu! That’s not who
you’re supposed to fight!
So as always, if Pikachu is there,
he’s the only one it’ll fight.
Good grief!
Get back to the battle!
Satoshi, now!
Go!
All right, this time for sure!
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
Oh? You’re gonna show us
another Fail-Move?
Then while you’re busy with that...
This is our...
...full power!
Oh, dear...
World’s End Fall!
Nooo!
Kiterugone’s turned back...
...into Kiteruguma!
What even is this feeling?
Yeah!
This is the result of
training all day-roto!
You did it, Satoshi! Lugarugan!
Satoshi and Lugarugan
have mastered the Rock Z-Move.
The Alolan evening sun
shines warmly on their hearts.
But what about Team Rocket?
I swear...
That Mimikkyu...
Next time, for sure!
We really won’t lose next time!
You seem to be in a good mood,
despite your complaining.
Not really.
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Yamikarasu!
You’re about a million years too young
to try and steal from me!
The Disgust Pokémon, Mimi—
Oh, it’s “Disguise” Pokémon?
My Mimikkyu
is a Pikachu-hating ty—
You’re a Ghost/Fairy type?
You had such a cutesy type as Fairy?
Good on you!
W-Where is its real body, meow?!
This is bad for my heart, meow...
Next episode
Alolan Television is coming
to our cafeteria!
“Local Famous Gourmet
Restaurants Feature”!
I wanna be on TV!
Then, wanna work in the cafeteria?
You can wear an apron
like Amamaiko does!
I’ll do it!
Welcome!
You have to say it cuter,
or you won’t get shown!
Welcome!
Huh? Who are you?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Runaway Mao and Yareyutan!
We will make Aina Cafeteria famous!
Next time
The Runaway Mao and Yareyutan!
Yeah!