Good day!
I, Lilie, will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem!
Nekkoala
Magearna
Kabigon
Musharna
Which Pokémon awakens today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Breakfast time!
Satoshi and the others have
made it through the Alola Pokémon League.
It’s been a while since they’ve
had breakfast at home...
Data on how Melmetal ingests food...
Updated-roto!
It’s Stockpiling at
an impressive rate, huh?
I love big families!
Agoyon?
It’s an Ultra Hole-roto!
Agoyon...
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Sun, the Moon
and Our Dreams!
You’re leaving, huh, Agoyon?
I see...
In your world, there’s all those Bebenom
waiting for you to come back, after all.
Agoyon.
Thank you for coming to help Alola...
For coming to help us.
Your 100,000 Volts was the coolest!
Let’s meet again.
Say hi to the Bebenom for me!
Oh, and the Radiant One, too!
All right, Pikachu!
Let’s send Agoyon off with a 100,000 Volts!
100,000 Volts!
See ya!
All right. Now, don’t forget
what you just learned!
Of course!
By the way, how do you guys plan to
spend the upcoming vacation?
Me! Me, me, me!
Man, you’re really excited, Māmane.
I’m going to Tokusane City
with Big Mu!
Tokusane City?
In the Hoenn Region?
Yeah!
I’ve been dying to go see the
Tokusane Space Center!
The Space Center? You mean...
That’s right!
I want to be an astronaut!
What?!
Your dream is so cool!
W-Well... Yeah...
So I’m starting with
what I can do now.
It’s your first step
towards your dream!
Just a small step, though...
No, it’s a giant leap!
Thank you.
So, Kaki, what are you gonna do
during vacation?
I...
...will battle Satoshi!
Huh?!
We didn’t get to face off
in the League, after all!
I want one more chance
to have an all-out battle with you!
Sure! You’re on!
I won’t lose!
Right back at you!
I will win!
No, I will!
They’re at it again...
Yeah...
All right, that’s enough!
I look forward to hearing
the results of your battle.
Thank you!
So, what are your plans, Suiren?
I’m helping Dad with
his ocean survey.
What are you surveying?
Believe it or not...
It’s Manaphy!
Manaphy?
That’ll be invaluable data-roto!
I hope you’ll let me record it-roto!
Manaphy. Seafaring Pokémon.
Water type.
Born on a cold seafloor,
it possesses a wondrous power that lets it
bond with any kind of Pokémon.
I’m going to give Aina Cafeteria
a little bit of a makeover!
I want to make it into a restaurant that not just humans,
but also Pokémon can enjoy!
Before that, I’m holding a tasting party for
the new Pokémon dishes, so please come, everyone!
I really want to awaken Magearna!
I will give that goal my full power
over the vacation!
You’re all awesome!
What are you gonna do,
other than battling Kaki?
Me?
Now that you mention it,
I haven’t really thought about it...
What’s wrong?
I was thinking...
Satoshi was thinking-roto?!
It’s not that shocking!
You know, we’ve finished
the Island Pilgrimage...
I’m not sure what to do now.
Catch more Pokémon, maybe?
What do you think, Professor?
I guess...
...you’ll have to
figure it out yourself.
It should be easy for you.
You’re the Alola Pokémon League
Champion, remember?
Well, you can take your time.
Right...
Have a look!
That’s the Space Center!
I’m so excited!
Manaphy is really quick.
Big Sis!
You’re gonna catch Manaphy?!
That’s right. In order to research it.
Ama-mazing!
Ta-dough!
Welcome to the unveiling of
Aina Cafeteria’s first-ever Pokémon menu items!
I made Fluffy Radish with different toppings
to suit everyone’s tastes!
Open up!
They’re chowing down like mad.
What an appetite!
I’m so glad they all seem to like it.
Yes! It’s amazing that you made food
that so perfectly appeals to everyone!
Whenever I think back to that time
I helped out in Master’s café...
Somehow, new Pokémon menu items
just keep popping into my mind!
People, Pokémon...
All of Aina Cafeteria’s customers...
I want to make dishes
that’ll make them all smile!
That’s right, Satoshi!
Ms. Lychee is going to be
the referee for our battle!
Ms. Lychee?!
I met her the other day
and told her about our battle,
and she was all in on it!
And she said she could do it tomorrow, even!
No need to wait for vacation!
Tomorrow?!
All right! Let’s do it then!
I’m all in!
Sure!
Yeah!
Oh yeah, how are things with Magearna?
Oh...
I tried quite a few things...
But nothing worked...
Don’t worry!
I’m sure you can do it!
Satoshi is right!
You’re always watching Pokémon carefully
and trying to understand them!
I’m sure your feelings will get through
sooner or later!
Keep going!
Thank you so much!
The Soul Heart is the key...
Father kept on trying to...
Oh, dear...
I must have fallen asleep.
Zoroark...
Fire Punch!
Accelerock!
Stone Edge!
Dodge and use Turning Swallow Strike!
Bite attack!
Use Slash!
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Manaphy
Type:   Water
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
Let’s finish this, Lizardon!
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
This is our...
...full power!
Radial Edgestorm!
Dynamic...
...Full Flame!
Stand up, Lizardon!
Lugarugan, can you still stand?!
Both are unable to—
Lugarugan!
Lizardon is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is Satoshi!
Thank you, Lugarugan!
That was an awesome battle-roto!
Thanks!
Lizardon, you fought well.
Thank you!
Satoshi, that was a great battle!
Yeah!
I used my full power!
I have no regrets.
Satoshi... Kaki...
You were just the best!
T-Thank you very much...
So, what next?
What do you mean?
How do the two of you plan on
becoming stronger in the future?
I’m... not really sure...
Professor Kukui said
I should figure it out for myself...
I have plenty of stuff I want to do!
I’ll continue my Island Pilgrimage!
I want to challenge Mr. Hala, Mr. Kuchinashi,
and Hāpu'u’s Grand Trials!
I want to master more types of Z-Moves!
And I’ll become much, much stronger!
All for the sake of
protecting the flames of Wela!
Just like Grandfather did!
Was that a declaration that
you’ll become the Island King?
Kaki’s dream is to
be the Island King-roto?!
That’s perfect for you!
You really think so?
Yeah!
If so, then you’ll have to learn about
the outside world, too.
The outside... world?
It’s important to know of
the outside world.
Changing your surroundings
broadens your perspective.
It allows you to calmly look back and
reconsider the person you’d been until then.
Isn’t that right, Satoshi?
You understand,
since you’ve been training in Alola, right?
Lilie...
Lilie.
Big brother!
I was really surprised...
...when James contacted me
out of the blue.
I’m so sorry for the short notice.
I wanted to let Zoroark
meet Magearna.
Zoroark?
Look at this.
Zoroark must have been watching
Father’s research right by his side.
I see.
I was thinking about that,
and then it hit me that Magearna and Zoroark...
...would love to be reunited, too.
Figures you’d think of that.
Zoroark!
Look, Magearna. It’s Zoroark!
You recognize it, don’t you?
Zoroark!
Look! It’s Magearna!
I knew it’d remember!
Yeah.
Father?
This is Zoroark’s illusion.
You called, Princess Lilie?
Come here.
I didn’t know you were
such a tomboy.
I was still a baby!
Lilie, I hope you and Magearna
will be good friends.
Magearna.
Once you can move again,
look after Lilie for me.
Please protect my little princess.
We’re home!
We’re back.
Lilie!
You’re standing up!
Mohn, when?!
When did she learn to stand?!
Just now.
It was just a few seconds ago.
Oh, I missed
a priceless moment!
Good work, Lilie!
Such a good girl.
Father...
I want to see you...
Thank you...
Magearna...
You’re...
...awake?
At last!
I’m so happy, Magearna!
It’s important to know of
the outside world.
Changing your surroundings
broadens your perspective.
It allows you to calmly look back and
reconsider the person you’d been until then.
Isn’t that right, Satoshi?
You understand,
since you’ve been training in Alola, right?
I’ve decided!
I want to see the rest of the world!
Pikachu, let’s go back to Masara Town.
I’m sure there’s so much more
awesome stuff to see in the world!
There’s gotta be loads more
Pokémon out there!
Satoshi has chosen his own path.
Where will that path
take him?
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you very much for waiting!
The Pokémon who woke up today
was Magearna!
At last, Magearna is awake!
It’s all thanks to Zoroark
showing me its memories of Father!
Thank you so much, Zoroark!
How does the fresh air feel,
Magearna?
A-Are you all right?!
Next episode
Satoshi is late...
It’s kinda quiet without him, isn’t it?
He’s always burning hot
at full power, after all.
He’s loud, too...
Especially while battling.
That’s why it’s kinda quiet.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Thank you, Alola!
The Start of New Journeys!!
Won’t Satoshi be here soon?
Next time
Thank You, Alola!
The Start of New Journeys!!