Alola! Kukui here!
Today’s PokéProblem comes to you
from yours truly!
Tsutsukera
Nyabby
Agojimushi
Iwanko
Which Pokémon does Satoshi catch today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
We’re home!
Huh? Iwanko?
Did he go out somewhere-roto?
Now, Satoshi,
where do we leave our backpacks?
Oh, right!
Welcome back, Iwa—
What?!
Iwanko, what happened?!
These are scrapes,
claw marks, scratch marks...
He’s got burns, too-roto.
Iwanko, let me see.
This’ll sting a little.
Did he get into a fight?
Come on, didn’t I ask you
to watch over the house?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Clawmark Hill,
Iwanko and Lugarugan!!
And there you have it.
Um, in that case...
Would it not be better to
keep Iwanko in his Monster Ball?
Iwanko isn’t
the Professor’s Pokémon.
He isn’t?
No. The Professor told me he fed him Pokémon food,
and then he just stuck around.
So he’s like a freeloader?
I thought for sure
he was his Pokémon...
Me, too. He’s really close
with Professor Kukui, after all.
Iwanko is well known for
taking to humans easily-roto.
Iwanko. Puppy Pokémon.
Rock type.
This Pokémon has lived with people
since times long ago.
It trains by running around.
He hurt himself through training!
Huh? Training?
Maybe Iwanko is close to evolving.
Evolving?
Iwanko’s evolution, Lugarugan,
has two forms.
Evolving during the day will
make it assume its Midday Form,
whereas evolving at night will
make it assume its Midnight Form.
Really? It evolves into a different form
depending on the time of day?
Additionally,
when its evolution draws near,
its disposition grows
wilder and more aggressive.
You may notice it’s
gone missing,
only for it to suddenly
come back later, having evolved.
What?!
I’m home!
Have you been good today?
Ow! Come on, that hurts!
I told you, when an Iwanko rubs the rocks on its neck
against you, that’s proof of its love for you.
The more it hurts, the deeper their love is,
so the trainer’s just gotta Bide it!
Oh, you were already home?
I was worried about Iwanko.
Look at this, Satoshi.
I set up cameras
all across the room.
Please let me have
this footage later-roto!
Does he always
wait for us like that?
The important part comes next.
Huh?
Several hours later...
30 minutes before I came home...
It’s just like last time!
Where were you,
and what were you doing?
Later, Iwanko!
Keep watch of the house.
What’s that, Professor?
It’s his playmate.
See ya!
Perfect image!
Professor, what’s...?
I don’t know, either.
I’ve left him with
the toy before, but...
What’s that light?
Commence chase.
Hang on... This path leads to...
Lugarugan!
Both its Midday Form and its
Midnight Form, at that-roto!
What a fascinating place-roto!
I knew it! This is Clawmark Hill!
Clawmark Hill?
A Rock Throw followed by Accelerock?!
This Lugarugan’s tough!
Counter!
Yeah.
Midnight Form Lugarugan likes to
take its opponent’s moves head-on,
and then send a finishing blow
right back at them!
This is no time to admire them-roto!
Record! Record!
Where’s Iwanko?
There!
All right, that explains it!
Wait!
We may know why he got hurt,
but we need to know Iwanko’s goal.
Wait and see for
a little longer, Satoshi!
Goal, huh...?
Huh? Those two are...
Professor!
Bide your time, Satoshi!
But...
That’s...
Yeah, it’s the sign of
a move activating!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
-roto!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lugarugan
..                      (Midday Form)
Type:   Rock
I-Iwanko!
He’s blatantly outmatched.
Professor, what’s...?
You see, it’s not a fight.
They’re training each other.
It’s not like Boobur is just
taking down opponents for no reason.
This is a place humans
should not interfere with.
It’s the Pokémon’s
very own dojo.
Do you think Iwanko was
practicing his moves here-roto?
That just makes me want
his data even more-roto!
Welcome back.
Are you okay?
You’re awesome!
You looked so cool,
facing all those strong opponents!
Hey, you know how
you started glowing here earlier?
The Professor said
that might have been a move of some kind.
You wanna train with me?
To master your new move!
Pikachu says he’s helping, too.
Why would you go so far-roto?
I’m not really sure,
but I feel like I can’t turn my back on him.
What more reason do I need?
Can’t turn your back on him...
Can’t turn your back on h—
“Can’t turn your back on him”
has been learned-roto!
What do you think, Iwanko?
Use an amazing move to win...
...against that Boobur!
Owww!
That hurts!
Iwanko is probably
trying to learn Rock Throw.
Rock Throw?
Yeah, one of the most basic moves
for Rock-type Pokémon.
A move that launches rocks
at the opponent.
It should be particularly effective
on the Fire-type Boobur-roto!
I see.
Listen up, Iwanko!
Focus your power right here!
And then you...
Well?
Amazing, yeah?
You can do that, too!
You know, when you were thinking how
you refused to lose to Boobur,
you glowed here, yeah?
Whenever we feel all “Ghhh,”
during battling,
we always get ourselves fired up,
like, “Whooooo!”
then our power flares up,
like, “Kaaaaah!”
and our moves jet out,
like, “Ka-pow!”
Right, Pikachu?
You just spouted a bunch of onomatopoeia.
How was that an explanation-roto?
You do get it!
Then let’s go all “Whoooo!”
and do this!
You, too, Pikachu!
Training part one:
Power up to give birth to a new move!
Time to run!
Mokuroh! Don’t get left behind!
Will this even work-roto?
Seems interesting.
I quite like Satoshi’s approach.
I can’t find any
logical basis for it, though-roto...
Don’t worry about it.
Their willpower is what matters.
Did you see
Satoshi’s eyes, Rotom?
Satoshi’s eyes?
Satoshi was speaking to
Iwanko’s eyes.
He wasn’t speaking with words,
but with willpower!
Watch closely.
See through his movements!
One! Two! One! Two! One! Two!
One! Two! One! Two!
Just standing around waiting
won’t get us anywhere
Willpower...
Does not compute.
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl
all turn to look in awe
Bakugames! Flamethrower!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing,
naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere,
it’s almost too much
Impressive!
Now let’s keep going on and on
and on and on and on!
Did you see that?
Just dodge like he did.
The Flamethrower is harmless
if it misses you!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
Well, sure, but...
For heated battles, I choose you!
(For heated battles, I choose you!)
Kaki, one more time!
Flamethrower!
Now, let’s finish it! I got you!
(Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint
with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage
will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
Focus your power
in your backside!
With your full body and soul,
give it all you’ve got
Just wiggle it real good!
All right, Iwanko! Bring it on!
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Faster!
Now!
For heated battles, I choose you!
(For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you!
(Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
That was great, Iwanko!
Hey, Satoshi...
Using yourself as the target...
That’s just too crazy!
Sun, sun, burn hotter!
Just get back up if you fall!
Doesn’t it hurt?
It has to hurt!
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage
flares up and explodes! (Ay-ya-ya!)
Great, Iwanko! One more time!
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint
with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage
will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
All right!
With your full body and soul,
and every last bit of your power
You did it, Iwanko!
Ouch!
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Give yourself one more push,
just give it all you’ve got
You got Rock Throw!
You can do it now, I’m sure!
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Everybody look at this-roto!
Lugarugan?
At Iwanko’s eyes-roto!
You wanna be like that?
Even stronger, huh?
I get it. They are really cool!
Professor!
Yeah. The time has come!
We’re pretty far away-roto.
Doesn’t matter,
as long as we can see.
Good, Iwanko!
Here it comes!
He’s preparing a Rock Throw-roto!
Finish it, Iwanko!
No way!
He did it!
It’s super effective-roto!
Well done, Iwanko!
But Satoshi, I can’t believe you’d go this far
just because you “can’t turn your back on him”-roto!
It shouldn’t be that surprising.
Hey, Iwanko.
Your Rock Throw was the best!
Ow, ow, ow, ow...
Satoshi.
This is just a suggestion, but...
Why don’t you catch that Iwanko?
Unbelievable!
Catch him...?
Really, Professor?
He’s been in your care
for so long, hasn’t he?
It’s fine.
You’re the one he
trusts the most right now.
You helped him perfect Rock Throw
and defeat Boobur.
You’d be the best partner
for Iwanko!
Yeah.
Iwanko...
What do you think?
All right...
Then, come with us!
I got Iwanko!
Come out, Iwanko!
All right, training part two:
Time to run!
“Running” was both part one and two
of his training-roto...
That’s Satoshi’s way.
We’re running, too, Rotom!
What?!
Satoshi has gained
a new partner: Iwanko!
Make sure you keep
watching their exploits!
Roto!
To be continued!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Iwanko!
It seems like everybody thought
Iwanko was my Pokémon.
The Puppy Pokémon Iwanko
is a Rock type.
When he first came to my house, he was wobbling
from hunger, looking like he’d used Teeter Dance,
so I gave him some Pokémon food,
but then he ended up
just staying with me.
It seems he liked
my special blend of Pokémon food!
All right, Iwanko!
Where’s Mokuroh?
Sharp as ever!
Next episode
I want a bed fit for a princess
in our secret base!
It’d just get in the way!
Are you saying no?
It’s essential
for a young maiden!
Those are really expensive, meow.
Right, I got it!
I’ll make one!
You will?!
You’re such a man’s man,
Kojiro, meow!
Leave it all to me!
First, I gotta pick out the materials!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Tiny Trio on a Big Adventure!
Next time