Alola!
I’ll be giving you today’s PokéProblem!
Kapu-Kokeko
Kapu-Tetefu
Kapu-Bulul
Kapu-Rehire
Who do I battle in today’s episode?
Blue: Kapu-Kokeko?
Red: Kapu-Tetefu?
Green: Kapu-Bulul?
Or Yellow: Kapu-Rehire?
Get the answer at the end!
It’s Satoshi and the others’
fourth day on Poni Island.
Having seen off
Suiren’s master, I'a,
they've returned to the Pokémon Center
and now enjoy Mao’s homemade breakfast.
What is this?
It’s delicious!
It’s pot-au-feu.
These malasada doughnuts
are great, too!
As are the cookies!
They’re all made from
Poni Radishes!
Mao’s a genius...
That’s unusual...
I’m sleep-deprived.
‘Cause of the balloon training.
Suiren and Māmane both accomplished
their research project goals-roto!
The rest of you,
do your best, too-roto!
Of course!
That’s right! I wanted to have
Hāpu'u taste this food, too!
Today’s the day
I battle Kapu-Rehire!
I was thinking the same.
You, too, Kaki?
My project is to surmount
my current self.
I’ve honed my skills in the great wilderness
over the past few days...
But to finish my training,
I want to battle Kapu-Rehire!
Well, then let’s look for
Kapu-Rehire together!
First, we have to offer our prayers
at the Ruins of Paradise,
to show respect towards
the Guardian Deity!
Okay!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Run, Kaki! Surpass Yourself!!
Alola, Hāpu'u!
Alola!
What brings you here?
I had something I wanted to ask you.
Ask me?
Ta-dough!
Look! Cookies, malasada doughnuts, and pot-au-feu,
all made from Poni Radishes!
What of it?
My family runs a cafeteria
on Melemele Island,
so I’ve been wanting to try and make
some new, Poni Radish-based menu items!
Since you know so much about Poni Radishes,
I wanted to have you taste them,
and get your thoughts!
I see. That is a simple request!
Really?!
All right!
Wonderful!
But let me make one thing clear first.
Poni Radishes taste best
when eaten unprocessed!
Unprocessed?
Behold!
You simply take the morning harvest,
cleanse it and then bite into it!
Delicious!
You have a taste, as well.
Got it!
It’s just like Ms. Joy said!
Hāpu'u’s radishes are mellow
without losing the spiciness,
and have a rich taste to them!
They’re delicious!
I wanna try some, too!
As do I!
Why are you in such a hurry?
Because you’re hurrying.
Can’t we just walk side by side?
Sure.
C’mon, slow down already!
I will if you do!
You really can’t stand losing,
can you?
Well, neither can you!
Fine, let’s race, then!
Not fair!
Wait-roto!
Whoever reaches the Ruins of Paradise first
gets to battle Kapu-Rehire!
Fine by me!
First to touch that rock wins!
I win!
I was just a tiny bit faster!
No, I was faster!
I’ll verify it using
video footage-roto!
You arrived at
exactly the same time-roto.
Well, then let’s have Kapu-Rehire decide
who gets to battle first!
Fine.
The entrance to the Ruins of Paradise
will reveal itself here at low tide-roto.
I see.
Then let us offer our prayers to
the Guardian Deity of Poni Island!
O, Kapu-Rehire! I am one who strives to better himself
through rigorous daily training!
I have come to you today
because—
I wanna battle you,
Kapu-Rehire!
Come out!
Hey, now!
Do you have any idea
how crude that sounds?!
Well in that case,
let’s battle, Kaki!
You and me? Why?
When I was battling Gladio the other day,
I caught a glimpse of Kapu-Rehire.
So if you and I have
an even more heated battle,
it might show itself for real!
I see.
All right!
How’s a Double Battle sound
if you want something more heated?
Okay! Come out, Nyaheat!
One! Two! Three! Four!
Two! Two! Three! Four!
All right, let’s go, Oshamari!
Good, keep it up!
Try again!
Oh, my!
W-What’s wrong?
I am astonished!
This truly is delicious!
Oh, my!
What a relief! Simmering Poni Radishes
brings out their sweetness.
I see! They are quite delicious
when eaten raw, too,
but this certainly has its own appeal!
Try this, too!
Very well...
...or so I would like to say,
but I must get to work in the field.
Well, then I want to help you!
Me, too!
And me.
Ready... Go-roto!
Pikachu, use Lightning Speed
on Bakugames!
Nyaheat, you use Fire Fang
on Garagara!
Bakugames! Dragon Tail!
Garagara,
counter with Iron Head!
They’re evenly matched-roto!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Nyaheat, use Nitro Charge!
Bakugames! Shell Smash!
Awesome!
Garagara, use Bone Boomerang on Pikachu!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Nyaheat, use Ember
on Bakugames!
Bakugames! Flamethrower!
Are you all right, Nyaheat?
Right! Use Revenge!
Pikachu, you use Iron Tail!
Bakugames! Trap Shell!
Garagara, you use Shadow Bone!
Kaki, I’m having so much fun!
This is awesome!
Same here, Satoshi!
And I’m just getting started!
It’s the burning friendship
of two rivals-roto!
What?
Mist?
We can’t see anything like this.
Satoshi, it’s not safe to move around
when you can’t see.
You should stay still.
Satoshi?!
Behold.
If you wish not to break them during harvest,
then you must pull them straight upwards.
Quite informative!
Let us try, too!
How exciting!
Waku waku!
Certainly.
Will you be all right?
Of course!
Kuwagannon, let’s do this!
Carefully...
All right, now fly up, slowly.
Remarkable!
You did it!
Great job, Kuwagannon!
Satoshi, where are you?
Are you all right?!
Kaki!
I can’t get out!
Satoshi, Bakugames, Garagara!
I’ll save you!
Kaki!
What is this?!
Why, you...!
Are you okay?!
Yeah...
Kapu-Rehire!
Kapu-Rehire is enraged.
Who are you?
Do you still fail to realize
that you have committed a most grave sin?
A grave sin?
You have harmed
this sacred ground!
What? How did we harm...?
Come to think of it...
That wasn’t on purp—
Those who sin on this sacred ground
must pay for it with their lives!
W-With our lives?!
Kapu-Rehire, I’m sorry!
They’re all dear friends of mine.
Please, forgive them!
What is this?
A water clock.
Water clock?
If you wish to quell
Kapu-Rehire’s rage,
then bring
Kapu-Tetefu’s scales here!
Kapu-Tetefu’s scales?
Indeed.
You have until all the water in the clock
has moved to the other side.
Take any more time than that,
and your friends will pay the price.
Oh, no...
That is the only way by which
their lives may be spared!
I understand.
Kaki!
I’ll be back before
time runs out, I swear!
Satoshi, look after them!
Sorry... Take care
of yourself, Kaki!
Lizardon,
we’re going to Akala Island!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kuwagannon
Type:   Bug/Electric
Taking a nap after training
is the best...
Mao’s special Poni Radish Doughnuts
are the best!
Have some cookies, too.
Much obliged.
Oh, my!
It feels as if my cheeks
are melting!
Glad to hear it!
The pot-au-feu, the doughnuts
and the cookies are all outstanding!
You should just add them all
to the Aina Cafeteria menu!
I agree!
Yeah!
But I’d like to implement some
traditional Poni Island cuisine, too, while I’m at it!
Well, then,
perhaps some Fluffy Radish?
Fluffy Radish?
Grandfather used to
make them for me.
I wanna give it a try!
It’s done!
How did I do?
We shall see.
Everybody, give it a taste.
Thanks for the food!
It’s delicious!
It still has the crispness
of the Poni Radish!
You could eat this as a snack!
Indeed,
this taste brings me back.
Really? All right!
I got your approval,
so this might be perfect for the cafeteria menu!
I see Akala Island!
O, Kapu-Tetefu, Guardian Deity
who watches over Akala Island!
Come forth!
Please!
Please show yourself,
Kapu-Tetefu!
I have a request!
Please share your scales with me!
My friend’s life is in danger!
I need your scales!
What’s this?
Is it challenging us
to a battle, Lizardon?
All right, let’s do this!
Flamethrower!
Lizardon!
Good! Now use Slash!
Fire Punch!
Dodge!
Good, shake it off!
We’ll lose if this goes on...
What can we do?
Are you scared?
N-Not at all!
You need to be one with Lizardon,
both in body and spirit.
Then your fears will fade.
I’m not even scared!
That’s the spirit. Now let’s go!
Turning Swallow Strike!
You’d better shape up, if you want to be
a wielder of the life-nourishing flames!
Be one, both in body and spirit... That’s right!
Watch over me, Grandfather!
Lizardon, let’s do this, together!
Turning Swallow Strike!
Kapu-Tetefu!
Thank you, Kapu-Tetefu.
We have to hurry!
You may run, if you wish.
Do so, and we will claim
Kaki’s life in place of yours.
What do you mean-roto?
He abandoned you and fled.
He will not return.
Kaki would never do that!
Are you quite certain?
I know he’ll be back!
We’re friends!
Oh, so you will not leave?
I’ll wait for Kaki!
All right,
we’re back at Poni Island!
We can still make it!
Lizardon, are you all right?!
You did well
to carry me this far.
Thank you.
Leave the rest to me!
Thank you for today.
It was fun!
I had fun, as well.
Really?
Does that mean we can
come visit again?
But of course!
You will always be welcome!
We’ll come again, for sure!
Well, then...
Take care on your way home!
Of course!
I must make it clear, I certainly did not
call you out because I felt lonesome!
Satoshi, if it’s...
If it’s to protect people or Pokémon...
To protect my friends...
Then I’ll ignite my soul
like a burning flame!
That’s what it means to be
a wielder of the life-nurturing flames!
Time is nearly up.
He did not return.
Kaki!
Are you all right?
Am I on time?
Yes, you just barely made it.
Lizardon?!
Lizardon!
It’s back to perfect health-roto!
Is this...?
A Flying-Z!
That Lizardon of yours can
use Turning Swallow Strike, can it not?
How did you know?
Never you mind
such trivial details...
Let your Lizardon unleash its Z-Move with its courageous wings!
All right! Let’s go, Lizardon!
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become the burning wind that
flies across the fields of Akala!
Final Dive Crash!
Awesome!
I got it-roto!
According to the great Alolan Detective Rotom’s
infallible deduction,
this was most likely a Trial
Kapu-Rehire set up for Kaki-roto!
A Trial for me?
Really?
Huh?
Come to think of it,
where is Kapu-Rehire?
Hey... The old guy is gone, too!
Who was that old man?
Good question...
Kaki has overcome Kapu-Rehire’s Trial
and obtained the Flying-Z.
And Mao has developed her new menu.
But the research projects
on Poni Island will continue!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
I battled Kapu-Tetefu!
The Pokémon who gave me
my Trial, Kapu-Rehire,
is the Land God Pokémon
and a Water/Fairy type.
It’s said that ocean currents are
the source of its energy,
and that it confuses enemies
with its deep fog.
That fog sure gave me
some trouble, all right!
I’m really tired after all
that’s happened today!
That was great!
Huh? Kaki?
He’s asleep?
Next episode
Kaki said he’s going to bed early.
What? But he promised me
he’d show me the Final Dive Crash...
Want me to go get him?
You can’t!
Let him sleep!
That’s right!
Why are you being so loud?
He can’t what?
Sheesh, quiet down...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters...
Sun & Moon...
Within Kapu-Rehire’s Mist.
Next time
Within Kapu-Rehire’s Mist