I am Hala!
I will present today’s PokéProblem.
Hala (Yours truly)
Lychee
Kuchinashi
Hapu'u
-
Who serves as referee today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I am Hala!
The first match of the
Alola Pokémon League semifinals...
...was an intense showdown
between Kaki and Gladio.
Gladio was the winner.
But the two acknowledged
each other as rivals,
and promised to battle again.
The second match was between
Satoshi and Guzma.
Gusokumusha fled
from Nyaheat’s attack,
and Hassam entered the battlefield.
But Hassam was immediately
defeated by Nyaheat.
Gusokumusha’s selfish actions
enraged Guzma.
Now the battle enters its second half!
Was it part of his plan
for Hassam to come out?
The timing seemed strange.
Yeah. It was anything but helpful...
It completely backfired on him.
Does not compute.
Poor Hassam.
Gusokumusha.
This is your last chance. Get it?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Guzma the Undefeated Emperor!
Now, Hassam has
been incapacitated,
and Gusokumusha is
back on the battlefield.
What will it do against Nyaheat?
That didn’t go exactly according to plan,
but my victory is still certain.
Your Pokémon’s
a worn-out wreck!
Counting on you, Nyaheat!
Ugh! I’m ending this right now!
Poison Jab!
Dodge it, Nyaheat!
Nyaheat!
Nyaheat was poisoned!
See? I told you so!
Finish it off with Throat Chop!
Nyaheat! Fire Fang!
Nyaheat!
Nyaheat is unable to battle!
Made me sweat...
Thank you, Nyaheat.
Kid, send out
your next Pokémon.
Pikachu, I choose you!
Competitor Satoshi
sends out Pikachu!
Now both sides are down to
their last Pokémon!
I wasn’t sure what you’d call out,
but I didn’t expect that one.
You wanna get thrashed again?
You’ll get no mercy this time.
Go home while you have the chance.
I won’t run away!
You never know what’s gonna happen
until the battle’s over!
Try all you want...
You can never beat me!
Weaklings should know their place!
Yo, yo!
We’re the unbeatable Team Skull!
Our boss is the undefeated
Mr. Guzma! Woo!
We’re the unbeatable Team Skull!
The undefeated Guzma...
Huh? Ya say somethin’, Big Sis?
Nothing.
I’ll teach you that
some things in this world...
...just can’t be conquered!
Poison Jab!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
Aqua Break!
Throat Chop!
Pikachu!
Gusokumusha’s Throat Chop hit its mark!
Pikachu has taken massive damage!
Calm down, Togedemaru!
That Gusokumusha really is strong.
Yeah. So strong.
I am strong.
Guzma hasn’t changed, I see.
Yeah...
It is quite regrettable.
He had considerable talent.
But he failed to learn
the most important thing.
Had he learned that,
he could have grown so much more.
Go, Mr. Guzma!
Ya can win!
Guzma... You’re their hope.
Wherever you go in the world,
there’ll always be...
...those who have failed, run away,
and don’t know what to do.
Not everyone can be
optimistic all the time.
You gave those guys
a place to call home.
Can you go on, Pikachu?
Just give up and accept your loss!
No!
We won’t give up!
What is with this kid?!
There’s no way this kid could...
Gusokumusha! Pin Missile!
Electroweb!
100,000 Volts!
It blocked the super effective
Electric-type move!
That won’t work!
I know!
So...
Iron Tail!
Then another 100,000 Volts!
It can’t block this!
A 100,000 Volts straight to the gut!
Gusokumusha’s defense
has finally crumbled!
Amazing!
How can this be...?
I’m being pushed into a corner?!
You did it, Pikachu!
Both Pokémon
are heavily damaged!
Who will be the winner?!
Satoshi and Pikachu
still have their Z-Move-roto!
Now’s your chance!
Go!
M-Mr. Guzma’ll be fine...
Won’t he?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Warrgle
Type:   Normal/Flying
What is this?
I really can’t stand the look
in this kid’s eyes!
Warrgle! Brave Bird!
That’s enough for today!
You’ve gotten a lot better.
You should just try improving your teamwork
with Gusokumusha a bit more.
Why? Why can’t I beat him?!
That high-and-mighty
“I’ll follow the righteous path” attitude of yours...
...really gets on my nerves!
I’ve had enough of your “Trials” and
“Offer gratitude to the nature of Alola” drivel!
Guzma...
Guzma!
Makes my skin crawl...
Kukui... And this kid!
If I’m gonna lose to this brat,
then I might as well use those guys
to wreck this whole League!
Mr. Guzma?
What’s goin’ on?
I know what you’re thinking.
You’re afraid to lose, right?
Mr. Guzma was
so cool today, too!
Team Skull ain’t got no equals, long as
we got the undefeated Mr. Guzma on our side!
Right, Mr. Guzma?
Guzma the undefeated...
Of course, because you only take on
fights you can win.
You and Gusokumusha
are a lot alike.
Hiding behind your armor, running and running
so that you can’t get hurt any more...
But can you really
keep going like that forever?
Big Sis?
What? Quit being nosy!
Now!
You...!
Pikachu, go!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Here comes the Z-Move!
It’s a Sparking Gigavolt!
What happened-roto?
I can’t believe it withstood
the Sparking Gigavolt!
Awesome!
Gusokumusha really is strong!
Gusokumusha...
You wanna keep going?
I see... You’re not gonna
run away anymore?
Why?! Why can’t I beat him?!
That high-and-mighty
“I’ll follow the righteous path” attitude of yours...
...really gets on my nerves!
Ya really are
the undefeated Mr. Guzma!
When I’m Champion,
I’ll make sure you’ll never hold another League!
Are you just going to
run away like that again?
Just like you ran from the Island Pilgrimage,
and the Island King?
Guzma!
What is wrong with you?!
Fine! Let’s see
how far we can go!
Pin Missile!
Lightning Speed!
Iron Tail!
Aqua Break!
Damp from the morning rain,
the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Electroweb!
As if! Gusokumusha!
Gazing on the clear blue sky,
Poison Jab!
we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise,
What a fight!
Neither side is backing down!
as the clock marks the new day
Both continue to dazzle!
I refuse to fall here
after getting this far.
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
We will win!
Go, Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Aqua Break!
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page,
your memories on the last
You are on a great journey,
a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Gusokumusha is unable to battle!
The winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
You did it, Pikachu!
They did it!
Incredible!
All right!
I’ve got their victory
on video-roto!
Take a nice, long break, Pikachu.
Let’s go.
Competitors Satoshi and Guzma
have shown us an intense battle...
They’re being showered with applause!
Guzma.
I’ll be waiting for you
in the next League.
Now, only the finals remain!
Competitor Satoshi,
with his heated, aggressive battle style...
...VS Competitor Gladio,
with his calm, bold battling style!
Which of these two will become
the Alola Pokémon League’s first-ever Champion?!
This is the end of the
“undefeated” Mr. Guzma.
Go wherever you want.
That was so movin’!
Mr. Guzma!
Ya were incredible!
You guys...
They all got real fired up
watching you battle.
We wanna have battles
as awesome as that one, too!
Can ya give us some battlin’ tips?
We wanna have
some real battles!
Me, too!
And me!
Looks like they
still wanna follow you.
Oh, wait, Mr. Guzma!
Perhaps it’s time for Team Skull
to take a step forward?
Of course, I’ll be with you...
if that’s what you want, Guzma.
Thank you for waiting!
We’ve restored your Pokémon
to full health.
Pikachu! Nyaheat!
Look at them eat...
Battling sure makes you hungry,
right, Pikachu? Nyaheat?
Here.
There’s plenty more.
The finals, huh?
You’re so lucky!
Satoshi! Give it everything you have,
for all of us!
Fight!
Win!
Of course I’ll win!
Everyone’s got
motivation to spare-roto!
Huh? Where’s Mokuroh?
I look forward to an incredible battle
between you and my brother!
Thank you, Lilie!
It’s finally time...
I can’t wait... Satoshi! Gladio!
The Alola Pokémon League finals
are about to begin!
Will the winner be
Satoshi or Gladio?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
I am Hala!
The referee was...
...Mr. Kuchinashi, huh?
It seems Guzma learned something
from his battle with Satoshi.
Pokémon battles are
a truly complicated affair!
All right!
Let’s get some
battle trainin’ done!
Strike while the iron’s hot!
Let’s try to be as awesome
as Mr. Guzma!
Yeah!
Pipe down!
Do you know what time it is?!
We start tomorrow... I guess?
Yeah.
Guess so...
Next episode
How should we cheer them on
for the finals?
A cheer dance!
Great idea!
With some flashy outfits!
Should I make
a custom shaped banner?
Great idea!
You think too small!
You cheer with
your full body and soul!
Let every last ounce of
your spirit resonate!
Everyone, follow my lead!
Hooray! Hooray!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Sa-to-shi!
The Finals! Ultimate Rival Showdown!
Blaze up! Blaze up! Sa-to-shi!
Next time
The Finals!
Ultimate Rival Showdown!!
Let’s go.
Yeah...
With your full—