Alola!
Today’s PokéProblem will be
brought to you by yours truly, Mao!
Yowashi
Kapu-Tetefu
Larantes
Dekagoose
Which one of these is
the Totem Pokémon who appears today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Well then, Akala’s
Island Queen, Lychee,
VS Island Pilgrimage
challenger Satoshi...
Let the Grand Trial battle begin!
Please give me a good battle!
Okay! Hit me with your full power!
Sure!
Nyabby, I choose you!
Huh? What’s wrong?
Hey, Nyabby! Come out!
Oh, fine.
Then, Mokuroh! I choose you!
What’s going on?
Hey! Come out!
Hey!
Bibiridama?!
Ow...
What?! What’s going on?!
Huh? It was just a dream?
Come on, don’t scare us.
Yeah... You’re such a noisy guy.
Pikachu.
All right! Today is the day I face
Island Queen Lychee’s Grand Trial!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
An Elegant Curry Battle!
Larantes’s Dance!!
Satoshi and his friends are taking lessons from
Island Queen Lychee, their special teacher on Akala Island.
Every day is full of
thrills and excitement.
Hey! Stop fighting.
Guess I have no choice.
All right, everyone’s here.
Then I’ll tell you what today’s
extracurricular lesson entails.
I wonder what it’ll be today?
I look forward to it.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
What is it, Satoshi?
I wanna get to use
a new Z-Move!
So, Ms. Lychee, please let me
face your Grand Trial!
Okay!
Then let’s go right now.
Really?!
Just kidding!
I don’t think you’re ready
for my Grand Trial yet.
Really...?
As you know, before you can
challenge the Grand Trial,
you first have to conquer another Trial
to prove you’re worthy.
I’ll do it! I’ll face the Trial!
I’ll conquer it, for sure!
Don’t be so impatient.
All right, come this way.
Today’s assignment is to make
Akala Island’s traditional dish;
Akala Curry!
I’ve always wanted to
try and make that!
Oh. Well, I’m a great cook, too!
You saw the croquette sandwich
I made, right?
Just cramming a croquette between two slices of bread
does not count as cooking-roto!
Cooking, huh? I’m no good at that.
And I must be careful to ensure
I measure my ingredients right.
You guys are so pathetic.
You mean you can cook?
Of course.
Does that mean
you’ve made Akala Curry?
No.
Oh, you haven’t?
I can do home cooking. That’s it.
I seem to recall that
the traditional Akala Curry recipe...
...required some ingredients
that are pretty hard to get.
Indeed.
Today’s assignment isn’t just
about making the dish.
Finding the ingredients
is part of it as well.
First off, we’ll have you split into three teams
to look for ingredients.
Now we’ll announce the teams,
and the ingredients.
Team Kaki and Lilie get these.
Team Māmane and Suiren get these.
Team Satoshi and Mao get these.
Um... a Mago Berry,
Revival Herb and Miracle Seed?
That’s the one!
That last one, the Miracle Seed...
...is said to be pretty hard to get!
Really?
Hearing that gets me
kinda fired up!
I’ll give you a simple map.
We’ve put markers in the places
the ingredients are likely to be found.
Use those markers as guides.
Got it?
If you miss even a single ingredient, you can’t make Akala Curry!
Understood!
All right, let’s go!
Yeah!
Mao.
Got a second?
Mao, which one’s closest?
Um, I guess the Mago Berry.
Looks like it’s atop the hill.
The hill?
You mean that one?
What’re those?
Vegetables?
Wrong-roto.
They’re Pokémon-roto.
Karikiri. Grass Sickle Pokémon.
Grass type.
During the day, it naps while
spreading its leaves to use Photosynthesis.
Karikiri, huh?
So they’re all enjoying nap time together.
Let’s see...
I’d feel bad about waking them up.
I guess you’re right.
Mago Berry... Mago Berry...
There!
That’s Karikiri’s Leafage-roto!
W-What’d you have to attack us for?!
Karikiri’s greatest joy in life is
using Photosynthesis while napping-roto.
If they get disturbed doing that,
they become very angry-roto.
Couldn’t you have
said that sooner?
What now? Do we give up.
I know!
Mokuroh.
Wake up!
It’s your time to shine!
You see those Mago Berries
growing on the top of the hill?
Fly there silently,
and grab one of them!
All right... Go, Mokuroh!
Hey! Wake up!
Fly to the top of the hill without making a sound,
and pick one of these.
Got it?
Does he really understand?
Don’t worry. Mokuroh
pulls through when it counts.
Mokuroh’s speciality is to approach from the air
without making any noise-roto.
Good... Now he just needs to
get the Mago Berry...
Should’ve figured that would happen.
We gotta figure out our next move.
Of course.
All right, me too!
This is taking too long-roto.
I’m going ahead-roto!
Hurry-roto!
Here they come!
Before they do,
I gotta grab this...
...and this!
Mao, go ahead!
Huh? But...
Just do it!
Pardon me-roto!
Mokuroh!
Fight Leafage with Leafage!
There’s too many!
Are you all right?!
Ow...
I’m fine, I’m fine...
I got the Mago Berry...
What’s next?
From here, I guess we should go to
the rocky mountains for the Revival Herbs.
Searching through this
is gonna be tough.
It might be growing in
the gaps between rocks.
Pikachu!
Revival Herbs!
Finally, a Miracle Seed.
It looks like it’s through this cave.
Right, let’s go!
Which way do we go?
The odds of this way
being correct are 50%.
The odds of that way
being correct are 50%-roto.
So which way do we go?
The odds of this way
being correct are 50%.
This way!
It’s branching again!
The odds of this way
being correct—
Then this way!
You’ve been extra confident
since we entered the cave.
We won’t get anywhere
if we don’t keep moving.
You’re so reliable!
Yeah... Actually I’m just
bad at standing still.
Wait!
I told you, I’m bad at—
Satoshi!
This is why I told you to wait...
It’s a Digda!
I’m sorry I stepped on you,
Digda.
We’re safe for now...
This cave is a Digda nest-roto.
I estimate there being 100 of them-roto.
We have to move without
provoking the Digda.
What’s this?
A Digda whisker-roto.
I know!
Iwanko, come out!
Tell us which way
you can smell this from.
All right!
That means there won’t be
any Digda this way!
Then, this way!
All right, we’re out!
Iwanko, you’re awesome!
Thanks!
There’s a Miracle Seed
here somewhere...
Yeah.
Pikachu, did you find something?
So many berries!
It’s a Miracle Seed!
Amazing!
I can’t believe you found it!
Truly a miracle!
Well done, Pikachu!
All right! Now we’ve gotten
all three ingredients!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Larantes
Type:   Grass
What’s this?
Larantes. Bloom Sickle Pokémon.
Grass type. Karikiri’s evolved form.
It lures in its foes with its flower-like appearance and scent,
and finishes them off!
But this Larantes is more than twice
as big as a regular one-roto!
You’re right! It’s huge!
Then, could this be...
...a Totem Pokémon?!
It’s Petal Blizzard-roto!
Run-roto!
If it’s a battle you want,
you’ll get one!
Pikachu, the opponent’s a Grass type.
Let’s go with a Fire type here!
Nyabby, I choose you!
Use Ember!
It’s super effective-roto!
All right!
What’s it doing?
There’s a 99% chance it’s preparing
to use a Solar Blade-roto!
Victory goes to he who strikes first!
Use Fire Fang!
Here it comes!
Nyabby, dodge it!
Its power is amazing!
So what? We’ll be fine
as long as it doesn’t hit!
Unbelievable!
It called its ally Pokémon-roto!
Who’s that Pokémon?
Powarun. Weather Pokémon.
Normal type.
This Pokémon gained the ability to use
the vast power of nature to protect its tiny body.
What now? What’s happening?
This is Clear Skies-roto!
It evolved?
No-roto.
This is its Sunny Form-roto.
Powarun’s appearance and typing
change depending on the weather-roto!
Another Solar Blade, huh?
Then let’s finish this before
it can store enough power!
Nyabby, use Fire...
It’s fast!
In harsh sunlight, it no longer
needs to store power-roto!
What’s this?
It can use Water Gun, too-roto!
If they’re gonna fight as a duo,
then we’ll do the same!
Mokuroh, I choose you!
Of course...
Mokuroh!
Use Peck on Larantes!
Nyabby, you use
Ember on Larantes!
What’s that?
Using Photosynthesis in harsh sunlight
lets it recover its health-roto!
No way...
Nyabby!
Satoshi, you’ll lose at this rate!
We gotta defeat Powarun first!
Mokuroh, grab on to Nyabby!
Mokuroh, use Peck!
Nyabby, use Scratch!
Are you all right, Nyabby?
Nyabby is nearly down-roto!
Hang in there, Nyabby!
Nyabby, dodge it!
Nyabby!
Mokuroh!
Mokuroh, you acted as a shield?
Thanks, Mokuroh! You’re so cool!
Use Tackle!
Now only Larantes is left.
The sunlight’s faded-roto.
Now’s your chance-roto!
Let’s do this, Nyabby!
Go! This is our full power!
Ultra Dash Attack!
You did it!
We won!
It’s a good thing I took
a lot of Revival Herbs with me.
You’re better now, huh?
What a relief.
Isn’t this...
It’s a Grass-Z!
You’re giving it to me?
Thank you!
I got a Grass-Z!
Huh? So, you really
were a Totem Pokémon?
Exactly!
Ms. Lychee!
Yes!
You did it, Satoshi and Pikachu!
That was so inspiring!
And you two did well, too.
Thank you!
Nyabby, Mokuroh,
you did well, too!
You’re both great!
What does this mean?
Well, the truth is...
...finding the three ingredients
was my Trial for you!
But I got the ingredients
with Mao...
Wait, Mao, did you know?
I’m sorry, Satoshi.
I told her that whatever happens,
she should try to just watch and not get involved.
I see!
You and your Pokémon’s hard work...
I saw all of it!
As Akala Island’s Island Queen,
I acknowledge that you have cleared this Trial!
Does that mean...
I can take the Grand Trial?
Of course!
All right!
In that case...
Say cheese-roto!
Ta-daah! It’s done!
All right, everybody eat up!
Thanks for the food!
You guys go ahead and...
...keep eating...
This is really good!
Delicious!
It tastes great!
I agree!
Eat as much as you want!
It’s spicy!
Satoshi! I heard!
You cleared the Trial!
Congratulations!
Thank you, everyone!
You’re as bright as
a Clear Skies right now!
Satoshi, I won’t hold back.
I’ll use my full power!
Of course, I wouldn’t
want it any other way!
Let’s all do our best
on the Grand Trial!
Satoshi and Pikachu
have cleared a Trial on Akala Island.
Next up, it’s finally time for
Island Queen Lychee’s Grand Trial!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Larantes!
The Bloom Scythe Pokémon
Larantes is a Grass type!
They say it’s the most glamorous Grass Pokémon,
and indeed, it’s truly beautiful!
But its Solar Blade was amazing!
You’d never expect that power from something so beautiful!
Mao, what’s that?
All right, it’s perfect!
Here.
Since Snowball seems to dislike spicy food,
have some Akala Sweet Curry!
Mao!
Next episode
No, Satoshi, you’re doing it all wrong!
Huh? I’m pretty sure I got it right...
Bloom Shine Extra!
Wrong!
Come on... I spent so much time
teaching you yesterday!
Stretch out your arms like this!
Mao, your face looks like an Onigohri.
Really?
Onigohri.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Lychee’s Grand Trial! The Hardest Pokémon Battle!!
Next time
Lychee’s Grand Trial!
The Hardest Pokémon Battle!!