Alola!
It’s me, Kukui!
For the second week in a row,
I’ll be giving the PokéProblem!
Ashimari
Nyabby
Iwanko
Mokuroh
Who’s the Pokémon that evolves today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Go!
World’s End Fall!
Now, Mokuroh!
I won’t let you!
Dainose, use Giga Impact!
Take this, Dainose!
This is our full power!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Now, Iwanko! Use Rock Throw!
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
After watching him battle today,
it occurred to me...
...that your Iwanko
might be about to evolve.
What?
Iwanko, you’re gonna evolve?
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Iwanko and the Guardian Deity
From the Ruins of Life!!
Satoshi has cleared his Grand Trial
against Island Queen Lychee,
and now he and his friends are sound asleep,
anticipating their return to Melemele tomorrow.
Mokuroh!
What’s up, Pikachu?
Iwanko?!
Iwanko!
Where are you?!
Iwanko, come here!
Iwanko! Are you all right?!
You’re covered in bruises!
Iwanko! Let’s get back
to the Pokémon Center, right now.
We gotta have Ms. Joy
take a look at you!
Iwanko...
Could...
...this be...?
Where are you going?
Iwanko!
Find them?
No.
What about you?
They’re nowhere to be found-roto!
I looked everywhere in
the outskirts of Ohana Town, but...
Where did they go?
Professor!
Satoshi?
Hey! Who just wanders off without a word
in the middle of the night?!
Sorry, Professor, everybody...
Iwanko snuck out of the room
in the middle of the night.
So I went to look for him.
I did find him,
but he ran away again.
Could this have something to do with
him being close to evolving, too?
Mine also left without warning
right before it evolved.
It only came back to me after
it had evolved into Lugarugan.
But Iwanko was on the ground,
covered in bruises!
What?
We should broaden our search!
Let’s go, Ashimari.
You too, Amamaiko.
I’ll look from the sky on Lizardon!
Then I...
I’ll run a simulation for
places Iwanko might have gone!
Everybody...
Thank you!
What’s wrong?
Come back by tonight.
You’ll be safe in here.
You can’t go outside.
It’s still daytime.
We can’t let anybody see you.
If only I could take this off...
I’m sure you’d be more comfortable.
Not here.
Iwanko!
Where are you?
Where are you, Iwanko?!
Iwanko!
Where are you-roto?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Kapu-Tetefu
Type:   Psychic/Fairy
Iwanko!
Where are you?
If you’re there, respond-roto!
Satoshi, can you think of any places
Iwanko would be likely to go?
Likely to go?
Could this be...?
Kapu-Tetefu is nearby!
Kapu-Tetefu? Really?
Professor, Iwanko might have
gone to see Kapu-Tetefu!
That’s worrying.
Ms. Lychee?
It’s true that Akala’s Guardian Deity,
Kapu-Tetefu...
...can give energy to Pokémon
using its glittering scales,
but it’s got a guilelessly
cruel side to it as well.
Guilelessly cruel-roto?
Does not compute.
For instance, Kapu-Tetefu loves
playing around in battles,
but due to its strength,
it can often overwhelm its opponents,
leaving them in critical condition.
Satoshi!
Kapu-Tetefu might be
in the Ruins of Life!
Iwanko was covered in bruises.
Does that mean he was
beaten by Kapu-Tetefu?
Stop!
Lugarugan!
Satoshi!
Wait!
Kapu-Tetefu is trying to help Iwanko!
I see! It’s using Draining Kiss!
Draining Kiss?
The Fairy-type move that absorbs
the opponent’s energy-roto?
Yeah.
Kapu-Tetefu is taking the energy it absorbed
from Satoshi and both Lugarugan,
and sharing it with Iwanko.
Iwanko...
Thank goodness.
Iwanko!
The sun is...
This is...
...a green flash!
Iwanko?
He’s evolving?!
Lugarugan!
No data! No data!
He evolved into a Lugarugan who is
neither Midday Form nor Midnight Form-roto!
You’re so cool, Lugarugan!
It might have been the influence of the green flash
that made him evolve like this.
Green flash?
You saw the sun shine green
just now, right?
That’s called a green flash.
It’s a rare natural phenomenon that
occurs at sunset or sunrise.
It’s such a rarely seen phenomenon...
So there’s a legend on this island that says that anyone
who sees a green flash will be blessed with happiness...
Amazing... You’re both amazing!
A-Are you all right, Ms. Lychee?
Lugarugan’s eyes are as green
as the sun was just now!
Since he evolved at dusk,
I guess that makes him a
Dusk Form Lugarugan.
Dusk Form Lugarugan...
Lugarugan is so cool!
I can’t believe he was
a tiny Iwanko until yesterday!
I’ve never read anything
about this evolution in any books!
It’s an “Unbelievable Form”
Lugarugan!
It’s “Dusk Form”.
Hey, Rotom? How do you handle
the data of Pokémon that aren’t in the Index?
I have just now updated the
photograph data-roto.
Next, I need to come up
with a description-roto.
I will personally update and fill in explanations
for any Pokémon that are not in my database-roto!
Sounds great!
It’s a wonderful idea.
I guess the Index Rotom
is evolving, too.
Even now, as a professor,
I still get surprised by how mysterious Pokémon can be.
Human children are just as mysterious.
Sometimes they display growth that
far exceeds your expectations.
True!
We had so much fun on Akala Island,
and now it’s getting further and further away!
Come back anytime.
Give me a call, and I’ll come
pick you up with the boat right away.
All right!
Let’s come again, Lugarugan...
...to Akala Island, where you evolved!
Midday Form, Midnight Form...
Satoshi’s Iwanko evolved into a form
that was neither of these.
What sort of growth will we be seeing from
Dusk Form Lugarugan from now on?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Iwanko!
Satoshi’s Dusk Form Lugarugan...
There are still many mysteries surrounding this unique form,
which is neither Midday Form nor Midnight Form.
Is it combining the good traits of the two forms,
or are the two canceling each other out?
We’ll have to Quash the answer
to that until the future.
Who would have thought he’d
evolve during the green flash?
It was such a surprise!
Pokémon are so complex!
My guess was off,
but I’m kinda happy.
Me, too! I wonder how Satoshi’s Lugarugan
will grow from now on.
There’s so much to look forward to!
Right?
Next episode
Theme: Words that have “kawa” in them!
kawarimi
Substitution!
Everstone!
kawarazu no ishi
Vegetable peel.
yasai no kawa
Impostor!
kawarimono
Brick Break!
kawarawari!
Berry peel.
kinomi no kawa
Musashi, you haven’t been doing any switching up at all!
kawaribae
Yeah! Can’t you say something different?
kawatta
Easier said than done...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Mimikkyu’s Disguise!
bake no kawa
I thought of one!
Let’s hear it, meow!
Next time
Mimikkyu’s Disguise!
Musashi is cute!
kawaii