Attention, please!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Emperte
Goukazaru
Dodaitoise
Lucario
Which of these Pokémon will Professor Kukui use
to battle Melmetal today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Nyaheat! I choose you!
I knew you’d use Nyaheat.
Then I’ll use...
Bring it, Satoshi!
Let’s go at full power, Nyaheat!
The exhibition match between the
Alola Pokémon League’s first Champion Satoshi...
...and Royal Mask, a.k.a.
Professor Kukui...
...has begun at last.
The first match was
Satoshi’s Nyaheat VS Kukui’s Gaogaen.
Their grudge match began with
Gaogaen taking the upper hand,
and Satoshi switched out
Nyaheat for Lugarugan,
while Kukui switched out
Gaogaen for Warrgle.
The battle is now heating up!
Warrgle, use Rock Slide!
Here it comes, Lugarugan!
How will the battle turn out?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A Flaming, Seething
Full Battle!!!
Counter!
Good, Lugarugan!
Impressive...
Now it’s our turn!
Freefall!
Bite attack!
Lugarugan!
Warrgle rapidly ascends!
But Lugarugan’s Bite attack
is having an effect as well!
If he gets dropped from
all the way up there...
Massive damage!
Altitude 400 meters...
500 meters!
600 meters!
700 meters!
800 meters!
Now, Warrgle!
Lugarugan is still standing!
What resilience!
He withstood it?!
I should have guessed!
Stone Edge!
Steel Wing!
Superpower!
Lugarugan!
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
The first one to suffer a knockout
was Satoshi!
Thanks. You gave it your all.
Fight air with air.
Mokuroh, I choose you!
Mokuroh!
Time to show your stuff!
Razor Leaf!
Steel Wing!
Go!
An aerial battle, huh?
Very well!
After him, Warrgle!
Warrgle chases after Mokuroh
while maintaining its Steel Wings!
Here they come...
Seed Bomb!
Keep using Seed Bomb!
Nice work, Mokuroh!
Keep it up!
Oh, my! Warrgle is at the mercy
of Mokuroh’s Seed Bomb!
Fatal Moku Bomb!
You got this, Mokuroh!
Oh, no!
Steel Wing makes contact at last!
Use Superpower!
Go! Brave Bird!
What?!
Warrgle is unable to battle!
All right!
You did it, Mokuroh!
Come back, Warrgle.
The winner is Mokuroh!
Thank you.
Competitor Satoshi is not yielding
any ground to Competitor Kukui!
It wasn’t just Mokuroh’s win.
Lugarugan’s Counter and Bite slowed Warrgle down,
which played a part in securing the victory.
A victory thanks to teamwork, then?
Well, then... How’s this?!
Fushigibana, huh?
That one’s a real heavyweight!
Fushigibana. Seed Pokémon.
Grass/Poison type.
The flower on its back catches the sun’s rays.
The sunlight is then absorbed and used for energy.
Well?
Isn’t my Fushigibana cool?!
The flower is its pride and joy!
My Mokuroh is cool, too!
Then let the battle begin!
Brave Bird!
Fushigibana... Block it!
Fushigibana’s flower
trapped Mokuroh!
The flower can be used like that?
Mokuroh!
Break free using Brave Bird!
Fushigibana is enduring
the super effective Brave Bird!
Mokuroh is completely trapped!
Mokuroh!
Like an iron wall, isn’t it?
You’d better break out fast,
or you’ll fall victim to this move!
Prepare to fire a Solar Beam!
What?
W-With Mokuroh still inside?!
Run, Mokuroh!
Get out of there!
Is there no hope for Mokuroh?!
We have to do something!
I know!
Mokuroh! Feather Dance!
Fire!
What?!
It worked!
Was that the
art of substitution again?!
Competitor Satoshi’s quick thinking
let him escape the Solar Beam!
You’re kidding!
Oh, my...
You’re just the best, Satoshi!
You exceed my expectations with ease!
Another Brave Bird,
and make this one count!
Sludge Bomb!
Vine Whip!
Mokuroh is unable to battle!
After a valiant struggle,
Mokuroh goes down!
Mokuroh!
You did well, Mokuroh.
Come back.
Fushigibana sure is strong.
In that case...
Go, Nyaheat!
There he is...
Counting on you, Nyaheat!
We’ll need your strength
to take out Fushigibana!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Fushigibana
Type:   Grass/Poison
Competitor Satoshi
sends out Nyaheat again!
Nyaheat, how’s your power?
Can you do this?
All right! I believe in you!
Hang in there, Nyabi-chan!
Don’t push yourself too hard,
Fushigibana.
Vine Whip!
Go! Fire Fang!
Awesome!
What power!
Now! Great Blaze!
Nyaheat shows immense firepower!
Sludge Bomb!
Fushigibana is unable to battle!
All right, Nyaheat!
The plan worked!
Very impressive.
Now he’s beaten two.
Nyaheat’s flames
have gotten way stronger!
The heat emitting from Nyaheat’s Fire Bell
has far exceeded my previous data-roto!
Congratulations, Nyabi-chan!
He has done a marvelous job
making Blast Burn’s immense power his own.
Come back, Fushigibana.
Well done.
Thank you, Nyaheat.
Now you can duke it out
with Gaogaen!
So you were sizing up
Nyaheat’s power?
But don’t take us lightly!
I’ve got plenty of tough
partners on my side!
Go!
Emperte!
Emperte. Emperor Pokémon.
Water/Steel type.
It swims as fast as a jet boat.
The edges of its wings are sharp
and can slice apart drifting ice.
So cool!
Are you surprised, Satoshi?
This Emperte has swum all around the world
researching sea currents!
It’s a veritable Explosion
of toughness!
Now, who will you send out?
All right, Pikachu!
It’s your turn!
I choose you!
He faces the Water-type Emperte
with the Electric-type Pikachu!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Emperte! Metal Claw!
Emperte made quick work
of the Electroweb!
Then we’ll fight Steel with Steel!
Iron Tail!
Metal Claw!
He’s positively beaming.
As is Satoshi.
Your dream came true
in the best way possible, Kukui.
Drill Peck!
Electroweb!
It stopped!
Electroweb did its job!
Whirlpool!
Pikachu is trapped in the Whirlpool!
Pikachu!
Pikachu, hang in there!
He’ll be in trouble
if he takes a hit now!
Come back, Pikachu!
Melmetal, I choose you!
So you finally bring in Melmetal.
That’s an opponent
not even I know anything about!
Emperte, we’ll keep going!
Melmetal, give them
a full power spin!
Hydro Pump!
It was repelled!
What?!
Good!
Luster Cannon!
Luster Cannon hits its mark!
All right! That did the trick!
This one sure is fearsome!
Emperte! Whirlpool!
The Whirlpool that tormented Pikachu
makes another appearance!
But... What’s this?!
Awesome!
That’s way too heavy, yeah?
Take this!
Double Panzer!
That did it!
Emperte is unable to battle!
You did it, Melmetal!
Pikachu!
We took out Emperte!
All right!
Double Panzer is so strong!
Return, Emperte.
That was a great punch!
You’ve done well to draw out
Melmetal’s power, Satoshi!
Your Pokémon are
crazy strong, too!
Thank you!
I’m so glad I got to have
a battle so filled with surprises!
Professor...
Now this is a Pokémon battle!
Royal Mask...
...would have gone “Enjoy” there!
And so, Satoshi...
I will defeat you
with my full power!
We’ll go at full power, too!
Go, Gaogaen!
There it is!
DD Lariat!
Luster Cannon!
DD Lariat’s spinning
is pushing back against Luster Cannon!
Guess it won’t go down from that...
Double Panzer!
Grab it!
They stopped it!
Seeing Nyaheat’s power...
...got both me and Gaogaen
even more fired up!
Can you defeat this fire?!
Blast Burn!
Melmetal!
Melmetal is unable to battle!
How’s that!
Gaogaen truly is mighty!
Royal Mask’s ace is
in a league of its own!
That was a good battle.
Return, Gaogaen.
Next up,
I’ll have you battle this one!
Go!
Lucario!
Competitor Kukui’s fifth is Lucario!
So cool!
Looks tough!
Lucario. Aura Pokémon.
Fighting/Steel type.
It concentrates its mental energy
and fires off mysterious waves called auras,
which can crush boulders
of large size to dust.
Lucario, huh?
In that case...
That’s...
It’s an Ultra Ball!
Unbelievable!
Professor!
My next Pokémon is this one!
Competitor Satoshi’s sixth
is Agoyon!
Oh, my! Goyo-chan!
“Goyo-chan”?
It’s Agoyon, so “Goyo-chan”!
An Ultra Beast appearing in a Pokémon battle arena
under the command of a trainer...
I feel the romanticism in the air!
Giving it to Satoshi
was the right choice.
Counting on you, Agoyon!
Show them your power!
This’ll be a fun battle!
Lucario! Let’s go all out!
The unknown Ultra Beast, Agoyon, VS the Aura Pokémon, Lucario!
In all the vast history of Pokémon battling,
you won’t find many examples of a match-up like this one!
Here we go! Cross Scissor!
Infight!
Satoshi VS Kukui!
The fierce back-and-forth continues next time!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon that battled Melmetal
was Emperte!
The Emperor Pokémon Emperte
is a Water/Steel type.
The three horns that extend from its beak
attest to its power.
The leader has the biggest horns.
Professor Kukui’s Emperte
had massive horns!
Lucario! Go! Go! Go!
Get them, Agoyon!
Royal Mask’s Lucario will not lose!
No, Satoshi’s Agoyon is unstoppable!
Hang in there!
Lucario!
Satoshi! Agoyon!
Next episode
What a battle!
Satoshi and Professor Kukui
are both so strong!
Who will win?!
Even my programs can’t
predict the outcome!
Yeah, there’s no telling!
What?
Satoshi?!
The battle is in progress!
You can’t be here!
Yeah, but this seemed like
such a fun conversation!
Don’t you “Yeah, but” us!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Conclusion! Gaogaen VS Nyaheat!!
Got that?
Next time
Conclusion!
Gaogaen VS Nyaheat!!
Don’t you “Got that?” us!