Alola!
Ashimari, Balloon!
Togedemaru,
run the charging program!
Mao...
If you add Mago Berries or Bango Berries
to the recipe you were thinking of,
you should be able to make Pokémon food
that’s even more nutritionally balanced.
I knew I could count on you, Lilie!
I’ll try making some right away!
Thank you!
You’re quite welcome...
It’s just a shame that you can’t touch Pokémon,
despite knowing so much about them...
I can touch them...
It’s entirely logical to conclude that,
were I to put my mind to it...
Alola...
Alola! Out doing deliveries
again this morning?
Yeah. Over at Ula'ula Island.
Ula'ula Island?
That’s pretty far, isn’t it?
My Lizardon can fly there with ease!
Alola!
Starting today, Satoshi will be
studying here at the Pokémon School.
Lend him a Helping Hand
if there’s anything he doesn’t understand.
I’m trying to become a Pokémon Master!
I hope you’ll teach me about
how stuff works here!
Please!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Enter the Guardian Deity Kapu-Kokeko!
Let’s Put Our Z-Move to the Test!!
Satoshi and Pikachu have
recently arrived in the Alola Region,
where they learned about the Pokémon School,
had a mysterious encounter with Kapu-Kokeko,
and have now started
a new life on this island.
Whoa, it’s so cool!
Umm... Is this a Z-Crystal?
Yeah. It’s an Electric-Z.
Where did you get that Z-Ring?
You haven’t cleared any
Island Pilgrimage Trials, have you?
Kapu-Kokeko gave it to me.
Kapu-Kokeko?!
You met it again after that?!
Yeah! I heard Kapu-Kokeko’s voice,
so Pikachu and I followed it.
Kapu-Kokeko was really there,
and then this Ring just floated down in front of me!
Where did Kapu-Kokeko
get that Z-Ring from?
And then?
Well, I felt like Kapu-Kokeko was
telling me to take the Ring...
So I did!
I’ve read about this in books.
Kapu-Kokeko is rather capricious,
and though it is a Guardian Deity,
it doesn’t just help the islanders out.
It has been known to play pranks or
deliver judgment upon people, as well.
And in rare cases, it may give mysterious gifts
to the people it’s taken a shine to.
Does that mean Kapu-Kokeko’s
taken a shine to Satoshi?
Kaki, you got your Z-Ring from
the Island Queen on Akala Island, right?
Yeah, after I cleared her Grand Trial.
Does this mean I can
use Z-Moves now, too, like you can?
Don’t treat Z-Moves so lightly!
Only after Pokémon and trainers
unite their hearts as one,
will the Z-Ring
turn their feelings into power.
And this act must be held sacred.
Sacred?
For the island...
For the Pokémon...
For somebody...
Only those who truly care for all life in this world
are permitted to use Z-Moves.
I don’t know what it is
that made Kapu-Kokeko like you,
but wearing that Z-Ring requires
a great deal of determination.
Kaki...
I’m not too good with
complicated stuff,
but I’ll be sure to treat this thing
with respect!
I’ll treat the Z-Moves
with respect, too.
I can’t promise anything
more right now, though...
Very well.
A clash of 100,000 Volts and
Flamethrower, huh...
That’s great!
All right, everyone!
It’s about time to start
Pokémon Science class!
Principal Okido will be
your teacher today.
Much like this Nasshi
and Alolan Nasshi,
there are many Pokémon
in the Alola Region...
...whose appearance and typing differ
from their equivalents in other regions.
Huh... Ours is a lot taller.
Their faces are similar.
The reason why Alolan Nasshi
have grown so tall...
...is because of the climate
in the Alola Region.
This humid region where
the sun shines brightly all year round...
...was the ideal environment
for Tamatama and Nasshi.
Because of this, it’s been suggested that
Alolan Nasshi might just be Nasshi’s native state.
These Pokémon forms which have been altered
by their surroundings are known as Regional Forms.
Incidentally, this Nasshi’s typing
is Grass/Psychic...
Psychic?
But does anyone know what type
Alolan Nasshi is, if I may asKairiky?
I do! It’s Grass/Dragon!
Grass/Dragon?
Wow, you’re a Dragon type?
That’s awesome!
You’ve even got a tail!
Alolan Nasshi’s tail...
Good grief...
Are you all right?
Alolan Nasshi’s tail moves independently,
and it’s capable of attacking...
I was trying to tell you
to be careful...
You should have said so sooner, Lilie...
You just have to
have a cracKentauros at it!
Experience is
the greatest teacheRoubushin!
Dinner looks great!
It’s an Alola Plate.
A traditional home dish in this region.
Is it good?
Yeah, it’s the best!
I see. The best, huh?
Glad to hear it!
Pikachu and Iwanko seem to
have become fast friends.
Iwanko does seem pretty friendly.
Thanks for the food!
That was fast!
You, too?
Come here, Iwanko.
There, there...
Oww...
Iwanko greet one another by rubbing
the rocks on their necks against each other.
It looks like he
really likes you two!
Is that true, Iwanko?
Ow, that hurts!
It’s me. What’s up?
What? Oh, I see.
That’s a copy.
Everyone!
The Professor gave us the go-ahead!
Guess it’s time to
run the program!
Yeah!
Yup!
Understood.
I can’t wait!
Everyone do your part tomorrow.
Follow the plan!
Of course!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kapu-Kokeko
Type:   Electric/Fairy
I’m gonna be late!
No, I might still barely make it!
Let’s hurry up, Pikachu!
What... was that?
Alola surprise!
Surprise?
Looks like it worked.
Well, of course!
We’ve decided to hold
a surprise welcoming party for you today!
That was the first surprise just now.
The first?
Satoshi!
Your second surprise is a challenge
from Togedemaru and I, Māmane!
Challenge?
You mean a Pokémon Battle?!
Okay! You’re on, Māmane!
Right, Pikachu?
What’s this?
Well, you see...
This is a game where whoever
pops all the balloons first, wins!
Huh?
Oh, just so we’re clear, both people and Pokémon
are allowed to pop balloons.
Pop...
...balloons?
That’ll be a piece of cake!
Ready...
Start!
It’s pretty hard...
Finally got one.
Here.
And another.
So fast!
There!
Satoshi, Pikachu,
hang in there!
Go, go!
You may use Pokémon moves.
O-Oh, right...
All right!
Pikachu! Let’s pop ‘em all
with 100,000 Volts!
Grin!
This is our chance, Togedemaru!
Togedemaru!
Shocking Prickles!
Wh-What’s going on?
Togedemaru has
the ability Lightning Rod.
It can absorb electricity through its spikes,
and then fire off that electricity as an attack!
Togedemaru’s amazing!
Hey, now...
Do you really have time to admire them?
Oh, shoot!
Māmane and Togedemaru
win this battle!
You did it, Togedemaru!
We lost...
Satoshi.
The third surprise is
a battle against us!
Go! Go! You can do it!
A sport that combines swimming and running;
the Pokémon Aquathlon!
Who will win?
Go, Pikachu!
Pikachu, Ashimari,
both of you do your best!
Looking good!
Keep it up ‘til the finish line!
I doubt it’ll be that easy.
What?!
Just one last spurt!
You gave it your all,
Ashimari!
Well done!
Ashimari has a swim speed of
40 kilometers per hour...
I knew she could do it!
Really?
You tried your best, Pikachu!
Ashimari, you were incredible!
I didn’t expect her to be
that fast a swimmer!
Wait, don’t tell me...
The fourth surprise will be
a one-on-one contest between you and me!
Go! Both of you, give it your all!
Go! Go! Keep it up!
You’re neck-and-neck!
Go!
Glad to see they’re so lively!
They’re right in the middle of
the surprise welcoming party for Satoshi.
That’s great to sEevee!
Buoysel!
Xerneas!
The Cross Chop of friendship
is always a critical hit, after all.
Speaking of which...
Are you sure you shouldn’t be
down there with them, Professor Kukui?
I’ll join them soon.
Right, Iwanko?
The fifth surprise is me.
I get it!
It was real close,
but Kaki wins!
I almost had that, too...
That was some fine racing.
Thank you, Kentauros.
Pikachu, thanks for cheering me on.
Professor Kukui! Iwanko!
We’re your fifth surprise!
Satoshi. Pikachu.
I challenge you to a Pokémon Battle!
A Pokémon Battle, huh?
And with Professor Kukui, too...
Awesome! This is the best surprise ever!
But before that,
it’s time for lunch, cooked by yours truly,
the poster girl of the Aina Cafeteria, Mao!
Lunch?
I am hungry,
come to think of it...
Yeah...
Same...
Thanks for your patience!
Here, this is for you.
Is it good?
I’m glad!
I made the Pokémon food
according to the recipe Lilie taught me.
It’s both delicious and
good for the Pokémon’s health.
Tastes great!
It sure does!
The Aina Cafeteria is really popular
for its great food!
I see!
That voice...!
Melemele Island’s Guardian Deity...
Kapu-Kokeko!
It’s my first time seeing it!
Same...
I’m glad I got to see you!
I still haven’t thanked you
for the Z-Ring, after all!
Thank you!
What?
Hey...
I can’t see it moving at all!
M-My cap!
Please, wait!
Satoshi!
Come on, you’re almost there!
Where is it?
Where’d it go?!
Are you...?
...challenging me to a battle?
A battle?!
So the fifth surprise turned out to be
Kapu-Kokeko instead of me, huh...?
I’ve read about this in a book.
Apparently Kapu-Kokeko is
a highly curious Pokémon...
...and it’s been known to challenge islanders
to Pokémon Battles or Alolan Sumo!
You got it, Kapu-Kokeko!
Let’s have a battle!
Electric Field!
Satoshi!
Within Electric Field, Electric-type moves
should become more effective!
That’s real lucky for us!
We’re ready, Kapu-Kokeko!
Get down, Pikachu!
All right! Now it’s our turn!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
All right!
The 100,000 Volts didn’t work!
There’s too big a power gap
between them!
You mean...?
You want me to use...
...the Z-Ring and Electric-Z?
I don’t have any idea
what to do...
But let’s show ‘em
our Z-Move, Pikachu!
Satoshi...
Can he even pull off a Z-Move?
All right!
Go, Pikachu!
This is our...
...full power!
Sparking Gigavolt
The Electric-type Z-Move...
Sparking Gigavolt!
That was...
...a Z-Move?
Kapu-Kokeko!
Wait!
Satoshi!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I don’t believe it!
You two are that strong?
Well...
That Z-Ring...
So it shattered...
That means you’re
not yet ready to use Z-Moves.
You haven’t undertaken
any Trials yet.
I’ll take on the Island Pilgrimage!
I’ll take the Island Pilgrimage Trials, get Z-Crystals,
and then I’ll be able to use Z-Moves for real!
I see.
Sounds great!
We’ll be rooting for you!
Won’t we?
Yup!
Naturally!
Togedemaru and I know lots
about the Electric type!
Kaki.
Come on, now...
Oh, fine!
I’m the only one here
who has a Z-Ring, after all.
Thank you, everyone!
Satoshi and Pikachu have found
their goal in the Alola Region!
The two have taken their first step on a grand adventure
together with their Pokémon School classmates!
Time for breakfast!
Satoshi. I have a present for you.
A present?
What’s this?
It’s a Pokémon Index.
A Pokémon Index!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Next episode
Yahoo!
The Alola Region’s just
the best, isn’t it?!
Blue skies, white clouds,
and the emerald ocean!
And Alola’s famous malasada doughnuts,
coated in golden honey! Can’t miss those, meow!
I know, right?
They’re super delicious!
We’ll play a crucial part
in this new land, too!
Team Rocket’s
moving up in the world!
Don’t miss our great deeds, meow!
Next time, on—
...Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
It’s a Pleasuroto to Meet You,
I’m the Index Rotom-roto!
Next time
It’s a Pleasuroto to Meet You,
I’m the Index Rotom-roto!
Huh?
What’s this voice?
Roto... Wait, what is this?