Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
The ocean floor
The flower field
The bamboo grove
The city
Where do we find the Ultra Beast
that’s featured today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The moon framed by the bamboo
is so beautiful...
Isn’t it?
The tourism center is thinking of making
Bamboo Hill a new featured tourism spot,
with the catchphrase “The hill where
you can watch the moon amidst the bamboo”.
Oh, my! Impressive as always,
vice president of the center!
Oh, I’m not not that impressive!
Māmane, won’t you
come out and see?
The moon looks amazing!
You don’t get it, do you?
According to my simulation,
the moon will be at its prettiest an hour from now.
That’s when I’ll go see it!
Oh.
This is Bamboo Hill on Melemele Island.
It looks like Māmane is out camping
with his parents today.
I must have fallen asleep...
It’s almost time!
Huh?
This isn’t what my simulation showed.
Mom and Dad are asleep, huh?
I guess we’ll wait for a bit longer...
Look!
I knew this would be the right time!
The moon above
the bamboo grove, huh...
Hey, have you heard this fairy tale?
It’s one of my favorite stories.
It’s called “Starship Kaguya”.
A long, long time ago...
A beautiful star, shining green,
fell from the round moon.
It landed in a large bamboo grove.
Surprised by what had happened, an old man and woman
who lived nearby went to look,
and found a bamboo sprout,
shining with a mysterious glow.
This bamboo sprout had a cute, lovable face,
so the childless couple named it “Kaguya”
and decided to look after it.
But as Kaguya grew bigger,
the villagers found that it was
drying up the surrounding bamboo,
and came barging in to complain.
Despite that, the old man and woman
desperately protected Kaguya.
And then...
Kaguya took flight,
and returned to the moon...
...looking like a ship
sailing into the stars.
After that, lots of bamboo canes started sprouting
in the field where Kaguya had lived,
and the people lived happily ever after,
no longer having to worry about getting food.
The end.
Wasn’t that a nice story?
It might be a bit too complex for you...
There’s bamboo everywhere else,
so why is that spot barren?
Togedemaru!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Shine On, Starship Tekkaguya!
Are you all right, Togedemaru?
What’s this?
Looks like it’s buried...
There’s something
over there, too?
Bamboo? But...
It seems to be made of metal.
Here we go...
Togedemaru! Light! Light!
Thank you...
A... A face?
Could this be...
...Starship Kaguya?
It smiled!
Does the moonlight
make it happy?
Starship Kaguya?!
Yeah! I was out camping
when I just stumbled across it!
Isn’t “Starship Kaguya”
that famous fairy tale?
Does it really exist?
He’s just kidding!
No, I’m telling the truth!
It’s all green, looks like a bamboo,
and though I’ve only seen the top,
I can tell it’s enormous!
Wow!
This is a huge scoop-roto!
I wanna see it!
As do I!
Then let’s all go together
once school’s out!
Yeah!
Yeah...
This?
Oh, my!
Hello, are you doing well?
I brought my friends today.
See? Looks just like
Starship Kaguya, doesn’t it?
Yeah...
Wasn’t Kaguya supposed to be
shaped like a bamboo shoot?
If we want to verify that,
we need to dig up its entire body-roto!
Yup! That being said,
I brought enough shovels for everyone!
I get it now!
You told us about this so we could help you dig it out, didn’t you?
W-Well... yeah...
Māmane, you’re pretty cunning...
Fine by me! Let’s all dig it out!
Yeah!
Sure...
Yo! Champ in the making!
Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!)
Now, let’s keep making friends!
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Looks like this’ll take a while...
Yeah...
How big is this thing?
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
The world’s greatest Fighting men go
Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
What’s up?
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
They’re Agojimushi!
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
But why?
Let’s walk while holding hands,
and stay together even through painful times
I see. You brought them to help us?
Thank you, Agojimushi!
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
It’s pretty amazing.
This has to be Starship Kaguya!
Really?
It’s pretty hard to believe.
Rotom! Is this listed in the Index?
Searching... Searching...
No data-roto.
If this is an undiscovered Pokémon,
then I will be the first to record it in the Index-roto!
It could be an Ultra Beast!
If so, we have to contact Mother.
You mean we’ll have to
put it in an Ultra Ball?
But if we do, it won’t be able to
go back to the moon!
And I’d like to
investigate it a little more...
To find out when, and why, it came here,
and why it was buried in the ground...
Can’t we wait to contact the
Aether Foundation until after that?
That is quite logical.
I’ll dig up some soil samples.
There you go!
Let’s go home.
Look at that!
It’s smiling!
Yup!
It smiled happily
while looking at the moon last night, too.
Kaguya, you want to go home,
don’t you?
Back to the moon,
just like in the fairy tale...
Māmane.
He’s really focused.
Yes, he seems to be having a lot of fun.
I’ll leave your supper here for you.
Sure...
All right! Analysis complete!
What?!
Two hundred years?!
It’s been buried there for
two hundred whole years?!
Yeah! I analyzed the dirt layers it was buried in,
so I’m certain of it!
Amazing!
It’s so long-lived!
It’s got my grandpa beat!
Does that mean it has been
growing in the dirt for all that time?
I can’t say for sure yet,
but since it was rooted down there...
Everyone! It’s an emergency dispatch call
for the Ultra Guardians!
But that means...
A new Ultra Beast has appeared!
Let’s go, everyone!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
Alola, Ultra Guardians!
Alola!
Please have a look at this.
It’s eyewitness information
that just came in.
The strong Ultra Aura readings
we’ve got from the surrounding area...
...confirms that it is an Ultra Beast.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Tekkaguya
Type:   Steel/Flying
So it really was an Ultra Beast...
You know something?
I stumbled across that Ultra Beast,
and yesterday,
we all dug it out together.
What?!
What is its name-roto?
We were inspired by
the fairy tale of Starship Kaguya,
so we named it Tekkaguya.
Tekkaguya...
Requesting permission to download
the information on Tekkaguya-roto!
Pixie.
Download complete-roto!
Tekkaguya. Launch Pokémon.
Steel/Flying type.
Launch Pokémon?
According to our data,
Tekkaguya came through an Ultra Hole that naturally opened
above Melemele Island, roughly 200 years ago.
And for 200 years, it’s been
absorbing nutrients from the soil,
producing high temperature,
high pressure gas.
So the lack of growth
right around where Tekkaguya was...
It was because of Tekkaguya...
Just like in the fairy tale.
There is one more problem.
It seems that Tekkaguya propels itself
once it’s stored up enough gas,
but it’s such a powerful blast that
it might incinerate its surroundings.
What?!
C-Could the data be mistaken?
Perhaps.
But if that does happen,
it’ll be too late.
Māmane, it seems you have
some special attachment to Tekkaguya.
I just love the story of Starship Kaguya,
and I thought that if that really was Kaguya,
I wanted to let it go back to the moon, like in the story.
Don’t worry.
All you have to do is restrain it in an Ultra Ball
for a little while, and it’ll be fine! Same as always!
Then we’ll take Tekkaguya elsewhere,
where it can launch safely.
Right.
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-roger!
I found a huge one, meow!
Looks delicious!
W-Wait a sec...
It’s the brat boys, meow.
They’re wearing some strange outfit.
H-Hey, what’s the big idea?!
Why do they have Ride Pokémon with them?
That’s repulsive!
What is that thing?
A huge bamboo, meow?
Isn’t it some sort of decoration?
Let’s get right to it...
Please do.
Go, Ultra Ball!
It bounced back-roto!
All right, let’s try again!
No good, huh.
Why?
Maybe it can’t go inside the Ball
since it’s still rooted down?
Let me have a look.
It’s just like Professor Burnet said!
It’s got tons of gas stored up!
Then we must do something
before it launches its rockets!
Hey, did you hear that?
Sure did!
That’s a Rocket Pokémon, meow!
A Pokémon we, Team Rocket,
couldn’t possibly go without!
This is an incredible find!
We’ll get the Rocket Pokémon!
What a great feeling!
It’s finally taking off...
Oh, no!
Māmane, what do we do?
Is there no way to stop it?!
I really wanted to just
keep watching over it, but...
If all this gas ignites,
the bamboo grove really will burn down!
What can we do... What can we do?!
I know!
We just have to make a wall
that’ll prevent the rockets’ heat from spreading!
A wall?
We don’t have time for that!
I know a way!
Yeah! Let’s do that!
W-What’s that?!
When asked “W-What’s that?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
An intense rustle in the bamboo grove.
A lone bamboo-splitting evil flower
in this bamboo grove cut off from the mortal world!
Musashi!
Read from the front: takeyabu yaketa.
(The bamboo grove burned down)
Read from the back: takeyabu yaketa.
The apostle of palindromes!
Kojiro!
I bid a view bamboo grew through adie...
I bid a...
Nyarth, who messed up
his tongue twister!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket!
What did you come for?!
Team Rocket needs a rocket...
We’ll be taking that Rocket Pokémon!
Yeah!
And then we will become
the true Team Rocket, meow!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Tekkaguya! Hold on until
we can put up a protective wall!
Let us build it, right now!
Yeah!
Got it!
We’ll handle Team Rocket!
Yeah!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
Why, you little...
How dare you, meow?!
Time to show them
the true power of the Great Nyarth Robot Mk. 2!
Team Rocket Punch!
The rockets could ignite
at any moment-roto!
Tekkaguya, wait just a little longer!
Hurry, Lilie!
Yes!
Please, Flygon! Rock Slide!
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Tyltalis!
Hakuryu!
Ice Beam!
Get back, everyone!
Hurry!
All right!
The pests are gone, meow!
All right, let’s go get it!
Team Rocket Punch!
What?!
No way no way no way no way!
What even is this feeling?
Tekkaguya...
Amazing!
It didn’t go according to plan at all...
True. But this is fine.
They found their own way
to send the Ultra Beast home,
protecting the peace of Alola.
This is what the Ultra Guardians should be.
Māmane, let’s go say goodbye!
Yeah!
Take care!
Let’s meet again someday!
Farewell!
Tekkaguya, bye bye!
Māmane, Satoshi and the others experienced
a fleeting friendship with Tekkaguya.
Now then, what kind of Ultra Beast
will the Ultra Guardians encounter next?
To be continued!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Ultra Beast, Tekkaguya,
was in the bamboo grove!
The Launch Pokémon Tekkaguya
is a Steel/Flying type.
It has to have inspired
the “Starship Kaguya” fairy tale, right?
I didn’t expect it to be
an Ultra Beast, but...
I’m glad you got to
take flight, Tekkaguya!
I wonder, did Tekkaguya
make it back to the moon?
Togedemaru, you’re not
a Launch Pokémon.
Next episode
Delicious!
Kaki, your family’s
ice cream is the best!
Isn’t it?
Our farm’s grass is in
a different class from other farms!
Satoshi! This cheese is great too!
It’s grown up receiving the warmth of Wela Volcano,
making it soft and fragrant!
Try heating it up a bit and let it
melt over the food It’s amazing!
And our Miltank eat plenty of it,
making their...
I want some, too!
Listen to what I’m saying, will you?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Protect the Farm!
The Blue Flame Strikes Back!!
We will protect this farm!
Next time
Protect the Farm!
The Blue Flame Strikes Back