Alola!
I, Suiren, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem.
Ghos
Nemush
Ghost
Mimikkyu
Which Pokémon scares us today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Like this?
Yeah, that’s good.
Now do that eleven more times.
Satoshi has gone camping
with his classmates.
They seem to have gotten right to work
on setting up their tents.
Thanks a lot, Amamaiko!
Would you mind lighting
the fire for me, please?
Thank you so much!
Oh, Snowball...
It’s done!
We did it!
It looks perfect-roto!
Very comfortable-roto!
And the curry’s almost ready, too!
All right!
I can hardly wait.
Have you all heard?
About the...
...scary rumors
surrounding this forest?
S-Scary rumors?
People who enter this forest...
...fall asleep for no good reason.
And when they wake up...
When they... wake up...
They’ve suddenly gotten
super skinny!
Like, they’re just skin and bones!
J-Just skin and bones?
I-It’s just a rumor, right?
It flies in the face
of science-roto!
Oh, come on, Suiren.
You and your jokes...
S-She’s right...
Oh, it was just Iwanko.
Don’t scare us like that!
Suiren’s weird story
got us all jumpy...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Musht You Sleep
in the Nemush Forest, Too?
It’s time to eat!
Delicious!
This is the best!
It’s not too spicy,
so it’s very easy to eat.
You think so? I’m so glad!
You just gotta have curry
when you’re out camping!
I’d like to reserve
another portion!
Yeah, me too!
Ask for as many refills
as you want.
We made quite a lot!
Hey... That’s too much!
I didn’t know rice expands
when it’s cooked...
And I made enough curry
for the rice.
So it’s curry for dinner, too!
I’m sorry.
I read quite a few books
about camping,
but I didn’t get to
researching cooking.
You’ve never been
camping before?
Just look at her luggage.
Doesn’t it just scream
“First-time camper”?
Was it too much?
So, what did you bring?
Well... A change of clothes,
towel and pajamas...
Gold Spray and a Potion,
a spare change of clothes...
a spare towel, spare pajamas, spare Gold Spray
and spare Potion... and a spare spare...
I see...
I’ve never slept in a tent or sleeping bag.
I am a bit nervous.
Do you think
I’ll be able to sleep?
We’re out camping, so you can stay up
later than usual if you want!
Yeah!
Gathering around the campfire
and chatting is great, too!
Yeah!
I brought marshmallows,
so let’s roast some!
Sounds great!
I want some!
Speaking of, Māmane, it gets really
dark at night. Will you be okay?
I brought a secret weapon
for that very reason!
Ta-daah!
Now I’ll be able to relax at night!
Denjimushi, you’re up!
Now I’ll be fine
whenever it gets dark!
Wouldn’t a flashlight
do the same thing?
Not even close!
Reading while surrounded
by Mother Nature.
I feel like a grown-up!
Let’s have these after dinner.
Pikachu! Use Lightning Speed!
Block it, Bakugames!
Way to go!
All right!
Keep it up, Bakugames!
Is something out there-roto?
Iwanko again-roto?!
Stop confusing me-roto!
Oh, that also looks delicious!
These, too! Can you carry
any more, Amamaiko?
Huh?
They’re still not back.
How far out did they go?
Mao? Suiren? Lilie? Māmane?
What’s up, Pikachu?
It’s probably Iwanko again-roto.
H-Hey!
Pikachu!
Satoshi!
Hold up, Pikachu!
Wait-roto!
Mokuroh!
You okay?!
You’re sleeping?
Oh, man. What am I
gonna do with you?
I have no data on a Mokuroh
who sleeps this much-roto.
Wake up, Mokuroh.
Good morning, Mokuroh.
Māmane! Māmane!
Gotta lose some weight...
Satoshi? Huh? When did I...
You look like Mokuroh right now!
That’s weird...
Hey, do you know where
the others went?
Huh? No...
Okay. I wonder where they are.
You get hungry too fast, Māmane!
W-Well, I was reading, and that
takes a lot of brainpower...
Pikachu... Mokuroh...
Somehow, I seem to have entered
sleep mode without realizing-roto.
My energy has decreased
by 30%-roto!
S-Satoshi...
Māmane...
Satoshi...
I’m starving!
Just a little more!
Satoshi...
Māmane...
Y... You too?
You look like us...
There’s still more, if you want...
Seconds!!
A-All right...
I’m so full, I could burst!
Yeah!
Finally, I can relax.
Yeah...
All right.
Let’s get to the bottom of this.
We all fell asleep for
no apparent reason, right?
And when Māmane and I woke up,
we were insanely hungry!
Same for me.
Yeah, I was picking some berries,
and then I suddenly noticed that
Amamaiko was missing...
I went into the forest with Suiren
to look for Snowball,
then before I knew it,
I’d fallen asleep.
But I wasn’t hungry.
I was with her,
but I was hungry.
Why was Lilie the only one?
I thought I saw something
just before I fell asleep.
I’m not entirely sure,
but it looked like...
...an umbrella...
Umbrella?
I know-roto!
According to my deduction,
the culprit is...
...you, Lilie!
Me?!
Do you think that a master detective such as myself
wouldn’t notice your parasol open this afternoon-roto?
But more importantly...
The fact that you, and only you,
were not hungry...
proves it beyond any doubt-roto!
But... How could I...
You might fancy yourself a trickster...
But there’s no fooling the eyes of Rotom,
nor the blue sea of Al—
Cut!
All right, that’s a wrap,
everyone!
Why did you cut-roto?!
Because there’s no way in the world
Lilie is the culprit!
First off, how would she
make us hungry, exactly?
Yeah!
Well...
First we fell asleep...
and then we woke up hungry...
They were true...
The rumors...
Rumors?
You mean the scary rumors
about the forest?
Then...
Are we all going to end up
nothing but skin and bones?
C-Come on, it was just a rumor!
But we did fall asleep
for no reason!
We were tired
after playing so much!
We’ve had our curry,
so for tonight...
Go to sh’leep?
Nemush?
Yeah, that’s right, let’s sl—
A Pokémon!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Mo—
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nemush
Type:   Grass/Fairy
Ow...
We fell asleep again?
But there was something
there before we...
I saw something
floating and glowing...
I heard something like
“Going to sleep,” or “Let’s sleep,” or...
You’re hungry, too?
My energy’s decreased-roto!
But I’m not feeling hungry at all.
It’s dark! I’m scared!
Light! Light!
I-Is that...
Leave it to me-roto!
Nemush. Illuminating Pokémon.
Grass/Fairy type.
It sends out glowing spores that
put its opponents to sleep,
then it drains their energy
using its foot-like roots.
So it was Nemush that
drained all of our energy...
If so, I understand why I was
the only one who wasn’t hungry.
I had been spraying Gold Spray on myself
to keep wild Pokémon away!
Does that mean those scary
rumors Suiren mentioned...
...were caused by this Pokémon?
It’s possible...
Huh?
It fell asleep?
Could it be... the light from
its own spores put it to sleep?
I have no data on that-roto!
It sure is cute.
Be careful!
Don’t look at the spores-roto!
Can I open my eyes yet?
You guys all r—
Kaki!
A Pippi doll?
I brought it with me because
I always sleep with it.
I was afraid I couldn’t
sleep otherwise...
I’m Satoshi.
Let’s be friends, Nemush!
Satoshi!
Be careful!
It’ll drain all your energy
and make you skin and bones!
Energy?
I know!
Nemush?
Come here.
Satoshi!
If you want energy that badly...
Take as much as you want!
Bring it on!
That was nothing!
I won’t lose!
Satoshi?
Does not compute...
I get it!
Satoshi’s energy is getting drained,
but at the same time,
he’s getting energy back
from eating curry!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
A-Amazing!
I guess it is... kinda...
Who else could do this but him?
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Seconds, please!
O-Of course!
Thanks!
Let’s walk while holding hands,
and stay together even through painful times
Seconds!
Of course
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Seconds!
Of course!
You’re pretty good, Nemush.
They’ve become friends!
I didn’t know one could
connect like this...
Methods of befriending Nemush:
Updated-roto!
Something’s glowing!
W-What could it be?
Lost spirits?
No, those are...
Nemush!
H-Hey!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Hey, Satoshi, wait up!
Amazing!
Look at all of them!
Where do you think
they’re going?
No idea!
But I’m really excited!
So pretty!
This must be the Nemush’s
favorite spot!
Could this light be...
Yeah...
All these Nemush
evolved at once?
Awesome! Awesome! Awesome!
Mushade. The evolved form
of Nemush.
Like Nemush, they put their foes to sleep
and drain their energy.
But they can also share energy
with those they like.
Oh, I get it!
The Nemush were gathering energy
to help this tree get better!
They say the best parts of camping are
the campfire and roasted marshmallows...
But this is so much better!
Yes!
I wonder if that’s
the Nemush from before?
You evolved, too? Good for you!
Nem... ush...
Hey, guys...
Huh? I’m not hungry!
Me, neither!
In fact...
I feel full!
My energy is fully recharged-roto!
Could this be...
The Mushade’s way
of thanking us?
Satoshi and the others have had
an unexpected, mysterious encounter.
The Nemush’s nature-loving hearts
have lit a gentle light in their hearts.
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Mimikkyu!
Just kidding.
It was Nemush!
The Illuminating Pokémon Nemush
is a Grass/Fairy type.
Be careful of the light from
the spores it releases.
If you look at it, you’ll fall asleep
and have your energy sucked out of you.
But Satoshi overcame it by force.
Incredible!
Mokuroh,
it’s not Nemush’s fault.
Next episode
All right, time for some training!
Let’s go, Snowball!
Snowball?
Not Pikachu?
What are you saying, Lilie?
Satoshi’s partner
is Snowball, right?
They’re a great team,
aren’t they?
They’re like-minded.
They’re great partners!
As are you two!
Me?
Me and who?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Lilie, Take Good Care of Pikachu
Next time