Alola!
I will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Satoshi
Kaki
Mokuroh
Pikachu
With whom do I quarrel
in today’s episode-roto?
Blue: Satoshi, Red: Kaki,
Green: Mokuroh, or Yellow: Pikachu?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Indeed! That was when the culprit
made a fatal mistake!
How can you tell?
This isn’t the first time I’ve solved a case through
traces a Pokémon left behind at the scene of the crime.
Isn’t that right,
my dear Doble?
In that revolting
Mermaid’s Necklace case,
Tsutsukera’s feather being left on the crime scene
provided me with a vital clue,
and this time—
That’s wrong-roto!
The vital clue
in the Mermaid’s Necklace case...
...wasn’t Tsutsukera’s feather,
but Kerarappa’s-roto!
C-Cut!
Satoshi and the Pokémon are spectating
the filming of the popular TV show, Alolan Detective Laki.
But now it seems that Rotom
has interrupted the recording.
You can’t just barge in like that!
The cameras are rolling!
I’m sorry!
Hey, Rotom! What are you doing?!
I’m sure-roto!
In season 2, episode 6,
“The Mermaid’s Necklace Case”,
Tsutsukera dropping the Kerarappa feather it was wearing
proved vital in determining the criminal’s identity-roto!
Check it.
Y-Yes!
It’s true! It was a Kerarappa feather
that was dropped in season 2, episode 6!
I’m so sorry!
I didn’t go back to check!
Really?
Nothing gets past you, Rotom!
Such is to be expected
of any true Alolan Detective Laki fan-roto!
Oh? Well then...
In season 1, episode 8...
What Pokémon did the client have?
A Blacky-roto!
Who was the villain in
season 3, episode 11?
Sam, the director-roto!
What’s my catchphrase?!
You might fancy yourself a trickster...
But there’s no fooling the eyes of Laki,
nor the blue sea of Alola!
Resolution rate: 100%!
Alolan Detective Laki’s deductions...
...never miss the mark!
You really are a fan of this show!
Thank you!
I got to shake hands
with the real Laki-roto!
Rotom, you can’t get in the way
of the shoot!
We’ll leave now!
Good! No worries!
I’m the producer of
Alolan Detective Laki...
George Charanpino!
It’s a pleasure to meet you!
Really, you’re good!
No worries!
A person... or Pokémon, rather...
A Pokémon this fascinating...
...is a rare sight to see!
Would you like to be in
Alolan Detective Laki?
Who, Rotom?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Duo Splits Up?!
Satoshi and Rotom
I’m sure you know that Alolan Detective Laki,
currently airing, is a huge hit with audiences,
and that we’re
shooting season 5 right now.
I never miss an episode-roto!
Thank you!
I’m watching it, too!
Satoshi always falls asleep
halfway through-roto!
But you know, with long series,
you tend to fall into a rut after a while...
I’ve been wanting to do
something shocking, something impactful!
Impactful?
So I was thinking...
...the explosive debut of
a new character!
The dynamic duo of Laki
and Doble gets a new partner!
Well? What do you think?
Pretty impactful, right?!
A new partner, huh?
Yeah! It’s always exciting
to get new friends!
The problem lies in
what kind of partner to give them...
Someone who can work well with Laki and Doble,
while being both engaging and unique!
And just as we were looking
for someone like that,
we meet you!
Good! No worries!
Please, be in my show,
my dear Rotom!
I agree. We can tell some
great stories with you.
Right, Doble?
I’ll do it-roto!
I’ll absolutely do it-roto!
Awesome!
Rotom’s gonna be on TV?!
Hooray-roto!
It’s like I’m dreaming-roto!
Alolan Detective Laki’s deductions
never miss the mark!
So you see, Rotom’s been
flying high since yesterday.
You get to be in Alolan Detective Laki?
That’s incredible!
Yeah, amazing!
But he’s just been doing
Laki impressions non-stop!
I can do others, too-roto!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!”
“I’ll get Pokémon!”
“I’m burning fiercely right now!”
Who’s that supposed to be?
How creepy...
“I’m Mao, the super-duper pretty
idol of Aina Cafeteria!”
“Have a taste of our
super-delicious special lunch plate!”
I’d never say anything like that!
I can play any role perfectly-roto!
You’re so good, Rotom!
Do your best, Rotom.
I will record your episodes
and watch them over and over!
But all you’ve done is imitate people.
Are you sure you can act?
What do you mean?
You lack character!
Shock!
Come on, Māmane,
you don’t have to be so blunt about it!
Do you expect to become a first-rate actor
just by mimicking others?!
Refine your own character
to understand the one you’re playing!
Who is that?
Good question...
Only then will you be able to deliver
a heart-stirring performance!
Director!
What should I do-roto?
Just kidding!
You should just be yourself.
Oh, of course.
You’re an incredibly
rare Index Rotom, so...
...just take that and run with it!
I agree.
The director asked after seeing
Rotom’s true self,
so the regular Rotom we all know
is most likely what he wanted!
Work hard,
and be true to yourself!
We’ll be cheering you on!
I see... That’s right-roto!
I’ll do my best-roto!
All right, then let’s do some practice,
so you can be as Rotom-like as possible!
Um... I-I... have proof that
you are the culprit...
Well then,
why don’t you let me hear it?
My dear Rotom.
Yes, leave it to me-roto!
This footprint left on the scene
is Bakugames’s footprint-roto!
Don’t worry, Bakugames.
It’s just an act.
Since you know,
you leave me with no choice...
I’ll just have to
force my way out of this!
Bakugames!
Oh, a battle?
Sure, I’ll take you on!
Pikachu! I choose you!
Cut!
That’s a wrap, everyone!
The two of you derailed into
your usual habit of battling!
Oh, sorry. I forgot...
Sorry.
How was I-roto?
You were great!
You were really Rotom-like!
Yes, quite!
Really-roto?
I really am a natural at this-roto!
Rotom sure is cocky...
Rotom will be
quite busy from now on.
Yeah... But if you’re doing what you love,
it barely even feels like work!
Rotom... Your data will help me
solve all kinds of crimes.
Please, work with me.
Very well-roto!
I swear I’ll be of use to you-roto!
How was that?
Good! No worries!
You’re in perfect sync!
But I would like for it to be
just a bit more impactful...
How about you perform an action
for the end of your line?
Like this! Make it flashy!
Like this-roto?
I know I’ll be of use to you-roto!
Good! No worries!
And we’ve decided the role you’ll be playing:
Rotom the Pokédex!
Sounds cool, right?
Oh! Yes, that’s amazing-roto!
This should keep us going
for three more seasons.
Yes!
I was only watching,
and I got nervous...
Congratulations!
Now you’re one of
the Alolan Detective’s partners!
I’ll do my best-roto!
Congratulations, Rotom!
I look forward to
working with you,
my new partner!
The pleasuroto’s all mine!
And there’s even more big news!
We’re going to shoot
on-location overseas!
The Alolan Detective leaves Alola...
...and sets off to solve
a global crime!
A new world, a new crime,
a new partner...
All eyes will be on the show,
for sure!
Of course, Rotom,
you’ll have to come, too...
So get ready!
Understood-roto!
Pocket Monsters...
Sun & Moon-roto!
I’ll get Pokémon!
It’s me-roto!
Name: Index Rotom
We’re leaving Alola?
Where will we be solving crimes-roto?
I can’t believe I get to go overseas!
This is awesome-roto!
Rotom...
You’re really going?
Of course-roto!
What’s wrong-roto, Satoshi?
I mean, overseas...
That means you’ll be going
far away, right?
Yes-roto.
Does that mean
you’re leaving us behind?
How long will we be gone for
these overseas shoots-roto?
Let’s see...
At least half a year.
If audience reception is good, we might go on
to film in all sorts of places, and be gone for years.
Try to make that happen, Rotom!
I-I’ll come back when I have
days off and whatnot-roto!
That just means you have no idea
when you’ll be able to come back!
Are you really fine with leaving us?!
I didn’t say that-roto!
You pretty much did!
I didn’t-roto!
You did!
Well, you can’t do this!
I’m not gonna accept it!
It’s not like you ever
caught me-roto!
I’m free-roto!
What?!
Then, I’ll catch you now!
You can’t hit me-roto!
Why, you...!
Fine!
I’m done with you!
Have it your way!
Let’s go!
Yeah, I’ll have it my way-roto!
Snowball likes yogurt and pancakes.
Ashimari likes seaweed salad.
Alola, Satoshi!
How’d Rotom do yesterday?
Who cares?
Satoshi’s acting weird.
Did something happen?
Looks like Rotom
isn’t with him, either.
Alola! Time to start class!
Today’s lesson is looking for
Pokémon feathers in the forest...
...and researching
the Pokémon they belong to!
Understood!
Okay! Let’s go,
Pikachu, everyone!
Definitely weird.
Professor Kukui,
did something happen?
Well, you see...
Feathers, feathers,
Pokémon feathers!
Thanks, Pikachu!
What kind of feather
was this again, Rotom?
The culprit is...
...you!
Cut!
Time to take a break!
How was my acting?
I-It was great-roto!
As always-roto!
Thank you.
After you get introduced,
I’m sure we’ll become
a phenomenal team!
Oh, yeah.
Would you like to come over to my place today,
so we can get to know each other better?
Really-roto?!
I’ll go-roto!
Hooray-roto!
Satoshi, can we talk for a little?
Talk?
Professor Kukui told us that
Rotom is going overseas to film Laki.
I understand how you feel.
Back when I first started
living away from Mother,
I cried and complained so much.
“Which is more important,
your work or me?!”
Lilie...
I thought I understood...
...just how hard Mother’s work was...
Yet I still ended up wondering
why we couldn’t be together...
Ever since we met,
Rotom’s been a pain to deal with...
We’ve fought sometimes, too, but...
...we’ve been together
since I first came to Alola.
I guess it’s true...
It’s not like I ever caught Rotom,
so he’s free to go
wherever he wants.
I believe that freedom
was precisely why Rotom stayed with you, Satoshi.
I believe that Rotom
stayed with you...
...because he loved you!
Watching the two of you,
I always felt you made a great team.
Rotom was a dear friend to you,
even if you never caught him.
You’re right...
Rotom is my friend.
You ought to talk things over.
It was only after a long talk
with Mother...
...that I was able to understand
how she felt.
I learned that we both
cared deeply for one another!
Lilie...
Yeah.
I’ll go talk to Rotom!
Wonderful!
It’s Laki’s room-roto!
Amazing-roto!
You look so cool-roto!
Doble’s just killing it, too-roto!
What’s this poster for-roto?
Oh, that? It’s a poster from a play I was in
back before I made it big.
Look, that’s me there.
That’s you-roto?
It’s not like I got to play
big roles from day one.
At first, all I got were bit parts
with almost no lines,
making me wonder if
I just didn’t have it in me,
and if I should just quit acting.
But being an actor had been my dream since I was a kid,
and I didn’t want to give up on it.
The only reason I am where I am today
is because I never gave up on my dream.
Right, Doble?
Dream...
My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!
I’ll never, ever give up!
What’s your dream, Rotom?
My dream...
The culprit is... you!
Um, Mr. Laki...
Where is Rotom?
I knew you’d be here.
Rotom is right here.
Why’d you tell him-roto?!
Because I thought
you should talk things through!
Um, Rotom...
What-roto?
I’m sorry I yelled at you!
You’re always helping me out...
So I thought we’d
always be together...
But... But even if I want
to be with you...
If this is something you
absolutely wanna do, then...
I’ll just have to support you!
Oh, fine...
I won’t do it-roto.
I’ll do my best to—
I’m telling you I’ll stay-roto.
Huh?
I won’t leave-roto.
Then what about your role
in Alolan Detective?
I won’t be in it-roto.
What?! Really?!
My dream is to become the world’s greatest...
No, the universe’s greatest Pokémon Index!
The best way to accomplish that dream is to stay with you,
the one most likely to encounter rare Pokémon-roto!
Rotom...
Besides, you can’t do anything
without me around-roto!
I’ll stay with you
because I’m worried-roto!
What’s that supposed to mean?!
I’m just being honest-roto!
Wait, Rotom!
Not a chance-roto!
Wait!
I said I wouldn’t,
and that’s final-roto!
They make a great duo...
Just like us.
You can’t fall asleep today-roto!
I wanna see how
things turned out after that, too!
My dear Perap.
Your data will help me
solve all kinds of crimes.
Please, work with me.
Very well-pera!
I swear I’ll be of use to you-pera!
I didn’t expect them to
replace Rotom with a Perap.
Alolan Detective Laki’s deductions...
...never miss the mark!
Let’s go back to Alola,
my dear Doble and Perap.
They’re coming back to Alola?!
That’s right-roto!
George said...
Alolan Detective Laki’s
gotta stay in Alola, you know?
I mean, we’d have to
change the title and everything!
So the overseas location shoot
was just for one episode-roto!
Are you kidding me?
You can keep leaving
the peace of Alola...
...in the capable hands of
Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
Rotom really does belong
at Satoshi’s side!
Keep working towards becoming
the universe’s best Pokémon Index, Rotom!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The one with whom I quarreled was
Blue: Satoshi-roto!
Perap, who took my place in the show,
is a Normal/Flying type-roto.
Perap mimics the cries of other Pokémon
to trick them into thinking it’s one of them.
It can learn and speak
human words-roto.
Hiring Perap was the director’s idea-roto!
Get ready...
Action!
You might fancy yourself a trickster...
But there—
But there’s no fooling the eyes of Laki,
nor the blue sea of Alola!
Cut!
Perap, that was my line...
Next episode
I wanna get Pokémon!
Me, too!
Wait until you grow up.
What do you mean by “grow up”?
What do you mean?
Um...
Grow as big as Kabigon?
Not like that...
Then as big as Wela Volcano!
That’s it!
I didn’t mean it like that...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Anywhere, to Find You!
Next time
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Anywhere, to Find You!