Alola!
I, Kaki, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem!
Poké-Soccer
Poké-Rugby
Poké-Baseball
Poké-Ping Pong
Which sport is played at the tournament
that Ilima participates in today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Alola!
Today’s class will be on Poké-Ping Pong!
And here is your special teacher...
Hello, it’s me, Ilima.
I look forward to working with you again today.
All right! It’s Ilima!
But why is he teaching us?
Ilima has won plenty of
Poké-Ping Pong tournaments!
He’s really good!
First of all,
I shall explain the rules.
Poké-Ping Pong is a Ping Pong game where
trainers and their Pokémon play together as a pair.
You start with a serve.
You make the ball bounce on your own court,
before sending it over to the opponent’s court
in a diagonal line.
It must also bounce on the opponent’s court,
or it will be considered out of bounds.
And then the opponent
hits the ball back.
Here, too, the ball has to bounce once on the
opponent’s side of the field or it won’t count.
This is where the server changes.
The trainer and their Pokémon
have to take turns serving and receiving.
I’m not sure I get it...
It’s easier to show you
than to explain.
I will give you a demonstration.
Suiren, would you be my opponent?
Yes!
Do your best, Suiren!
Well then... Here I come!
His partner’s Doble!
Doble. Painter Pokémon.
Normal type.
They paint individualized symbols
with the fluid that oozes from their tail,
to mark their territory.
You start by making a serve.
Pokémon may use a racket,
a part of their body,
or even a special move
to return the ball.
Awesome!
Suiren and Ashimari are
quite skilled, as well!
All data on Poké-Ping Pong
has been recorded-roto!
Games consist of three matches,
each lasting until one side has 11 points.
Whichever side wins two matches,
wins the game-roto!
Now then,
why don’t you all give it a try?
Yeah!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Smashing With Sketch!
The Fierce Poké-Ping Pong Match!
Poké-Ping Pong, a game played through
trainers and Pokémon working together...
It seems the Pokémon have gotten
quite used to it as well.
It’s no fun just to
hit the ball back and forth...
Then let’s get
a real game going!
All right!
Pikachu, smash!
A-Are you all right?
I’m fine, I’m fine!
We’ll get it right next time!
Now, bring it!
S-Sure...
Here I come!
Go!
Sheesh! Didn’t I just tell you
I had that one?
Are you all right?
Oh dear, this won’t do at all.
What do you think is
the most important thing in Poké-Ping Pong?
Um... Oh! A powerful smash!
It’s gotta be the serves, right?
No.
It’s empathy.
Empathy?
Poké-Ping Pong is a sport where
trainers and Pokémon battle together as partners.
If you forget about empathy,
your feelings and your partner’s will go out of sync,
and you won’t be able to play well.
I get it!
Sorry...
Ilima, what should we do
in order to work better with our partners?
You should strive to bring out
each others’ strengths.
For instance, you ought to determine
who will be on defense and who will be on offense.
Defense...
...and offense?
In other words, defending through a receive,
and attacking with a smash.
You should work out
who is best suited for each.
Pikachu’s an attacker, for sure!
Garagara’s definitely an attacker, too.
Um, I have one more question.
What can I do to become better?
All I can say is, do things the normal way,
because simplicity is best.
Return the ball
when it comes your way. That’s all.
when it comes my way...
I like that!
Easy to understand.
I’m flattered.
All right. Anyone want to
play some games?
Yeah, let’s!
Game 1 is Satoshi and Pikachu VS...
...Mao and Amamaiko-roto!
Let’s go!
There!
That was a good return!
Easy return!
Pikachu!
Smash with Iron Tail!
Amazing!
Did they win?!
Return it with Magical Leaf!
Something smells nice...
It’s a scented Magical Leaf-roto!
For real?!
In that case,
we’ll counter it with Electro Ball!
Amamaiko!
Smash with Double Hit!
Softening them with the scent,
and then delivering a Round-Trip Slap smash...
This is the mythical technique:
“From Heaven to Hell”-roto!
We did it!
Next is Lilie and Snowball VS...
...Māmane and Togedemaru-roto!
Here I go!
This looks like it’ll be
a long rally-roto...
No, I can finish this!
It is entirely logical to conclude that,
if I were to put my mind to it,
I should be able to finish this!
We did it!
The last game is
Kaki and Garagara VS...
...Suiren and Ashimari-roto!
We start with my serve!
Kaki sure is fired up!
Bring it!
So is Suiren!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame Serve!
...is what I’ll make her think I’m doing,
and then flip.
What?!
A feint.
Easy return!
End it with a Shadow Bone smash!
Ashimari!
Good, Ashimari!
Nice return!
What’s more, it’s a drive!
A drive?
A drive is all about spinning.
A ball with a strong spin behind it
will change its trajectory!
An easy return!
Go, Suiren!
Huh? She returned it normally!
I see. Suiren is focusing on defense.
This’ll be an easy return
for Garagara!
All right! Use Iron Head!
Ashimari, Aqua Jet!
Amazing!
The drive is even stronger
than before!
This time it’ll work!
Reach beyond the horizon!
Incoming! Garagara, stand back!
Super Aqua Tornado Attack!
...is what I’ll make him think I’m doing,
and then flip.
A feint!
Just like what Kaki did!
They won’t be able to reach this one!
This is the supreme technique:
“Bone-Toss Return”-roto!
Well done, Garagara!
I was waiting for this timing!
Ashimari!
A total defeat...
No.
It was out of bounds,
so one point for you.
That was fun!
Yes!
It was the best!
Everybody, would you perhaps like
to come watch me...
...in this Sunday’s
Poké-Ping Pong tournament?
You’re participating?!
Yes, though I have
some reservations about it.
Then we’ll all come cheer you on!
Yeah!
I’m flattered.
Awesome! It’s packed with people!
This tournament will decide
which team is the strongest in Alola, after all.
So, Ilima and Doble’s team
won last time?
According to my data,
they lost in the finals-roto.
Actually, there’s this incredible player
who wins this tournament every year.
So, he lost to that player.
What kind of player?
His name is Ikari.
Also known as Ikari the Dragon!
So, he’s a Dragon-type user?
No, it’s the vibe he gives off.
He gives off the vibe of a dragon!
Look, there he is!
Ilima! Did you forget
how I crushed you last time?!
Of course I haven’t forgotten.
Then why would you
come back to Alola just to lose?!
I signed up for this tournament
so that I may beat you.
Don’t make me laugh!
I don’t know how hard you’ve trained in Kalos,
but don’t delude yourself into
thinking you could beat me!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’m flattered.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Doble
Type:   Normal
I’m flattered.
It’s time for the first round.
Ikari the Dragon
makes his appearance right away!
I wonder how he’ll fight.
Here I go!
That Pokémon is...
Kojondo. Martial Arts Pokémon.
Fighting type.
Using the long fur on its arms like whips,
it launches into combo attacks that,
once started, no one can stop.
We’ll finish this in three seconds.
Got it?!
Bring it!
One - Love!
You’re soft!
Aim for the very edge of the field!
What’s with him?
He doesn’t have any of the empathy
that Ilima was talking about.
That’s it! That must be why
Ilima signed up for this tournament.
Ilima must have been frustrated with losing
to an opponent like that.
So he’s come to win.
All the more reason for us
to cheer for him!
Oh! Ilima is on the scene-roto!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Silence! Bringing your impure spirits
into this sacred battleground...
...is blasphemy against
Pokémon Ping Pong!
But you don’t even know the meaning
of the word “blasphemy”, do you?!
What’s that lady’s problem?
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
Gorgeousness is best!
That is what I, Mrs. Gorgeous, believe!
And this is my partner, Sona Sonami!
Aim to become the Serve Ace!
Yes, coach!
Sonami, are you ready?
There!
I’m going for the win!
We can do it, right, Sonami?
Counter, is it?
Then we will use Sketch!
Sketch?
A move that lets the user learn
whatever move their opponent last used-roto!
There!
It’s a Counter battle!
Hair toss, and... On!
This is your chance, meow!
Love - One!
Sonami,
we’re just getting started!
Ah! H-Hey, hang on a second!
Uh, things are just about
to get good!
We haven’t even done
anything yet today!
What even is this feeling?
It’s time for the finals at last-roto!
And of course it’s
between those two.
Yeah!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
I challenge you,
Ikari the Dragon!
Don’t make me laugh!
I’ll destroy you!
That’s all that’ll happen in this match!
Shouldn’t that be
“We’ll destroy you”?
You’re trying to lecture me?
Don’t get cocky!
Ilima!
Finish this with Pound,
Kojondo!
One - Love!
All right!
Right up in the corner!
He really is strong!
Hang in there, Ilima!
Don’t worry, Sir Ilima!
Doble,
the match is only beginning.
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
Learn your place, Ilima!
Finish the job, Kojondo!
One - All!
That was a nice return!
Kojondo!
I’m burning with rage right now!
Because of you, we lost that point!
Finish him off with a return!
He lost that point
because of his own mistake!
I feel so sorry for Kojondo.
Same. But they’re evenly matched!
Finish it properly!
Ilima’s caught up to him!
Now they both have ten points!
It’s a deuce!
I read about this in a book!
A deuce means that both players
have to serve one after another,
and once one of them
gains a two-point lead, he’s won.
They’ve been neck-to-neck
the whole time, so...
Yes!
Whoever wins this round,
wins the game!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Here I go!
There!
Pick it up!
Advantage, Ilima and Doble!
That was an excellent drive, Doble!
Kojondo!
I’m burning with rage!
Miss one more time,
and you’ll pay for it!
This will not do.
You focus only on the negatives.
You ought to say more positive things
and cheer your partner on.
Don’t make me laugh!
I have my own way of doing things!
You really don’t say “We”.
What?!
You can’t win with just
a trainer’s strength alone.
I believe only in
my own strength!
I taught Kojondo
to think the same way!
If I become strong, then naturally,
the team will also be stronger!
That is not real Poké-Ping Pong.
Don’t make me laugh!
You can spare me the high-and-mighty lectures
until after you’ve won!
Ilima!
Smash with Drain Punch!
Sketch!
Hmph!
I will end you with my super smash!
Take this!
Look out!
Dodge it!
I, Ilima...
...will not give up!
Deliver the finishing blow with
a High Jump Kick smash!
Doble!
Kojondo...
Game set!
Ilima and Doble win!
They did it!
They won!
Good, good, Sir Ilima!
You’re the best, Sir Ilima!
Thank you, Doble.
I apologize for
speaking out of line before.
There are infinite kinds of relationships
between Pokémon and their trainers.
I guess there are cases where you can
refine your teamwork through strictness.
We’ll win next time, for sure.
What?
Until then, don’t you lose
to anyone other than us!
Yes.
Please keep being a good rival!
Yeah!
Stay well, stay well, Sir Ilima...
Good bye, good bye, Sir Ilima...
Please don’t cry for me.
I gotta say, you’ve got class!
Going cruising around the nearby islands
before going back to Kalos...
I will come back here.
I look forward to
seeing you all again when I do.
We do, too!
It’s such a shame you have to go,
just as we finally got to know each other.
I’m flattered.
We weren’t together for long,
but I’ve learned a lot from you.
Let us continue
aiming for the top together!
Yes!
Good bye, Ilima!
Good bye!
The group parts ways with
the Pokémon School graduate Ilima for now.
Let’s hope that they can all show each other
how much they’ve grown the next time they meet.
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The tournament Ilima participated in
was a Poké-Ping Pong tournament!
Doble, the Pokémon Ilima had with him,
is a Normal type.
Sketch, the move Doble used, has the effect of
making the opponent’s last move into your own!
Ilima and Doble were an amazing pair!
Feels nice, doesn’t it, Eevee?
I’m flattered that
you came to see us off!
Next episode
A notice delivered to a millionaire...
A secret hidden in a purple bottle...
The search for the culprit transcends time,
and brings us back into the ancient past!
Next time, on Alolan Detective Laki:
“The Treacherous Beachside!”
Resolution rate: 100!
Laki’s deductions never miss!
Sounds fun-roto!
I’ll definitely watch it-roto!
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Lover of Light!
Bebenom Spins Round and Round!
Next time
The Lover of Light!
Twirling Bebenom!!
Rotom’s deductions never miss!
Again, that’s not what it’s about!