Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Guardie
Garura
Gaburias
Gamageroge
Who is the wild Pokémon
that shows up at my family’s farm today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Lunch time!
Takeshi and Kasumi have
come to visit Alola,
and are currently having fun
with Satoshi and his friends.
What will today bring?
It’s great!
Delicious!
Nothing beats Takeshi’s cooking!
Looks like they all have
quite the appetite!
Takeshi’s speciality: Cooking...
Data updated-roto!
It tastes good enough to make me
want to add it to the Aina Cafeteria menu!
It’s all thanks to the cheese
from Kaki’s farm.
Right, Kaki?
Well, yeah... Our farm’s cheese
is the best on Akala!
Maybe even the best in Alo—
Akala!
Isn’t Akala Island home to the
ravishing Island Queen, Ms. Lychee?!
Check!
Yes, beautiful indeed!
A lady handbook...
Sheesh... I was wondering what it was
he was studying so hard on the plane...
Well, let’s go! Right now!
Go? To meet Ms. Lychee?
Don’t misunderstand me.
I’m going to check out Kaki’s farm.
Then I might as well also go
see the ravishing Ms. Lychee while I’m there!
My goal is the farm,
and nothing else.
As a Pokémon Doctor,
I want to know how the Pokémon on Alolan farms
are raised and how—
But Ms. Lychee goes all over the place.
You might not have a chance to see her.
In other words... If we do meet,
it’ll be a fateful encounter!
If we’re going to Kaki’s place,
then I’d like some Moomoo Milk ice cream!
Moomoo Milk ice cream, huh?
Sounds delicious!
That settles it!
So how are we getting
to Akala Island?
I guess by boat... Or by plane...
Feels great!
Doesn’t it?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A Rock-Smassing Passionate Heart!
Lychee and Takeshi!!
Yahoo!
Come out, Ashimari, Sandy!
You’re so quick, Sandy!
Go, go!
You can’t swim, remember?
Looks like the brats are
heading for Akala Island, meow.
Let’s go after them,
right now!
There’s no way we can just
give up like this!
We will get Pikachu, for Sakaki!
But, you know...
We have to fix the
Nyarth Robo Giga Mk. 03, meow.
This’ll take a fair while.
I’m fairly fed up with things taking a fair while!
Fix the thing, pronto!
Right, right...
This looks like a great place
for Pokémon to live!
Its belly is huge!
Eat up!
They really are eating mud!
Alola!
Big bro!
What?
Mom said it’s time for a break.
I’ve been waiting for this!
Let’s eat!
This is the best!
Isn’t it?
Delicious!
You want some, huh?
Here.
Hey!
Oh, for crying out loud...
What was that?
What’s wrong?
A Garura! Is it wild?
What’s it doing here?
It might have
stumbled its way in here.
Garura. Parent and Child Pokémon.
Normal type.
It raises its offspring
in its belly pouch.
Garura’s maternal love is so deep that
it will brave death to protect its offspring.
The mother’s angry.
So it seems.
Nobody will get any water
if we don’t do something!
Should I use Bakugames to
intimidate her and drive her off?
Wait. Look at Garura’s pouch.
The baby’s gone!
You’re right!
Look over there!
It doesn’t seem to
be doing well...
Its leg is swollen.
Does that mean it’s injured?
It could be. I can’t say for sure
unless I get a closer look, though.
Poor baby.
We have to treat it!
It’s dangerous to get too close!
But we have to do something!
I’ll go.
How?
Calculating odds that he can get close
without being attacked...
I’ll go, too.
Me, too.
I’m still calculating-roto!
No, leave this to me.
Do you have an idea-roto?
I am a Pokémon Doctor
in training, after all.
Cuwawa-roto?
Takeshi, when did you get that?
It was a present from Ms. Joy.
You’re giving me Cuwawa?!
To thank you for helping me.
Please help the good
Pokémon Doctor in training.
Ms. Joy!
It’s all right.
I won’t harm you, or your child.
Cuwawa.
Thank you.
There, there... Be good, now.
I won’t do anything to you. See?
There, there...
I know. You want to keep
your injured child safe, right?
Please, let me have a look at it.
I’ll help it get better. I promise.
Thank you.
Hello there, little one.
Will you let me take a look at you?
It’s swollen pretty badly.
It hurts, doesn’t it?
But the bone
doesn’t seem to be broken.
Be good and stay still...
That should do it.
You’re done?
Well done, Takeshi!
Stay still in your mother’s pouch
for a while.
Do that,
and you’ll heal up faster!
Keep looking after each other!
Take care!
Takeshi’s awesome!
He and Garura completely
understood one another!
He’s not just
some girl-obsessed guy.
Takeshi can be pretty reliable
when it counts.
Well then, that just leaves...
Ms. Lychee! Ms. Lychee!
Ms. Lychee!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Garura
Type:   Normal
Are you okay, Takeshi?
Hang in there!
Go!
Ms. Lychee...
Where are you, my beloved?
Ms. Lychee!
Where are you?! Here?!
Ms. Lychee! Ms. Lychee!
Ms. Lychee!
Ms.! Ly! Chee!
How far does fate intend to string me along
before it’s satisfied?!
Long time, no see!
Yo-hoo!
It’s Ms. Lychee!
Ms. Lychee!
Have you been doing well?
What brings you all here tod—
Ms. Lychee! Are you okay?!
I’m fine, I’m fine...
It’s a pleasure to meet you. My name is Takeshi,
and I’m a Pokémon Doctor in training.
Truly, fate had not
abandoned me after all.
Please... marry me, Ms. Lychee!
M-Marry?!
She’s all over the place...
Tripping, laughing, being proposed to...
Ours was a fated meeting,
brought forth by the fires of Wela Volcano.
Fated meeting?
Yet, those flames are nothing compared to
the burning feelings for you in my h—
Okay, that’s enough out of you.
Owww...
You went that far out of your way to find her,
and you call this fate?
It’s a pleasure to meet you!
My name is Kasumi.
This is my first time in Alola,
and I’m out sightseeing!
Today is the day I offer the Crown of Wela
up to the sacred flames.
This is another one of the Akala
Island Queen’s important jobs.
What a wonderful job!
Oh, that’s right, Ms. Lychee!
Do you mind if we take a picture together...
...to commemorate us coming to Wela Volcano
with Kasumi and Takeshi?
Great idea! Let’s take one!
All right!
Rotom, please.
Leave it to me-roto!
Ready, and...
Namakobushi!
Got it-roto!
Hikers?!
Oh, hi there! You called?
Twirl!
I’ve asked them to patrol
Wela Volcano Park.
Their tendency to photobomb
can get to be disruptive, though...
My precious
commemorative photo is ruined!
Bye!
Hey, stop! Where’d you go,
lousy Hikers?!
Oh, Ms. Lychee! Takeshi is a
super strong Pokémon battler!
Really?
He used to be a Gym Leader
in the Kanto Region!
I was a Rock-type Gym Leader!
Rock type?!
Takeshi, would you mind
battling with me?
Really?!
Here I come, Ms. Lychee!
Haven’t seen that one in a while!
Usokki. Imitation Pokémon.
Rock type.
It disguises itself as a tree to avoid attack,
but its body is closer to rocks and stones.
It hates water, so it will disappear
if it starts raining.
It looks like a Grass type, though.
Let the battle...
...begin!
Lugarugan, Rock Slide!
Usokki, use Arm Hammer!
I knew Ms. Lychee would go
straight for a Rock Slide!
Usokki is no slouch, either!
He knocked all of the rocks away-roto!
They’re both awesome!
Very impressive, Takeshi!
You, too, Ms. Lychee!
Thank you!
I won’t hold back, though!
Shadow Clones!
Accelerock!
Can you tell where
the attack will come from?
Well then, Usokki!
Use Sneak Attack!
I didn’t expect that!
Then how about this?
Drill Liner!
It can even endure a Drill Liner?
You’ve raised your Usokki well!
You really are an Island Queen!
That attack had me a bit on edge!
I’m just getting started!
Show me more of what
a former Gym Leader can do!
Of course!
This is turning into
one awesome battle!
Pikachu?!
Sandy! Ashimari!
Snowball!
Amajo!
Togedemaru!
Garagara!
What’s that?!
When asked “What’s that?!” “Ngh!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Unwavering resolve to carry out her goals!
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
There is but one unchanging
path to the truth!
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
Turning the tables in one shot,
all to advance our career!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket?
They’re bad guys who try
to steal people’s Pokémon!
We just beat you yesterday!
Man, you’re persistent!
And that persistence will soon
bring us victory!
Indeed! Perseverance is power!
The latest model of the Nyarth Robot, the Nyavil Oniyarth,
will be taking Pikachu and the other Pokémon, meow!
That said...
We’re leaving!
Byesy-meow!
I won’t let you take the Pokémon,
Team Rocket!
That’s right!
Get ready!
Usokki, use Kick Down!
Hey! That’s unfair,
attacking us outta nowhere like that!
That’s right!
That’s what we should be saying!
Let everyone go, Team Rocket!
How dare you, meow?!
Leave this to me.
Let’s go, Lugarugan!
Ms. Lychee, I’ll help you!
Roar...
Heartbeats of life!
O, echoes of the bedrock,
piercing through heaven and earth!
Go!
World’s End Fall!
...in Love!
Full power, meow!
Good! Push it back!
We can do it!
We can really do it this time!
The latest model Nyarth Robot,
the Nyavil Oniyarth DX’s power is no joke, meow!
What? What were you
doing in there?
Again with this timing, meow?!
Thanks, Pikachu!
You did it!
It’s falling apart!
What even is this feeling?
I don’t think I’ve ever gotten to see the
Melemele Island fireworks this close before.
This will be fun.
Won’t they start soon?
So, how was Akala Island?
It was so much fun!
It was time well spent!
No, I should say it is time well spent,
in progressive form!
After all, I get to watch the
fireworks show with Ms. Lychee!
Thank you so much
for inviting her, too!
Good job, Professor Kukui!
Good job, Professor Burnet!
I see... Well, I’m happy
that you’re happy...
Beautiful...
I feel fantastic!
I love you, Alola!
Thanks, Satoshi.
I’ll never forget this vacation.
Really. Thank you, Satoshi.
Thank you, too.
It was so much fun
having you come for a visit!
Whoa! Awesome!
You know, I’m gonna keep
learning about Pokémon here in Alola...
I’m gonna learn to
love Pokémon even more...
And then I’ll become a
Pokémon Master, for sure!
We know.
We’ve known each other for so long.
You don’t need to tell us that stuff.
I’m gonna keep on mastering
Water-type Pokémon more and more...
...and make Hanada Gym
the greatest Gym in the world!
I’ll take you on
whenever you want!
Okay! Let’s battle again!
Of course!
Hey, hey, don’t forget about me!
Of course not!
Let’s hope Takeshi and Kasumi
come visit Alola again sometime.
What a show!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon that came to
my family farm was Garura!
The Parent and Child Pokémon Garura
is a Normal type.
It’s said that the child in its pouch
leaves home after roughly three years.
But I can’t believe he was able to calm
that enraged Garura and treat its child’s leg...
Takeshi’s skills are frightening!
You’re going home
tomorrow, huh...?
Yup. I’d like to
come back sometime.
Me, too.
Alola is such a nice place.
Agreed!
It’s the perfect place to go refresh!
...And he’s asleep.
Next episode
Quiz! Poni Island Grand Prix!
Question one:
“Odoridori live on Poni Island.”
True or false?
Ding!
Yes, Mr. Satoshi?
True!
Correct!
Question two:
“Poni Island is known for its
particularly long... what?”
Um...
Ding! Slides?
Bzzzz!
What?! Then what’s
the right answer?! What?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Research Projects on Poni Island!
Find the Island King!!
Tune in next week, too!
Next time
Research Projects on Poni Island!
Find the Island King!!
Tell me the answer!