Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Victory for Mamane
-
Victory for Kaki
A draw
Postponed due to storm
How will today’s battle
between Kaki and Māmane go?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s the second round
of the Alola Pokémon League.
Gladio won the first match.
In the second match, Satoshi struggled greatly against Hau,
but ultimately came out on top.
Now the third match has begun.
Māmane has researched
Kaki’s battle style thoroughly,
and is pushing Lizardon into a corner
with Kuwagannon.
Lizardon!
Here we go, Kuwagannon!
All of our systems
are in perfect sync!
Full Power Program... Run!
Absolute Predatory Spin-Out!
Go!
Lizardon!
Lizardon escaped at
the last moment!
It broke free thanks to
its amazing resilience!
Lizardon is still paralyzed!
Signal Beam!
Hit the ground with Fire Punch!
I don’t expect the battle to end
so quickly.
You really are strong.
You’ve gotten better, Māmane.
The real battle begins now!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Everyone’s at Full Power!
The Road to the Semifinals!!
The third match of the second round:
Competitor Kaki VS Competitor Māmane!
The match is immediately off to
an intense back-and-forth!
Great, Māmane!
Hang in there, Kaki!
You’re just getting started!
Do your best, both of you!
Signal Beam!
Dodge it, Lizardon!
String Shot!
Fall back!
Don’t let them get away!
String Shot!
Fire Punch!
Rush! Rush! Rush!
Kuwagannon’s onslaught
has Lizardon on the defensive!
Use String Shot again!
Use your Slash attack!
Let’s back them into a corner!
As if!
Flamethrower!
String Shot!
Dodge!
Now! Wild Bolt!
This is the day I defeat Kaki!
Go, Kuwagannon!
Use Fire Punch!
Kuwagannon charged in!
Lizardon blocked it!
It’s a spectacular clash!
Kuwagannon!
I gotta hand it to you, Māmane...
You’ve done well to draw out
so much power from Kuwagannon.
I’ve been looking forward
to this battle!
And you haven’t let me down!
Kaki...
But I’ll keep getting stronger!
Can you keep up with me, Māmane?!
Of course!
Kuwagannon and I
have no intention of losing!
Then, until the end...
We’ll have a full power...
...battle!
Kuwagannon! String Shot!
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Dodge it!
All right!
Now, Lizardon!
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become the burning wind that
flies across the fields of Akala!
Final Dive Crash!
Ram them with Wild Bolt!
Concentrate your power...
If we can break through,
we’ll have conquered the Z-Move!
He’s blocking the Z-Move-roto!
Amazing, Māmane!
Kuwagannon is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Kaki!
Kuwagannon!
Thank you, Kuwagannon.
You fought well.
You were really strong, Māmane.
I won’t lose next time!
Yeah! I’ll become stronger, too,
and take you on!
Māmane did really well!
Absolutely! We’ll throw him a Malasada party
when he gets back!
Give it your all!
You gotta win, Suiren!
Of course.
I wanna go to the semifinals!
Yer wastin’ yer time!
Mr. Guzma’s gonna
mop the floor with ya in no time!
A battle is like water.
You can’t know
what shape it will take.
Right. The end only comes
after you give your all.
Don’t get cocky just ‘cause
ya can use Z-Moves!
Them moves ain’t nothin’
compared to Mr. Guzma’s might!
Ain’t that right?
Z-Moves, huh...?
What a load of trash.
Yo, Mr. Guzma, wait for us!
H-Hang on a sec!
What an awful bunch.
Be careful.
There’s no telling
what Guzma will do.
Yeah.
It’s finally time for the fourth match!
This will be the final match
of round two!
Will it be Competitor Suiren or Competitor Guzma
who advances to the semifinals?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gusokumusha
Type:   Bug/Water
Both sides,
send out your Pokémon!
I’m counting on you, Ashirène!
Destroy ‘em, Gusokumusha!
Competitor Guzma will face the second round
with Gusokumusha.
How will Competitor Suiren and Ashirène
stand up to its hard shell?
Gusokumusha...
First Impression.
Ashirène.
Watch out for First Impression.
You got this, Suiren!
Meltan, go cheer her on
with the rest!
Oh, it’s the blue brat girl’s match.
So this is the last match of the day.
Our time comes when the battle ends!
We’ll be flooded by hungry customers, meow!
All right, both of you!
Let’s get ready
while we have time!
Yeah!
Yo, yo!
Beat down and smash this rotten world!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
Our glorious leader, Mr. Guzma!
I want a fair fight
from both of you.
Yes!
Let the match begin!
Here it comes, Ashirène.
If you won’t attack, then we will!
Sparkling Aria!
Throat Chop.
Ashirène!
Her voice...
Now she can’t use
Sparkling Aria-roto!
In that case... Aqua Jet!
Block it, Gusokumusha.
Poison Jab.
Ashirène!
Don’t let it get away!
Poison Jab.
Run!
Poison Jab!
Icy Wind!
Ashirène narrowly
managed to escape!
But poison flows through
its veins!
What are you doing,
Gusokumusha?!
One more Poison Jab!
Icy Wind!
Good! Start by preventing
Gusokumusha from moving!
Relax!
Just take it one step at a time!
Hang in there!
Aqua Jet!
What’s this?! Gusokumusha...
...used its shield to avoid
a direct hit from the Icy Wind!
And then it seems to have bode its time
until Ashirène lowered its guard!
What remarkable cool-headedness!
What remarkable resilience!
Run, Ashirène!
As if!
Poison Jab.
Shake it off!
Yo, yo!
Beat down and smash your foe!
Team Skull rules!
Our leader
Mr. Guzma rules!
Icy Wind!
Throat Chop.
Think we’d fall for that again?
See that, Kukui?
The battle isn’t over yet!
Suiren!
You’re absolutely right!
Don’t give up!
You can still win!
You’re not done yet!
Pin Missile!
Surf!
What?!
When...
Gusokumusha bode its time
for too long!
It didn’t completely block Icy Wind.
It stayed within Ashirène’s
Icy Wind for so long,
its feet froze!
This is your chance!
Go!
Ashirène.
Embraced by our mother, the sea...
Echo...
...beyond the horizon!
Sea God’s Symphonia!
Ashirène’s singing voice
has fully recovered-roto!
Finish it!
I’ll destroy your pathetic Z-Move!
Gusokumusha! Aqua Break!
Ashirène is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Guzma!
Competitor Guzma made it through
the brutal battle!
He moves on to the semifinals!
Yo, yo!
Let out steam
by smashing a rotten foe!
We’re the all-powerful Team Skull!
Our glorious leader, Mr. Guzma!
Ashirène...
Small-fry.
Wait!
A Pokémon battle isn’t over until
both trainers acknowledge each other!
Mr. Guzma!
Yer so cool!
Knew ya could do it!
You rock!
Mao... Everyone...
You did your best.
Xiemi. Aromatherapy.
Thank you.
What a relief.
But you should still let
Ms. Joy take a look at her.
Yeah.
You did well, Ashirène.
But he was so violent!
Yes.
He didn’t break any rules.
True.
He kept a cool head to find weaknesses
in Ashirène’s attacks,
and made efficient use of
his own moves.
I cannot approve of
such a battling style.
I can’t accept it!
We gave it our full power.
But our foe was above us.
I’ll retrain my Pokémon,
and myself!
We’ve restored your Pokémon
to full health.
Thank you very much.
You are quite welcome.
Thank you for waiting!
It’s time to announce the match-ups
for the Pokémon League semifinals tomorrow!
The first match is...
Competitor Kaki VS...
...Competitor Gladio!
You’re facing my brother...
Yeah. He’ll be a worthy opponent!
This should be
one heck of a match-up!
And that means, the match-up for
the second match will be these two!
Competitor Satoshi VS...
...Competitor Guzma!
Satoshi!
Guzma and Satoshi...
Avenge Suiren!
Yeah, you got it!
The match-ups leading to the finals
have been unveiled.
Kaki VS Gladio.
Satoshi VS Guzma.
What kind of battles are going to
unfold before us?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting!
The battle ended with
Red: Victory for Competitor Kaki!
The Flame Pokémon Lizardon
is a Fire/Flying type.
Its wings can carry this Pokémon
close to an altitude of 1200 meters.
Competitor Kaki, Lizardon...
Congratulations on
reaching the semifinals!
It’s finally time for
the semifinals!
Those are some
exciting match-ups!
We’ll have to work extra hard!
Next episode
I think I’ve fallen in love.
What?!
W-With who?!
Mr. Gladio.
Why did it have to be
my opponent?!
I mean, he’s just so cool!
All right! I’ll just become
cool enough to rival Gladio!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Semifinals! Kaki VS Gladio!!
You can do it if you try.
Next time
The Semifinals!
Kaki VS Gladio!!
Mr. Gladio!
Hoshi!