Alola-roto!
I will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
It’ll be my pleasuroto!
The shopping mall
The TV station
The staff office
The Principal’s office
To which of these places
do I not go today-roto?
The correct answer will be given
at the end of the episode-roto!
The one who committed this crime
was smart indeed.
They made Mr. Makani himself
hide the hidden treasure, the Princess’s Tear,
in order to clear their own name
of any suspicion.
What? My husband took it?!
Madame, your husband
was deceived by clever words.
And then, as instructed by the criminal,
he removed himself from the picture!
“Criminal” this, “Criminal” that...
Who are you saying the criminal is?!
A fine question indeed!
What’s this? Satoshi and the others
are watching TV together.
This is “Alolan Detective Lucky,”
a very popular show in Alola.
According to my deduction,
the criminal is this man-roto!
I’m absolutely certain-roto!
Are you really certain?
Personally, I’m convinced
it’s Makani’s wife.
I see...
Quite the bold deduction!
You’re totally hooked
on Lucky, huh?
But of course!
It’s interesting-roto!
Rotom, what’s with the hair?
A fine question indeed!
This is a Lucky Role Play Set-roto!
The Professor bought it for me-roto!
It even came with seven detective tools!
It was on bargain-roto!
The criminal is the only person who knows where
the Princess’s Tear is hidden...
Furthermore, it’s someone who has failed to realize
that I have found its hiding place.
The culprit is...
...you!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Alolan Detective Rotom!
The Mystery of the Vanished Crystal!!
You are the culprit, Doctor!
What?!
Me?!
Impossible! Where is the proof?!
Naturally, Doctor.
The proof is...
...this Yamirami doll.
And one more thing:
My dear Doble.
Thank you. You are an impeccable
assistant, my dear Doble.
Doctor. You intended to replace the Yamirami doll
with this one behind everyone’s backs, did you not?
After all...
The Yamirami doll in this room...
...held the Princess’s Tear
hidden within!
I found it for you as promised,
Mrs. Makani.
Yes...
But getting the jewel back
will not bring back my husband!
This wasn’t how it was
supposed to end...
You might fancy yourself a trickster...
But there’s no fooling the eyes of Lucky,
nor the blue sea of Alola!
Resolution rate: 100%!
Alolan Detective Lucky’s deductions
never miss the mark!
He’s the best!
His logical deductions and his
daring confrontation of the criminal!
Alolan Detective Lucky
is awesome-roto!
Right, Sato-
He’s asleep-roto!
Oh, what are we going
to do with you...
Hey, wake up, Satoshi!
If you doze off there, you’ll catch a cold!
Satoshi, do you want to know
who the culprit was-roto?
I can tell you if you do-roto!
Um, I’m sleepy,
so you can tell me tomorrow...
And you’re still wearing that wig?
So, Satoshi, it was...
He’s asleep-roto!
“The culprit is... you!”
No, maybe more like this-roto?
“You.”
”You! You. You!”
It’s gone! Gone! Gone! Gone!
Where is it? Where’d it go?!
I can’t find it!
Satoshi? What’s “gone”?
Something I can lend you?
I can’t find my Electric-Z anywhere!
I have the Normal-Z
right here, though.
Electric-Z? Do you mean
the Z-Crystal you received...
...after clearing Mr. Hala’s Grand Trial?
It was an important gift
from Kapu-Kokeko!
Oh, no!
Kapu-Kokeko’s gonna be
so mad at me...
If Kaki hears you lost such a precious Crystal,
he’ll be mad, too!
You lost a precious Crystal?!
S-Sorry, Kaki!
“Sorry” isn’t gonna cut it!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Oh, well. Satoshi’s life is over.
Leave it to me-roto!
Rotom!
I, Alolan Detective Rotom...
...shall solve the mystery
of the vanished Crystal-roto!
Pikachu, stop that-roto!
Counting on you, Rotom.
I’m on it-roto!
Alola!
A-Alola...
Huh? Is something wrong?
Not at all!
Okay...
Rotom, hurry!
I’ll start asking around
immediately-roto!
Pikachu, you help Rotom, too!
My dear Pikachu,
you are hereby my assistant-roto!
The most basic aspect of a detective’s job
is asking around-roto!
I shall now demonstrate
how it is done-roto!
Satoshi lost his Electric-Z?
If you have info, whether it be about home, school,
or anywhere else, then I want it-roto!
Hmmm... Yesterday,
at the end of lunch break,
I saw Satoshi and Kaki
practicing Z-Moves together.
He was practicing with Mokuroh,
so he was most likely using the Normal-Z.
In which case, perhaps he dropped the Electric-Z
in the courtyard during training?
The courtyard-roto...
The Pokémon School courtyard
is too big-roto!
The odds of finding
that tiny Electric-Z here are...
...0.0000002%.
Nekkoala, have you seen
Satoshi’s Z-Crystal-roto?
Will you kindly answer me-roto?!
Come to think of it,
Nekkoala is always asleep...
So it couldn’t possibly have...
...seen the Z-Crystal-roto.
Cut that out,
you electric mouse-roto!
I can’t find it-roto...
Did you find it-roto?
You are an impeccable assistant,
my dear Pikachu!
Oh! What are these photos?
Oh, Rotom.
A cameraman from Alola TV
came and took them yesterday.
Looks like they want to use them on the poster
for next year’s Pokémon Pancake Race.
They’re very well shot-roto.
The cameraman must be highly skilled-roto!
Let’s try to win next year’s race,
togetheRokon!
Very good, Rokon!
Again: TogetheRokon!
TogetheRokon!
I’m training Rokon to respond
whenever its name gets used in Pokémon gags!
What kind of training is that...?
Huh? The cameraman yesterday
thought it was a great trick,
enough so that he deemed it
worth filminGamale!
Filming? Was Rokon the only thing
he caught on video-roto?!
Not at all! He recorded plenty of things
from all over the Pokémon School.
Satoshi and Kaki particularly impressed him
when they were practicing their Z-Moves.
That’s it-roto!
Resolution rate: 100%!
Alolan Detective Rotom’s deductions
never miss the mark!
We must make haste towards Alola TV,
my dear Pikachu-roto!
I’m sure if we watch those video recordings,
we’ll figure out where the Electric-Z went-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nekkoala
Type:   Normal
The next class will be on
practicing Pokémon moves.
Everyone meet up in the courtyard!
Let’s go, Amakaji.
Ashimari, let’s try making
an even bigger balloon today!
Hey, Satoshi, where’s Pikachu?
W-Well, he had...
stuff to do...
I see... I wanted to practice defending
against a Sparking Gigavolt...
S-Spa-Sparking Gigavolt?
Sorry, I was thinking of training
Iwanko today, you s-s-s-see...
Why are you stuttering?
Y-Yeah, Iwanko! Great idea!
Iwanko, Iwanko! What a good boy!
Iwanko doesn’t use
the Electric-Z, after all!
Māmane!
Oh, no!
Electric-Z?
What’s that got to do with it?
W-What, indeed...
C’mon, let’s go!
What?
Alola TV located, just where the map
said it would be-roto!
Alola!
Nice work today!
Alola-roto!
Hold it!
Pikachu!
You’re adowwable!
Pwecious li’l Pikachu!
Where’s your trainer?
I’m so sowwy, but Pokémon
can’t go in here on their own.
If you want to go in,
you’ll have to get your trainer.
I’m sure you are aware,
but what we are here to seek...
...is the video camera with footage
from the Pokémon School, my dear Pikachu.
H-He’s not here-roto!
Oh, well. Seeking out the video camera
takes precedence-roto!
Pardon me-roto.
Yes, what is it?
Oh, a new face!
I am Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
The way you flip your hair...
You must be quite the Lucky fan!
I am, too.
That makes us
kindred spirits-roto!
Indeed.
Yay!
I’m searching for the video camera that was used
at the Pokémon School yesterday-roto!
The Pokémon School, huh...?
Ah, for the Pancake Race article?
Well, in that case...
I believe that was the cameraman
who went there.
Thank you-roto!
You’re quite welcome!
Pardon me-roto.
I’d like to see the footage you took of
the Pokémon School yesterday!
The Pokémon School?
It could help me solve
a most complex case-roto!
Complex case?
I don’t really get it...
But anyway, I haven’t edited that footage yet,
and I need to head to my next shoot.
It’ll only take a moment-roto!
All I need is to connect my arm
to the camera for a bit-roto!
Well, I guess that’s okay.
Thank you-roto!
Index Feature Expansion: On!
This is the first time I’ve
expanded my Index features-roto!
It feels as if something is welling up inside my body...
What a fascinating sensation-roto!
Index Rotom has gained
the video camera feature-roto!
I will now copy the
relevant footage-roto!
Ashimari! Balloon!
Incredible!
She broke another size record!
Very good, Ashimari!
Lilie! Think we could try having Snowball
go into the balloon now?
It’s a lot of fun, Snowball!
Isn’t it, Amakaji?
I suppose we can give it a try.
Snowball seems happy!
Got it, Iwanko?
You have to remember this scent.
I might’ve dropped the Electric-Z
around here somewhere.
Very suspicious...
Satoshi!
W-What is it, Kaki?
Weren’t you going to
practice Iwanko’s moves?
Practice?
You’ve just been
walking around in circles.
That doesn’t look like
practicing to me.
T-This is, well...
O-Oh, right!
He’s practicing Odor Sleuth!
He’s learned Odor Sleuth?
Not good...!
Um, Iwanko was
helping Snowball train.
T-That’s right!
Isn’t it, Snowball?
Now, Snowball,
pretend you’re Iwanko!
Go “Woof”!
Satoshi’s in...
...trouble!
Staaaare...
Satoshi!
Pikachu! Rotom!
Did you find my missing Electric-Z?
What?!
All the mysteries
have been solved-roto!
Thank you, Rotom, Pikachu!
Satoshi...
You mean to tell me... you lost the precious Z-Crystal
Kapu-Kokeko so generously gifted you?!
Y-Y-Yes, I did!
Get back here, Satoshi!
Yup. Satoshi’s life is over.
Dynamic Full Flame!
Hold it-roto!
There’s plenty of time to be angry
after you’ve heard my brilliant deduction-roto!
Okay...
My dear Pikachu!
Bring everyone to
the classroom-roto!
I, the esteemed
Alolan Detective Rotom...
...have at long last cracked this exceptionally unique case:
The mystery of the vanished Z-Crystal-roto!
Rotom, quit showing off.
If you’ve found the Electric-Z,
then give it to me.
I cannot do that-roto.
Why not?!
Because the Crystal is still
within the criminal’s grasp-roto!
Whaaat?!
Wait, “Criminal”?
Isn’t that a bit overblown, Rotom?
Glare! Professor,
you be quiet-roto!
The scene where the criminal is exposed
is the coolest part-roto!
R-Right!
And the culprit behind this case...
...is you!
Whaaaaat?!
K-Kaki is the culprit?!
Why me?!
The proof is right here-roto!
Replay mode: On!
Here comes the important part-roto.
Become a blazing flame...
A bit further ahead-roto.
Thanks for helping me train, Kaki.
That was a pretty good Z-Move.
Focus on this part-roto!
I deduced that right here, Satoshi accidentally
handed the Electric-Z over to Kaki-roto!
Huh?!
So that’s it...
Whaaat?!
That is the only possible
explanation-roto.
Good grief...
Impossible!
There’s no way!
First off, if there was a Crystal in his hand,
we’d notice during our handshake!
I didn’t notice!
Because the Electric-Z
wasn’t there!
Just give it up-roto!
You might fancy yourself a trickster...
But there’s no fooling the eyes of Rotom,
nor the blue sea of Alola-roto!
This doesn’t make any sense!
Rotom! Wait a second!
I’d like to see a little further back.
A bit before their training session.
Very well-roto. Rewind: On-roto!
That part!
I just see Suiren and Ashimari...
Rewind just a little more, please.
Stop!
Here! At the edge of the frame!
It’s Satoshi!
Satoshi is putting something
in his pocket here.
That’s it! My pocket!
You remember something?
When Kaki and I were training,
I swapped the Electric-Z on my Z-Ring for the Normal-Z,
and put the Electric-Z
in my pocket!
Then I kinda forgot about it,
and I only took it back out of my pocket
right before bed, in my room...
You know, after we all
watched TV together!
Then I was trying to sleep,
when Rotom came...
Satoshi, do you want to know
who the culprit was-roto?
I can tell you if-
Does that mean the Electric-Z
is in Satoshi’s room-roto?!
Probably.
Sorry, Rotom! I totally forgot!
T-This cannot be-roto!
There’s my Electric-Z!
T-That’s...
Does this mean the Electric-Z
got stuck in my wig back then-roto?!
So the culprit was...
...you?!
Oh, well. Rotom’s life is over.
Rotom!
Halt!
This is really good!
This should be useful
for practicing moves.
I edited it together for Kaki-roto!
That’s so cool, Rotom!
Call me whenever you want to
record your training-roto!
Rotom’s Index features
have been expanded,
and he now has
a video camera feature!
Will Rotom continue
to grow in the future?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The answer to the PokéProblem was
the shopping mall-roto!
This was a tricky case
indeed-roto...
My Rotom Index has
a new feature-roto!
The video camera is truly
a revolutionary addition-roto!
Now on top of the Pokémon’s behavior,
I can capture Satoshi and the others’ battles-roto!
Rotom, I don’t mind if you want
to shoot a documentary,
but are you gonna
film my bath, too?
Stopping recording-roto.
Manners are also important
during filming-roto!
Next episode
It’s time for
“Mao’s 30-Second Cooking”!
30-second?!
First we present the ingredients!
But to save time,
we’re skipping that.
Huh?
We put the prepared
ingredients in a pot!
But to save time,
we’re skipping that.
Huh?
It’s done!
Presenting Mao’s
Alola Special Plate!
Huh?!
Wow, it looks delicious!
Can I have some?
To save time,
we’re skipping that!
Huuuh?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Seriously?!
Mao’s Cooking Master Plan!!
Seriously?! Mao’s Cooking Master Plan!!