Good day!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Victory for Satoshi
A draw
Victory for Hau
Canceled because of rain
How does today’s battle
between Satoshi and Hau end?
Choose one of the above,
and get the answer at the end of the episode!
Gladio won the first match of
the Alola Pokémon League’s second round.
And for the second match...
Satoshi’s Mokuroh trained
with Dodekabashi’s flock,
and is now facing Hau’s Ju'niper.
Go, Mokuroh!
This is our full power!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Now, Ju'niper!
Here we go!
Shadow Arrows Strike!
Mokuroh!
Is this the end?!
Mokuroh?
Both sides managed to dodge each other’s Z-Moves,
and their heated battle now continues!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A Soaring Showdown!
Brave Bird VS God Bird!!
I’ll give it back after the match.
Let the battle resume!
Fly, Mokuroh!
Get above Ju'niper!
Ju'niper!
Don’t let Mokuroh escape!
Knock him down
with Leaf Blade!
Dodge it, Mokuroh!
The battle takes to the air!
Who will rule the skies?!
Leaf Cutter!
Run, Mokuroh!
Seed Bomb!
Leaf Blade!
Didn’t expect a battle like this...
Those kids are good!
Leaf Blade!
Mokuroh!
Use Leaf Cutter!
Now attack from the right,
Mokuroh!
Satoshi’s setting up.
Setting up?
He wants to turn the tide with a single move.
Brave Bird, most likely.
Will that work on Ju'niper?
If he hits, he can turn the tables!
But he’ll take recoil damage.
Yeah, and that could
result in a draw.
Hang in there, Mokuroh!
Leaf Cutter!
Now! Leaf Blade!
Dodge it, Mokuroh!
Mokuroh is shot down!
Ju'niper has conquered the skies!
Mokuroh, get up!
Now, Ju'niper!
Shadow Stitch!
Mokuroh!
Ju'niper, let’s finish this,
once and for all!
Close in and use Leaf Blade!
Mokuroh!
Use Feather Dance!
Competitor Satoshi’s Mokuroh
crashes into the wall!
Is it all right?!
Mokuroh!
Mokuroh is back on its feet!
But it seems to have
taken damage!
Hang in there, Mokuroh!
Feather Dance?
He was practicing it with Dodekabashi
right before the match-roto.
With Dodekabashi?!
But the battle started
before he could perfect it-roto...
It looks like he was still able
to reduce the damage, though.
Now’s our chance, Ju'niper!
Leaf Cutter!
Mokuroh! Up!
All right!
Mokuroh, Brave Bird!
I expected as much.
Ju'niper!
Counter with God Bird!
Please...
Go!
Ju'niper!
Two mighty moves
clash head-on!
Now...
Both have fallen!
Can they get back up?!
Mokuroh!
Ju'niper!
Mokuroh...
Mokuroh! Get up-roto!
You have to stand up-roto!
Ju'niper!
Amazing!
Competitor Hau’s Ju'niper
got back up first!
What of Competitor Satoshi’s
Mokuroh?!
Mokuroh!
Guess that’s that.
Mokuroh is unable to battle!
The winners are
Competitor Hau and Ju'niper!
We did it...
We won, Ju'niper!
We did it!
Great job!
It was a fierce struggle,
but Competitor Hau’s Ju'niper came out on top!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kerarappa
Type:   Normal/Flying
It was a fierce struggle,
but Competitor Hau’s Ju'niper came out on top!
Ju'niper, you’re the best!
Satoshi...
One moment, please!
Gramps?
What’s this? The chief referee, Mr. Hala,
has called the match’s referee over to him.
I, Hala, have an objection
to that verdict.
Objection?
It was ruled that both moves hit their mark,
and that Ju'niper won after getting back up...
But Mokuroh is
not yet incapacitated!
What?
You don’t mean...?!
Take a closer look.
It has merely fallen asleep!
Mokuroh?!
Wake up, Mokuroh!
We’re in the middle of a battle!
Good grief...
Your Mokuroh
always catches me off guard.
Sorry.
Don’t worry.
We’re here to beat
that Mokuroh, after all!
Thank you, Hau!
So sorry...
Your Pokémon’ve caused the referees
some massive headaches...
The fight’s resuming.
Get back to your positions.
Yes, sir!
Let the match begin!
The match resumes!
The two are staring each other down,
and won’t move!
I can’t believe Mokuroh
withstood that!
That God Bird was probably
not fully charged.
But I doubt either of them
have much energy left.
Competitor Satoshi’s Mokuroh
made the first move!
Go! Use Leaf Cutter!
Leaf Cutter!
Seed Bomb!
Send it back with Leaf Blade!
Now, Ju'niper!
Shadow Stitch!
No!
We’ll charge it up
all the way this time!
God Bird!
Mokuroh!
Use Feather Dance!
Go, Ju'niper!
Mokuroh!
Ju'niper! Above you!
Use Brave Bird!
Ju'niper!
Ju'niper is unable to battle!
The winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
Talk about a comeback win!
An amazing comeback for
Competitor Satoshi’s Mokuroh!
You did it, Mokuroh!
So that was
your Feather Dance?
They did it!
It looked nothing like
Dodekabashi’s-roto!
You can sleep
as long as you want today!
Satoshi!
Congratulations!
Thank you, Hau.
Ju'niper was really strong!
Thanks!
Let’s battle again!
Sure!
A true Reversal.
We’re up next, huh?
Yeah.
Gramps.
Satoshi and Mokuroh
really are amazing.
You fought very well.
All right, the match is over!
Here come the customers!
It’s time to rake in the cash!
We’ll sell, sell, and then
sell some more, meow!
One, please.
Got it!
I’ll have two with drinks, please!
Got it! One doughnut,
and two with drinks!
Okay!
One doughnut, and two with drinks!
Welcomeow, welcomeow!
We’ve got Manalo Stadium’s exclusive
Manalo Doughnuts! They’re delicious, meow!
Kaki.
At first, I thought there was
no way I could beat you.
After all, your grandfather
was an Island King,
and you were the first in our class
to get a Z-Ring.
But now I know how fun battling can be,
and it’s made me think...
...that I want to beat you someday.
So I won’t lose today!
Good! Give it all you have!
Competitors Kaki and Māmane,
please proceed to the battlefield.
Let’s go!
Yeah!
I repeat...
The third match of the Alola Pokémon League
is Competitor Kaki VS Competitor Māmane.
They’re classmates
at the Pokémon School,
and students of the League’s organizer,
Professor Kukui.
As they both know
each other’s tricks well,
I wonder what battle
lies in store for us!
I made it!
Well done, Satoshi!
That was a great fight!
Congratulations on
advancing to the semifinals!
Thanks!
Huh?
Where’s Meltan?
Over there-roto.
It’s been doing that
ever since Mokuroh’s battle ended-roto.
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Kuwagannon,
we’re gonna win!
Well, then,
let the battle begin!
Flamethrower!
Dodge to the left!
Here they come!
Now hit them
with a Fire Punch!
I figured you’d do that.
Kuwagannon, swerve
and use String Shot!
Dodge it!
String Shot!
Competitor Kaki’s Lizardon
expertly dodges Kuwagannon’s attacks!
Good, Lizardon! Keep it up!
Guess our timing
was a bit off.
But we’re just getting started,
Kuwagannon!
Do your best, both of you!
Fight!
Fire Punch!
Now! Signal Beam!
Dodge it, Lizardon!
Now send it sideways!
Up!
Turning Swallow Strike!
Kuwagannon,
prepare an EM Cannon!
What?!
Fire!
Lizardon!
Here we go, Kuwagannon!
Competitor Māmane
unleashes a Z-Move!
All of our systems
are in perfect sync!
Full Power Program... Run!
Absolute Predatory Spin-Out!
Lizardon is entangled in strings
and can’t move!
Go!
How will
this battle end?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you very much for waiting!
The battle ended with
Satoshi’s victory!
Feather Dance, the move Mokuroh learned,
has the effect of weakening the opponent’s attacks.
But to think that he
fell asleep in battle...
How very much like Mokuroh, yes?
Next episode
The second round is
getting really exciting, right?
Who are you all cheering for?
Competitor Kaki,
for representing Akala Island!
Mokuroh’s really moved me,
so I’m cheerin’ for Satoshi.
I’m cheering for them all.
They’re all great battlers!
It seems we have a customer.
Welcome to the Pokémon Center!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Everyone’s at Full Power!
The Road to the Semifinals!!
Next time
Everyone’s at Full Power!
The Road to the Semifinals!!