Kanmon Straits!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Ilima
Musashi
Sauboh
Satoshi
Who do they describe as the favorite to win
the Alola Pokémon League in today’s episode?
You already know, don’t you?
Get the answer
a little bit before the show ends!
The Alola Pokémon League...
The tournament to determine the strongest trainer in Alola.
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
We’ve got Manalo Doughnuts
for sale, meow!
Here in Manalo Stadium,
the preliminary Battle Royal
is about to begin!
It’s 'Olu'olu!
And the Fishing Guru!
Ms. Matsurika!
And there’s Ms. Kahili, too!
Everyone in here
is our opponent...
And someone in here will be
our first-ever Champion!
I’m gonna win my way
up the ranks, for sure!
Me, too!
So am I!
Acerola! You’re here, too?
I brought Uncle Kuchinashi,
and figured I’d sign up while I was here.
It looked like fun, after all!
Didn’t it, Mimikins?
Trainers have come here
from all over Alola, huh?
All right, for the Battle Royal...
We’re gonna run like crazy.
Yup! If we fight, we lose, after all.
What?
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Your encouragement flatters me.
Th-That jerk, Ilima!
I don’t care if he’s the favorite to win or whatever,
I just can’t stand the guy!
Numbskulls!
Don’t get in the boss’s way, got it?
Got it, Big Sis!
I hear that Ilima kid’s
pretty tough.
I think you’ll do fine, but...
You should still be careful.
It’s Professor Kukui!
Alola!
I can’t tell you how grateful I am to see
so many competitors gathered here at Manalo Stadium!
I hereby declare
the Alola Pokémon League open!
It’s time to Gear Change!
Give us a full power Explosion!
Yeah!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Brawl!
Battle Royal 151!!
It’s the Alola Pokémon League
preliminary Battle Royal!
I, Jeekyo, will be the referee.
It’s almost time to begin.
The judges will be Ms. Lychee, Mr. Hala,
Ms. Hāpu'u, and Mr. Kuchinashi.
Now, please turn your attention
to the screen.
This shows that there are 151 pairs
of competitors and Pokémon.
The Battle Royal will continue
until this number reaches 16.
We’re all gonna clear
the preliminary, yeah?
Yeah!
It’s finally time.
Yes! I can’t wait!
Oh, yeah, didn’t Sauboh say
he was participating?
All competitors,
assume your starting positions.
It’s starting-roto!
Pokémon, stand by!
Pikachu!
Let’s give it our all!
Bakugames,
I’m counting on you!
We’re gonna win this,
Togedemaru!
Sandy! Full power!
Hang in there, Xiemi!
Snowball, let’s go!
The countdown is almost at zero.
Three...
Two...
One...
Begin!
The curtain now rises on the fierce battles
of the Alola Pokémon League!
All right!
All of you, come at me!
Wha—?!
I... am... a... Champion...
Or not...
Dorobanko is unable to battle!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Usokki is unable to battle!
You did it, Pikachu!
Stay sharp, Satoshi!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
Nyorobon and Onishizukumo
are both unable to battle!
Thanks, Kaki!
Hey, you don’t have time
to thank me!
Bakugames! Dragon Tail!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
Bohmander is incapacitated, too!
Well done, Lilie!
I saw a chance and took it!
Xiemi, you can still go on, right?
You fought well, Sandy!
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Togedemaru! Needle Guard!
Awesome!
Togedemaru’s learned a new move?
W-Well... Yeah...
I won’t lose, either!
Hang in there, everyone!
Their training has paid off-roto!
There’s Sauboh!
Houdin! Use Psychokinesis!
Now Gantle has been
incapacitated, as well!
Gyarados, huh?
Oh, no! It’s an Airm'd!
Now, Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Competitor Satoshi’s Pikachu takes out
both Gyarados and Airm'd in one fell swoop!
Well done, Pikachu!
Where are Kaki and the others?
Bakugames! Trap Shell!
Next! Let’s go!
Koiking!
Oh, dear...
Koiking and Namakobushi
are unable to battle!
Who defeated them?!
Boruto, you did it-pika!
Competitor Pikarla’s Pikachu is
unable to battle!
Oh, no-pika!
Hey! Hold it!
The plan... was that...
...we not do... anything!
That Mimikkyu...
If it sees a Pikachu...
it loses all restraint...
Isn’t that, like... really bad?
I said wait!
Let’s go, Hidoide!
The Battle Royal
is approaching its climax.
We can look forward to even more intense
battles for survival from here on!
Dodge, Silvuddy!
Sacred Beast Silvuddy,
I grant you further power!
Receive the Rock Memory!
Fangs of stone that pierce all...
Bring the wings of flame
to the ground!
Multi-Attack!
Silvuddy, let’s do this!
Ow...
Satoshi?
Gladio!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ennewt
Type:   Poison/Fire
Incoming.
Silvuddy! Break Claw!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Don’t lose here.
Right back at you!
Now, listen up, ya two!
Teach dat kid a lesson
he’ll never forget!
Here we go, Bakugames!
Use Flamethrower!
Think that’ll work?!
Elecible!
Use Thunder Punch!
Bakugames! Shell Smash!
Then get them both
with Dragon Tail!
Wha—?!
Ya kiddin’ me?!
Competitors Mad Boobur and Mr. Elec
have both been defeated!
Only a few more remain until we have our sixteen
who will advance to the final tournament!
But out of all who have made it this far,
the one to keep an eye on...
...has to be this man!
The Normal-type specialist,
Competitor Ilima!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Eevee, use Ace in the Hole.
Splendid work, Eevee.
Hey, you!
I hear you’re the favorite?
Don’t get cocky just ‘cause
you beat these guys.
Big Sis...
Ennewt! Sludge Wave!
Eevee, use Lightning Speed!
Too easy.
Ennewt! Dragon Claw!
Dragon Pulse!
Eevee!
Use Lightning Speed to
get away, please!
I won’t let you escape.
Speed Star!
Ennewt is unable to battle!
So I lost, huh?
Whatever.
I did what I came here to do.
Eevee, are you all right?
Now, we’ve got
nothing but tough trainers left!
Jararanga is unable to battle!
Jararanga has fallen!
Who could have brought it down?!
Is this really all
the Alola League’s got?
It was Competitor Guzma’s Hassam!
Guzma...
One last push, Pikachu!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Huh?
That Mimikkyu...
Hey! Mimikkyu!
What?! The brat...
Pikachu! Electric Net!
Oh, come on!
Why are you battling?!
It’s almost over,
so just run away!
Dynamic Full Flame!
That concludes the preliminary round!
It’s over?
Don’t!
That was close...
We made it, but only just.
Satoshi!
Kaki!
Lilie!
They’re all here-roto!
Well done!
What a relief...
Indeed!
Pikachu, we did it!
Thank you, Bakugames.
Snowball, we gave it our all.
You fought well, Xiemi.
Keep it up, Sandy!
You did it, Togedemaru!
Awesome! Everyone made it
through the preliminaries!
Satoshi.
Hau!
Let’s face each other
in the final tournament!
Yeah!
We’ll give it our full power!
We’ve restored your Pokémon
to full health.
Thank you very much!
The Joys from all four islands
are here-roto!
Eevee, take it easy for a bit.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
We will now announce the match-ups for
the first round of the final tournament!
The first match is...
Competitor Satoshi VS...
...Competitor Sauboh!
I’m first, huh?
Do your best.
Yeah!
I see...
So my opponent is Satoshi.
I will have to come up with a plan...
The second match is...
Competitor Ilima VS...
...Competitor Guzma!
So there you have it,
Mr. Guzma.
The third match is...
Competitor Hau VS...
...Competitor Okido!
All right!
We’ll win for sure!
I’m as excited as can be!
Melecie! Diancie!
The fourth match is...
Competitor Mao VS...
...Competitor Suiren!
Us?!
I’m up against you?!
The fifth match is...
Competitor Māmane VS...
...Competitor Matsurika!
Now I’m nervous!
The sixth match is...
Competitor Musasina VS...
...Competitor Dekojiro!
Only one of you
gets past round one, meow!
The seventh match is...
Competitor Kaki VS...
...Competitor Acerola!
I’m fired up
like the mountain of Akala!
Won’t this be fun, Mimikins?
The eighth match is...
Competitor Lilie VS...
...Competitor Gladio!
Big Brother...
Let’s give it our full power,
everyone!
Yeah!
Satoshi and the others have won their way through
the Pokémon League preliminary Battle Royal.
Next time,
the final tournament begins!
What kind of battles
will we see?
You’ll have to
wait and find out!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Moji and Shimonoseki!
The favorite to win
the Alola Pokémon League was...
...I-Ilima!
Whoever remains standing at the end
of a Battle Royal is the winner.
Team Rocket’s tactic was
to win without battling!
Despite Musashi’s Mimikkyu
going after Pikachu,
our flawless plan carried us through the preliminaries
and into the final tournament!
We wanted to participate, too!
I’ll be back!
Next episode
Mao, if you win,
I’ll give you a discount at my stand!
You don’t have to!
You’re embarrassing me!
Don’t be shy!
Win the first round,
and the topping will be free!
Win the second,
and you’ll get a free refill!
Win the tournament,
and everything’s free!
Gonna get busy!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Mao and Suiren!
A Full Power Battle of Friendship!!
Mao, don’t ignore me!
Knock it off!
Next time
Mao and Suiren!
A Full Power Battle of Friendship!!