Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Lugarugan
Nyaheat
Mokuroh
Pikachu
Which Pokémon do I send out for
Hāpu'u’s Grand Trial today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
A fine harvest!
Oh, indeed!
I must start preparing myself.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
An Island Queen is Born!
Satoshi’s Grand Trial!!
These are the Ruins of Paradise
on Poni Island.
It seems that Hāpu'u’s Island Queen
inauguration ceremony is about to begin.
Finally!
This is an incredibly
important ceremony.
Nobody make any noise.
I’m so excited-roto!
I’ll be recording every bit of this-roto!
I just said not to
make any noise!
Sorry...
I, Hāpu'u of Poni Island,
offer up this dance to Kapu-Rehire,
who slumbers in the island’s waters.
It’s started.
Is she mimicking Kapu-Rehire?
Maybe.
Look!
Pretty.
Yeah.
Bestow upon me the duty of watching over
Poni Island and her surrounding seas.
Awesome...
Recording-roto...
I accept this purified Ring,
which symbolizes our bond!
Island Queen Hāpu'u is born!
You have all been of great aid.
I thank you.
Congratulations, Hāpu'u!
I have kept you waiting,
Satoshi.
At long last, you will face
your Grand Trial.
All right!
Where? Where’re we doing
the Grand Trial?!
Do not be so hasty.
Look there, Satoshi!
I don’t see anything...
No, look under the water.
Under the water?
A battlefield?!
Quite conveniently,
it is a spring tide tonight.
At low tide,
the battlefield will emerge.
There, my Pokémon Banbadoro and your Pokémon
shall have a one-on-one Grand Trial battle.
Do you accept, Satoshi?
Of course I do!
I’ll win, for sure!
Then I shall look forward
to our battle!
Golugh.
All right, Xiemi,
here comes the wave!
Snowball, come here.
Safe! You did it!
Snowball, one more time!
Lugarugan,
is something buried there?
How’d he even get there?
Satoshi.
Oshamari, that was perfect!
Now you’ve done it...
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Oshamari, fight back!
Sorry, Pikachu...
Satoshi sure is relaxed.
Think he’s decided on a Pokémon
for the Grand Trial?
If it were me, I’d go with
Mokuroh, the Grass type.
But this is Satoshi
we’re talking about.
So maybe Lugarugan?
Or Nyaheat? Or even Pikachu?
He’s fighting Banbadoro!
Pikachu would put him at the biggest disadvantage-roto!
Neither 100,000 Volts nor Electric Net
will work on it-roto!
Satoshi, have you decided
who you’ll be using in the Grand Trial?
Yeah!
You’re wide open!
I see...
Do your best!
Thanks, Kaki!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Oshamari
Type:   Water
Which Pokémon shall be
facing my Banbadoro in battle?
Pikachu.
I choose you!
Oh, Pikachu?
I was not mistaken about you...
You truly do have
quite the backbone.
Kaki.
Will you serve as the referee
for this Grand Trial?
You are an Island King’s
grandson, are you not?
That’s right!
You can count on me!
The Island Pilgrimage ritual of the Grand Trial
is about to commence.
Kapu-Rehire, ye who drift in
the waters of Poni...
With the gentleness of the water
and thy fierce strength...
Please purify me
and my opponent!
The challenger Satoshi
faces Island Queen Hāpu'u!
The Poni Island Grand Trial
will now commence...
Begin!
Grand Trial
Right, let’s—
Banbadoro!
100,000 Horsepower!
Right off the bat, huh?
Pikachu, dodge it with Lightning Speed!
Now go!
How’d you like that?!
That’s...
I read in a book that Banbadoro’s ability
boosts its Defense whenever it’s hit by an attack!
She stole my line-roto...
Does that mean that
the more Satoshi attacks,
the less effective
his attacks will be?
But it takes a lot of courage to
just take attacks on purpose.
I’m sure Hāpu'u has a lot of faith
in her own Pokémon.
It’s her first outing,
yet she’s an amazing Island Queen!
I hope they both give it
everything they have in this Grand Trial.
That did not hurt us.
Then we’ll try a combo attack!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Right! You got it!
Pikachu’s attacks aren’t hurting it.
Is it because Banbadoro’s
Defense has gone up?
This will be a long battle.
Banbadoro, attack with
100,000 Horsepower!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
And then Iron Tail!
Even if its Defense has gone up,
Iron Tail’s definitely gonna hurt!
Banbadoro, use Double Kick!
Pikachu!
Banbadoro’s power
is amazing-roto!
Pikachu’s on the ropes.
Electric moves don’t work,
after all.
But Satoshi must surely have known that
before challenging this Grand Trial!
And Hāpu'u is battling at full power,
fully aware of her advantage.
They’re both so cool!
Well, Satoshi,
what will you do next?
You shouldn’t even have to ask!
We always fight at full power!
Isn’t that right, Pikachu?
Banbadoro! Can you, too,
feel their determination?
If so... Ground Stomp!
Pikachu, dodge!
Pikachu!
I’m soaked!
Be careful-roto!
Pikachu, are you all right?!
You narrowly succeeded
in evading it, did you?
But I will not hold back!
Banbadoro, it is time for
a Ground Stomp combo attack!
Dodge, Pikachu!
Here comes another!
We managed to dodge that,
but she’s totally controlling the battle.
How do we beat that Banbadoro?
They are using the pillars
surrounding the field as footing...
...to evade Banbadoro’s
attacks, are they?
Satoshi, Pikachu...
You truly are fascinating.
Banbadoro! Let us demonstrate
to them our full power!
A Z-Move?!
Pikachu, be careful!
Vast roots spreading through
Poni Island’s soil...
Bestow upon us your power!
Rising Land Over!
Pikachu, run!
Pikachu!
A fall from that height has
a 100% chance of incapacitating him-roto!
Calm down!
Pikachu, fire an Electric Net down!
Are you all right?
Great call, Satoshi!
He utilized an Electric move that
would have no effect in this battle...
...in quite the unusual fashion.
Oh, I know!
Pikachu, our counterattack
starts now!
Now?
Jump between the pillars
with Lightning Speed!
Is your “counterattack”
a mere attempt to throw us off with speed?
Banbadoro,
restrain them with Stomp!
We will not lose
a battle of endurance!
Banbadoro,
continue attacking with Stomp!
Pikachu,
stop where you are!
Now! Ground Stomp!
Pikachu, jump off the pillar!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
What?!
Analyzing... Analyzing...
Unbelievable! The seawater covering Banbadoro
has induced the effects of the move Soak-roto!
Now Electric moves
will hurt it-roto!
Is that even possible?
Satoshi is incredible!
Go! Go!
All right!
Let’s finish this, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Banbadoro!
Banbadoro is unable to battle!
As such, the winner
of this Grand Trial is Satoshi!
We did it, Pikachu!
You did well, Banbadoro.
I am beaten!
Quite remarkable of you to come up
with such an unconventional strategy!
Congratulations, Satoshi!
Thanks, everyone!
And now...
The Island Queen has a present for you.
Pick whichever one you wish.
What? Whichever one I want?!
Pikachu, you can choose.
You were the one who won, after all!
Now, which will he pick?
Oh, the Steel-Z!
That is quite the interesting one
you have chosen.
Treat it with care!
Yeah!
I got a Steel-Z!
I, the Island Queen Hāpu'u...
...hereby declare that the Island Pilgrim,
Satoshi, has cleared his Grand Trial!
Kapu-Rehire!
You were watching?!
I...
Satoshi?!
Oh, my...
You truly are quite rash.
Ms. Joy, thank you
for looking after us!
It was my pleasure!
It seems they all carried out
their projects beautifully.
Did they? Well, what did—
I cleared the Grand Trial
and got a Steel-Z!
Denjimushi has evolved
into Kuwagannon!
And Ashimari into Oshamari!
I’ve made a new dish...
And look at this! It’s Xiemi!
I got a Flying-Z!
I got to meet my brother,
and look at all the records I have
from my Poni Island observation!
You all did great!
Thank you!
Everybody!
Hāpu'u!
I bring souvenirs! Feel free to take these
freshly plucked Poni Radishes with you!
All of these?!
Wow! I can make plenty
of my new dish now!
Hāpu'u, let’s battle
again some time!
Naturally! I await your return!
Good bye!
Take care of yourselves!
Hāpu'u, see you later!
See you later!
Satoshi and the others have finished
their research projects on Poni Island.
They’ve all developed in their own ways...
And the group seems to have gotten a bit bigger.
The ship now heads for Melemele Island.
There, Professor Burnet, Principal Okido
and all the others are...
Hm? What is this?
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon I sent out for
Hāpu'u’s Grand Trial was Pikachu!
The Draft Horse Pokémon
Banbadoro is a Ground type.
It doesn’t run all that fast,
but its power and stamina are amazing!
Apparently it can keep running for three days
and nights straight, while dragging a load with it!
Awesome!
Pikachu, you fought really hard!
It feels like the silence
after a storm has lifted.
Oh, feeling lonely already?
Most certainly not!
I said nothing about feeling lonely!
In any event,
I am accustomed to being alone!
Next episode
Led by the gentle Alolan breeze,
the 991th Poké-Golf Major Title League...
...is finally opening in Alola!
I, Kukui, will be the referee,
while the commentary...
...me, the legendary Poké-Golf Caddy Guru,
will be the provider of!
Let’s study golf!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Hole-In-One at Poké-Golf!
Next time
Professor, who is that guy?