The PokéProblem!
I, Māmane, will be giving
this week’s question!
Heights
Crowds
The lake by the forest
Dark places
Ta-daah! Here’s the question:
I just can’t stand one
of these places. Which one is it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
So sorry, Satoshi.
I thought that we could get some food together
after I showed you the way to the shopping mall,
but my researcher colleagues
called me out of the blue.
Don’t worry about it!
I’ll just train for battle.
Right, everyone?
I’ll provide support
during his training-roto!
Counting on you!
But man, I must say...
I was happy to get
some time off, for once...
Pokémon researchers
sure do love discussing theories...
Though to be fair, so do I.
Have a nice trip!
Sure! Thanks!
Satoshi has enrolled at
the Pokémon School,
and now lives with Professor Kukui,
his teacher, along with Pikachu and the others.
But it looks like today,
they’re watching the house on their own.
I fear trouble awaits...
What kind of training should we do?
It might be fun to
go get some Pokémon, too!
Aw, man...
The expansion rate of that stain
is at 25%-roto!
Aw, look at that mess...
First priority: Laundry-roto!
Yeah!
Right...
Is this dirty laundry, too?
Wash it!
This, too!
And this!
Let’s just throw it all in!
Then throw in some detergent...
And... Push!
The power of machinery
is amazing!
Did you set it up properly-roto?
Yeah! Perfectly!
It was a piece of cake!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Shocking Prickles Togedemaru!
What was that-roto?
What is this?!
Emergency! Emergency! Emergency!
What’s up, Rotom?
How did this happen?
Man, I’m starving!
Anything edible here?
This’ll do!
Lunch ti—
Wait-roto!
What, Rotom?
You have to cook it first-roto!
I can’t really cook...
I watched a cooking show
with Professor Kukui-roto!
You can do it, too,
if you just follow my instructions-roto!
Fine, fine...
Well, it’s better to
have it taste good, I guess.
First, chop the vegetables
into small cubes-roto.
Chop the round ones into cubes...?
Second, add appropriate amounts
of salt and pepper-roto!
“Appropriate” amounts?
So whatever feels right, yeah?
Then flambé it once it’s
warmed all the way through-roto!
Flabébé?
It looks pretty different
from what was on TV-roto...
Well, you know...
It’s not the look that matters!
Lunch time!
There’s nothing else left...
Guess we’re going shopping!
So this is the shopping mall...
It’s huge!
There are all kinds of stores-roto!
Um...
Where do they sell food?
Huh?
Māmane! And Togedemaru, too!
Flinch!
Huh? Satoshi?
Alola!
You out shopping, too?
Well... Yeah...
No, Togedemaru!
Looks like Pikachu has a fan!
Togedemaru. Roly-Poly Pokémon.
Electric/Steel type.
Its capacity to produce electricity
is somewhat limited,
but the long hairs on its back act as lightning rods.
The bolts of lightning it attracts...
...are stored as energy
in its electric sac!
Oh! I remember!
When it’s happy,
it’ll curl up and roll around.
But once it starts rolling,
it can’t control itself-roto!
So... What are you shopping for?
Well, I want...
...ice cream and stuff...
Ice cream?! I want some, too!
You want it that badly?
Yeah!
Customer number ten!
Your order is ready.
Thank you very much!
We finally got through
all the customers...
That was a crazy long line...
Way too much work...
Of course, meow!
This malasada doughnut shop attracts
more people than any other in Alola, meow!
Good job!
You can take a break now.
Thank you...
This is the place.
They’ve got so many tastes!
Which one should I pick?
Time for some ice cream!
It’s great!
I’ve never had ice cream
this good before!
I know, right?
I think this is the best ice cream
in all of Alola!
They use the highest quality milk and
vanilla beans, sparing no expense!
And they’re all exclusive,
hand-made products!
They sell out fast...
So we were really lucky
to get some today!
You sure know your stuff!
I guess you like sweet stuff
like ice cream?
N-No!
I just love gathering up
all kinds of info!
Oh, and... stuff like this, too!
Creating and analyzing programs...
I made this myself, too!
A Togedemaru training program!
Run!
That’s awesome, Māmane!
A training program?
How fascinating-roto!
I’d like to see the data-roto!
I’ll show you, if you’ll allow me to
dissect and analyze you!
I must decline-roto!
I just can’t get enough of these!
They’re super popular
with Pokémon, too, meow!
Wait, no!
Our initial goal was collecting information
in a place where lots of people gather!
And also, to infiltrate the place for Operation
“Get All the Pokémon Gathered in the Shopping Mall”!
Oh, dear.
I completely forgot.
Is this the security system?
I’ll keep watch, meow.
How long have you
been there, meow?!
What?
Pikachu!
Togedemaru!
Pikachu! Rotom!
Pocket MonStarmie! Tattsu! Dugtrio!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Togedemaru
Type:   Electric/Steel
What happened?
What was that?
Hey! Pikachu! Rotom!
Are you there?! Please answer!
Togedemaru!
Emergency! Emergency-roto!
Right!
Then I’ll just have to tackle the—
Stop!
You can’t just break
the shopping mall’s property!
But...
We’re terribly sorry!
There’s been a machine malfunction,
and it’s caused all the shutter doors to close.
We’re investigating the cause now,
so please remain patient.
I-I-It’s dark! I’m scared!
It’s dark! I’m scared!
Hey... Māmane?
Oh, Satoshi, I’m so sorry!
Say, Māmane...
Are you afraid of the dark?
Uh, no, it just caught me
off guard for a second!
I’m totally fine!
I mean, at night I’m not scared at all,
because Togedemaru is there with me!
Well then, we’d better meet back up with
Togedemaru and the others as quickly as possible!
Yeah!
Um, how long ‘til
the shutters open again?
I’m sorry... I’m trying, but...
Let me see.
Can you do it, Māmane?
You can leave
the system analysis to me.
It’s easy!
I just do this, and...
There!
Looks like the only solution here is
to reboot the entire system.
The main controls are
in the power supply room...
Excuse me?
Oh, excuse me for a moment.
Māmane, looks like it’s up to us!
What?! Are we even
allowed to do that?
Pikachu! Rotom!
How are you doing?
I heard everything-roto!
I just got the map
to the power supply room-roto!
I knew I could count on you!
Let me dissect you later, okay?
Let’s meet in
the power supply room!
Roger that!
Follow me-roto.
Right! Let’s go, Māmane!
Wait!
Hey!
What is going on here?!
It looks like the mall’s
equipment malfunctioned.
Well, fix it!
That’s easy for you to say, but...
I want out!
I can’t believe I’m trapped
with that thing...
It’s like a horror movie, meow...
Can’t you just get along?
It’s not that easy, meow...
What’s your problem, Nyarth?!
That hurts!
This is a shortcut-roto!
Now turn right!
Okay!
Māmane...
Huh?
Well, now I’ve got it!
Turn left here!
Sure!
Māmane...
Left here! Left!
I’ve had enough...
Give it your all...!
Why won’t this stupid door open?!
Hey, Musashi?
Musashi, I said!
Kojiro’s calling for you,
meow, Musashi.
The thing just refuses to open!
It was open.
Then we’ll just
get out through there!
This one’s shut, too!
That’s strange... It shouldn’t be.
What’s going on here,
Māmane?! Explain!
Don’t blame me!
I’m just looking at what the map says!
It’s closing!
Māmane!
T-Thank you...
Guess this is no time
to be squabbling.
True!
We’re out!
What a relief, meow!
We’re almost at
the power supply room-roto.
Pikachu?!
What are you...
...doing here, meow?!
Entering caution mode-roto!
Hey, you! Don’t just start battling
without my permission!
Mimikkyu does hate Pikachu.
What’s that?
It’s coming from above.
Pikachu!
Where’s Pikachu?
Over there, meow!
That’s just fine.
Let’s get this round one, too,
and then get out of here!
Oh, my,
what a darling discharge!
We’re here!
Wait, was this all your doing?!
When asked
“Wait, was this all your doing?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Everyone’s in trouble
because of you!
Pikachu!
Whoa, there! Not so fast!
Today is the day we finally
take your Pikachu, meow!
In times like these...
What do I do? What do I do?
What do I do?!
Of course!
Satoshi! Have Pikachu
fire a 100,000 Volts!
A 100,000 Volts?
Right, Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Were you even trying to hit us?
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Mokuroh, I’m counting on you!
Save Pikachu!
Are you all right, Pikachu?
Oh, this is bad...
I’ve got an awful feeling about this...
We’re doomed, meow!
Why?!
What even is this feeling?
Not only did it
absorb the 100,000 Volts,
but it used that electricity
to power up its own Shocking Prickles-roto!
Data updated-roto!
Looks like you two
make a good team.
Right, Pikachu?
Togedemaru is a girl, though...
A girl?
Doesn’t make them
any less of a team!
Oh, right!
The power supply room!
It’s over there-roto.
Let’s get this sorted out.
Yeah!
Good thing everyone got out okay.
Yeah.
We can do anything
if we work together!
Yeah!
Satoshi! What about our objective?!
What?
Oh, no! The shopping!
Wasn’t really any time for that...
Remembering that
made me hungry...
Oh, there he is.
Satoshi!
Professor Kukui!
I’ve been looking for you.
I saw the note back home saying
you’d gone shopping...
I’m sorry!
I wasted all the food...
I know.
So, today we’re having dinner
at the Aina Cafeteria.
Māmane, want to come along?
I want some mixed grill!
With a huge side helping
of potato chips!
I want some of that, too!
With that settled...
Let’s all run!
H-Hey, what about me?
There was some trouble, but Satoshi and the others
had fun on their first day off in Alola.
What will tomorrow bring?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was dark places!
Everyone’s got something
they can’t stand, right?
But I'm not afraid of them, either,
because I’ve got Togedemaru with me!
Togedemaru is a huge help,
because she glows in the dark!
Her spike-like fur hurts a bit, but...
I mean, that’s no big deal
compared to being in the dark!
It’s about time for bed,
Togedemaru...
G’night...
Next episode
A streak of red wind dashes through
the cities of Alola!
It stalks its prey without being seen!
Who do those eyes shining in the dark
belong to, meow?
Nyabby!
Young Satoshi VS Nyabby...
Who will be the winner?
Next time...
...on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Nyabby, the Marketplace Wanderer!
What even is this feeling?
Next time
Nyabby, the Marketplace Wanderer!