Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Get the right answer!
The Johto Region
The Kalos Region
The Isshu Region
The Kanto Region
Where do we go for
the special extracurricular lesson today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
In order to celebrate the 20th anniversary
of the Pokémon School,
you will be going on a special extracurricular class,
we’ve decideDangoro! Gantle! Gigaiath!
Special?!
Does that mean we’ll be going
somewhere amazing?!
Our destination is the Kanto Region.
Aww, just Kanto?
You came from
the Kanto Region, right, Satoshi?
Yeah.
That’s where the famous
Professor Okido’s lab is, right?
Exactly. We wanted to let you visit
my cousin Professor Okido’s lab...
...and see plenty of Kanto Pokémon.
That’s not all.
You’ll be joined by some special guests,
who’ll help you Tackle a certain experience
you can’t have here!
Special guests?
An experience we
can’t have in Alola?
You’ll find out what I mean
when we get there.
Sounds fun!
Sure does!
Are we there yet?
When we arrive in Kanto,
I’ll show you around.
Thanks!
Hey, Māmane!
How does this thing fly?!
You can fly on Lizardon,
but this scares you?
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way! (We’re waiting!)
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Alola, Kanto!
Takeshi and Kasumi!!
We’re here! We’re here!
I hope I can see a Rafflesia!
And I want to see
Tattsu and Seadra!
Oh? What seems to
be the matter, Snowball?
Oh, how awful!
Are you all right?
What do I do?
Oh, what’s this?
Would you let me have a look at that Rokon?
I’m a Pokémon Doctor in training,
for what it’s worth.
Please do. She got like this
right as we got off the plane.
Leave it to me.
Aww, this makes me
feel melancholy.
I can’t believe they made us take
the long journey back to Headquarters...
Why’d that bowl-headed four-eyes
have to call us back?!
I’m sure we’ll be getting
a drawn-out lecture.
It’s all right, meow.
Once we give her these Honey Doughnuts,
even Matori should cheer up...
Or not, meow...
Thought so.
It’s motion sickness.
She’ll get better soon.
Thank you very much.
Lilie’s late.
Huh?! Takeshi!
Hey, Takeshi!
Beautiful! What a beautiful
cabin attendant you are!
A flight with you would be
like paradise to me!
Let us embark together on
a flight of love!
I swear... We come to the airport to greet them,
and you go off acting like an idiot.
Kasumi!
Satoshi,
have you been doing well?
Long time no see, Pikachu!
Brat boy #1, #2,
and the original brat girl!
Why are they here?
Let me introduce you to my friends.
We used to travel together.
Pleasure to meet you!
I’m the world’s greatest beauty, Kasumi!
I’m the Gym Leader of Hanada Gym.
Gym Leader?
The world’s greatest beauty?
I’m a Pokémon Breeder,
a Pokémon Doctor in training,
as well as the former Gym Leader of Nibi Gym.
I’m Takeshi. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you! I’m Māmane.
My name is Lilie.
I’m Kaki.
The name’s Mao!
I’m Suiren.
What are you guys doing here?
Professor Okido
asked us to come here.
What?!
So the “special guests” are...
Oh, sorry to Quash your discussion,
but save it for the road.
Let’s go before Professor Okido
gets worried sicKaranakushi!
Looks like they’re going
to Okido Lab.
Oh, right, meow!
There were tons of Pokémon there, meow!
If we get all of them
and offer them to Sakaki,
we might avoid being lectured!
Nariya!
Yukinari!
Congratulations on the
Pokémon School’s 20th anniversary!
Thank you!
They look just like each other-roto!
Putting their hairstyles aside,
their eyes, nose, mouth and such match 99%-roto!
Everybody,
this man is my cousin,
and the leading authority on Pokémon research,
Professor Okido Yukinari!
Well then,
let me give a Pokémon haiku.
Twenty years it’s been
Truly the flow of time is
Quite a mystery
You all get Pokémon, too!
I will respond with
my own haiku-roto!
Two men side by side
Their faces a mirror match
Quite a mystery
Well done!
Heh heh-roto!
I asked Takeshi and Kasumi
to show you around the place.
Counting on you two.
Yes.
Leave it to us.
It’s huge!
There are so many Pokémon here!
Right?
There are many Pokémon here
that their trainers left with us,
Pokémon that we’re sheltering, as well as Pokémon
who just settled down here on their own.
Let’s go see them right away!
This place is perfect for
gathering data on Pokémon-roto!
I want to meet a Kantonian Raichu!
The most interesting thing about Kanto
has gotta be the Fire types!
Tattsu and Seadra!
There are far too many
Pokémon I wish to see...
Ah! Onisuzume!
We have those in Alola, too!
Oh, of course.
My own Pokémon are here, too.
Oh, there they are!
Hey, Kentauros!
Amazing!
Wait, Satoshi!
Kentauros!
Oh, that’s...
Gallop. Fire Horse Pokémon.
Fire type.
Just loves to run. If it sees something faster than itself,
it will give chase in the hopes of racing it.
All right! Come out, Lizardon!
Let’s go!
Gallop, let’s race!
What? You’re telling me
to ride you?
I’m so moved!
Kaki! Where are you going-roto?!
So this is Rafflesia!
And these are Kusaihana!
Alola!
That pollen is poisonous!
Stand back!
Get out of there!
Noooo!
There’s one!
Are you all right?
Snowball, that’s a Kantonian Kyukon.
There’s a cute Pokémon!
You’re so good!
Actually, going to Kanto isn’t so bad
with you guys coming along!
Huh? Where’s Rotom?
I’ll keep this up and get a complete Index
on all Pokémon in the Kanto Region-roto!
Next up is these guys!
See the difference! There!
Kantonian Nasshi are so small!
It must be because they
don’t get enough sunlight.
They really are different.
Here’s my partner!
This Ishitsubute
doesn’t have eyebrows!
They’re eyebrows?
Long time no see,
Betobeton...
Their sacred whiskers have fallen off!
Well then, I must!
Please, wear my wig.
Dugtrio are all hairless here.
And lastly, this one!
Let me showcase
Alolan Garagara!
Hold on!
No fighting!
They have their short fuses in common,
at least.
But they’re different types,
aren’t they?
Yeah. My Garagara is
Fire and Ghost.
If I recall correctly,
Kantonian Garagara are Ground types.
I’m impressed that you know.
Well, I have studied the subject.
Togedemaru!
Wait!
I haven’t felt this in quite a while...
Me neither!
Ashimari’s gone!
Garagara’s not here either!
What?!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Garagara
Type:   Ground
Ashimari!
Garagara!
Come out!
Are they there, Pikachu?
Stay away from me!
You still haven’t gotten over
your fear of Bug Pokémon?
Bugs will always bug me!
You haven’t changed, Kasumi.
This really takes me back.
To when the three of us
traveled together like this.
We had so much fun.
It wasn’t all fun, though.
I think it was all fun!
You sure have it nice,
being so upbeat all the time.
What’s that?
Let’s have a look!
Fushigidane!
How’ve you been?
Looks like Fushigidane
really missed him, too.
Yeah.
Ashimari!
Where are you?
Everyone!
You still can’t find Ashimari?
No.
Then let’s go to
the lake up ahead.
All right!
She might be playing
in the water.
I’ll go look!
That girl sure has guts!
All right, I won’t lose to her!
Garagara!
Where are you?
Knowing Garagara,
I’m worried he might have
gotten into another fight.
All right,
I’ll use this program I developed to...
An Iwark!
Let’s do this, Bakugames!
Calm down. It’ll be fine
if you don’t make a fuss.
Takeshi... What happens if
we do make a fuss?
If that happens...
Run!
Well, at least we found everyone.
What?!
If you ask us about “this” or “that”...
We’ll answer out of
sympathy for the world!
To protect the world from devastation.
To preserve world peace.
Championing the evils
of truth and love.
We’re the lovely, charming villains.
Musashi!
Kojiro!
Team Rocket duo
soars through the galaxy!
Like a white hole,
a white tomorrow awaits us!
Just kidding, meow!
Team Rocket?!
You’re still doing this?!
Give everybody back
their Pokémon!
Shut it, original brat girl
and brat boy #2!
We’ll be taking your Pokémon, too!
As if I’d let you do that!
Lugarugan! I choose you!
Use Rock Throw!
Great Nyarth Punch, meow!
We’ll fight with him!
Go, Crobat!
You’re up, my steady!
Lugarugan, use Accelerock!
You insolent little mutt, meow!
Crobat, use Supersonic Waves!
Meow, it’s electrifying!
Hitodeman, Bubble Beam!
Pikachu!
We’re not done!
Here we go, Mimikkyu!
What?! You’re kidding!
What even is this feeling?
I don’t know...
It’s so cute!
It’s a Purin!
It’s my first time seeing one!
It’s holding something!
Does that mean it’s that Purin?!
We’re in trouble!
If we hear its song,
we’ll all fall asl—
What’s with your face?
Yours is just as bad!
You all look awful!
You’re one to talk!
Not me, too?
Yeah.
Satoshi!
Mom!
The preparations for your
welcome party are finished!
A toast to our reunion!
Cheers!
Welcome to Masara Town.
Since you’re here,
you should have a look around.
Yes!
Want to see
Satoshi’s room, too?
It’s a real mess.
Stop it, Mom!
Hmm, it’s not here-roto.
I just need one more Pokémon to complete the set!
What? Rotom, where did you go?
I went on a journey to complete
the Kanto Index-roto.
Well then, I’m gonna announce
the plan for tomorrow.
What? What are we
gonna do, Professor?
We’re moving at Lightning Speed towards Hanada Gym
to have a Gym Battle!
You can see it now.
That’s Hanada Gym?
Yes, that’s right.
That’s where we’ll be
having a Gym Battle...
I’m getting pumped!
Satoshi and the others have had a lot of fun
watching the Pokémon in Kanto.
Next time, the Gym Battles against
Kasumi and Takeshi will finally take place!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was the Kanto Region!
I’m glad Kentauros, Betobeton and the others
at Professor Okido’s place were doing well.
Fushigidane,
keep looking after them!
By the way, Takeshi,
who’s the Nibi Gym Leader these days?
My little brother Jiro
is still doing it.
It’s nice that your little brother
cares about you.
All three of my sisters ditched the Gym
and went off on a trip somewhere.
Your sisters aren’t there?
Next episode
All right, Yukinari,
let’s get poetiCrebase!
The subject will be Gyarados!
I accept your challenge, Nariya!
The Gyarados was
Before its evolution
A mere Koiking
Call that a Pokémon haiKairyu?
If I say it’s a haiku, then it is!
I understanDonphan!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Gym Battle!
Z-Moves VS Mega Evolution!!
Next time
Gym Battle!
Z-Moves VS Mega Evolution!!
You all get Pokémon, too!