Alola!
You all doing well?
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Give it your all!
Alolan Ishitsubute
Alolan Koratta
Alolan Nasshi
Alolan Betobeton
Which Pokémon do I try to catch today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi and the others are taking
extracurricular lessons on Akala Island.
They were on the way there with
Lychee, the Island Queen,
when they were distracted by
a little accident that had taken place.
Despite this, they arrived safely
at their destination, Ohana Town.
The lessons start today,
early in the morning.
Oh, so this is what the town’s like.
Nice to meet you, Ohana Town.
What are you doing, Satoshi?
Everyone else is in place.
Get back here already!
Yikes!
So sorry!
You sure are carefree.
Alola!
All right, everyone’s here.
It’s finally time for the
extracurricular lessons on Akala Island to start.
Will there be any
cooking practice?!
Now, now, don’t be too hasty.
First we gotta move
with lots of Agility.
There are so many Mooland!
Herderrie and Yorterrie too!
Today you’ll be using the Ride Pokémon Mooland
to search for treasure!
Search for treasure?
That’s right.
The Mooland on this ranch are really good at
finding things buried in the ground.
You might find rare food ingredients,
stones, or maybe even fossils!
Will you be able to befriend your Mooland
and draw out its searching abilities?
That’s today’s assignment.
And whoever finds
the greatest treasure, wins!
Everyone, first you gotta pick a Mooland
that’s compatible with you!
Yes, sir!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Treasure Spotted!
Mooland Search!!
Whoa, you’re great!
So are you!
And you!
You, too!
You’re all awesome!
I choose this Mooland!
I’m going with this one!
I’ll take this one.
I will take this one.
Um, I...
Wow, it’s so fluffy!
Ow...
This is the wildest one
of the herd.
It’s still inexperienced as a Ride Pokémon,
so I’d recommend picking ano—
This is the one I want.
It’s got such clear eyes.
Nice to meet you.
Then I’ll pick...
This one looks good!
Ow...
That tickles!
And you’re heavy,
just so you know...
Mooland...
Nyabby’s doing just fine
living with me.
Don’t worry!
Satoshi!
Look at what’s happening
to you right now!
I choose this Mooland!
Well then,
let me explain the rules.
You’re free to search
wherever you want,
but as soon as you hear the bell ring,
make your way back here.
I’ll be appraising and scoring
the treasures you’ve found halfway through.
And once the bell rings
a second time, you’re done.
Do your best, and try to win!
Yes!
Kaki, I challenge you!
Fine by me!
Let the Mooland Treasure Hunt...
...begin!
All right!
I’m gonna win for sure!
Wait-roto!
Let’s go, too!
Satoshi and Kaki
sure are quick.
We can’t let them beat us!
Shall we go to the forest,
Amamaiko?
All right, Mooland.
Counting on you!
Let’s go to a rocky area!
Let’s set off.
There we go...
Suiren!
Are you all right?
Absolutely!
I won’t fall again, I’m sure!
Suiren’s Tackling the situation.
I can do this!
She sure has guts.
There’s treasure that way?
They managed to get going.
Yeah. Now all that’s left...
My preparations are complete!
You’re really motivated!
Can you do it?
Yes! I can!
It is perfectly logical to conclude that,
were I to put my mind to it...
I can surely...
It’s all right!
You have plenty of time!
Take your time to
get to know each other.
Y-Yes...
Mooland sure is in high spirits!
This’ll be good!
Mooland,
did you find something?
I hope it’s treasure!
What’s this?
That’s a Red Shard, which certain enthusiasts
would be happy to receive-roto!
Good job finding it.
Cut it out...
What is it this time?
That’s a Blue Shard, which certain enthusiasts
would be happy to receive-roto!
All right, all right...
Thanks, Mooland.
This time it’s gotta be
an awesome treasure!
All right!
This wouldn’t happen to be...
A Green Shard, which certain enthusiasts
would be happy to receive-roto!
Thought so.
I’m soaked!
Ancient layers of sediment
are exposed.
This is it!
Search every inch.
There’s treasure here?
Did you find it?
Oh, you were just hungry?
Let’s go looking for treasure
when you’re done eating!
Tiny Mushrooms!
These are delicious when you
sauté them with butter!
Thank you, Mooland!
Big Mushrooms!
These are delicious when
added to a pot-au-feu!
Great work, Mooland!
Well? Do you think
there’s treasure here?
No reaction, huh?
I feel like there’s something here.
Some treasure in this area
that’ll net me a high score...
A Star Piece?
Rare fruits, pretty stones, fossils...
It’s just like Ms. Lychee said!
I see.
“Three hundred years ago,
a meteor struck Akala Island,
and Star Pieces from that impact
are scattered across the island.”
This is it!
We might find one if we
keep going this way!
Mooland, run!
Mooland, you eat too much.
It’s the bell!
Mooland, we’re going back.
Right, everyone’s back.
Ms. Lychee, I leave the appraisal to you.
Well then, let’s start with Satoshi.
Red, Blue and Green Shards.
Fifteen points total.
All right, I’m first!
You’re the first to get points.
Next, Mao.
Tiny Mushrooms and Big Mushrooms.
Twenty points!
All right!
I’ve already been outdone.
Māmane and Suiren...
...haven’t found anything yet,
so zero points.
I’m aiming for something special
that’ll turn the tables in one go, so I’m fine!
And Lilie...
She’s undergoing training
to ride Mooland!
Lilie, hang in there!
I know you can ride it!
Yes! I shall do my best!
Lastly, Kaki.
Yes.
What’s that? A pebble?
No, this is a Pokémon fossil.
Part of a Zugaidos’s head!
You get one hundred points!
You’ve got a strong lead.
How’s that, Satoshi?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Herderrie
Type:   Normal
You and Kaki are 85 points apart.
At this rate, there’s a 99% chance
that you will lose-roto!
Yeah...
Mooland...
If we wanna beat Kaki,
we gotta find something really awesome!
You found something?
This time, for sure...
All right!
Oh, my!
That’s a Yellow Shard, which certain enthusiasts
would be happy to receive-roto!
Enough with the Shards already!
Look properly this time.
You’re sleeping?!
Wake up, Mooland!
This is bad.
Should we search on our own?
Ashimari?
Do you smell something, Ashimari?
What happened?!
Are you all right, Ashimari?
Ashimari, I’m so sorry!
We have to get out of here!
But now Mooland will be in danger!
You’re gonna fight, Ashimari?
All right.
Bubble Beam!
Ashimari!
You did well, Ashimari.
I’ll protect both Ashimari
and Mooland!
Mooland?
Thank you, Mooland.
You want me to get on?
Did you find something?
Mooland, it looks like fossils will get us
more points than food will.
Could it be a fossil?!
There are so many
delicious-looking fruits!
I have to say,
you really are a glutton!
Huh?
The meteor that fell three hundred years ago
was found and recovered.
So if I simulate where the pieces
would have flown off from that point...
It looks like there’s
something up ahead!
All right, it’s this way!
Mooland, run!
Mooland, you’ve found
something awesome, right?
This, huh?
Ishitsubute?!
But its face is kind of different.
Ishitsubute: Alolan Form.
Rock Pokémon. Rock/Electric type.
If you accidentally step on an Ishitsubute
sleeping on the ground, you’ll hear a crunching sound,
and feel a shock ripple
through your entire body.
Really? It’s an Electric type?
The Ishitsubute you know
is this one-roto.
Yeah, that’s the one!
All right, I’m gonna
catch its Alolan form!
Hey, wait!
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
They’re both Electric types,
so it’s not very effective-roto!
Here it comes, Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
Go, Monster Ball!
That’s Thunder Punch-roto!
Ishitsubute fled-roto.
Good, Lilie!
You’re almost there!
Remember!
You managed to befriend
Snowball and Pikachu, didn’t you?
I...
I want to...
...touch more Pokémon!
Mooland,
there isn’t much time left.
See? That’s the closing bell.
Did you find something?
Now only Suiren’s left.
There she is!
We’re late! We’re so late!
Well then, Ms. Lychee.
Your final appraisals, please.
First, Satoshi.
One Yellow Shard.
That’s five points.
With the first half,
that’s twenty points total!
Figures...
Kaki got a hundred points
in the first half alone...
I win!
You wasted the second half
with not even an Ishitsubute to show for it-roto.
Let’s have a look, Mao.
Mao found a Sang Berry!
It’s huge!
Yes, they’re rare
even at their normal size,
but ones this big
are particularly rare!
75 points!
With the first half,
that’s 95 points total!
So close...
I’m next!
What Māmane found...
...is a piece of a meteor that
fell on Akala Island 300 years ago.
It’s a meteorite,
also known as a Star Piece!
Wow...
You did well to find it.
150 points!
Māmane’s in first place!
W-Well... Yeah...
And Lilie’s treasure is...
...that!
Lilie, you’ve managed to ride it!
Awesome!
You’re so cool!
You did it, Lilie.
Thank you all so much.
Her efforts have been rewarded
with so much love.
Yeah.
In that case, I’ll let you
ride my Lizardon later!
I... I think I’ll pass, for now...
Well then, next up is Kaki.
Another fossil!
It looks like a plume of some kind.
Yes, this is an Archen fossil.
Two hundred points.
That’s three hundred in total.
All right!
And here I thought I’d won...
Kaki wins after all, huh?
There’s still Suiren.
And Suiren’s got...
Ms. Lychee, what’s this?
The ore Z-Rings are made of.
The ore Z-Rings are made of?!
Five hundred points!
The Mooland Ride
treasure hunt’s winner...
...is Suiren!
Congratulations!
You did it, Suiren!
I lost.
It’s all thanks to Mooland.
I’ll use this ore to make a Z-Ring.
A Z-Ring...
For me?!
Of course.
Awesome!
Suiren!
I’m so jealous!
I’m happy for you, Suiren.
And I for you.
Thank you.
The curtains close on the treasure hunt,
with Suiren as the winner.
But the greatest treasure of all may just be
the friendship everyone formed with their Mooland!
Well then, the extracurricular
lessons will continue!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Alolan Ishitsubute!
The Rock Pokémon, Ishitsubute...
In Kanto, it’s a Rock/Ground type,
but in Alola it’s a Rock/Electric type.
Apparently the things that look like
hair and eyebrows are iron sand,
which got stuck to its body
due to magnetism!
Awesome!
That bath felt great,
right, Pikachu?
Come on!
I just got out of the bath!
Next episode
Hey!
According to the top secret
information I got a hold of,
you can catch a Pokémon called
the “Lord of the Lake” on Akala Island!
Huh? It’s so far away,
sounds like a total pain...
I’ve got a shift at my part time job,
and I’ve got a manicure scheduled...
Quit whining! Let’s go, meow!
The balloon’s ready to go!
Seriously?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Mighty Yowashi, Lord of the Lake!
Hey! I told you,
it sounded like a total pain!
Next time
The Mighty Yowashi,
Lord of the Lake!