Alola! You guys doing all right?
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Hope you like it!
Kosokumushi
Makenkani
Alolan
Nasshi
Abuly
Which Pokémon tries
to rob my backpack today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is the biggest shopping mall on
Melemele Island in the Alola Region.
What’re these?
Some kind of candy?
This is a Pokémon food
known as PokéBeans-roto!
Huh, PokéBeans?
I wonder which one Pikachu would like.
Amamaiko prefers
the flower-patterned PokéBeans.
Oh, my!
Flower-patterned-roto?!
Data updated-roto!
I never knew there were PokéBeans
with that pattern-roto!
These Pikachu-colored ones
might be good.
What do you think, Pikachu?
I’ll have some of these!
Mao, Suiren, I would like to look at
some scarves and bandanas for Snowball.
Wouldn’t you, Snowball?
Sounds good!
Let’s go!
Girls really love their shopping,
don’t they?
Yeah...
Statistics show that, when asked
“Do you like shopping?”
more than 87% of the women surveyed answer
that they either like it, or at least do not dislike it-roto!
More than 87%?!
I’m glad they had one that fit!
The shopping’s finally over, huh?
Not even close, Māmane!
Next, off to Alola Sunrise we go!
Go!
Huh?!
Alola Sunrise!
Long have I wished to go there!
Alola Sunrise?
An accessory shop. It’s super popular
with girls on Melemele Island!
Accessory shop...
...super popular...
...among girls?
Heart Scales
washed up on the beach,
or Sunnygo branches!
Their accessories made from natural objects
are absolutely gorgeous!
That’s right!
Sorry, but I’m going home.
I don’t want to keep the Pokémon at the farm
waiting for the food I just bought them!
Got it.
Later!
I forgot to water the flowers
in my yard! See ya!
Watering flowers?
Was that Māmane’s job?
Alolan Detective Laki is on
in just 17 minutes and 35 seconds-roto!
You’ve set it to record.
A true Laki fan both records it
and watches it live-roto!
Pardon me-roto!
Oh, come to think of it, I...
I’m sure you’ll love
Alola Sunrise, too!
Come on! You too, Pikachu!
Okay...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Promise Between
Satoshi and Pikachu
This feels great!
I often gaze upon the sea, too,
during my work breaks.
You here with your friends?
Quite the sociable little boy.
Say, can you see
that small island over there?
Yes!
People call it Treasure Island.
Treasure Island?
I like to go there to collect materials
for our accessories sometimes.
I meet lots of wild Pokémon, too.
Pokémon?
I wanna go to this Treasure Island!
You, Pikachu?
Well, in that case you can
use my sea kayak.
Sea kayak?
It’s a boat.
I’ll lend it to you just for today.
Thank you!
Satoshi!
We’re sorry to have
kept you waiting.
Shopping complete!
Really? Great timing!
Can I borrow your
sea kayak right now?
Of course!
We’re going off to
explore Treasure Island!
Right, Pikachu?
The sea in front of us,
and the sea behind us.
The sea to our right,
and the sea to our left!
It’s all sea!
And...
...the sky that’s
as blue as the sea!
You know, Pikachu, it’s like...
...we’re the only ones
in the world right now.
It’s a real mysterious feeling, huh?
Mysterious and exciting!
All right, almost there!
Full speed ahead!
Landfall!
There!
The Makenkani are boxing!
Awesome!
Those were some awesome punches!
Hey, can we join you?
Hey!
Oh, come on...
Who’s this Pokémon?
If only Rotom were here
to tell me...
Was that a sneeze?
Someone was talking about me
behind my back-roto...
Maybe it thought
you were a flower.
Let’s follow it!
It’s like paradise!
It’s a flock of Nasshi!
Alolan Nasshi really are huge!
Let’s follow ‘em!
Nasshi, Nasshi, Nasshi, Nasshi!
Nasshi!
Nasshi...
Delicious!
So this was where
they were headed.
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Thank you, Nasshi!
You tired?
I know!
Let’s have some snacks!
Is it good?
I guess I’ll try some myself, too!
Feels like it’s been ages since
we were on our own like this, huh?
We first met at
Professor Okido’s lab...
We’ve had so many battles since...
Then we came to Alola...
Professor Kukui and Rotom...
Mokuroh, Iwanko, Nyabby...
Kaki, Māmane, Mao...
Suiren, Lilie...
Principal Okido...
And all the other people we’ve met...
I love the Alola Region!
Everyone’s as warm as the sun,
and people and Pokémon
live together with nature!
Pikachu.
I wanna keep growing
stronger here, with you.
There’s so many strong people and Pokémon here,
like the Island Kings or the Totem Pokémon.
I really feel like I can get something vital
to becoming a Pokémon Master here!
I knew you’d understand,
Pikachu!
I hope I can keep
counting on you!
That tickles!
Stop it! Cut it out!
Pikachu!
Wh-What are these guys?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nasshi
..                 (Alolan Form)
Type:   Grass/Dragon
Why are there so many of them?!
Hey! That’s ours!
Hold it!
Pikachu, after them!
Well done, Pikachu!
I’ve never seen
that Pokémon before, either.
I guess we’d better head back.
What’s that noise?
Where’s it coming from?
From here?
You figured it out?
Oh, there?
You’re right.
It’s coming from in here.
The Pokémon from before!
It must have wandered in here
and gotten stuck!
Where’d it even come in from?
We gotta get it out.
Maybe if we climb up there!
All right...!
Right, one more try!
Thank you, Pikachu.
It’ll be all right.
We’ll get to you, I promise.
Hey, Pikachu,
where are you going?
Oww... Aw, c'mon...
If only I had Mokuroh
here right now...
I’m sure he’s asleep...
Nasshi?
Pikachu! Nasshi!
What’s going on?
I see. Awesome, Pikachu!
You’re a genius!
Nasshi! There’s a Pokémon in trouble
between these rocks!
Help me save it!
All right!
Thanks, Nasshi!
Are you okay?
I’ll come down to you now.
That’s right... Don’t move.
It’s dangerous.
One, two... Three!
Sorry I startled you.
I said I was sorry!
So this is where
you came in from.
But then the rocks crumbled
and you got stuck?
Good thing you weren’t crushed.
It’s all right.
Pikachu!
I’m counting on you!
Use Iron Tail on this rock!
Good job, Pikachu!
See? You can get out now.
Go on. I’m sure your friends
are waiting for you somewhere.
Are those...
...your friends?
Take care of yourself!
You...
A Pokémon?!
Wh-What’s this?
Thank you!
That must have been Kapu-Tetefu.
Kapu-Tetefu?
Does the “Kapu” mean
it’s like Kapu-Kokeko?
Yeah. It’s not easy to come across.
And the one you helped
was probably Kosokumushi.
Kosokumushi?
Rotom, show me the Index data.
I got it-roto!
Kapu-Tetefu. Land God Pokémon.
Psychic/Fairy type.
As it flutters about,
it scatters its strangely glowing scales.
Touching them is said to
restore good health on the spot.
So that’s why
my bruises faded...
Kosokumushi. Hightail Pokémon.
Bug/Water type.
Its habitat varies from
beaches to seabeds.
Nature’s very own cleaner, it will gleefully chow down on
anything edible, no matter how rotten.
Kapu-Tetefu is regarded as
Akala Island’s Guardian Deity.
You were really lucky
to meet it, Satoshi!
I want to meet it again!
Do you think I can?
Maybe if your luck holds.
Luck or not, I will go see it again!
Don’t you agree, Pikachu?
We’ll let you guys meet it, too.
Dinner time!
Satoshi and Pikachu have made
new memories together,
through having a small adventure
and meeting new Pokémon.
Will there come a day when
they meet Kapu-Tetefu again?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Kosokumushi!
Treasure Island was so fun!
Apparently Kosokumushi are like cleaners;
They’ll eat anything on the ground!
I was shocked at how many of them
there were, though!
Oh, and there was a small
yellow Pokémon flying around, too!
That was Abuly-roto!
Abuly. Bee Fly Pokémon.
Bug/Fairy type.
It feeds on the nectar and
pollen of flowers.
Because it’s able to sense auras,
it can identify which flowers are about to bloom.
Yeah, that’s the Pokémon!
I knew I could count on you, Rotom!
Next episode
Satoshi, do you have a moment?
What is it, Ms. Joy?
There’s something you need to know.
What?
The truth is...
Whatever it is,
please tell me, Ms. Joy!
The truth is...
Your Pokémon has
awfully stiff shoulders!
What?
Your Rotom!
Rotom?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
It’s Time for Nyabby to Set Off!
Where are my shoulders-roto?
Next time
It’s Time for Nyabby to Set Off!