Alola!
I, Kaki, will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Sunnygo
Metamon
Tsutsukera
Cuwawa
Which one of these Pokémon
causes a commotion today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Nebby has very mysterious powers.
One of them is Teleport.
That power sent us off to
unbelievable places.
Team Rocket came and
tried to capture Nebby,
and we were all teleported
to the roof of the School.
It was quite the commotion.
But every day is full of
thrills and excitement.
This is how I feel today.
Everyone, you can see it now!
That is Aether Paradise!
It’s huge!
Thank you all for coming.
Welcome!
It’s Wicke and Sauboh!
Thank you very much for
taking the time to come and greet us.
We’ve been waiting for you,
Lilie, everybody.
It’s your first time coming to Aether Paradise
in quite a while, correct, Little Ms. Lilie?
Oh, come on! I’ve been telling you to
stop calling me “Little” for a long time now!
To me, you will always be
our Little Ms. Lilie.
By the way, where is Mother?
She’s waiting for you in the mansion.
What? But I brought everyone here because
Mother said “Please come by for a tour”!
She’s got her hands full with work.
By the way, Lady... Um...
Where is Nebby today?
Here!
What are you doing?!
Sauboh!
Oh, excuse me!
I’m sorry, Satoshi.
It’s all right.
Now then, Young Lady,
let us head for the mansion.
But I thought we might give my friends
a tour around the facility...
You can do that after
meeting with President Lusamine.
Now, let us be off.
This way. Come along.
Thank you for coming all this way...
...to our Aether Paradise.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
C’mon, Let’s Search for the
Transformed Metamon!
This way.
Please, go on.
I can’t believe the brats came to us.
I’m more amazed by...
Welcome! Would you like
some Honey Doughnuts?
Today’s a complete bust.
How many have we sold?
Um...
Since this morning, one, meow.
That’s gotta be the one I ate earlier.
Oh, my!
Allow me to introduce you to an easier,
better-paying job...
Little talking Nyarth!
Gulp!
And then we were just hired right there and then,
as that guy’s underlings.
However!
Who’d have expected
this turn of events, meow?
The plan was to wait for a good time
to steal all the Pokémon here, but...
Pikachu and that
mega rare PetitDogas!
If we hand them over to Sakaki,
we’ll get promoted for sure, meow!
We’ll be going outside now.
It’s even grander than I’d imagined!
Liliemama’s house...
This is her work home.
That house never ceases
to amaze me, meow.
The President is waiting inside.
President! We’re here!
Welcome! I’m so glad you’re...
Thank you for coming!
It must have been a long journey...
Make yourselves at home!
I’m very sorry.
Yes, hello?
Oh, the interview?
I’m sorry...
T-Thank you for having us...
Eat up!
Looks delicious!
Thanks for the food!
No need to be shy.
Eat to your hearts’ content!
Oh, I’m sorry. So...
Oh, no, there’s no problem!
So, about that interview
we were discussing earlier...
Hey, don’t just stand there!
Bring some more drinks!
Oh, of course!
Thank you very much!
Why do we have to serve
the brats drinks?
“Brats”?
B-Brought you some more drinks!
Drink up, everyone!
Hey!
If you eat too many at once,
you’ll get a stomachache!
So it likes sugar stars.
Well then, why don’t you tell me
what Lilie is like at school?
M-Mother!
What is this about?
“What”? In here, I can
talk to you all while working.
Right, little Snowball?
You mean you called us all out
to Aether Paradise just for that?
What about showing everyone
around the facility?
Of course! I was going to
do that after we talked...
Oh? Um...
Oh, fine!
Let’s go.
I will show you around!
What? But I haven’t
finished my chocolate cake!
U-Understood...
Come along, everybody.
My chocolate cake...
That was delicious!
Oh, wait, Nebby!
I mean, Lady Lilie!
I will show you around
the conservation area!
Leave it to me!
Oh, yes. About that...
I swear, Mother is just...
Are you sure? Aren’t we-
It’s fine! I shouldn’t have to cater
to Mother’s needs all the time.
It’s completely unfair!
Unfair, huh...
Such is the fate of parents
and their children.
Here we are.
This is the Aether Foundation’s pride and joy,
the Pokémon conservation area.
Awesome!
We’re indoors,
but it looks like the outside.
I’m speechless!
Even Lizardon would have
plenty of room to fly in here.
Look!
They’re so cute!
Did you find something,
Ashimari?
What’s that?
A monster!
“A monster”?
What a rough reception.
Professor Burnet!
You know her, Satoshi?
Alola, Satoshi!
Professor Burnet is
helping Mother with her research.
Professor! These are my friends
from the Pokémon School.
Alola!
Alola! This is my partner, Gonbe.
Professor Burnet!
What are you researching today?
I’m determining whether or not this preservation area is
a comfortable place for the Pokémon to live.
I do regular dives to check that.
There’s no need to dive as
frequently as you do, though.
Really? It’s both my hobby and it serves a practical purpose.
Wouldn’t you say that’s good?
Yes! It’s fantastic!
Aether Paradise is an artificial island
the Aether Foundation built to look after Pokémon.
We gather injured Pokémon or ones who have gotten
separated from their tribes, from different regions,
and then we release them back into the wild
once they’ve recovered.
That’s what this facility is for.
Now’s our chance!
Look.
They’re Metamon!
You mean, the Metamon?
Leave it to me-roto!
Metamon. Transform Pokémon.
Normal type.
It can freely recombine its own cellular structure
to transform into other life-forms.
Thanks, Rotom!
I’ve never seen a Metamon before.
Neither have I!
When it transforms, it can blend in with other Pokémon
and then you can’t recognize it, right?
That’s why we’re treating them
in a separate room.
Are you sure you can open it?
I’m going to vaccinate them.
Will you all help me out?
Yes!
They sure are calm.
This won’t hurt a bit.
There.
Good child.
You’re the last one.
Metamon fled-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Metamon
Type:   Normal
Heave, ho! Heave, ho!
Hey, will we really be able to catch that PetitDogas if we have this?
Yeah... As long as we have this,
we’re sure to catch it!
I know that, but...
It stinks!
The Dogas line loves
putrid garbage.
This is the best way to lure it out!
But it still stinks!
Hey, you! Have you seen
a Metamon around...
It stinks!
What is this? It reeks!
W-Well, you see...
We got lost trying to get
to the garbage dump.
Found it?
It wasn’t over here.
Well?
It wasn’t there.
I’m sorry.
If only I had caught it properly...
It’s not your fault.
Yeah. That Metamon is just
particularly scared of shots.
So am I.
Me, too.
Same.
Everybody...
It’ll be fine!
Let’s all split up and find it!
It might have already transformed
into another Pokémon.
Metamon’s transformation ability
is amazing-roto.
We’ll have trouble recognizing it-roto.
What’s up-roto?
Wicke, was there a mirror up there?
No, there shouldn’t be one there.
Then, could that be...?
Unbelievable! It disguised itself
as me-roto!
Wait!
Where are you?
It’s not here.
Did you find it?
That Tamatama...
Something bothers me about it...
Why am I so bothered by it?
Um... One, two...
Three, four, five, six...
Seven...
That one has too many eggs!
It’s not here.
I’m sure it came this way...
Huh? That one...
I noticed that Metamon’s transformations
can be recognized by their eyes.
Everybody! You just have to look for
a Pokémon with beady eyes-roto!
All right! We’ll find it for sure this time!
Those are Nuoh-roto!
Suspicious.
It’s gotta be among them!
One with small eyes...
Oh... But if I recall, Nuoh...
...look like that to begin with.
Beady eyes!
With them looking all over the place like that,
there’s no chance for us to get close, meow.
Let’s just waste some time
while waiting for the brats to quiet down.
What’s that?
Nice, isn’t it?
I got some when leaving the room.
PetitDogas!
W-Where did it go?!
You won’t get away again!
Snowball, are you all right?
Why can’t I touch Snowball?
Snowball?
Then, this is...
Got it!
Amazing, Satoshi!
It’ll be over in a second.
There. All done.
Don’t run away again.
Thank goodness.
It’s all because you were
so quick to react.
I’m glad I was able to help.
Thanks a lot, all of you.
You really helped.
Actually, yesterday, some Cuwawa got stuck
to each other while taking a nap.
It was really troublesome.
Yeah! And before that, a Tsutsukera caused a real commotion
when it mistook Usokki for a tree and started pecking it.
We’re working with Pokémon after all.
There’s always something going on.
Must be tough.
But even so, we work hard to treat them,
and put them back in the wild.
That’s the job the President,
Lilie’s mother, is working hard at.
Awesome! Lilie, your mom
really is awesome!
You might be right.
Lilie!
Where are you?
Mother!
Are you all right?
I got a report saying that
a Metamon had run away...
You’re too late! We all worked together,
and we already caught it.
You caught it?!
Amazing, Lilie!
You really are
my cute little baby!
Stop doing that
in front of everybody!
Yes? This is Lusamine.
Oh, yes, the Aether Foundation is...
Geez!
Little Ms. Lilie being able to touch Pokémon
may be a problem.
If something happens to remind her of
what happened back then...
It would be trouble!
Man, it’s nowhere to be found!
Where did PetitDogas go?
Also, is it just me,
or are we walking in circles?
Now that you mention it...
It’s open over there, meow!
It was closed earlier, right?
Are you here, little PetitDogas?
Come out, come out!
Huh? Looks like some sort of lab.
What’s this, meow?
An experiment using Pokémon?
Type: Null’s ability to
counter Ultra Beasts...
Ultra Beasts?
My whiskers are tingling.
I got a bad feeling about this...
I feel like we really
shouldn’t be seeing this, meow!
PetitDogas!
Now’s my chance!
There!
You!
What are you doing in my lab?!
What? This is...
Oh, we weren’t doing anything!
It’s true!
Indeed! We were doing so little,
you might as well say we were doing nothing!
Well, it’s all right.
After all, you saw nothing.
Of course we saw nothing!
We saw so little,
you might as well say we saw nothing!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
was Metamon!
The Transform Pokémon Metamon
is a Normal type.
It can transform into anything,
but apparently some can do it more accurately than others.
It’s a good thing this Metamon
wasn’t the best at transforming.
Stare...
You’re a Metamon, aren’t you?
You can’t fool my eyes!
Next episode
The rocks are bathed in the Z-Power
of the blue moon’s glow,
and seal up the crumbling world!
Don’t play with my voice, Rotom!
I wanted to make your Z-Moves cooler,
so I was making some tests
with my voice sampling feature-roto.
Now, give it a try-roto, Satoshi!
The rocks are bathed in the Z-Power of the blue moon’s glow,
and seal up the crubbling...
Crumbling-roto!
Seal up the crumbling...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Gladio and Silvuddy!
The Confinement Mask!!
Gladio and Silvuddy! The Confinement Mask!!
-roto!