Alola!
I was told something about this or that,
and so I, Kojiro, am presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Hidoide
Nyabby
Makenkani
Pikachu
Which Pokémon joins Team Rocket
in today’s episode?
Get the answer at the end!
Get that for me...
Sure, here...
This berry is really good,
too, meow...
Ah, I just...
don’t wanna do anything!
We have delicious food,
a soft place to sleep...
This is super perfect!
This is heaven, meow.
What’s that sound?
Where’s it coming from?
It’s so annoying, meow.
It’s a call from HQ!
W-W-W-Wait a second!
Gotta get my face looking sharp, meow!
The report on your activities
in the Alola Region is long overdue.
We make our own judgments on
when to do what, thank you very much.
Musashi!
So...
Have you produced any results?
Oh, Sakaki, sir!
Um, well... You see...
We’ve caught a new Pokémon!
Uh... Hey, you! Come on!
Let them see you!
I-It’s called Mimikkyu.
It’s a very strong Pokémon!
I see.
Have you only caught
one single Pokémon?
N-No, we have more, meow!
That’s Kiteruguma, meow.
That’s right. Kiteruguma is
a very strong Pokémon, as well.
We have so many, we’re not even sure
who’s strong and who isn’t!
We’re not... Not...
So it seems.
For the sake of
Team Rocket’s continued progress,
I expect great work from you.
Y-Yes, sir!
Understood!
We’ll be sure to live up to
your expectations, meow!
Do not forget your
regular reports in the future.
What’s the deal with that
bowl-headed four-eyes?!
Just ‘cause she gets to be
closer to Sakaki, she’s...
Well, in any case,
we managed to fool them this time.
But what do we do, meow?
The only Pokémon we’ve caught...
...is Mimikkyu, and we don’t even know
what it is, meow!
Well, I guess we’ll just have to
catch Kiteruguma...
There’s no way, meow.
In that case...
We’ll go catch a new Pokémon!
Yeah!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
A Hidoidestructive
Extracurricular Lesson?!
The sun shines over Alola.
It seems today’s class at the Pokémon School
is being held at the beach.
Looks like they’re having fun.
Come on.
You’ll pay for that! There!
Come with us, Rotom!
It feels great!
No-roto.
Seawater is dangerous-roto.
Your body has been made to be
completely waterproof,
so you’ve got an Iron Defense up!
But what if the worst happens
and water does get in-roto?
My data would get ruined-roto!
Yup, you’re completely
waterproof, Rotom!
What are you doing-roto?!
What’s that, Māmane?
It’s a Bloster Water Gun!
It’s got automatic aim and
a water pressure control feature!
I made it thinking it might be useful
if we were gonna play in the water.
You made it yourself? Awesome!
Go, Togedemaru!
This water gun and Togedemaru are
an invincible combo!
Now you’ve done it!
Let’s strike back, Pikachu!
There!
How primitive-roto.
His scooping up of water
is far too inefficient-roto.
The water is spilling from his hands
at a rate of 50%.
The odds of hitting his opponent
aren’t even 30%-roto.
Let’s go, Lilie!
Professor Kukui, look after the egg!
Sure, leave it to me.
You’re wide open!
There!
Oh, come on...
Mao!
Let’s fight together!
Of course!
Amakaji, get them!
Oh, what was that?
You wanna fight?!
We won’t lose!
Lilie, Suiren, let’s go!
Got it.
Yes!
Kaki, come join the boys’ team!
Guess I gotta...
Let’s hope you can play
with everyone soon, too.
I’ve had enough of just
sitting around and waiting!
Well, what else do you suggest...?
You guys just do it yourselves.
I’m thirsty.
A Malasada Doughnut, meow!
When did you...
I bought it myself,
so it’s m—
My Malasada!
Hey, you, give that back!
Hey!
A Camome, huh?
Why not catch that?
Absolutely not!
It took my precious Malasada!
This is unacceptable!
That’s a Pearshen, meow!
Looks kinda tough, huh?
Let’s catch it.
It’s sleeping.
Now’s our chance!
What, already?!
You have to battle it, meow!
Huh?
My precious Monster Ball!
Hey you! Give it back!
Give it back!
Give... it... back!
Looks like we’ll just have to
drag it off by force, meow.
I-It’s too heavy, meow...
Come on! Do something!
I’ve had enough.
I’ve had enough!
Man, I lost...
You put up a good fight.
I’ll win next time!
Bring it on!
Those are Sunnygo.
They’re pretty common around here.
All right! I’ll catch a Sunnygo!
Counting on you, Mokuroh!
Run, Satoshi!
What?
What are these?!
It’s Hidoide.
Don’t let them get near you!
They have poison!
Poison?!
Let’s get out of here!
That was close, huh?
Hidoide are particularly dangerous
when they’re with their herd.
Hidoide. Brutal Star Pokémon.
Poison/Water type.
It has a poison spike on its head,
and when it attacks,
it turns upside down
and traps prey with its 10 legs.
I really wanted to battle them!
There’s loads of them
around here.
You might meet one again.
You can just battle it then.
I guess.
Everyone, let’s take a break.
Oh, a Kibanha!
I’ll take that!
All right!
Come on, what are you doing?
Too bad, meow.
By the way,
where’d Mimikkyu go, meow?
Its body...
Where’d its body go, meow?!
Hey, Nyarth!
Quit playing around!
I nearly went to
the great beyond again, meow!
You all right?
Mimikkyu... What’s beneath Mimikkyu’s rag
is dangerous, meow!
Huh? Mimikkyu’s right there.
New plan: Ambush them
underwater wearing this!
Nobody would bat an eye
at seeing a Sunnygo around here.
I see. Well, hang in there.
Wait, just me?!
Well, duh.
The sun’s killer for my skin.
If you lure Pokémon here,
I can battle them, meow.
I’d be at a disadvantage battling in water,
after all, meow.
Yup. So... Good luck!
Sure, sure...
Just gotta wait around here...
I hope I find the Kibanha from earlier...
Mamanbou, huh?
Right! I’ll lure them in and—
W-What?!
What’s happened, meow?!
Kojiro!
It was awful...
What’s this spiny thing?
I see... Hidoide, huh?
Hey, now that I look a bit closer,
it’s pretty cute!
Ow! What are you doing?!
Be careful! Apparently it’s poisonous.
Huh?!
A Poison Pokémon could be useful, yeah?
Hang in there!
Kojiro, are you all right, meow?!
Classic Poison Pokémon.
It’s real tough.
Now’s not the time, meow!
Stay away...
What?
Pocket...
...Monsters...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Hidoide
Type:   Poison/Water
All right, it’s time to start
observing Pokémon.
Each of you, find a target
and observe them.
All right!
Let’s look over there!
Got it-roto!
Stay away...
Why is it following me?
What’s the deal here?
It seems that Kojiro looks like
her first love, meow!
Huh...?
Makes sense to me.
Stay away...
She’s saying
you’re a real stud, meow!
No...
She’s all over him, meow.
That’s fine, yeah?
I’m not seeing any Pokémon...
Maybe over here?
Brat boy?!
And Pikachu?!
Team Rocket?!
We meet again-roto!
What are you doing here?
Right back at you!
Are you planning something evil again?!
Hah! Like a Kofukimushi
to a flame!
We’re gonna catch Pikachu!
Mimikkyu! Get him!
Iron Tail!
Nyarth! Sonansu! You, too!
100,000 Volts!
This is our big chance
to get Pikachu, and you’re...
Dodge it, Pikachu!
You...
She’s saying she’ll
battle with us, meow!
Got it! Let’s go, Hidoide!
That’s a Hidoide!
Hey, now!
What’re you looking at?
Mokuroh! Leafage!
Hidoide! Spike Cannon!
Mokuroh! Escape into the air!
Don’t let him get away, Hidoide!
Mokuroh!
He’s been poisoned-roto!
Pikachu!
Impressive, Hidoide!
Pikachu! Mokuroh!
Could this be...?!
Our first victory
seems imminent, meow!
Pikachu! Mokuroh!
Are you all right?!
We can win...
We can totally win!
The time has finally come!
Now, let us grasp our
long-awaited victory, meow!
Huh?
H-Hey, hang on!
Things were just getting good!
Victory was within our reach!
Let us go, meow!
What even is this feeling?
Pikachu!
Mokuroh!
Here’s an Antidote.
Thank you.
Here, Mokuroh.
Nothing more to
worry about now, Satoshi.
I’m so glad you’re okay,
Mokuroh!
Thanks, everyone!
Let’s keep going!
Now let’s play some
beach volleyball!
Sounds great!
In that case...
Ashimari! Balloon!
Let’s do this!
Pikachu, it’s coming your way!
There!
Togedemaru! Attack!
Too bad, Togedemaru.
Ashimari, do it again!
All right, I got it!
Hey! We were this close to win—
So sweet!
Looks like it’s gathered
tons of food for us again.
You got all of this for us?
We really should be grateful, meow.
Well, I’ll take what gifts I’m given.
I know! Why don’t we make this place
Team Rocket’s secret base?
Secret base?
Great idea, meow!
Here we have a warm bed,
and we don’t have to worry about food, meow.
And then, if we can catch Kiteruguma,
that’ll be just perfect!
Yeah, I guess that works.
All right! Starting today,
this is Team Rocket’s secret base!
Yeah!
Thank you for
the help earlier, Hidoide.
Would you come with me?
She’s saying “Yes, I can,” meow!
All right!
I caught Hidoide!
Come out!
Glad to be working with you, Hidoide.
Ow ow ow ow ow ow!
Well, we’ve got another ally,
so I guess we can call it good for—
Don’t stand behind me, meow!
Stay back, meow!
More honey, please!
Team Rocket has
made their secret base on Melemele Island.
What kind of evil schemes
will they come up with next?
Their battle with Satoshi and his friends
will continue!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Hi there!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Hidoide!
I got Hidoide!
The Brutal Star Pokémon Hidoide
is a Poison/Water type.
I’m glad we’ve got a Poison type
on our team now, but...
Her stabbing me
with poison spikes—
I could go without that...
Now, come out, Hidoide!
Huh? She’s not coming?
A feint...
Next episode
What are Alola’s
most famous foods?
Pile Juice!
How about Roserade Tea?
Or Alola Plates?
Can’t forget Malasada Doughnuts!
It’s gotta be our farm’s
Moomoo Milk!
Oh, mYadon!
I believe you’ve forgotten
a very important one!
Important?
Namely...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Great Alola Pancake Race!
Next time
Yes, that! RemembeRekkuuza!