Ta-daah!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Rumba
Cardigan
Samba
Guardian
Today we see Kapu-Kokeko’s Z-Move; “___ de Alola.”
What is the first word?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The battle between Satoshi and Professor Kukui
grew ever more intense,
and Nyaheat finally
managed to defeat Gaogaen.
But immediately after Nyaheat evolved
into Gaogaen himself, he ran out of strength.
As Professor Kukui was about to
send out his final Pokémon,
Kapu-Kokeko made an unexpected appearance,
and requested a battle with Satoshi.
Kapu-Kokeko!
We don’t mind! Let’s do this!
This just got really interesting!
Let’s do it!
How about all of you?
Do you want to see Kapu-Kokeko battle?!
Let me fight with this guy first!
Competitor Satoshi rises
to the challenge with Agoyon!
Alola’s mightiest combo; Melemele Island’s
Guardian Deity Kapu-Kokeko and Professor Kukui...
Their battle with Satoshi and
the Ultra Beast Agoyon is about to start!
The entire battlefield has become
Electro Field!
It’s like a sea of electricity!
In Electro Field,
Electric-type moves become stronger.
Kapu-Kokeko! If we’re gonna
fight together, we gotta win!
Yeah?
All right! Let’s go
at full power, Agoyon!
Sludge Bomb!
Dodge it, Kapu-Kokeko!
Steel Wing, huh?
Cross Scissor!
Use Steel Wing again!
What speed! What power!
Is this the power possessed by
an Ultra Beast and a Guardian Deity?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Alola’s Mightiest Z!
Kapu-Kokeko VS Pikachu!!
Cross Scissor again!
Magical Shine!
Steel Wing!
Dragon Pulse!
What?!
Dragon-type moves have no effect on
the Fairy-type Kapu-Kokeko-roto!
He used the Dragon Pulse
to blind them!
Satoshi shocks!
That’s just like him.
Impressive...
Kapu-Kokeko! Magical Shine!
Sludge Bomb!
Then charge straight in!
Discharge!
100,000 Volts!
Agoyon!
Agoyon is unable to battle!
Kapu-Kokeko, the Guardian Deity from
the Ruins of Conflict, truly lives up to the legends!
Is its astonishing power and speed
utterly unmatched?!
Kapu-Kokeko is strong.
But Agoyon sure fought hard!
Yes! We should applaud
Agoyon, as well.
Yeah!
Thank you.
I’m really glad I got to battle with you
in the Alola League.
The young Ultra Beast’s power was no match for
the experience of the Alolan Guardian Deity, I suppose.
I knew you could do it,
Professor Kukui!
Or rather, Royal Mask!
Pikachu! It’s all on you!
Both men are now down to
their final Pokémon!
Pikachu VS Kapu-Kokeko!
Whoever wins this fight will be
the winner of this spectacular exhibition match!
Let the battle begin!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Charge in with Magical Shine!
Are you all right, Pikachu?!
That’s the spirit!
Lightning Speed!
Magical Shine!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
Pikachu scores a hit
with Iron Tail!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Use Nature’s Madness!
Guard with Electroweb!
Lightning Speed!
Now!
Go!
Electroweb!
Dodge it!
100,000 Volts!
Discharge!
Oh, my!
Satoshi!
You’ve gotten stronger!
Just over the past few days
battling in the League...
You’ve shown rapid growth!
You hear that, Pikachu?!
We’ve gotten stronger!
Kapu-Kokeko...
You mean you wanna use a Z-Move?
Sorry, but I just used up
my Z-Move with Gaogaen.
What?
Kapu-Kokeko?
What is this?
Kapu-Kokeko has started singing!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kapu-Kokeko
Type:   Electric/Fairy
The Kapu have assembled!
What an exquisite harmony!
I feel romanticism in the air!
A Kapu shower!
It’s like a rainbow!
It’s so warm!
Me, too!
Did the Guardian Deities
share their power with us?
Wha—?!
So, now I can use it again?
Is this...
...a Kapu-Z?
What?! A Kapu-Z?!
The Guardian Deities’ exclusive Z-Move,
spoken of in ancient folklore!
The legendary Z-Move they say the Kapu fired alongside
a great hero, to save Alola in its time of need...
You mean you want to
use that Z-Move, here, now?!
Now this is getting
really interesting!
Satoshi!
I will fire a Z-Move
with Kapu-Kokeko!
You and Pikachu fire one, too!
Will you win...
...or will Kapu-Kokeko and I win?!
It’ll be a full power VS
full power showdown!
A full power VS full power...
...showdown?
That’s great, Professor! I love it!
All right!
The legendary move passed on
since ancient times...
Only when people,
Pokémon and nature...
...live together and share all,
is the ultimate Z-Power born!
Whoa...
No way!
What is that?!
An earth...
...titan?
Hang on! Satoshi is gonna
have to fight that titan?!
That’s way too big!
You can do it, Satoshi!
Hang in there!
All right. Let’s go, Pikachu!
Let’s show them our full power!
How long has it been since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Guardian de Alola!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
Pikachu!
10,000,000 Volts!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
I don’t need a suitcase, photos, or a guide on this journey
but I’ll keep the warmth of everyone I’ve met as a souvenir!
This is our...
...full power!
I had some really harsh memories along the way, too
What?!
Pikachu, can you feel...
...the power of Alola?
We’ve felt this power so many times
while we’ve been here in Alola!
Facing the Island Pilgrimage
Trials and Grand Trials...
Meeting plenty of Pokémon...
Having loads of battles
with our new friends and rivals...
We could always feel
the power of Alola!
Now it’s time to become one
with that power!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...so much more! Type: Wild!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Kapu-Kokeko is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
They did it-roto!
They won-roto!
Satoshi won!
He beat Professor Kukui
and Kapu-Kokeko!
He won, Lilie!
Yes! Yes, he did!
He won, Kaki! Mao! Suiren!
I’m so moved!
Yeah, this is incredible!
Satoshi, the ultimate Champion!
Satoshi, you did it.
Congratulations, Satoshi.
We won...
Pikachu...
We won!
Thanks!
The Alola Pokémon League Champion,
Competitor Satoshi...
...has also triumphed in his exhibition match
with Competitor Kukui!
Kapu-Tetefu?
You did it, Pikachu!
Are you all right?
Kapu-Kokeko.
Thank you.
That was an incredible battle!
Thank you, Kapu-Kokeko,
Professor Kukui!
Congratulations, Satoshi!
Could this battle have been...
...Kapu-Kokeko’s Grand Trial
for young Satoshi?
No, I suppose it could be seen as
a final exam!
Satoshi!
Congratulations!
Mom! Professor Burnet!
You, too, Pika-chan!
That was a superb battle!
You were so cool!
Yeah! You were incredible, Satoshi!
And Kukui, so were you!
Thank you!
That was a great League,
wasn’t it?
Yeah, the Alola Pokémon League
was the best!
Thanks.
But the real “best” here
are you guys, Satoshi!
Guess you’re right!
Hey! Don’t get cocky!
But I mean...
Man, you guys are just...
Following their victory
in the Alola Pokémon League,
Satoshi, Pikachu and the team have won
their exhibition match against Professor Kukui, as well!
Congratulations, Satoshi!
Congratulations,
Pikachu!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you very much for waiting!
Kapu-Kokeko’s Z-Move was
“Guardian de Alola”!
The legendary Z-Move Kapu-Kokeko unleashed with Kukui,
Guardian de Alola, defied imagination, did it not?
A power befitting of our Guardian Deity!
That really was quite the show!
Professor, we should get going.
Ms. Burnet, could you please
give Satoshi our regards?
All right.
Take care.
Next episode
What could be wrong
with Professor Kukui?
He’s been like this since yesterday.
Does he have burnout?
Post-League melancholy, huh?
Professor! Please!
Give us some battle training!
Huh?
For next year!
Next year...
Of course! Next year!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Sun, the Moon and Our Dreams!
Yeah! Alola’s second Pokémon League!
Next time
The Sun, the Moon and Our Dreams!
Good grief...