Got here on time thanks to Fly!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Amemoth
Hassam
Kaiross
Gusokumusha
What Pokémon does Guzma
send out first today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Alola Pokémon League has
finally reached the semifinals!
It’s starting!
Big brother!
Big bro!
Here I am!
Big brother!
Do your best!
Iron Head!
Well done, Garagara!
I was waiting for this!
Oh, no! Garagara, dodge it!
Stone Edge!
Garagara!
In the first match,
between Kaki and Gladio,
Garagara was knocked out first,
followed by Lugarugan.
They now only have
one Pokémon left each.
Will the winner be Kaki?
Or Gladio?
Big brother...
Big bro! You can do it!
Kaki and Bakugames...
Gladio and Silvuddy...
They’re all so intense!
Hang in there, both of you!
I will win!
The one to face Satoshi
in the finals...
...will be me!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Rising Fire!
There’s More Than One Rival!!
Now, Competitors Kaki and Gladio
are both down to just one Pokémon!
Who will give
the first Attack Order?
Silvuddy! Air Slash!
Bakugames!
Counter it with Flamethrower!
Break Claw!
Dragon Tail!
Break Claw again!
Use Shell Smash,
Bakugames!
Shell Smash has boosted
Bakugames’s attack-power and speed-roto!
Now!
Let’s go...
Bakugames!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Silvuddy!
What?!
They withstood it!
No way!
He changed Silvuddy into a Fire type
to withstand the Dynamic Full Flame?!
The sacred beast Silvuddy,
clad in a robe of crimson flames!
Having become
the incarnation of fire,
there exist no flames on heaven or earth
that can burn its body!
Break Claw!
Use Dragon Tail!
Bakugames!
Bakugames is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Gladio!
S-Such heat!
That semifinal battle burned
hotter than the hottest flame!
The winner of this fierce clash, who now gets to
advance to the finals, is Competitor Gladio!
You fought well.
Thank you, Bakugames.
Awesome!
Yup. He was so close.
True.
Big bro lost,
but he was so cool!
Yeah!
Gladio, too.
They were both super cool!
Yeah! Both of them!
Both of them, indeed!
Kaki.
That was a good battle.
Yeah!
Gladio!
Until now, I’ve always thought
Satoshi was my rival.
But...
As of now,
you’re my rival, too!
I won’t lose next time!
I look forward to it.
This is what a Pokémon battle
should be!
He sure made a mess...
Second place...
Silver medal...
This might not have happened
if you were victory trophies...
Ow...
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Next customer, your two
Manalo Doughnuts are ready!
Thank you very much!
If this keeps up, we’ll be able to
make an amazing mech, for sure!
Yeah!
This time, our sweat, tears, effort
and scientific brilliance will take the form...
...of the ultimate,
mightiest mech of all time!
Thank you for waiting!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Silvuddy
..                     (Fire Type)
Type:   Fire
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
Boss! Where ya at?
We wanna give ya some cheers
before the match!
Mr. Guzma!
Give it your all, Satoshi!
Don’t let your guard down!
Got it!
You have to beat that guy!
I will!
Hold it!
Team Skull-roto!
I can’t let that slide!
There ain’t no way the boss
is losin’ to you!
Got that right!
Ya said it, Bro!
The boss ain’t ever lost!
You can’t tell how a battle will end
before it’s begun!
This one’s obvious!
The boss’ll win, no sweat!
Satoshi will win!
No, the boss’ll win!
Satoshi!
We’re tellin’ ya,
it’ll be the boss!
It will be Satoshi!
Drop it!
Boss!
Yo, listen to this!
They were all,
“You have to beat that guy!”
They called you “that guy,” boss!
Can ya believe it?!
I just wanna wreck their annoyin’ faces!
Ya see that?
Yer not even worth acknowledgin’!
T-That’s what was goin’ on?!
That was scary...
Okay! Let’s give the boss
some more cheers!
Yeah!
Beat down and smash—
Drop it!
You’re distracting the boss!
Wha—?!
Got it...
Mr. Kuchinashi.
You should get ready.
It’s time, huh...?
Can’t believe that kid of yours
is facing Guzma.
Please judge them fairly.
Just hope the battle
won’t be too much trouble...
I agree.
I get that you want new stuff...
...to replace those stuffy old customs,
like the Island Kings or the Grand Trials...
But a Pokémon League?
That’s no good.
‘Cause everyone already knows
who the strongest trainer is!
If you think so,
then just join the League yourself.
Prove in battle that you really are the strongest,
and that it isn’t just talk.
If you refuse to back down,
then I’ll just wreck your League!
Let’s cheer him on,
Ashirène.
Give ‘im all you got,
Satoshi!
Team Skull! We gonna cheer for the boss together
and liven up this match!
Yeah!
The second match of the semifinals...
Competitor Guzma VS...
...Competitor Satoshi.
Same rules as in
the first semifinal! Over!
You both ready?
Yes, sir!
Let the match begin!
Here we go, Nyaheat!
Great Blaze!
Dragonfly Turnaround.
Oh, my! Competitor Guzma immediately
recalls Hassam using Dragonfly Turnaround!
Aqua Break.
Dodge it, Nyaheat!
Hassam was a much better
match-up for Nyaheat!
You’re right-roto.
Hassam is a Bug/Steel type.
Fire types would have
a significant advantage against it-roto.
And so he used Dragonfly Turnaround...
He is very cool-headed.
Gusokumusha’s Water-type moves
are strong against Nyaheat.
That Guzma.
He’s pretty shrewd.
Wrap this up quick and pain-free!
Aqua Break!
Nyaheat! Dodge and
use Fire Fang!
Throat Chop!
Are you all right?!
Right!
Another Great Blaze!
Aqua Break!
Another Aqua Break!
Dodge it, Nyaheat!
Nitro Charge!
Pin Missile!
Fire Fang!
Throat Chop!
Use Revenge!
Nitro Charge!
Pin Missile!
A tremendous
back-and-forth of moves!
My eyes can’t keep up
with their speed!
Yo, yo!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
Nyaheat...
You can do it, Nyaheat!
What will you do, Satoshi?
Didn’t I say quick and pain-free?
Aqua Break!
Use Revenge!
Good, Nyaheat!
Great Blaze!
Aqua—
What?!
Dodge it, Hassam!
Hassam is unable to battle!
...unable to battle!
Nyaheat defeated Hassam-roto!
Now if he can just
beat the other...
He’ll be in the finals!
Satoshi.
Don’t let your guard down.
Get back out here,
Gusokumusha!
What were you thinking...
Gusokumusha?!
You could’ve destroyed them
on your own!
What is wrong with you?!
Calm down, Guzma!
It’s your fault they took out Hassam!
Now what?!
How are you gonna fix this?!
Nyaheat, can you go on?
Competitor Guzma’s Hassam
was the first to be eliminated.
He only has Gusokumusha left!
Don’t you dare lose now.
Will it be Satoshi or Guzma
who moves on to the League finals?
The fierce battle will keep going!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Did you pull off a Future Sight?
The first Pokémon Guzma sent out
was Hassam!
Since Gusokumusha switched out
with Hassam so abruptly,
it might have the ability Emergency Exit,
which allows it to retreat if it feels it’s in danger.
Seems even Guzma
didn’t expect that.
It’s too bad about your big bro.
Yeah...
I would have liked to see the finals...
Yes, so would I.
Next episode
Let’s show our love
for Mr. Guzma by rapping!
Yay!
Yo, yo!
I can’t handle this stupid world!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
Guzma = Emperor of destruction!
Guzma = Undefeated, KOing his foes!
Our idol, Mr. Guzma!
Everybody’s bro, Mr. Guzma!
Pipe down!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
Next time
Guzma the Undefeated Emperor!
Sheesh...