Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Suiren and Satoshi
Kaki and Satoshi
Mao and Kaki
Mamane and Lilie
-
Which of us get to battle
the Gym Leader today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi and the others are in Malie City
on Ula'ula Island for sightseeing.
Where will the second day
of their trip take them?
All right, let’s go!
To the Gym of Kanto!
You sure are fired up, Satoshi.
Of course I am!
We’re going to a Gym!
I’m interested, too!
I’d love to challenge it!
I’m brimming with curiosity!
I want to get data on this Gym-roto!
I didn’t know there were Gyms in Alola.
Well, about that...
Apparently this Gym was created as an attraction,
based off the Gyms in Kanto.
Oh, Togedemaru...
So it isn’t an official Gym, then?
Doesn’t matter!
I’ll still get to battle, right?
Sheesh...
Mokuroh, Meltan!
Quit playing around! Let’s go!
Now, let us be off!
Yeah!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Aim for the Top Floor!
The Explosive Dragon Gym!!
So, where is this “Gym of Kanto”?
I assumed that Mr. Chikuwa would show us the way,
since he was our guide, but...
There he is!
I was wrong.
That was the Substitution Jutsu!
Believe it!
Mr. Chikuwa?
How long have you been there?
Entertaining the guests is part of
a guide’s job, too! Believe it!
Now, then, today I’ll be showing you
the Gym of Kanto! Believe it!
Much appreciated!
Here it is! Believe it!
Quite a peculiar building.
They built it to look as much like
a Kantonian Gym as possible! Believe it!
Not sure there were
any Gyms like this in Kanto...
You know about Kanto?! Believe it!
I come from Masara Town, in Kanto!
This is huge, believe it!
Masara Town! That’s where the leading authority
on Pokémon, Professor Okido, lives! Indeed!
What is the real
Kanto Region like, Sir?!
I hope our outfits look
at least a little Kanto-esque!
Indeed!
That I do!
Desu!
Believe it!
What’s with these guys?
They’re all ninjas!
U-Um, please calm down and listen...
Sorry! We got carried away,
believe it!
We have been quite rude, indeed.
We are Gym Trainers here
at the Gym of Kanto, that we are.
We look up to the Gyms of Kanto,
so we were excited to meet
a real trainer from Kanto, desu.
Let me welcome you once more,
to the Gym of Kanto!
Does that mean I’ll get to have
Pokémon Battles with all of you?
I want to do that, too!
We don’t do
Pokémon Battles, desu.
What? Really?
Here in this tower,
you’ll have to play our games! Believe it!
Games?
One of us is on each floor, desu.
You have to win in each of our games...
Only those who win all our games will get to
reach the top floor and battle our chief, indeed!
Sounds fun! Let’s try, too!
Yeah!
It is an attraction, after all...
While we’re here, we might as well
try it! Right, Snowball?
Let’s give it a go, too,
Togedemaru!
Of course, we’re in!
All right, we’re all in!
Understood, believe it!
Now, then...
He disappeared again!
Poof!
Well, then, let us commence
the first game!
Pretty!
I can’t believe you have
such a large pond and fountain indoors.
But what are we
supposed to do here?
My name is Hanpen, indeed!
Can you folks win against me?
Absolutely!
I’ll win and face the Pokémon Battle!
I like your enthusiasm, indeed!
The first game will be
water crossing, indeed!
Water crossing?
You must cross this pond, indeed!
I got this! I’m a great swimmer!
No, wrong!
Your task is not to swim! You must cross the surface,
or you will be disqualified, indeed!
Huh?
You may use the tools in this basket.
You may get assistance
from your Pokémon.
In any case, you must simply
reach the other side, indeed!
How do you use these?
You put them on like shoes,
and walk like this, indeed.
Amazing!
He’s walking on the water!
Wow!
That’s it? Looks easy!
Looks pretty hard to balance-roto.
No sweat!
Easy does it...
Agh... Stop! Stop!
What should we do, Lilie?
Snowball! Powder Snow!
I’m done for...
I’m saved...
We’re allowed to get assistance
from our Pokémon, right?
Indeed.
Let us go, everybody.
Amazing, Lilie!
You’re a lifesaver!
I’m glad to have been of help.
See ya!
You have done well to
clear the first floor!
Right!
You may advance to
the next floor, indeed!
Yes!
Next up is...
I am glad you have come, that I am!
I am the guardian of the second floor, Ganmo!
This is my challenge
for you here, that it is!
Each of you must eat everything
on one of these plates, that you must!
Just eat this-roto?
They’ve got Octan-yaki!
Looks delicious!
What’s this?
It is Malie City’s famed
Tosakinto yōkan, that it is!
How cute! It almost
seems a shame to eat it...
This is a perfect snack, right, Sandy?
I was just getting hungry, too!
Lunch time!
I’m sorry!
It’s sweet and delicious!
This is all great!
Thank you!
That was delicious.
Thanks for the food!
Yes, you have done well
to clear the second floor!
Was that really all we had to do?
The purpose of this floor is to have the guests
fully appreciate the greatness of Malie City, that it is!
Yes, we fully appreciated it!
But the next challenge is
a tough one, that it is.
Prepare yourselves!
Y-Yes!
Sounds good to me!
All right, let’s go!
More, please!
Māmane?
I’ll have a bit more to eat.
I want to know the recipe
to this candy!
Excuse me, could I...?
Well, see you later, then.
Hi, I’m Shirataki, desu!
Your task here will be to
hit these targets, desu!
Aren’t these shuriken?!
A ninja tool-roto!
Hit the target three times,
and you may proceed to the next floor, desu!
All right!
You wanna try, too, Pikachu?
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Dynamic...
Me, too.
Whoa, whoa!
Oh, no control, desu!
I am very sorry!
Everybody, please don’t concern yourselves
with me. Just go on.
That’s for the best, desu.
The other three pass, desu!
You have cleared floor 3!
Congratulations, desu!
We did it!
All right!
Lilie, see you later!
Everybody, do your best.
Just a little further...
I’m glad you’re here!
Believe it!
If we win here, we’ll get to face your chief
in a Pokémon Battle, right?
That’s right, believe it!
So, the fourth floor’s task...
...is this! Believe it!
Clear this course, and you’ll claim the right
to battle our chief, believe it!
I got this. This type of thing
is my speciality!
Hang in there!
Kaki is incredible-roto!
Just a little further!
Watch out!
All right! I’m next!
Be careful. That thing will move
as soon as we start walking.
Here it comes!
Right! Go, Meltan!
All right!
I can’t cross...
Sorry, Suiren!
Oh, fine...
You two do your best.
It happens, believe it.
Satoshi and Kaki, you have done well to
clear the fourth floor! Believe it!
It’s time for the long-awaited battle!
Believe it!
Really, so sorry!
Hang in there!
It’s finally time...
Yeah.
It’s a battlefield-roto!
Where is this chief guy?
Is anybody here?
We’d like to battle you!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
Believe it!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Tosakinto
Type:   Water
You can spectate from here.
Believe it.
I wanted to battle, too.
Here they come!
Is that the chief-roto?
Who calls for me
by such an uncool name?!
He’s not a ninja...
Suiren?
The name’s Ryuki.
I’m what you might call a star.
I go my own way!
I ain’t got no plans of
changing my style, yeah!
I mean...
I’m a star, after all!
Chief, you’ve got some challengers who
want to battle you. Believe it!
“Chief” is so uncool!
Call me Leader, got it?!
Leader just refuses to go along
with our ninja style, believe it...
Come on...
Pick a theme and stick to it.
Now, bring it on, challengers!
The star will face you now!
All right!
I’ll go first.
I wanted to fight...
Okay, challenger!
I’ll be the referee. Believe it!
So, let the battle between Gym Leader Ryuki
and challenger Kaki begin! Believe it!
Both fighters,
bring forth your Pokémon!
Let’s go, Garagara!
Quite the rocking look
it’s got, there...
Allow me to introduce my bandmates!
Come on, babies!
It’s a Dihead!
Dihead. Hostile Pokémon.
Evil/Dragon type.
The two heads do not get along.
Whichever head eats more than the other
gets to be the leader.
Whoa, there, babies...
Be nice to each other, okay?
So noisy!
My ears!
Oh, yeah! Time to start
our concert, babies!
That Dihead seems to be
getting into it...
The heads won’t fight as long
as there’s music playing, then?
This won’t stop us!
Let’s go, Garagara!
Garagara?
Even you, Togedemaru?
They’re all slaves to my music!
Dihead! Evil Pulse!
Hey, Garagara!
Garagara!
Garagara is unable to battle!
The winner is Ryuki!
Time for my victory shout!
Oh, yeah!
I-Is that even allowed?
Guess that’s what you call
a winning strategy, huh?
Satoshi, don’t take him lightly.
Right!
If there’s anyone who won’t
get caught up in his flow...
Mokuroh! I choose you!
Oh, of course! Mokuroh!
He might not be distracted
by the music!
Hang in there!
Hey, wake up, Mokuroh!
Time for a battle!
That one sure goes
at its own pace...
Can it even battle like that?
Mokuroh pulls through
when it counts!
Pikachu, Meltan, you stand back.
Now, let the battle between Gym Leader Ryuki
and challenger Satoshi begin! Believe it!
Oh, yeah!
Let’s go, Mokuroh! Tackle!
Good! He’s making the first move,
without the music distracting him!
Dragon Dive!
Use Bite!
Mokuroh!
Yeah!
Now, to end this!
Play the requiem of the underworld!
My best outfit!
They started fighting
the second the music stopped...
I’m really sorry!
Meltan, we’re right in
the middle of a battle!
Seems like your boy there’s got
quite the rocking drive himself!
Very well...
Let’s make this a Double Battle!
He can change the rules,
just like that?
The Leader sets the Gym rules!
If I say it goes, it goes!
He heard me...
All right, that Pokémon may
participate in the battle, as well!
Thank you very much!
Meltan, he said you can battle, too.
Are you ready, Mokuroh?
Right!
Mr. Ryuki,
let’s do this Double Battle!
Okay! Okay!
Then I’ll call in another of my babies!
Come on!
That’s...
Crimgan. Cave Pokémon.
Dragon type.
It races through narrow caves,
using its sharp claws to catch prey.
The skin on its face is harder than a rock.
Let’s go! Meltan, use Headbutt!
Block it!
Mokuroh, use Seed Bo—
Hey! Don’t attack on your own!
Ride the rhythm... Yeah!
Crimgan! Dragon Claw!
And Dihead, attack with Bite!
Meltan, Mokuroh! Dodge!
That move is Harden-roto!
It’s just waiting to get
knocked out at this rate!
Meltan, run!
Mokuroh! Peck!
Meltan won’t last long-roto!
Mokuroh! Another Peck!
What?!
That’s...
Brave Bird-roto!
You’ve learned Brave Bird?!
I can’t believe he learned
a new move here!
Amazing, Mokuroh!
Mokuroh, Meltan,
you can still go on, right?
All right! Meltan, use Luster Cannon!
And Mokuroh, use Brave Bird!
Dihead and Crimgan
are unable to battle!
The winner is Satoshi!
All right!
Amazing!
They won!
They did it!
You did great, Mokuroh!
You too, Meltan!
I really felt your hot,
rocking soul!
I present you with your
proof of victory...
We’re getting a Gym Badge?!
Yeah!
One with my star face on it!
Feel free to brag about it!
You beat me, the great Ryuki, fair and square!
W-Well, it’s a souvenir...
H-How lucky you are!
Y-Yeah...
I got the Badge
from the Gym of Kanto!
Wasn’t that fun, Xiemi?
And we got a souvenir
for Amajo, too!
I wanna come here again!
I’ll win next time, for sure!
Do your best, Kaki.
That was an incredible battle!
Yeah!
Let’s do this again sometime,
Mokuroh, Meltan!
That’s our Mokuroh...
What’s wrong, Pikachu?
That’s not candy!
Satoshi and the others are happy to have had
an unexpected, fierce Gym battle!
Looks like this turned out
to be a nice vacation!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
The ones to battle the Gym Leader
were Satoshi and me, Kaki!
The Cave Pokémon, Crimgan,
is a Dragon type.
They say that, when its body temperature falls,
it can no longer move,
so it warms its body by
absorbing sunlight with its wings.
It’s pretty sensitive to cold,
in other words!
It’s about bedtime.
Big Sis, what’s that?
What’s that?
A souvenir from Malie City.
I want one, too!
And me!
I figured you’d say that, so...
Here!
Next episode
We’re sorry to have kept you waiting,
dear racing fans.
It’s finally time for
the Kuwagannon Race.
High Potential Monster Machines
chase each other with the turbo on...
Don’t be too dazzled by their
super drifting techniques!
My super heel-and-toe has
the tachometer locked in the red!
I have no idea
what he’s saying, meow...
Does that really matter?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Superspeed Kuwagannon!
Māmane Awakened!!
These techniques aren’t
something you’re taught...
They’re something you discover.
Next time
Superspeed Kuwagannon!
Māmane Awakened!!