Alola!
I will be giving today’s PokéProblem-roto.
It’ll be my pleasuroto!
Poké-Baseball
Trampoline
Poké-Soccer
Jump rope
What activity did Satoshi and the others
perform at the Pokémon School today?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
I can’t believe how foolish I was,
to forget about Silvuddy.
I owe Silvuddy my life,
as it saved me both back then and today.
From now on,
I want to touch all kinds of Pokémon.
I’m no longer the same me
I was until yesterday!
I still can’t believe...
that Sauboh opened an Ultra Hole and
summoned an Ultra Beast four years ago.
If it hadn’t been for Silvuddy saving her,
Lilie would have been...
She must have been so frightened.
I can’t forgive myself for not noticing.
It’s like Gladio said...
I’m a failure as a mother.
Now that we know
there are dangerous Ultra Beasts out there,
we’ll have to be more cautious than ever
when investigating Ultra Holes.
Indeed.
Still no sign of Sauboh?
No. We’ve searched his laboratory,
his quarters and any other places he frequents,
but of course, he wasn’t anywhere.
Come here, Mokuroh! Pikachu!
Then, this one, too!
Lugarugan!
What’s wrong? Come here.
You’re so cute!
It hurts! But I’m so happy!
Nyabby!
Your whiskers feel so nice!
Then, try my Bakugames!
Oh, Bakugames!
Are you nervous?
If you touch those...!
Alola!
Time to start another class that’s
as electrifying as a Sparking Gigavolt!
Yes!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Sauboh Strikes Back!
Nebby Kidnapped!!
Come in.
Gladio!
Did you find Sauboh?
Not yet...
I see.
Wait, Gladio!
I want to talk with you!
We don’t have time.
Who knows what Sauboh might do
if we don’t find him soon.
Gladio...
Please let us handle Sauboh.
Gladio!
Today’s class will consist of
jumping rope with Pokémon!
For Pokémon and their trainers
to jump together,
they’ll have to be perfectly in sync!
Really? Sounds fun!
So! Satoshi and Pikachu will go first.
All right!
Watch our timing carefully,
then jump in at the count of three!
Pikachu, here we go!
One, two... Three!
I just knew Satoshi and Pikachu
would be in perfect sync-roto.
Come on, this is easy!
Don’t get too comfortable.
No sweat! No sweat!
Too bad.
Here lies Satoshi, defeated.
How sad.
One more time!
This time, I’ll try with Nebby...
Huh? Where’d it go?
Satoshi! Over here!
They’re having a cozy nap together.
Guess so.
Now that she knows
what happened four years ago,
the only way for me to restore my honor is
to capture an Ultra Beast and fulfill the President’s dream!
To that end,
I must open an Ultra Hole.
If I can get Nebby and the machine Burnet is developing,
it should be possible!
If so...
Activate Electro Catcher!
Please wait for me,
President Lusamine!
Using this Electro Catcher,
I will capture Nebby,
and bring you an Ultra Beast without fail!
I’d stick out a bit too much
in these clothes...
Here we go, Snowball.
One, two... Three!
We did it!
Lilie’s good!
She’s great!
Good going, Lilie!
Now let’s add some more
Pokémon to the mix!
Pikachu, you go, too!
Ashimari!
Amazing! It looks like there’s
still room for you, too, Amamaiko!
You too, Togedemaru. Go!
All right... Go, Bakugames!
It’s so much fun,
jumping with everyone!
Man, I hope the heat
lets up, soon...
Keeping this up any longer is dangerous.
I must switch to Plan B.
Next up is me and Garagara!
Let’s do this! Ready... go!
All right, let’s up the speed a bit.
Roger that-roto!
Amazing!
I knew they could do it!
They’re good!
Plan B is a success.
Come on over, come on over!
Have some Kiteruguma brand
Honey Doughnuts, meow!
How would you like some
delicious Honey Doughnuts?
Man, that Sauboh sure was no good.
You’re telling me?
Selling doughnuts is way better
than working for that creep, meow.
What’s up?
Isn’t that Sauboh?
Speak of the devil...
What’s he doing?
He’s planning to steal
the brat boy’s Petitdogas, meow!
Unforgivable!
I can’t let him get away...
...with that tepid disguise of his!
That?
Disguises are our very souls.
I could never forgive
such a half-hearted one!
But more importantly,
Petitdogas, meow.
Yeah. Petitdogas is our prey.
Let’s steal it before it gets stolen.
Just a little more...
Now!
Plan successf—
Whaaaaat?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Blacky
Type:   Evil
A-Aren’t you
that useless trio’s...
Operation Capture is a success!
Ha ha, take that!
Hold it!
Once we offer up this Petitdogas to HQ,
Sakaki is sure to be pleased, meow!
That bowl-headed four-eyes’ll
be at a loss for words!
Let’s hightail it back
to our secret base!
Oh, no!
This sensation...
It feels as though we’re
on top of something...
And as if we’re in the bosom of
a far greater being...
What even is this feeling?
I was so close,
and then they had to interfere!
Nebby?
Lucky me! No, but wait...
By taking advantage of Nebby’s Teleport, I can get right back there!
Nebby, deary?
Here, have some sugar stars.
What’s wrong, Mokuroh?
Nebby’s gone!
You see, Nebby...
Satoshi and Little Miss Lilie
asked a favor of me.
I’d like you to take me to
a certain place, sweetie.
And then, we can wait for them
together there.
What’s wrong, Satoshi?
Nebby’s gone missing!
Satoshi, look!
Nebby?
Good, very good...
Thank you, Nebby!
The guy with Nebby,
wasn’t that...
It was Sauboh!
What about Sauboh?
Gladio!
Big Brother!
Sauboh disappeared with Nebby!
What?!
Do you have any idea
where they might have gone?
They’re probably at Aether Paradise.
Huh? If so, we’ll need them to
send us a ship again!
It’s all right.
If we’re going to where Mother is,
then we have a special means
of getting there.
Understood. I will be there
to pick you up in two minutes.
Ms. Lilie, Master Gladio,
I am sorry to have kept you waiting.
Now, come inside.
All right, we’re off.
Don’t do anything too crazy.
I won’t.
I’m really not sure I believe that...
Lilie, you stay here.
Yeah, Lilie.
Pikachu and I will deal with this.
But I’m worried about Nebby, too!
Please, take me with you!
Suit yourself.
Yes!
Oh, here it is!
Do you sense it too, Nebby?
This is the place where, four years ago,
the Ultra Beast UB 01: Parasite appeared.
Because of the special electronic waves,
you cannot use Teleport.
If I use the same coordinates
from four years ago,
and amplify the Ultra Aura
with Nebby’s power,
I should be able to open
the Ultra Hole once more!
Yes, keep it up!
Release more and more
of your Ultra Aura!
Sauboh?!
Nebby’s with him.
We have to hurry!
He’s probably in the Red Area.
Sauboh can’t be planning to...
Of course he is. He’s planning to
summon an Ultra Beast again!
Summon?!
Mother...
Space-time is being distorted?!
It’s coming from
the sealed off Red Area!
What?
Good, good... Just a little more!
What are you doing?!
Oh, if it isn’t President Lusamine!
Behold! Very soon,
the Ultra Hole will—
Stop this, Sauboh!
Why, you...!
What are you doing?!
Nebby!
Th-The Ultra Hole!
Stop the machine!
Why would I?
This is what you wanted!
I don’t want this!
Are you planning on
putting Lilie in danger again?!
Blacky, use Shadow Ball!
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
Nebby!
Nebby, are you all right?
You’re not hurt, are you?!
Nebby?
It shrunk!
It’s like a pupa... or a cocoon...
What happened?
No data. Verdict impossible to make!
Impossible!
What?!
At last... At last,
the Ultra Hole is open!
The Ultra Hole...
Something’s coming out!
Lilie!
That’s...
UB 01: Parasite!
What do you think,
President Lusamine?
I, Sauboh,
have fulfilled your dream...
I have successfully
summoned an Ultra Beast!
Behold! Such beauty!
Come to your senses,
Sauboh!
Not for a single moment over these past four years
have I ever forgotten you!
Pixie, use Magical Shine!
Come back, Pixie!
Mom, you look after Lilie!
Let’s go, Silvuddy!
Air Slash!
Big Brother!
Gladio!
Pikachu! Use 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
Lilie!
I won’t let you!
I will protect Lilie!
Mom!
Mother...
Mother!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting-roto!
The activity they did at the Pokémon School
was jump rope-roto!
Was Nebby’s transformation an evolution?
Or a temporary Forme-Change?
It’s difficult to determine-roto.
It’s an unknown Pokémon to begin with,
so I don’t know the details-roto!
Next episode
Big Brother, Mother has been kidnapped.
Let’s go save her!
Wait, Lilie.
What’s with the luggage?
Just in case, I’ve prepared
a change of clothes, towels, Gold Spray and snacks...
We’re not going on a picnic!
I’m sorry! But, but...
It’s entirely logical to conclude that
Nana Berries do not count as snacks, correct?
What?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
I Can RealLilie Do It!
A Determined Runaway Act!!
Next time
I Can RealLilie Do It!
A Determined Runaway Act!!