It’s a pleasure to meet you!
My name is Lilie.
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Butterfree
Kiteruguma
Cuwawa
Kapu-Kokeko
Problem: Which of these Pokémon
visits my house?
I will tell you the answer at
the end of the show!
There’s no stopping her
once she starts...
Lilie!
Are you all right, Pikachu?
Thank you, Mao.
Don’t mention it.
I’m sorry.
I’ll give Togedemaru
a stern talking-to later.
Oh, right. Lilie can’t—
I can touch Pokémon!
It is entirely logical to conclude that,
were I to put my mind to it, I’d be able to touch them!
But you haven’t touched one even once
since starting at this school.
Indeed...
Don’t push yourself.
He’s right! You’ll manage to touch them
sooner or later!
I... I suppose...
Is everybody here?
Professor Kukui!
We’re going to
the Principal’s office.
It’s time for Principal Okido’s
special lesson!
Special lesson?
Here they are.
Oh! I was lying
in waiTamanta! Mantine!
Two eggs?
This is the one you brought
from Kanto.
And this egg was discovered
on Lanakila Mountain the other day.
Have you found out
what kind of egg it is?
That’s a surprise we
don’t want to spoil.
I had an idea.
I will raise one egg, whereas you raise the other.
How does that sound?
Us?
This’ll make a great lesson.
Raising a Pokémon from an egg is a very educational experience.
You want us to
look after it together?
Exactly.
Observe the egg’s condition daily,
and record any changes to it.
Simple, right?
Yes, yeSonansu!
But don’t forget to give it love.
Now, first off, pick an egg.
Which do we choose?
I wonder...
Lilie, which do you think is better?
What?
Um...
I prefer this one.
How come?
These markings look like flowers.
I find it cute.
You’re right! It is cute!
So cute!
Because of that?
What’s wrong with that?
I mean, nothing wrong, but...
That settles it, then!
I wonder which Pokémon it has.
Who knows...
I hope it’ll be a strong one.
When the egg hatches,
we’re gonna play with it!
This concludes my special lesson!
Now, good lucKoduck! Golduck!
Yes, Sir!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Who’s On Egg-Watch Duty?
As part of a special lesson, Satoshi and his friends
were given an egg by Principal Okido.
Everyone’s brimming with curiosity.
It’s kinda warm!
You’re right! It really feels alive!
Let me feel it!
Lilie, you want to touch it?
What?
B-But...
Even if you can’t touch Pokémon,
maybe you can touch an egg, since it won’t move.
I suppose so.
It moved!
Yeah!
Proves it’s healthy.
I’m sorry, Lilie.
Oh, it’s quite all right.
But I wonder what’s going on
inside the egg?
Rotom, give it a scan!
I don’t have that function-roto...
Hey, what are we gonna do at night?
Oh, right.
We can’t really leave it
in the classroom, can we?
Guess somebody’ll have to
take it home with them.
All right, I’ll—
I think Lilie should do it!
What?
But Lilie’s...
That’s exactly why!
By looking after the egg,
she can slowly get used to Pokémon!
Well? Wanna try?
What?
U-Um... I...
Don’t force yourself.
I will try!
I am a student of the
Pokémon School, too! I can do this!
That’s right!
I know you can do it!
Will you really be all right?
If anyone can do it, it’s you!
Give it your all!
Counting on you.
Yes! I will give it my all!
I’m so sorry! I have to help out
at the cafeteria!
Satoshi, I’m counting on you.
I got this!
I’ll get the egg to Lilie’s house,
no problem!
You do your best, as well.
Now, see you tomorrow.
Yup! Later!
Come to think of it...
Where do you live?
It is a bit far off,
but I have an escort.
Ah! There it is!
Young Miss Lilie,
I am here to bring you home.
Whoa...
How much farther?
We’ve already reached our estate.
Huh? “Estate”?
It means this is part of
Lilie’s home-roto.
What?!
Welcome home, Young Miss Lilie.
I’m home!
This is my classmate, Satoshi,
and his partner, Pikachu.
And this is the Index Rotom.
I welcome you.
My name is James,
and I serve as a butler in this mansion.
Thanks for having me!
Pleasuroto to meet you!
I am terribly sorry,
but can you have your Pokémon, Pikachu,
wait in the courtyard?
It’s quite all right, James.
They’re here to help me.
Is that so?
Then come this way.
Whoa, this place is huge!
Pardon my rudeness earlier.
We do not normally
allow Pokémon inside.
Because they tend to frighten me...
Oh, I see.
Because of that, I had them make a Pokémon playground
in the courtyard, so I can watch them from afar.
I believe you will see wild Pokémon
come out to play here shortly.
For real?!
I really wanna see that!
If so, I shall show you in a bit.
All right!
This is my room.
Whoa, awesome!
Satoshi, put the egg here.
Perhaps someplace softer
would be better...
If I recall, the book
said eggs should be...
Um...
How about this?
Well? How’s it feel?
It says it likes it.
I-I see... That’s good.
I didn’t expect to be entrusted
with an egg...
I’ll need to read more...
So that this one may hatch safely.
You really do love Pokémon, huh?
Is something the matter?
This girl holding the Pokémon...
Isn’t that you?
Indeed.
So you used to be able to...
Yes.
Young Miss Lilie has loved Pokémon since she was small,
and she would often play with them.
Did something happen?
Well...
I don’t know.
Don’t know?
How to explain this...
She moved to a different mansion
with the madame,
and when she came back,
she was no longer able
to touch Pokémon.
So these other people are...
The madame and
the young master.
The madame is still working
in that other mansion.
My brother left on his own to...
Pardon me.
I have brought Roserade Tea
and some snacks.
A whole mountain of sweets!
Eat as much as you like.
Time for a snack!
They do have hearty appetites...
Y-Yes, I suppose...
Say, Lilie...
Wanna practice for a bit?
Practice?
Yeah. Practice touching Pokémon.
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Yatoumori
Type:   Poison/Fire
It’s fine! Pikachu’ll stay
completely still!
Now, Lilie... Trust Pikachu,
and touch him!
V-Very well...
Young Miss Lilie!
Pikachu! I told you not to move!
Right, now... Try this!
He’s asleep! Fast asleep, Lilie!
He’s asleep... Fast asleep!
Was that Sleep Talk?!
All right, then it’s time for
my ace in the hole!
Rotom!
Leave it to me-roto!
Now, listen up, Lilie!
That isn’t a Rotom!
It’s just a Pokémon Index!
Roto?
Yes!
T-This is a Pokémon Index...
Nothing more—
Wrong-roto!
I am the Index Rotom-roto!
Even Rotom’s a no-go, huh?
Well, don’t give up!
All right...
Whoa, it’s a Butterfree!
Wild Pokémon sometimes come
all the way up to the balcony.
Let’s see...
There it is!
Wait, you mean you have different foods
for different Pokémon?
Indeed.
Pokémon have their preferences as well.
I try to give them whatever food is best for them.
It’s eating it!
That particular food
is Butterfree’s favorite.
It really seems to be
enjoying it!
That’s awesome, Lilie!
I believe there will be Pokémon
in the garden, as well.
For real?!
Look at them!
Oh, Mao.
May I come in?
Certainly.
Awesome!
It’s a battlefield!
I take regular care of it,
so it is ready to use at any time.
For real?!
Satoshi loves Pokémon battling.
Feel free to use it if you like.
All right!
Pokémon battle!
Who will you be fighting-roto?
Oh, right...
I have no opponent...
You needn’t worry about that.
Mr. James?
He is among
the best battlers on staff.
Really?!
Please battle me!
Understood!
I, James, shall be
your opponent, if I may.
All right! Let’s do this!
Don’t hold back against me,
Mr. James!
Very well! But I ask that you
be gentle with me, Master Satoshi!
Sorry, Pikachu.
I’d like to have Mokuroh
battle this time.
You can go some other time.
Counting on you, Mokuroh.
So you will use Mokuroh...
In which case,
I shall be using this Pokémon!
I’ve never seen that Pokémon before!
Leave it to me-roto!
Odoridori, Clap-Clap Style.
Dancing Pokémon. Electric/Flying type.
It creates an electric charge
by rubbing its feathers together.
It dances over to its enemies
and delivers attacks.
Its typing changes by sipping the nectar of flowers
unique to each of Alola’s islands.
Typing?
Indeed.
This Odoridori has sipped the Yellow Nectar
that is only found on Melemele Island,
which turned it into
an Electric/Flying type.
I didn’t know there were
Pokémon like that!
Alola really is interesting!
Mokuroh! Let’s give it our all in
our first Pokémon battle together!
All right, here we go!
Use Leafage!
Revelation Dance!
Mokuroh!
Clap-Clap Style Odoridori’s
Revelation Dance...
...is an attack that uses the electricity it generates
by rubbing its feathers together-roto!
Mokuroh, can you keep going?!
Right! Use Tackle!
Parrot Mimicry!
It blocked it?!
Parrot Mimicry strikes back at the opponent
with the same move they used-roto!
What will you do next?
One more Tackle!
Parrot Mimicry!
I was waiting for this!
Mokuroh! Mirror Parrot Mimicry!
What?!
I cannot believe you would
mimic the Parrot Mimicry!
Mokuroh’s legs are real strong!
Quite remarkable...
Then, we will answer in turn!
Revelation Dance!
Don’t let it store up electricity!
Peck!
Move right!
Behind you!
All right!
Well done, Mokuroh!
It dodged it!
Truly, it has been a long time
since I had such a fun battle!
Thank you!
I have to watch the egg!
In that case,
how will you deal with this?
Teeter Dance!
Huh... I’m kinda... teetering...
Teeter Dance is... a move that uses wobbly movements...
to confuse the opponent-roto...
W-What?
Don’t, Mokuroh...
Don’t look at it...
You are much too late!
Round-Trip Slap!
Mokuroh!
Owww...
Mao?!
Ms. Mao?!
You found me...
What about the cafeteria?
Well, I was worried about Lilie,
so I finished my tasks as fast as I could.
Then I heard the sounds of battling...
You would go that far
for the young miss?
Y-You’re exaggerating...
N-No!
Stay away!
I will not let you have it!
No!
Young Miss!
Lilie!
James! Satoshi!
What’s that?!
Yatoumori. Toxic Lizard Pokémon.
Poison/Fire type.
Volcanoes or dry,
craggy places are its home.
This Pokémon emanates a sweet-smelling poisonous gas
that attracts its foes, then attacks them.
Oh, no!
Lilie!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Odoridori! Teeter Dance!
Mokuroh, use Tackle!
Lilie, are you all right?
Satoshi!
Mao?
I came by because I was worried.
But never mind that...
I-I was desperate to protect...
It’s so warm...
You did it, Lilie!
This is absolutely wonderful,
Young Miss Lilie!
I’m so happy for you!
Thank you!
Seems she isn’t
entirely over it yet. Sorry.
But you can touch the egg now.
That’s great, Lilie!
Yes, I am very happy!
Keep it up!
All right, I’ll leave the egg
in your capable hands!
Yes!
An unexpected disturbance allowed Lilie to
take a big step towards conquering her fear of Pokémon.
Now, what Pokémon will hatch
from this egg?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you very much for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was Butterfree!
Did you all get it correct?
I was most nervous about having to
look after a valuable Pokémon egg,
but I’m a bit more at ease
now that I can touch it.
I can’t wait to see what Pokémon
will hatch from it!
Young Miss.
If you can touch the egg,
then maybe you can also handle this?
Oh, my! There are so many!
I am so sorry!
I see Tamatama was too much for you...
Next episode
We, the Satoshi crew, are currently in the middle of
our expedition to find the Totem Pokémon-roto!
Totem Pokémon are exceedingly powerful Pokémon shrouded in a mysterious aura-roto.
Will we be able to
successfully find the Totem Pokémon...
...and clear this
Island Pilgrimage Trial?!
It’s that strong?
You didn’t know-roto, Satoshi?
I mean, I’ve never met
a Totem Pokémon before...
A-And there it is!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
The Totem Pokémon is Dekagoose!