Alola!
Here’s the PokéProblem, meow!
Alolan
Persian
Ratta
Alolan
Kyukon
Nyarth
My rival appears in today’s episode, meow.
Who is this rival, meow?
Get the answer at the
end of the episode, meow!
Thanks for waiting, guys!
I’ve got some great snacks
for you today!
Satoshi...
You’re giving them all of that?
Wait, wait! There’s plenty for everyone,
so no need to rush!
I bought all that stuff together
because it was on sale...
Attempt at saving money:
Failed-roto.
Snack time!
Food tastes better
when shared with others, doesn’t it?
On the other hand, they say that
grudges over food are a terrifying thing...
It’s gone! Gone! Gone, meow!
Where’d it go, meow?
What’s wrong, Nyarth?
The limited edition Rainbow Triple Berry
Rare Cheese Ice Cream I’d been saving...
I can’t find it anywhere, meow!
Sure you didn’t eat it yourself?
There’s no way, meow!
I was looking forward to having it today, meow!
What?
T-That’s... my limited edition
Rainbow Triple Berry Rare Cheese Ice Cream!
Thanks! It was delicious!
How could you, meow?!
Give it back, meow!
It’s already gone.
That was a super premium ice cream!
Only one per customer, and I was first in line, meow!
And yet you... You...
Musashi, I hate you, meow!
What’s going on?
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
The Dark Nyarth is
an Alolan Nyarth?!
Musashi is awful, meow!
My ice cream!
My limited edition
Rainbow Triple Berry Rare Cheese Ice Cream!
Nyarth!
When it rains, it pours, meow...
Who are you?
You’ll help me up, meow?
Thank you, meow!
Nyarth!
Oh, there he is!
Nyarth, cheer up already.
Musashi is sorry for what she did.
I didn’t know it was that rare.
My bad. Kojiro will buy you
another one just like it.
Me?!
Now, let’s go home.
Get that mud cleaned off.
Cheer up. You can have
the pudding I’d been saving.
What’s going on, meow?
I’m kinda thirsty.
Oh! How considerate of you!
Amazing!
You polished them
for me, Nyarth?
And you put them on
such a stylish display!
It feels like my Monster Ball
collection has been upgraded!
Thanks, Nyarth!
Don’t be fooled, meow!
Nyarth?!
Huh? Then who’s this?
That’s an impostor, meow!
Oh! This Nyarth seems
a lot more elegant! I like it!
As if, meow!
I’m a truly sophisticated
gentleman, meow!
Oh, right!
This is Nyarth’s Alolan form.
I see.
C’mon, translate.
Why should I?
“Indeed.
I am an Alolan Nyarth, meow.”
I thought it seemed
unusually calm for Nyarth.
And it was strangely considerate, too.
“Naturally! I can help you out in any
number of ways, meow!” it says, meow.
Does that mean you’ll join us?
“I have been in the care of many
different people across Alola,
“but I set off on a journey
to find a greater master to serve, meow.”
“You people appear to be
absolutely magnificent trainers, meow.”
“If you please, may I join you, meow?”
it’s saying, meow.
You’re so impudent, meow!
Team Rocket has me!
It doesn’t need any other Nyarth, meow!
Looks like Nyarth’s Alolan form
is a Dark type!
Doesn’t that mean it could use
that Dark Z-Crystal we picked up and thought was useless?!
Yeah!
Oh! The Dark-type
full power pose!
You can use the Z-Move, huh?
Let’s try it out right now!
It’s asking:
“Where’s your Z-Ring?”, meow.
Z-Ring?
What was that again?
It looks like we can’t use Z-Moves
without attaching the Z-Crystal to a Z-Ring, meow.
No way!
That’s right...
The hand-made Ring I put together
didn’t work, did it?
Well, whatever.
We can get the Ring later...
For now, we should just get you, right?
Wait, meow! You’re actually gonna
add that thing to our team, meow?!
I mean...
You can’t use the Dark Z-Move.
I could do it too if we had a Z-Ring, meow!
I know I could, meow!
This one’s got a nasty personality...
What are you doing, Nyarth?
It... It...
Now, let’s get it!
Huh? Nyarth, what’s it saying?
“I would like to join you right now,
“but I want to consider
my choice of masters carefully,
“so please, may I have some time?”,
it’s saying, meow.
Well, as long as you
join us later.
I just can’t trust this...
What are you doing, Nyarth?!
Sakaki, Sir?!
Surely you didn’t forget that
it was time for your regularly scheduled report?
We remembered!
We were just about to contact you!
That’s a strange Nyarth
you’ve got there.
Yes, Sir!
This is Nyarth’s Alolan form.
I see... So in Alola, it looks like that.
Yes! We are currently checking
what sort of power it has!
Don’t forget to report to us
once you have the necessary data.
We know!
Roger that!
I don’t like this one...
but I hate that one even more, meow!
I expect great results from you.
Yes, Sir!
Sakaki’s expecting something from us!
All right! It seems he likes you, too!
We’ll have you work hard
from now on.
And then we’ll have great results
to report to Sakaki!
All right! Let’s do this!
It’s gotta be
planning something, meow.
Limited edition Rainbow Triple Berry
Rare Cheese Ice Cream, meow...
It’s so delicious, meow!
This is heaven, meow!
I have no regrets, meow!
This is bliss, meow!
Where is that thing?!
That’s right!
Whenever we try to catch Pikachu,
that brat boy
always gets in the way!
We want that Pikachu, desperately!
I knew I could count on you!
What is it doing, meow?!
Oh... You be quiet.
It looks like we can
hatch an awesome plan!
What’s their deal, meow?!
Master, another Pile Juice, meow!
I’ve had too much to drink, is it?
How could I not be drinking right now, meow?!
We’ve been through so much together,
but now they’re ignoring me in favor of that thing!
Master...
I can’t believe them, meow!
They’re awful, meow!
All because I can’t use
the Dark Z-Move, meow!
I know, meow. I just have to make them understand
that the Alolan Nyarth is useless, meow!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon, meow...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nyarth (Alolan Form)
Type:   Dark
Hey! We need to talk, meow.
I’ll be waiting in front of the Pokémon School gates
in one hour, meow.
Be there, meow!
No matter what, meow!
Lugarugan, use Bite!
Bakugames, Flamethrower!
Now, Garagara! Iron Head!
Nyabby, use Fire Fang!
Good going, Nyabby!
A friendship combo-roto!
Great job backing it up, Nyabby!
Their teamwork is wonderful.
But what about
Bakugames and Garagara?
Only the best friends
fight like that.
All right, we can keep going!
Lugarugan, Nyabby!
Hey, hey! Cut it out already!
Pikachu, is something the matter?
I got Mokuroh, meow!
It’s you!
They found me, meow!
This is bad-roto!
Give Mokuroh back!
Let’s go, too!
Wait!
Thanks for waiting, meow.
Here you go, meow!
Wait!
Nyarth, give Mokuroh back!
Huh? Nyarth?
Satoshi, this is not the same
Nyarth from before.
It’s an Alolan Nyarth!
Nyarth, Alolan form.
Scratch Cat Pokémon. Dark type.
This Pokémon was
not originally found in Alola.
It was brought here by humans,
and eventually changed into this form.
They’re prideful and crafty.
Are you with Team Rocket, too?
You deserve to be beaten senseless
by the brats, meow!
What?
Hey, wait!
Is it telling us to
win him back through battle?
Don’t blame me if you get hurt!
Pikachu, use Lightning Speed!
Pikachu!
A Feint-roto!
It’s using 100,000 Volts?!
Incoming!
Look out!
Run!
If that hits us,
we’ll be paralyzed!
Togedemaru, please!
You did it, Togedemaru!
Are you all right?
Yeah, we’re fine.
Oww... What’s this?
Pikachu!
It’s fine, we’ll be right there.
The plan was a complete success.
We got Pikachu!
I knew it was you, Team Rocket!
We’re not the same old us today!
What is this, meow?
It was the Alolan Nyarth’s plan.
We made a trap here.
You were acting as bait, right?
Does this mean I was
the one being used, meow?!
All right, we’re going home!
Wait!
We have to get out of here!
I have an idea.
Come out, Bakugames!
Hey, what are you doing?!
T-There’s no space!
I’m getting crushed!
Tough it out!
Now climb on Bakugames’s shell,
but be careful not to touch his spikes.
I get it. Great idea, Kaki!
All right!
Satoshi, be careful.
I know!
Who else saw that coming?
What happened-roto?
Oh, Satoshi!
But at least we’re all out now.
Anyway, we have to chase
down Team Rocket!
Odds that they went East: 25%.
Where did they go?
I don’t know.
Odds that they went West: 25%.
What do we do?
Let’s split up and search!
Mokuroh?
They went that way?
Let’s go after them!
Yeah!
That went so much
better than expected.
You’re pretty good.
Let’s keep it up and get loads of Pokémon,
then report it to Sakaki!
I can’t believe you’d exploit my plan...
You’re unbelievably crafty, meow!
“I expected more of you”?!
We found you, Team Rocket!
What?! They’re here already?!
Give Pikachu back!
Man, you’re persistent...
Mimikkyu!
Hidoide!
Really, this again? Sheesh!
Mimikkyu, get them!
Huh? No, wrong target!
Pikachu!
Escape: Successful-roto!
Oh, come on!
What are you doing?!
Hidoide, use Sludge Bomb!
Lugarugan! Rock Throw!
Come on, you two fight, too!
In that case, I will win...
and prove that I’m the one
Team Rocket truly needs, meow!
Pikachu, let’s go for a Z-Move!
All right!
H-Hey... Wait, do something,
Alolan Nyarth!
Wait, what? It’s gone!
What?!
I told you we
couldn’t trust it, meow.
Go, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
What?!
Of course, it’s this feeling!
You did it, Pikachu!
I’m glad you’re all right.
It’s been several days,
but the Alolan Nyarth hasn’t come back.
What’s this mean?
How do we report this to Sakaki?
Forget that thing, meow.
All you need is me, meow.
Sakaki, Sir!
You did well.
I’ve made this Alolan Nyarth
my assistant.
It’s quite helpful, being so crafty.
W-Why?
Please keep on catching good Pokémon
and sending them to HQ.
I expect great things from you.
What was that? What’s going on?!
Hey, what are you doing?!
“I’m grateful to you, meow.”
“I was able to reach
a place befitting of me”?
What?!
“One day, I will sit on
Sakaki’s lap, meow”?
What are you saying, meow?!
I will be the one on Sakaki’s lap, meow!
We were used as a stepping stone
for that thing’s promotion?!
Argh! You mean you’d rather be
with that bowl-headed four-eyes than with me?!
I don’t believe this!
I told you, meow.
That thing is pure evil, meow.
I thought it was suspicious all along!
I’m so frustrated!
It seems the Alolan Nyarth was more cunning
than Team Rocket, and managed to one-up them.
But Nyarth might just be
relieved at this.
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting, meow!
My detestable rival was
an Alolan Nyarth, meow!
Alolan Nyarth is a Dark type, meow.
It seems it became a Dark type after
being brought in from another region, but...
how did it become so deceitful
here in the peaceful Alola region?
I don’t get it, meow.
Come to think of it,
how did that Nyarth get to HQ?
Kanto’s too far away
for a Ride Pokémon to reach...
My savings!
Next episode
To all the trainers in front of the TV!
We, the ten-time winners of the
Battle Royal, Royal Mask and...
...Gaogaen, possess the
hottest flame in all of Alola!
Can you defeat us?!
We’ll offer up a burning
DD Lariat to you!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Burn with Passion, Nyabby!
Down with Gaogaen!!
Enjoy a burning battle with us!
Next time
Burn with Passion, Nyabby! Down with Gaogaen!!