Are you watching?
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Makenkani
Bloster
Kingler
Scizarigar
Which Pokémon attacks us
in today’s episode?
Blue: Makenkani?
Red: Bloster?
Green: Kingler?
Or Yellow: Scizarigar?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Pokémon School
is as lively as ever.
Oh? What’s this?
Embraced by our mother,
the sea...
Echo...
...beyond the horizon!
Sea God’s Symphonia!
We did it!
Congratulations!
You’ve perfected another Z-Move!
Remarkable!
I’ve fulfilled my
promise with Master!
Z-Moves are so cool!
I want to learn how to do one, too.
You can!
Practice makes perfect!
We’ll need to keep working at ours,
as well, Snowball!
All right!
Let’s follow Suiren’s lead!
Hard at work, I see!
Professor Kukui!
We’re training for
the Pokémon League!
So you’ve decided
to participate, Suiren?
How about you, Mao, Lilie?
C’mon, join!
Very well.
I’ll do my best, too!
All right! That’s it!
Oh? Sounds like they’re
fired up over there, too.
Go, you two!
Kuwagannon! Signal Beam!
Now...
Let’s go, Kuwagannon!
Time for our Z-Move!
Um...
First I move my right arm like this...
My left leg like this...
What? Why?
You guys weren’t in sync at all.
What?!
But we should have been...
I gathered up data on the Z-Move...
...and ran a flawless simulation.
Data?
You can figure it out that way?
Data is important-roto!
He’s learned Signal Beam.
The Z-Move should come easily now!
So why? Was my right hand
at the wrong angle?
No, it seems right...
Wouldn’t it be better to practice and learn the moves,
instead of just analyzing them?
But...
You need some
real battle experience!
Come to my place tomorrow!
We’ll hold a Z-Move boot camp!
Boot camp? Sounds fun!
I’m totally in!
I’ll record the boot camp
for you-roto!
If we’re going to your place,
there’s gonna be ice cream, too, right? I’m in!
It’s settled, then!
Then we should meet up
at my home tomorrow, as well.
Great idea!
Let’s do it!
Give it your all,
everybody!
Yes!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Master Your Z-Move!
Kaki's Fiery Boot Camp!!
We’re not staying at your house?!
It’s better to stay out here
where no one can bother us.
Then we can train
to our hearts’ content!
Where are we going?
There’s an ancient altar up that path.
We’ll set up a tent there!
I’m coming with you!
Hoshi!
No, Hoshi.
They’re not going for fun.
Darn...
Now, come with me.
Hang in there, big bro!
Go nuts!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
Can’t we at least have
some ice cream first?!
What was this place built for-roto?
It’s a place where
people pray to Wela Volcano.
Grandfather and I came here often.
Now, let’s set up the tent
and then get right to training!
Yeah!
That’ll do it!
Now, come out, everyone!
Mokuroh! Meltan!
You guys, too!
I got it...
Let’s do our best,
Kuwagannon...
I’m starving...
Think Satoshi and the others
are doing all right?
They’re training like mad.
I know they are!
We mustn’t let them beat us.
Shall we get back to practicing?
Yeah!
Hey! Is this really Z-Move training?!
Of course! Feel the power
of nature with all your being!
I can’t...
Become one with nature!
I-Impossible!
Good, Satoshi!
Hey, is this really necessary?
Of course it is!
You gotta build stamina first!
I guess, but...
Aren’t there any more direct ways
of launching Z-Moves?
Absolutely not!
Feel the breath of Alola,
and offer up your gratitude to Mother Nature.
It’s only then that nature’s power
can well up inside of you!
Yeah! Yeah!
Satoshi?
Do you have any tips?
I go all fwoosh,
then get fired up, like wham,
and fire it, like bam!
I have no idea
what you’re saying...
This’ll never work...
That’s not true!
This place is under Wela’s divine protection!
You can surely learn something
by training here!
I just can’t be so unscientific
about this!
But that was how Kaki learned it...
Don’t think your method
works for everyone!
It’s hopeless for me!
I’m leaving!
Come on, Togedemaru,
Kuwagannon.
H-Huh?
Kuwagannon...
Kuwagannon still seems
pretty determined.
Māmane?
Sorry, Kaki, Satoshi.
I can’t give up, can I?
I’ll try for a bit longer!
So, what should I do?
All right! We got this!
We’re gonna help you
come out on top!
I told you, this won’t work!
Huh?
I’m sorry...
I wonder why it’s not working.
I don’t know.
This is something you have to
figure out on your own.
I’m starving...
Me, too...
Don’t tell me we’re gonna have to
make food ourselves, too?!
Someone’s coming-roto!
Hope we’re not late!
Food’s here, everyone!
I asked them to bring us food.
Th-Thank goodness...
So, is the training going well?
Well...
Um...
I’ve still got a long way to go...
Eat plenty and do your best!
Here, big bro!
Thank you, Hoshi!
Now, let’s go back
before it gets too dark.
Yeah!
See you later, big bro!
We’ll be back
tomorrow morning.
Bye bye!
Ah... Hoshi! Watch your step!
There’s rocks there!
Want me to give you
a piggyback ride?
I’m fine!
Come on, let’s have dinner.
Delicious!
I’m alive again!
Sheesh... What is it now?
But Bakugames really is kind,
isn’t he?
He’s like a big brother.
He’s always been compassionate.
I was on my way home
from a delivery...
...when I first met him.
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Scizarigar
Type:   Water/Evil
I was on my way home
from a delivery...
Is that a Bakugames?
How rare!
Are you all right?
Hey, you’re wobbling...
I’ll give you a berry...
I found out that Bakugames...
...wanted to stop Scizarigar from
hogging the pond to himself.
For the other Pokémon?
Yeah.
Bakugames really is kind.
So, what happened then?
Bakugames refused to give up.
He challenged Scizarigar
again and again.
Drink this.
You’re really passionate!
I like you!
I’m sure Wela Volcano is
watching over your burning heart!
You can win!
Here.
This’ll make you feel better.
All right! Let me help you,
so you can win!
Just charging in won’t work.
Watch your opponent closely,
and strike when the time is right!
This is...
A new move! So...
Did he win?
Of course!
You did it, Bakugames!
Your Trap Shell worked!
Congratulations!
Well, take care of yourself!
Let’s go home, Lizardon.
What?
You mean you want to
come with me?
And that’s how
we became partners.
Both of you are
really compassionate.
I couldn’t leave him alone,
you know?
The bond between you must be so strong
because you’re so alike!
I wonder,
is that what we're lacking?
It’s nothing.
I don’t think you guys
have a problem there, either.
Togedemaru and Kuwagannon
both love you.
R-Really?
Do you, Togedemaru?
Ouch!
But why can’t he pull off
the Z-Move-roto?
Yeah, that’s the question...
Rotom, you got a minute?
What-roto?
I want your help with something.
You, too, Bakugames.
What’s wrong, Rotom?
N-Nothing-roto!
Okay, then...
Are we training here today?
Yeah! But I have to prepare some stuff.
Can you help me out?
Sure!
What should I do?
Satoshi, you come with me.
Māmane, could you pick up
some sticks around here?
Sticks? What for?
I’ll explain later.
Come on, Satoshi.
Sure! Let’s go, everyone!
Māmane! Māmane,
hang in there-roto!
Um... Sure...
You can do it-roto!
It’s just picking up sticks...
Rotom is so weird.
Thank you,
Kuwagannon, Togedemaru.
Kaki... Why are we hiding?
Shh! Just watch.
What?!
Are you the Scizarigar
Kaki mentioned?!
This is bad!
We gotta help him!
No, wait!
This is their chance!
Their chance to have
a serious battle!
What do I do...
Kaki?! Satoshi?!
Kuwagannon!
You’re ready to fight?
Okay!
Let’s do this, Kuwagannon!
Dodge!
Are you all right?
D-Discharge!
We have to stop it from moving!
String Shot!
No!
This is their battle.
There’s just
no way I can do it!
Kuwagannon,
get out of—
Kuwagannon won’t give up.
That’s right... If we give up...
Then that’s the end.
We’re fighting together!
Kuwagannon!
Run!
What do we do...
What do we do?!
Kuwagannon!
Use Signal Beam on the ground!
All right!
It’s a new way
to use Signal Beam-roto!
Now use Discharge!
All right!
Kuwagannon... We might still
have a long way to go...
But I still want to fight
alongside you!
Here we go!
All of our systems
are in perfect sync!
Full Power Program... Run!
Absolute Predatory Spin-Out!
Finish it!
Awesome!
You did it, Māmane!
We... We did it...
We did it, everyone!
That hurts, Togedemaru...
That really hurts!
You’ve mastered your Z-Move!
Kaki! Satoshi!
You were watching?
It went wham and bam
just like I said, right?
You felt the breath of Alola,
didn’t you?!
No, I’m still totally lost...
Kaki, behind you!
Great job, Scizarigar!
Wh-What’s going on?
He had a change of heart
after losing to us.
...Though he’s still quick to fight.
Last night, Rotom and I
asked him to battle you guys.
Really, Rotom?
It was tough
keeping it a secret-roto!
Thank you, Scizarigar.
You were right!
They’re friends now!
He’s like a kind
big brother to them!
Couldn’t you have
told me that earlier?
If I had, you wouldn’t have
been able to battle at full power, right?
True, but...
Anyway, you’ve perfected
your Z-Move!
Yeah!
All right! Let’s keep training all day,
to prepare for the Alola League!
Yeah!
What? We’re still doing more?
Congratulations on
mastering your Z-Move, Māmane.
Now, the Alola League is
right around the corner!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
It was Scizarigar who
attacked us out of the blue!
The Rogue Pokémon Scizarigar
is a Water/Evil type.
It’s an incredibly territorial,
aggressive Pokémon.
But it helped us master our Z-Move.
Thank you, Kuwagannon!
Next episode
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
All right, let’s go!
Um...
I’ve been thinking this
for a while, but...
He says something else,
doesn’t he?
Huh? Who does?
Kaki.
He says “Ultra Jar!”
An amazing container...?
You’re late, everyone!
Hurry!
Oh, sorry!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Perfect Cutting Edge! Kamitsurugi Arrives!!
Next time
A Perfect Cutting Edge!
Kamitsurugi Arrives!!
Ultra Jar!