Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Tyltalis
Gaburias
Hakuryu
Metang
Which one of these Pokémon
develops a rivalry with my Flygon today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is the ferry port on Melemele Island.
Where are Satoshi and his friends headed?
Hey, look!
That’s the nonstop ferry to
the Pokémon Paradise Resort.
I’m so excited!
Aren’t you, Hakuryu?
Yeah! I’m excited, too!
It’s pretty hard
to get a reservation there.
Is it really that popular?
That Pokémon whatchamacallit?
Oh, so you don’t know?
The Pokémon Paradise Resort is
a spa for Pokémon on Akala Island.
They’ve got hot springs, a pool, a restaurant,
and plenty of other facilities.
It’s a super popular spot!
Customers come in from all around the world!
They guarantee absolute
satisfaction for any Pokémon.
Really?
They’ve been getting sent out on missions a lot lately,
so the Ride Pokémon must be exhausted as well.
Mother said that they, and we,
should get plenty of rest.
Ms. Lusamine was nice enough
to get us a reservation.
We’ll gladly take her up on that.
Right, Flygon?
Me, too!
Let’s have some fun,
Gaburias!
Y-Yareyutan?!
Oh, he’s a regular customer.
I see... I had no idea.
Big shot detected.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
I Choose This Place!
The Pokémon Steam Paradise!!
Alola!
Welcome to the Pokémon Paradise Resort!
He really is a regular...
You’re the Ultra Guardians, correct?
Which area would you like to visit?
Area?
This facility is split up into areas
with different purposes.
There’s the Care Area,
which focuses on Pokémon treatment,
and the Play Area,
where they can have fun playing.
Then I’m going to the Play Area!
Wrong!
We’re here to give our Ride Pokémon
some quality care!
Right, so the Care Area.
You guys wanna go over there,
huh, Pikachu?
All right! Come out, everyone!
You go have fun, too!
Off you go, Denjimushi!
I’ll lead the way.
Right over here.
I’ll stay with you-roto.
This Pokémon care fascinates me-roto!
Well, in that case,
please proceed to the counseling room.
First we’ll counsel them here,
and then we’ll select a care course
that fits each Pokémon’s condition.
It seems Lizardon
does a lot of heavy lifting.
Oh, yes.
It helps deliver Moomoo Milk.
Its muscles are quite tense,
so I recommend the Fatigue Recovery Course.
Its movements are a bit stiff...
I recommend the Joint Care Course.
I see this one has quite dry skin.
Let’s give it the Moisturising Course.
This one seems to have a lot of stress...
Let’s have it let it out on the Active Course.
This is awesome!
Well then, everyone,
please go change.
Let’s go, guys!
You’re rushing too much.
There they are.
Secretly spying on the brats paid off.
Chances like these
don’t come often, meow.
It’s Operation “Get Pikachu and
All the Ride Pokémon In One Fell Swoop”, meow!
H-Hello there...
Well then, start preparing!
Roger!
It’s huge!
This abundance of hot spring water...
Truly, this place is blessed by Wela Volcano!
This area is very effective against
stiffness, bruises, sprains, poor circulation...
I’m going in!
Diving in is dangerous!
Feels great!
Hurry in, you guys!
Sure, sure...
Hey, Satoshi!
Don’t make Flygon imitate you!
Sorry!
You’re both incredible!
Let us enter slowly.
Children, don’t try this at home!
Lizardon seems to be enjoying itself.
It loves hot springs.
Lizardon loves hot springs!
Data updated-roto!
But I must say, there really are
lots of Pokémon here.
I hope Pikachu and the others
are having fun, too.
Don’t force them to play along.
Some Pokémon don’t want to get wet.
But we have good news for
all those Pokémon!
Prepare to be amazed! On this boat, you, too,
can enjoy the wave pool without getting wet!
Come on board!
We’ll carry you to the pool!
There, there. Come on board.
Well... That was a load of bull.
It went well, meow!
It’s so easy to fool someone
who’s got their guard completely down!
Yeah! Pikachu and his merry friends
have been successfully caught!
That really warmed me up.
Hot springs are the best!
Is this Tyltalis?
I thought it was
a different Pokémon for a second...
Now we’ll all split up and go to
our own recommended courses.
Hey!
Go on ahead!
Lizardon likes long baths!
Okay! See you later!
These guys all seem
nice and careless, too.
We’ll attack when they’re
relaxing here at this popular resort!
There’s no way this plan could fail!
Let them keep getting all wrinkly and lax,
and powerless to fight back, meow!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gaburias
Type:   Dragon/Ground
This is our mud-based
beauty treatment.
It supplies plenty of minerals to the skin and plumage,
and enhances the Pokémon’s metabolism.
Sounds good!
Well then...
Let us do this, Tyltalis.
Tyltalis...
We aren’t playing in the mud.
Perfect!
The mud here is super effective
on trainers, too!
By all means, enjoy it
together with your Pokémon!
In that case...
Let’s get all muddy together!
There!
Now you, too.
Let’s go, Hakuryu!
Are you scared?
Now listen up, you’re supposed to go all out
and do this quickly!
Are you all right?
Really? I’ll help apply it to you!
We’ve got loads more,
so keep going!
It looks great on you, Metang!
You’re free to use as much of
this aroma oil as you want.
Oil massages are
perfect for Steel types!
I’ll focus on your joints,
since this is Joint Care.
Hmm? I can’t reach...
Oh, that’s exactly what I needed!
Well, Metang?
Feels great, doesn’t it?
I’ll make you sparkle all over,
even your spikes!
This is an awesome pool-roto!
Now, swim as fast as you want,
and blow your stress away!
Oh yeah, Flygon, can you swim?
Flygon’s doing the butterfly stroke!
Swimming Flygon...
Data updated-roto!
You’re so quick, Gaburias!
Swimming Gaburias has
been added, too-roto!
Hey... You’re going too fast!
Perhaps Gaburias doesn’t
want to lose to Flygon?
I mean, it looked like they
were competing earlier, too!
Now that you mention it...
They must be rivals!
I see! Then hang in there, Gaburias!
You, too, Flygon!
Please use these, meow.
What are these?
Cheering items?
Serious cheers from their trainers
will make the Pokémon even more fired up!
All together now...
Yeah! Go, go, both of you!
Go, go, both of you!
Yeah! Don’t lose, don’t lose,
both of you!
Don’t lose, don’t lose,
Yeah! Go, go...
Lizardon, I’ll devote my full power to
getting rid of your weariness!
That’s weird...
Is it here, then?
It’s working! Incredible!
Well, that’s because it’s me,
the man who has massaged ten thousand Pokémon!
Who are you...?
The tension’s built up here,
ya see.
Whoa, this is a big one...
Ya gotta push it.
Ready, and...
It’s hard!
Soften up them tense muscles!
I worked up a nice sweat.
How’d it go?
Perfectly, of course!
I put my all into
massaging it, after all!
We’ve got them
as soft as a noodle!
They’re completely beat after
all that cheering, meow!
In that case, it’s about time...
Now’s our chance!
The Pokémon Paradise Resort
really is great!
How’d it go for you?
Perfect! The mud treatment
made Hakuryu’s skin silky smooth!
Tyltalis is all fluffy!
Gaburias and Flygon are
completely refreshed, too!
The oil massage also
worked like a charm!
I polished Metang
until it was shining!
Amazing!
It’s like a Mirror Coat-roto!
Everyone seems satisfied.
Hey, where should we go next?
I want to try the flower bath!
Sounds lovely.
Then let’s go there!
Agreed!
What’s that?
Hello! Nice little kids over there!
We are holding a demonstration of
Pokémon health appliances right now!
Would you like to
give them a try?
Pokémon health appliances?
It’s an exclusive event,
just for today!
You are incredibly lucky,
dear customers!
Now, go right ahead!
Wanna try it, Gaburias?
Well then, dear Pokémon,
please come this way.
Partners, you wait over there.
Yes, right there. Don’t move...
Okay?
Uwah! What are you doing?!
When asked
“Uwah! What are you doing?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
So re-energizing, you’ll never grow old!
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
So empowering, you’ll never get sick!
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
Hot spring buns, coffee and milk!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
You guys were Team Rocket?!
What are you playing at?!
Isn’t it obvious?
We’re gonna get every last one
of your Ride Pokémon!
With this super powerful electromagnetic net,
we’ll take your completely limp Ride Pokémon-
So fast, meow!
Good going, Gaburias!
Huh? They’re completely re-energized?
They’re completely empowered?
They’re hot spring buns, meow?
Hey! This isn’t what we signed up for!
They’re not “powerless” in the slightest!
They’re brimming with energy!
The effectiveness of the Pokémon Paradise Resort
is frightening indeed...
We have no choice.
We’ll come back for
the Ride Pokémon later, meow!
We’re leaving!
Pikachu!
Oh, no!
We’re not leaving
empty-handed, meow!
We’ve got both that purple pointy-head and Pikachu!
What a great feeling!
Everybody, please!
Rescue Pikachu and the others!
Hey, they’re coming!
I won’t let them catch up!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
What’s that?!
Its skin is so smooth,
the poison’s just sliding off, meow!
W-W-Wha... This is bad!
Full retreat, meow!
As if!
Everyone!
Yeah!
Great Blaze!
Flamethrower!
Ice Beam!
Luster Cannon!
What an awful feel-
What even is this feeling?
Everybody, are you okay?
Thank you! You really saved us!
I’m sorry. This was supposed
to be your day off.
Metang, I’m so glad I polished you!
Now, time for the flower bath!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
So pretty...
It smells lovely.
This is paradise...
Yeah...
The flower bath’s great...
Over the course of their day at
the Pokémon Paradise Resort,
Satoshi’s group and the Ride Pokémon
have strengthened their bonds.
Seems they all got
a nice recharge.
As for Team Rocket...
How long are we
gonna do this?
I can’t take any more...
I’m getting out.
What?!
It’s saying you gotta
count to 100, meow.
What’s that supposed to mean?!
I’m not a kid!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The one that developed
a rivalry with Flygon...
...was Gaburias!
The Mach Pokémon Gaburias
is a Dragon/Ground type.
Apparently the protuberances
on its head serve as sensors!
But I must say, Satoshi’s Gaburias
really hates to lose!
Ninety-nine...
One hundred!
I’m done for...
I’m boiling, meow...
I... I never would have guessed that
Kiteruguma loved hot springs this much...
Next episode
Bebenom, what’s wrong?
Some sort of emergency-roto?
What’s it saying?
I got it-roto! It’s hungry-roto!
What? Wrong-roto?
But I heard your stomach rumble...
Sorry. That was me.
So confusing-roto!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Crisis in Alola! The Darkness that Eats Radiance!!
Next time
A Crisis In Alola!
The Darkness That Eats Radiance!!