Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Kaiogre
Buoizel
Phione
Manaphy
Which of these Pokémon
do I reel in today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I just can’t catch anything...
I’m not even getting a nibble.
Fishing is a game of patience.
I got something!
It’s Hagigishiri-roto!
Thank you, Amajo.
I got one, as well!
It’s a Lovecus-roto!
Here it comes!
Checking its weight and speed...
Determining the best timing
to reel it in...
Now!
This is an extra large
Namakobushi-roto!
What? Extra large?!
Oh, I’m sorry!
You finally got a nibble, Kaki!
Although I don’t think he wanted
a nibble on his face...
Why am I not hooking anything
when all of you are?
You hooked an Octan-roto!
Why is it just me?!
By the way,
where are Satoshi and Suiren?
Over there, see?
All the way over there?
Suiren, this balloon’s the best!
Yeah, Oshamari’s
in top form today!
Suiren, let’s race!
Whoever reaches
that rock first wins!
Okay!
Push me, Oshamari!
You kidding me?!
I won’t lose!
They’re gone-roto...
Doesn’t seem like
they’ll be back for a while...
Everyone’s spending the day
at the coral reef.
However,
in the depths of the sea...
It seems a grand adventure lurks.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Suiren Hooks a Kaiogre?!
I’ve been waiting for this!
Whoa! It’s a big one!
Kaki’s gonna fall-roto!
Oh, no!
Hang in there, Kaki!
Let’s all reel it in, together!
Do your best, everyone-roto!
Rotom, you help, too!
Guess I can’t beat Oshamari...
But you were quick.
What’s this?!
It’s a Pearshen-roto!
Th-Thanks, Amajo,
you’re a lifesaver...
Oshamari, help!
What’s that?!
Oshamari! What a relief!
What was that thing?
Whoa!
Kaiogre!
But it doesn’t look well...
It might be poisoned.
Kasumi!
She gave me this the other day.
I’ll attach some food
laced with Antidote to this...
Done.
Go!
Kaiogre, eat it!
Suiren!
Gamageroge?!
Don’t get in our way.
We finally had the thing cornered.
All right! Well done!
Satoshi.
Yeah. The poison must have
been their doing!
I told ya, don’t get in our way.
Start collecting it.
Roger that.
Even a Legendary Pokémon is no match for
a first-rate Pokémon Hunter like me!
Pokémon Hunter?
They’re bad guys who catch Pokémon by force
and then sell them off for money!
There’s no way I’ll let them
get away with that!
Yeah!
Kaiogre! You could handle those creeps easily
if you were healthy!
Thank you, Sandy, Oshamari!
Wait, Kaiogre!
I’ll save you now!
You just had to go and
get in our way, huh...
Grown-ups are scary
when you make ‘em angry...
Get ‘em!
Come out, everybody!
Nyaheat, Lugarugan, Mokuroh,
Meltan, and Pikachu!
We’re gonna save
Suiren and the others!
Let’s go! This is serious!
Gamagaru! Mud Shot!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Nyaheat, use Great Blaze!
Gamagaru! Hydro Pump!
Lightning Speed!
Desperate Tackle!
Raise the power!
Not happening!
Mokuroh! Seed Bomb!
I’ll make you better
on the double!
Go!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kaiogre
Type:   Water
Kaiogre, please notice!
I have no idea what
you’re playing at...
Gamageroge! Fighting Spirit Blast!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Thank you,
Satoshi, Pikachu!
Leave Gamageroge to us!
Sure!
One more time... Kaiogre, here!
You can do it, Kaiogre!
You did it!
All right!
You tryin’ to reel it in?
What a waste of time!
Nyaheat! Nitro Charge!
Lugarugan! Accelerock!
C’mon, what’re you doin’?!
Boss, damage confirmed on
the rear of the vessel!
The tractor beam is having trouble
maintaining a consistent power output!
What?!
What’s that thing?
Change of plans!
Contain Kaiogre inside the vessel itself!
Roger that!
Come here, Kaiogre!
The Antidote worked!
Oh, look at the sky over there...
Looks like we might be
getting rain.
You’ll pay for that!
Get back, everyone!
Oshamari, save everyone!
All right!
Suiren!
Ashirène?!
Yeah! She’s evolved!
All right!
That was Absolute Zero...
It’s still angry.
We have to reel in Kaiogre!
Let’s have it listen to your song!
That might quell its anger.
Ashirène, carry me!
Go!
Suiren!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Here it comes!
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
Keep it up, Ashirène!
In this world I wandered into all alone
It took the bait!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
You can do it!
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Now!
Ashirène, sing!
It’s all right now.
Kaiogre...
I’ve wanted to meet you...
I love you!
You hooked a Kaiogre?!
Oh, you and your jokes...
It’s true! Right, Ashirène?
She’s evolved into Ashirène!
Suiren and Ashirène were incredible!
They faced that huge Kaiogre!
Tell us more!
It was, like, splash! And boom!
And then?!
Ashirène sang for it!
I wish I could have
recorded that-roto!
What was supposed to be just
a peaceful trip to the coral reef...
...turned into quite the adventure.
Satoshi and Suiren are sure
to remember this encounter.
Kaiogre is still swimming through
the sea somewhere to this day.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
The Pokémon I reeled in was Kaiogre!
Score!
The Sea Basin Pokémon Kaiogre
is a Water type.
It’s a Legendary Pokémon said to have widened the seas
using its power to cause downpours.
Apparently it mostly sleeps
at the bottom of ocean trenches.
I’d love to meet it again someday!
Suiren, is that...?
Kaiogre’s scale!
Whaaaat?!
Oh? But that’s a Heart Scale...
Oh, come on... Where does
the truth end and the lying start?
Next episode
In order to soothe my weary heart...
I have no need for luxurious food
nor lively music, meow.
This is the stuff, meow!
Master’s Pile Juice!
Here in this bar, I can spend time alone,
in peace and quiet...
Solitude is the greatest luxury, meow.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Mao’s Struggle!
The Pokémon Café in the Forest!!
Nyarth! There you are!
No fair, going off on your own like that!
Next time
Mao’s Struggle!
The Pokémon Café in the Forest!!