Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Fishing Guru
Burnet
Sauboh
Hala
Who is the guest in today’s episode?
You’ll get a hint in just a moment,
and then the answer at the end of the episode!
It seems a special lecturer will be coming
to the Pokémon School today.
What kind of teacher could they be?
Alola!
Sauboh... Why are you here?
President Lusamine
requested my presence.
She wanted you all to know
how splendid science can be!
So for today,
please refer to me solely as “Sir”!
“Please refer to me solely as...”?
Sir!
Mr. Sauboh! What kind of science
are we gonna do?
Oh, yes!
Allow me to show you.
In fact,
I possess a second title as well!
From now on, please refer to me as
“Invention Branch Chief”!
It changed already?
Never mind that. What is this?
Invention Branch Chief Sauboh!
You’re gonna do science with this?
Indeed.
Here is the oh-so familiar Monster Ball
which all of you handle on a daily basis!
Have you ever considered
just how marvelous a work of science it is?
Take the enormously tall
Alolan Nasshi for example...
Or better yet,
the enormously heavy Kabigon...
It is a striking work of art capable of
compressing them down to such a minuscule size!
Yeah... It really is amazing.
As such, I took hints
from the Monster Ball...
...and invented a machine which can make any object,
no matter how large or heavy, fit into a tiny capsule!
I call it
the Super Storage Sauboh DX!
No matter how large an object is,
this machine will, with the press of a single button...
...shrink, shrink, shrink it down...
...and store it within the capsule.
Yay! Yay! Yay!
As a result,
it can easily be carried around with you.
Want to move?
It’s a piece of cake with this machine!
That’s incredible!
It may be the greatest invention
of this century!
Hey, show it to us!
Certainly.
I’ll demonstrate by shrinking this blackboard
and storing it inside a capsule.
Switch on!
Huh?
It’s not changing...
No, that can’t be...
Stare...
No change-roto.
But it worked flawlessly
during my experiments...
Slump.
Maybe you should reboot it?
Oh, of course!
It’s all right now!
Switch on! Part two!
Oh, no...
What is this?!
I didn’t plan for this!
Satoshi!
Lilie! Māmane!
They’re gone...
Have they been
stored in a capsule?!
No... The machine shut down...
Satoshi and the others disappeared...
This is a case-roto!
A case for Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
Hey!
What’s that? Someone’s voice?
It’s me! Me! Satoshi!
Satoshi?! Where are you?!
Everyone, we are down here!
Right here!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Satoshi Shrinks
What’s going on here?
We have become tiny!
Is this even possible?
This can’t be real!
Th-This is almost like...
A Satoshi figurine!
Rather, it’s exactly like
the Pokémon move, Shrink.
Sauboh!
What have you done?!
Oh, um...
It’s fine! No need to be alarmed!
All of this can be solved
with the machine’s capsules!
Well then, pardon me.
What? What?
Be quiet.
Right, now it’s your turn.
You, too.
Owww...
It’s cramped...
This feels quite odd.
Now, you’ll be returned to normal
after I’ve released you from these.
Back... to... normal...
There!
They’re not turning back.
Mr. Sauboh!
Th-That can’t be!
The President is
going to be so mad!
We can be turned back
to normal, right?
O-Of course!
Fail Branch Chief.
No thank you
to that title!
Let me check the machine!
You! I require your assistance!
Got it-roto!
Hurry up...
No, Togedemaru.
We’re in trouble right now.
Māmane!
The Ride Pikachu is super fun!
You don’t need to worry so much!
Sheesh...
Lucky them...
Seriously?!
Hurry and fix it!
I am! Don’t interrupt
a genius at work!
Commence program check scan!
Roger that-roto!
Yay!
Hey!
We’re safe...
But it feels like we’re being
carried off somewhere...
Over there!
This is bad!
We’re being sucked in!
Oh, no! We have to go after them!
Mokuroh!
Sorry, but this is an emergency!
Chase after
Satoshi and the others!
Don’t fly while sleeping!
Professor Kukui! I say we
dispatch the Ultra Guardians!
Can we?
Sure.
That’s a good idea.
I’m coming, too-roto!
You are my assistant!
Oh, right-roto...
How far will we go?
Don’t worry about it.
This is kinda fun.
But we’ve strayed quite far
from the school.
It’s a Banbadoro!
It’s huge!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Banbadoro
Type:   Ground
We survived...
Being this tiny means
every little thing becomes an odyssey...
It’s a Koratta!
It’s huge!
It’s not hungry... is it?
I-It couldn’t be...
Togedemaru!
Thanks! You really saved us!
I’ve made up my mind!
About what?
I am prepared to live at this size!
After all, we haven’t a clue when
we will return to our normal selves!
Huh?! We can’t just settle for this!
She’s right.
I’m sure it’ll work out!
Besides, it sounds fun!
It’ll be like we’re Pokémon!
What are you saying, Satoshi?!
We’re smaller than Togedemaru!
Dedenne!
They’re adorable!
Please don’t make sparks!
I can’t take this!
Let’s get back to
the Pokémon School already!
Māmane...
A tumultuous life awaits us.
That’s everything.
Did you all take proper notes?
Yes!
So heavy...
All right!
Now it’s Satoshi, Lilie,
and Māmane’s turn!
You say that...
But it’s impossible!
I can’t take this!
Let’s go back! We’ll go back
and have them turn us back to normal!
I wanna keep having adventures
like this for a bit longer!
We’ve had enough adventures!
Māmane, you come, too!
Hurry up!
Oh, no! Don’t leave me!
Sheesh!
Togedemaru!
Wait!
This is awesome!
It’s so much fun!
I gathered up some petals...
Left them in the sun to dry...
Put them on a plate
and left them in the room...
And it began to smell
just lovely inside!
Oh, how wonderful!
If you want, I can share
some of the petals with you.
Well? Did you find them?
No... They’re way too small
for us to see!
Pikachu?
Snowball is there, too!
Let’s try following them!
Huh? Where’s Māmane?
He was following us
a moment ago...
Oh, my!
Alola, Ms. Moani!
Alola!
So it’s happened to you, too?
Satoshi! Lilie!
Māmane!
Sorry... I was just so hungry.
Would you like some, too?
Go ahead and eat!
All right!
But these are much too big for us in this state.
We cannot even remove the skin.
Oh, right.
Oh, my...
Everyone,
please help pick them up!
Persian?!
That Persian...
I think it’s the same one who
bullied Nyabby a while ago!
That one?!
Incoming!
Togedemaru! Wake up!
Satoshi! Over there!
Yeah!
We’re saved...
What?!
Togedemaru?
Are you all right?
It’s Mao.
I’ve located Togedemaru.
Satoshi and the others may be
somewhere close by, too!
Why is it chasing after us?
I dunno, but it just won’t give up!
Oh no!
It’s a dead end!
In that case...
Persian!
Quit being such a bully!
Amajo!
Togedemaru!
Mao!
Amajo, we’re gonna save them!
Will they be all right?
Do your best, Amajo! Mao!
All right! Go, Amajo!
Wow!
Amazing!
Tropical Kick!
Whoa... Stomp?
It still hasn’t had enough?
S-She’s strong...
Amajo... You’re really starting
to look like an adult!
Togedemaru!
You’re too heavy...
Are they here?
Pikachu!
Snowball!
What a relief!
We made it here
thanks to Pikachu and Snowball.
I see.
Snowball, thank you!
Really, thank you, Pikachu.
Pikachu?
Huh?
We’re back to normal!
I’ve missed this!
All’s well that ends well.
Pikachu sneezing made them
turn back to normal...
This is seriously weird...
Perrie,
what happened to you?!
That was so much fun!
That was a valuable experience!
I never wanna
go through that again...
Everyone, I’m terribly sorry about
the trouble I’ve caused you...
I’ve completed the repairs.
I worked hard, too-roto!
So, without further ado, allow me to fully demonstrate
the power of the Super Storage Sauboh DX...
...using this chair!
Huh...?
What do you mean “Huh”?
What’s happening now?!
Mr. Sauboh,
what’s going on?!
I don’t know, either!
That was a rather busy day, wasn’t it?
Let’s hope Togedemaru
returns to normal soon...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The guest today was
Green: Sauboh!
The Dedenne we met on our adventure is
the Antenna Pokémon and an Electric/Fairy type.
Apparently they can communicate with their friends
using electronic waves!
The Dedenne really saved us by
contacting Pikachu and the others!
She’s back to normal!
Oh? How fortunate
it happened quickly this time!
Nothing fortunate about it!
Next episode
Satoshi! Wanna do
the Pokémon Drawing Song?
Okay!
There’s one pole
One pole...
A single Kago Berry
fallen over
Fallen over...
Three petals and
two PokéBeans
Two PokéBeans...
And before you know it...
It’s Bebenom!
What is this mess?!
Next time on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
The Shape of Family, Bebenom's Feelings!
The Shape of Family, Bebenom’s Feelings!