Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Alolan Kyukon
Alolan Persian
Alolan Nasshi
Alolan Sand
Which of these Pokémon
do we help out today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
After their trip to Hokulani Observatory,
Satoshi and his friends...
...appear to be on their way to the ferry terminal
to go back to Melemele Island.
What’s this?
It says
“Shortcut to the ferry terminal”.
Did you know about this,
Māmane?
Yeah. There’s a route through these caves
that goes straight to the port.
Sounds kinda fun!
Wanna go this way, then?
Yeah!
By the way, Māmane,
will you be all right in the dark?
Well, yeah!
Awesome! The wall’s glowing!
It’s bright because
the walls are covered in luminous moss.
Ah, so you don’t need a lamp.
How convenient!
And it’s a bit chilly in here.
Apparently one of the routes in this cave
goes to Lanakila Mountain!
I see! This must be
quite a vast cave, then.
Really wouldn’t want to
get lost here...
We’ll be fine! We just have to walk straight forward,
and we’ll reach the port just—
Hey! Stop that, Garagara!
Not good...!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
A Sand’s Storm!
An Ice Hole Double Battle!!
I can’t get out-roto!
Ow...
Is everyone all right?
We’re fine.
Amamaiko and I are okay, too.
That’s good.
But what about the others?
They don’t seem to be nearby.
Which means...
We got separated.
I finally got out-roto...
It’s all right.
Let’s look for them together.
You can leave that to me-roto!
I’ll navigate us to the others-roto!
Sure.
I’m counting on you, Rotom.
Hey, Pikachu!
Nyaheat! Lugarugan!
Doesn’t seem like they’re nearby.
They could have been sent
pretty far away.
We gotta find them fast!
I understand how you feel,
but calm down!
Pikachu!
There’s all sorts of dangerous things
inside this—
Kaki...
Sorry...
I seem to have stepped on something.
This is why I told you
to calm down!
Mokuroh! I’m counting on you!
Wake up, Mokuroh!
I’m not sure we can
find them in here...
Indeed...
Maybe we should try
using logic to find the exit!
How?
I read about this in a book!
If you can feel a draft on your fingertip,
then that is where the exit is!
I get it!
Let’s all try!
Which way?
There!
That way!
What’s that?
Isn’t that...
It’s a Ratta!
That was...
quite the marathon...
Indeed...
My battery’s run dry...
In times like these...
Ta-dough! Have some sweets!
Cookies!
Let’s eat them together!
Delicious!
Indeed.
Mao?
Sorry!
I just thought this was nice.
I love the happy looks on people’s faces
when they eat something tasty!
I hope that I’ll always be able to put
that same happy look on my customers’ faces!
Always?
That’s so like you!
This is kinda embarrassing...
But Māmane,
you have a dream, too, right?
All right,
I guess I’ll tell you.
The truth is,
I want to become an astronaut.
Astronaut?
Yeah!
I want to go out into the sea of stars,
and learn all the secrets of the universe!
That sounds wonderful!
You were thinking of stuff like that?
W-Well... yeah...
Then how about you, Lilie?
Me?
I’m not sure... Right now,
I just have so much fun interacting with the Pokémon.
I suppose all I can do is hope that
I will find my dream someday
I see.
I guess that works, too.
Snowball?
Can you hear that?
Yeah...
Those are Sand, aren’t they?
Are they fighting?
Looks more like they’re doing
some kind of training...
Oh, no!
Don’t, Togedemaru!
Sorry!
I wasn’t trying to disturb you!
We’re surrounded!
Um...
You... want this?
G-Go ahead.
A fork in the road...
Leave it to me-roto!
According to my calculations...
There’s a 50% chance
we’ll meet them by going this way,
and a 50% chance
we’ll meet them by going—
This way! Let’s go!
Wait, you’ve
already decided-roto?!
Wait-roto!
How’d you manage to step on
Gantle, Digda and Dekagoose?
I’m sorry...
Bakugames! Garagara!
I wanna see you!
Hey, Kaki! It’s the exit!
What?!
We’re free!
Cold!
Which means...
We came out on
the Lanakila Mountain side?!
Is it good?
They sure are eating a lot.
What a relief.
Seems they’ve calmed down.
Pretty crazy of them to keep training
until they were starving.
Indeed.
This Sand is a lot bigger
than the other ones.
It’s like it’s their king.
What got into them?
I am quite curious.
Let’s go have a look, too!
Yeah!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Sand
.                  (Alolan form)
Type:   Ice/Steel
It’s getting colder and colder...
The ground beneath our feet is frozen!
Be careful!
Amazing!
This is like...
A castle of ice...
There they are!
A Banguirus!
They’ve started fighting!
Against something that big?
Look, you two!
Aren’t these...
They’re probably
the Sand’s clawmarks.
It isn’t just the pillars, either.
The same scratches are on the walls and the floor, too.
Even that ice castle
might have been carved out by the Sand.
No, such a small group of Sand
couldn’t possibly have done that!
I don’t know why, but...
it looks as if this might be a gathering place for
large groups of Sand, not just those ones.
And then Banguirus
came wandering in?
Does that mean the Sand were
training to take back this place?
Hang in there!
It’s Sandstorm!
Snowball!
Snowball...
Lilie!
Now it’s four paths...
This time, my precise analysis
is sure to come in handy-roto!
The probability that everyone is
down this way is 25 p—
This way.
I hadn’t explained it yet-roto!
Wait-roto!
Lilie!
Are you okay?
S-Snowball and I
are both all right!
But the Sand are...
The Sand’s king
still wants to fight!
It’s firing its attacks
all over the place!
If we don’t do something,
this whole place’s going to collapse!
What do we do?
I will try!
I cannot leave them alone!
Lilie!
Can’t we do something
about this ice?
Oh, I know!
Come out, Denjimushi!
Denjimushi! Togedemaru!
Help us dig through the ice!
All right! Amamaiko,
we’ll help them!
Mao Kick!
Snowball! Hail!
Sand! These conditions should be
much more favorable for you Ice types!
Please allow me to aid you!
Let us protect this place together!
Thank you!
Banguirus! This is not your home!
The Sand simply want to
live here in peace!
Snowball! Sand! Please assist me
in a Double Battle!
Ms. Lychee really is good.
Lugarugan attacks, while Dainose provides support.
She has their Double Battle roles
clearly defined.
What’s important is to
have both offense and support.
Here we go!
Snowball! Aurora Veil!
Dodge, both of you!
Aurora Veil is protecting us!
Now!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
Sand! Rapid Spin!
Another Rapid Spin!
They’ve got it cornered!
Go, Lilie!
Now! Metal Claw!
We did it!
Banguirus...
You mustn’t come back here.
Lilie!
Mao...
I’m sorry we didn’t
make it in time!
But you were amazing!
I can’t believe you tag teamed with a
wild Pokémon and did a Double Battle!
It sent chills down my spine!
I was merely caught up in the moment...
It was all thanks to the
Pokémon’s hard work!
T-This time, for sure...
We’re out...!
I found you!
Suiren!
Garagara!
Satoshi!
I missed you so much!
Rotom, were you all right?
Bakugames!
I wanted to see you-roto!
Pikachu!
I’m sorry we got separated!
But I had it hard, too!
Mokuroh... Good morning...
Sheesh...
What a carefree one...
Now the Sand will be at ease.
Yeah.
Hey, look at this!
Denjimushi found it!
This might be an
Ice Stone mine!
Oh, my! An Ice Stone?
Um... What’s that mean?
The Ice Stone is an object that
causes Sand and Rokon to evolve!
So this is where the Sand
go to evolve?
That explains why they’d
work so hard to protect it.
It evolved into Sandpan!
This one’s so big...
It might be a Totem Pokémon!
What a relief!
You will protect this place
from now on, won’t you?
What?
What’s wrong?
Isn’t this...?
An Ice-Z!
You want me to have this?
But...
I don’t have a Z-Ring...
You should take it anyway!
You might get a Z-Ring
one of these days!
Yes! Well, then...
I got an Ice-Z!
There they are!
Did you get lost?
The way I see it...
We had an incredible adventure!
Yeah!
Adventure?
What kind?
We found a huge ice castle!
Then Lilie won in a Double Battle
and got an Ice-Z!
A castle?
Ice-Z?
You’ve been through a lot, huh?
Well... It all just sort of
turned out that way...
Awesome!
Pretty...
Let me see, too-roto!
What’s up, Denjimushi?
He found something else?
Amazing, Denjimushi!
The place we got lost in
was an Ice Stone mine!
If you got an Ice Stone, then...
Of course, I’ll give it to Lilie!
You can use it to
evolve Snowball, right?
T-Thank you very much.
Snowball’s gonna
become a Kyukon?
It is quite logical to conclude that
that would be possible, but...
What do you want to do,
Snowball?
She hid!
Seems it’s not time yet.
But someday we’ll see Snowball
become a Kyukon, right?
And Lilie’s Z-Move!
O-Oh, not at all...
You can do it!
That battle earlier was so cool!
Yeah, that’s right!
You should try to get stronger!
We’ll be cheering you on!
I’ll be rooting for you, too!
Me, too!
That might be nice.
Right, Snowball?
Lilie has experienced a Double Battle.
Battles might be another way
of getting closer to Pokémon,
Lilie felt once more.
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting.
The Pokémon we aided
was an Alolan Sand!
The Mouse Pokémon Sand’s
Alolan form is an Ice/Steel type.
Its steel shell is very hard,
and appears to be covered in ice.
I’m so glad the Sand managed
to protect their ice castle.
Well, I’m going to
Akala Island, so...
See you later!
That Kaki... If he was going home on Lizardon,
there was no need to come all this way with us.
Didn’t want to leave
his friends, huh...
Next episode
Mao, wanna go?
To what?
Tomorrow’s match!
You don’t mean...
Don’t tell me it’s...
Yeah! Royal Mask!
Amazing!
What’s more, Gaogaen’s opponents are
Dialga, Palkia, and Darkrai!
What?!
Just kidding.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Young Flame of Alola!
Royal Satoshi is Born!!
Now, everyone together...
Next time
The Young Flame of Alola!
Royal Satoshi is Born!!
Enjoy!