Alola! V! V! V!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Satoshi
Kaki
Mao
Mamane
-
Who tags up with Royal Mask
to battle in today’s episode?
Blue: Satoshi?
Red: Kaki?
Green: Mao?
Yellow: Māmane?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The main event, the Battle Royal,
is down to its final two teams!
The other team up against
Mr. Elec and Elecible is...
Royal Mask and Gaogaen!
Tonight’s announcer is
yours truly: Fire Kojiero.
Freezer Moosa and Thunder Nyatare
will be providing the play-by-play.
Once again, we are broadcasting
live from the Royal Dome!
Gaogaen! Cross Chop!
There it is! Gaogaen’s
Cross Chop bursts through!
Good going, Gaogaen!
Keep it up!
Oh no! Mr. Elec has
grabbed Gaogaen’s leg!
Who is this Mr. Elec?
You don’t know-roto?
Mr. Elec is a member
of the Revengers-roto.
Revengers?
The Revengers are an evil unit,
whose members keep ignoring and breaking the rules!
All the more reason for me
to root for Royal Mask!
Justice will triumph!
Do your best,
Royal Mask! Gaogaen!
Oh, my!
Aren’t those Suiren and Mao?
Lucky them...
They went to see today’s match?
Oh, my!
Elecible is coming in for a punch
from behind Gaogaen!
Gaogaen knocked Elecible back!
Hell Thrust!
There it is!
This is how
they usually win, meow!
What’s this? Mad Boobur and
Booburn interrupt the match!
Huh? The match is over?!
Mr. Elec and Elecible’s team
loses by rule violation, meow!
Huh? What’s he mean?
Booburn interfered with a match
it had no right to participate in,
so Elecible was disqualified-roto.
Royal Mask won’t be happy
winning like that!
Royal Mask and Gaogaen’s victory smiles
are nowhere to be seen.
Hey, Royal Mask!
If you’ve got
any courage at all...
then fight me in a single battle, with the title
of the Royal Dome’s strongest fighter on the line!
Oh, my! First he ruins the match,
then he challenges them to a single battle!
How shameless can you get?!
They truly are an evil unit!
I’d like to learn a thing or two
from them, meow.
Very well! I accept!
We’ll settle this during
the main event tomorrow!
Awesome!
Now we gotta go see it!
Right, Professor Burnet?
Of course! We’re all going!
Yeah!
All right,
we’ll settle this tomorrow, Gaogaen.
I’m home!
Enjoy!
Having fun, I see...
Kukui, you join in, too!
Ready, and...
Enjoy!
You’re good!
You’ve been practicing in secret,
haven’t you?
Exactly...
Now we’re ready for tomorrow!
What?
We’re all going to the Royal Dome
tomorrow to see the match.
You’re coming, too.
What, me?!
Hm? You have other plans?
N-No... I look forward to it.
I know, right?!
The others from the Pokémon School
are coming, too!
Tomorrow’s gonna be wild!
What do I do?
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
The Young Flame of Alola!
Royal Satoshi is Born!!
Today, at the Royal Dome,
the battle of the century will be held,
to see who’s the best of the best!
Hey, everyone!
Satoshi! Alola!
Alola!
Getting to see this with all of you
is so awesome!
Today’s battle is a must-see,
after all!
Royal Mask will absolutely win!
I’m so excited already!
Enjoy!
There it is! The Māmane Mask!
We will be cheering them on
with all we have!
Nyorobon! Hydro Pump!
Kairiky! Bullet Punch!
Ashirène! Sparkling Aria!
Ju’niper! Spirit Shackle!
This really is intense!
Of course!
It’s a four-on-four battle!
Awesome!
Huh?
Careful... Careful...
Where are you going?
The main event’s starting soon.
I... I’ve got some shopping to do!
Don’t worry,
I’ll make a Dragonfly Turnaround straight back!
Thank you for your patience!
It’s starting!
I’ve been waiting for this!
It’s finally time for
today’s main event!
The battle to be the
Royal Dome’s strongest!
The special single match
is about to begin, meow!
What?! Already?!
First off, there’s Mad Boobur
and Booburn! Come on!
Calm down! Calm down, me!
Next up, it’s Royal Mask
and Gaogaen! Come on, meow!
W-W-Wait just a second!
Enjoy!
They’re amazing!
Do your best!
I... I made it...
What, meow?
Trouble with the lighting?
Staff!
Oh, my! The Revengers intrude!
They’re planning to damage Gaogaen
before the battle starts, aren’t they?
Stop it!
Those guys...!
That’s unfair!
Nyaheat!
Oh, my! They’re aiming for a Fire Punch
from up on the corner post!
What?!
Now there’s an intrusion
from the audience seats!
That Nyaheat is...!
Man, now you’ve done it...
Booburn!
Honcho,
you keep impressing me, meow!
N-Nyaheat...
He did it again...
Nyaheat!
Brat boy!
Aren’t you...?
I’m Satoshi.
Oh, my! The intruder boy is Satoshi,
the same boy who intruded during the special day!
Don’t mess with us!
Cease your accusations!
He would not have interfered
if you hadn’t done so first!
Yeah!
But we can’t do
the main event like this.
It’s saying
“How dare you embarrass me?!”, meow.
An earth-shattering
development!
Now Mr. Elec and Elecible
have intruded! What a day!
It’s almost like
a tag team battle, isn’t it?
Now, dere’s an idea!
It’s him!
I’m da owner o’ da Rainbow Happy Resort Company,
th’ organization dat scares cryin’ kids into silence...
Name’s Bourgain!
What are you doing here?!
Be amazed...
I was da big boss backin’ da Revengers
from behind th’ scenes!
What?!
Oh, my! It turns out that the Revengers’ boss
is the greedy pig from hell, Bourgain!
Who ya callin’
greedy pig from hell?!
Yer booin’ sounds
just like cheerin’ ta me.
We Revengers’re here today ta win
th’ title of Royal Dome’s strongest...
Then we’ll buy da Dome itself an’ make it
part o’ da Rainbow Happy Resort Company!
What did you say?!
Get real!
Yo, Royal Mask.
Why don’tcha just accept our
challenge fer a revenge match?
Revenge match?
Booburn got disgraced real bad
in front o’ th’ audience.
It ain’t gun’ be satisfied unless
it gets t’ KO dat Nyaheat there!
So here’s da idea:
Ya team up with dat Nyaheat and its trainer dere,
and fight us Revengers fer
th’ title o’ da Royal Dome’s strongest!
We got a deal?
Or wouldya rather turn tail ‘n run?
Of course not!
Royal Mask!
Satoshi. Nyaheat.
Will you fight alongside us?
Of course we will!
Right, Nyaheat?
Very well.
I accept your challenge!
A tag team battle with Satoshi?!
Amazing! Absolutely amazing!
Well then, the gong for this special match will ring...
after these messages!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Booburn
Type:   Fire
Thank you for waiting!
It’s time for today’s main event!
The special single match turned
special tag team battle is about to begin, meow!
Satoshi, take this.
You don’t mean...
My very own...
Yeah. As of right now,
you are Royal Satoshi!
Royal Satoshi!
First up, it’s the Revengers...
Come on!
Next up, it’s the pair of Royal Mask and Royal Satoshi,
the Double Royals! Come on, come on!
Enjoy!
Satoshi’s wearing a mask, too!
Hear that? Royal Satoshi!
Did he say “Double Royals”?!
I’m too jealous!
In that case,
I’ll become Royal Suiren!
You must win!
We’re rooting for you-roto!
Where did Kukui go?
All right, the preparations
for the battle are complete!
It’s finally starting, meow!
Three!
Two!
One!
Use Flamethrower!
Counter it with Cross Chop!
Their moves clash instantly!
Karate Chop!
Hell Thrust!
Both their hits connected
this time, meow!
Royal Satoshi!
Yes!
Tag, Gaogaen!
Tag, Nyaheat!
That was such a perfect tag-out that you’d never think
it was their first Battle Royal tag team battle!
You’ve got some nerve,
attacking Booburn back there!
That was because you guys
broke the rules!
Sneak Attack!
Fling!
Oh, my! It’s Flinging Nyaheat around
with a rule-breaking move, meow!
Nyaheat!
Well done! Use Scratch!
That’s dirty!
Don’t matter, as long as I win.
Booburn! Tag!
Wild Bolt!
Kick Down!
Good, Nyaheat!
Tag, Gaogaen!
Thunder Punch!
Build Up!
Such amazing muscles!
It repelled the Thunder Punch
with a wall of sheer muscle!
The power of Gaogaen’s moves
has grown, meow!
Give ‘em another one!
DD Lariat!
DD Lariat won the clash!
Oh, my! This is bad!
The Revengers sure are evil,
aren’t they?!
Cut it out!
That’s against the rules!
How unfair!
Unacceptable!
Use Iron Head!
Aqua Jet!
Kaki! Suiren!
Ya kids!
What’re ya doin’?!
This is dangerous! Fall back!
I understand how you feel,
but leave the match to the Double Royals.
But...
Your intense passion
has reached me!
But even if the enemy
should fight dirty,
we will counter them
with a clean fight!
That is how
the Double Royals fight!
Yeah!
H-He’s so cool!
Got it!
Elecible! Use Thunder Punch!
DD Lariat!
Elecible was thrown back once again!
Keep it up!
Hang in there!
Let’s tag, too!
Yes!
Send ‘em flying with Fire Punch!
Then we’ll counter
with Fire Fang!
Oh, my! A spectacular leap
from the corner post!
And a Fire Fang!
Use the recoil from the rope
for a Karate Chop!
Karate Chop flurry!
Don’t give up, Nyaheat!
Go, Nyaheat!
That’s...
Revenge!
You’ve learned Revenge?!
Argh! Use Thunder Punch!
Nyaheat! Use Revenge!
Dat’s it!
Just wreck dis dumb match!
Oh, my! Another intrusion!
Nyaheat! Tag!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the ring ablaze
with the flames of victory!
Hey, gimme a sec,
why don’tcha?!
Hyper Dark Crusher!
The Revengers have all
been knocked out!
The Double Royals win!
They did it!
Satoshi, well done!
Royal Mask is so cool!
Curse ya! Not yet!
I ain’t done yet!
Go git ‘em!
Oh, my! Bourgain brings out
another assailant; Goronda!
I will not allow you to defile this
sacred ring any further!
Royal Satoshi!
Yes!
Nitro Charge!
DD Lariat!
Bourgain and Goronda have been knocked out
by Gaogaen and Nyaheat’s combo attack!
The Double Royals win!
Enjoy!
Enjoy! Enjoy!
The Double Royals
are the best!
I’m so moved!
Lilie, what did you think?
Next time, I, too,
will participate in the Battle Royal!
Royal Mask. Gaogaen.
Someday, let’s settle the score
between you and my Nyaheat.
Sure!
When we do,
we’ll clash with our full power,
and make it a great match
that will be remembered through the ages!
Yes!
The world... The Royal Dome...
...is smiling down on these two!
Honcho, you’re the best, meow!
All right! Let’s meet again!
Satoshi and Nyaheat have won an impressive victory
in their battle at the Royal Dome.
When will they be able to settle the score
with Royal Mask and Gaogaen?
To be continued!
Sorry to keep you waiting...
You’re far too late!
What were you doing?
Oh, you see, I got lost...
I said to be continued!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The one who formed
a tag team with Royal Mask...
...was Satoshi!
Satoshi’s Nyaheat is a Fire type,
just like Nyabby.
The bell-like object hanging around its neck is a fire bag,
which brings forth flames.
The flames rise in temperature
to match Nyaheat’s current mood!
He’s gotten even tougher
than he was as a Nyabby!
Nyaheat’s Revenge during yesterday’s fight
was a real sight to behold!
Yeah! It was awesome!
Huh?
You were watching, Kukui?
On a screen at the store...
I see.
Next episode
It hurts! I can’t stay standing!
What are you saying, Musashi?!
Do you think you can become a
world-class dancer by giving up?!
He’s right!
A dancer meowst keep dancing until the end
once she gets on the stage!
I got it! I won’t cry anymore!
I’ll keep dancing ‘til the end!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Won’t You Give Us
A Dance Dance Evolution?
Let’s dance!
Next time
Won't You Give Us
A Dance Dance Evolution?