Dosukoi!
I will present today’s PokéProblem.
Amemoth
Hassam
Kaiross
Gusokumusha
Which of these Pokémon
does Guzma send out today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Give us a full power Explosion!
At long last,
the Alola Pokémon League has begun.
First, Satoshi and the others
faced the preliminary Battle Royal.
Snowball! Powder Snow!
Multi-Attack!
Xiemi, you can still go on, right?
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Bakugames! Shell Smash!
I said wait!
Splendid work, Eevee.
Is this really all
the Alola League’s got?
After an intense battle, sixteen trainers
including Satoshi and his friends...
...advanced to
the final tournament!
Alola!
Today is the start of
the final tournament,
and thousands of people
have gathered here at Manalo Stadium to watch!
It’s time for the monumental
first match!
Competitors Satoshi and Sauboh
are entering the arena!
Competitor Satoshi is a boy who has
cleared all four Grand Trials!
Let’s give it our all, Pikachu!
His opponent, Competitor Sauboh,
is an elite from Aether Paradise!
It seems he’s a Psychic-type user!
Both sides, bring forth your Pokémon!
Here we go, Pikachu!
Now... Psychokinesis!
I choose—
Meltan?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Mao and Suiren!
A Full Power Battle of Friendship!
Meltan,
you wanna battle that badly?
Sorry, Pikachu.
Looks like you’ll have to wait a bit.
Really, I’m sorry.
Meltan, I choose you!
So, Competitor Satoshi’s Pokémon
is Meltan.
Meltan is a Pokémon species
that was only just discovered!
My plan seems to have succeeded.
Who looks to be
the weakest in that group?
Don’t think badly of me.
This is all so that
I may battle Royal Mask!
Satoshi isn’t using Pikachu?
How unexpected-roto!
Does he have some sort of plan-roto?
The first round will be
one-on-one single battles!
Both sides, are you ready?
Let the first round... begin!
Meltan, use Luster Cannon!
Dodge, Sleeper!
Attack with Headbutt!
Reflector!
Just as I anticipated...
I can surely defeat this one!
Sleeper! Hypnosis!
Don’t look, Meltan!
Oh, my! Meltan just
melted Sleeper’s pendulum!
I beg your pardon?!
Meltan! Luster Cannon!
Sleeper is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Satoshi!
He did it!
Judge! How is that legal?!
Meltan simply made
good use of its abilities.
Oh, no...
That was incredible, Meltan!
Satoshi, congratulations
on winning the first round.
Thank you!
Now it’s your turn, right?
Indeed. I shall do my best!
Now it’s time for the second match:
Competitor Ilima VS Competitor Guzma!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Ilima, the man receiving
enthusiastic cheers right now...
...has previously participated in the Kalos League,
and is the favorite to win this tournament!
His opponent, Competitor Guzma, may be an unknown,
but he made it through the preliminaries unscathed.
What could he be capable of?!
Ilima, ya puffed-up poser!
Get off yer high horse!
Sir Ilima!
Hey, don’t get all lovestruck!
Cheer for the boss, will ya?!
Destroy ‘im, Mr. Guzma!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
Our glorious leader, Mr. Guzma!
I, Ilima, challenge you!
I’ll destroy you.
Go!
It seems Competitor Ilima intends to battle with Garura,
and Competitor Guzma with Hassam!
I want a fair battle from both of you!
Let the match begin!
Garura! Grow Punch!
Hassam! Bullet Punch!
The favorite, Ilima,
does not disappoint!
That was a most elegant attack!
Grow Punch boosts attack power
every time it hits-roto!
Go, Ilima!
Another Grow Punch!
I won’t fall for that again!
Agility!
You are quite skilled.
But how will you deal with this?
If we may...
It is time to Mega Evolve!
Grow Punch!
Rock Slide!
Agility!
Kick Down!
Competitor Ilima’s relentless attacks
have Competitor Guzma up against the wall!
Keep going! Grow Punch!
Dodge backwards!
Now! Cross Scissor!
We’re not done!
Grow Punch!
Dodge to the right
and use Cross Scissor!
Hassam’s attacks
started landing all of a sudden!
What’s going on-roto?
It’s Hassam’s positioning.
Hassam is making sure to keep a straight line
between itself and both opponents.
Garura is worried about hitting her child,
and that’s making her attacks ever so slightly slower.
He’s using the child as a shield?
What could have happened?!
Competitor Ilima is struggling!
Sir Ilima!
Time to end this.
Destroy them, Hassam!
Cross Scissor!
Get out of the way, Garura!
Garura is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Guzma!
Yeah!
Sir Ilima!
You fought splendidly.
Thank you, Garura.
What a shake-up!
The favorite, Competitor Ilima,
was eliminated in the first round!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Hassam
Type:   Bug/Steel
Competitor Hau’s Raichu
demonstrates remarkable speed!
Competitor Okido’s Nasshi
is unable to keep up with it!
Raichu! 100,000 Volts!
Nasshi withstands
Raichu’s attack!
What amazing endurance!
It’ll take more than that...
...to bring us dowNasshi!
Now it’s time to strike Backuirus!
Nasshi! Use Dragon Hammer!
Dodge with Lightning Speed!
Focus Blast!
Nasshi is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Hau!
All right! We did it!
Sounds like the match is over.
Oh... Yeah.
What’s wrong, Mao?
I’m just kinda nervous...
Don’t worry!
Just treat it like any other match!
I guess.
Let’s fight at full power!
Of course!
Let me through!
The battle’s starting!
Wait for me, Mao!
The fourth match is
Competitor Mao VS Competitor Suiren!
Here we go, Ashirène!
I’m counting on you, Amajo!
The two are best friends,
studying together at the Pokémon School.
What kind of battle
will they give us?
Mao!
Suiren!
Both of you, give it your all!
Let’s cheer them on, together.
Let’s go, Mao!
Yeah!
Let the match begin!
Amajo! Magical Leaf!
Ashirène! Sparkling Aria!
Dodge it, Amajo!
The balloons serve as
both offense and defense!
Ashirène should be at
a disadvantage on land...
Amazing, Suiren!
It won’t be easy
for Amajo to get close.
But on the other hand,
if she does manage to close in, Amajo will win-roto!
I knew you’d be tough, Suiren.
Sparkling Aria!
In that case...
Amajo! Tropical Kick!
Now! Stomp!
Icy Wind!
Ashirène used an Ice move?!
Did she prepare to battle Grass types
to cover her weakness?
That’s awesome, Suiren!
Icy Wind!
Amajo!
Amajo...
That’s amazing, Suiren!
When did you learn that move?
Mao?
Come back, Amajo.
What’s this?
Competitor Mao
has brought out her Monster Ball.
What’s wrong, Amajo?
Come back!
Amajo?
Mao... Fight ‘til the end!
B-But...
You don’t want Amajo to have to
push herself any harder?
Do you think Amajo
wants to quit?
You’re always watching those around you
and considering how they feel.
That’s what I like about you.
But right now,
you have it all wrong.
Amajo still wants to battle!
Together with you!
I want to win, with you!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Mao!
Let’s go! Magical Leaf!
Now run, future hero,
and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Sparkling Aria!
Amajo! Stomp!
Dodge!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier,
but that’s the best look for you
Amajo’s at her limit.
She won’t be able
to withstand another attack.
Look, the tears of frustration
you’ve hidden beneath your cap
So we’ll have to finish this now!
will be dried up by the sun in no time
But...
Learning until you’re all worn out,
Of course, Amajo!
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
A Z-Move?!
how important it is
to speak our dreams out loud
Can they do it?!
Mao...
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
I get it...
I can feel power
unlike anything I’ve felt before.
Now swim, future hero,
and cross the vast waves
Let’s go!
Never forget your dreams
Feel the sprouting grass and trees,
and the breath of the forest!
With your backpack full of stuff,
you’re ready to go
Bloom Shine Extra!
It’s your adventure
which only you can picture
Amazing, Mao!
But we won’t lose!
I know you’ll be all right!
Embraced by our mother, the sea...
Echo...
...beyond the horizon!
Sea God’s Symphonia!
Pathetic and lame...
Obstinate and weak...
But in your eyes,
a single flame is blooming
It’s Z-Move VS Z-Move!
A clash of immense powers!
Who will win?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero,
and feel the Tailwind at your back!
The two full power Z-Moves
canceled each other out!
Aqua Jet!
Amajo! Tropical Kick!
Amajo is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Suiren!
A clash of power VS power,
move VS move...
...and will VS will!
The ones to come out on top...
...were Competitor Suiren
and Ashirène!
Well done, Amajo.
Mao!
Mao! I saw it all!
You gave it your all, Mao!
Big Brother...
The two of you were incredible!
As were you.
Thank you, Mao.
I should be thanking you!
Competitor Suiren and
Competitor Mao...
...commend each others’ efforts,
and share a firm handshake!
Say, Suiren... Unleashing your full power
is a lot of fun, isn’t it?
Yeah.
But... losing is so frustrating!
Yeah!
You were both really cool!
You were amazing-roto!
We can’t let them beat us!
No!
I won’t lose, either!
You both did great.
Fierce battles rage on
in the Alola League.
What sort of battles
will we see next time?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting!
The Pokémon Guzma sent out
was Hassam, huh?
The Pincer Pokémon Hassam
is a Bug/Steel type.
Once it has identified something as an enemy,
it will continue beating them with its steel-hard pincers...
This Pokémon is quite the warrior!
Guzma has trained it well,
though I can’t approve of his fighting style.
May I sit here?
Certainly! I would be honor—
I-I’m so sorry...
about the noodles!
I-I’m so sorry about the noodles!
I’m so sorry about the noodles!
Next episode
What a bothersome job I’ve got...
Don’t say that.
Maybe I should just
quit as Island King.
Being judge for the Alola Pokémon League
is one of the Island King’s duties.
The waiting room sucks, though...
Waiting room?
I gotta share it with the other
Island Kings and Queens.
One wouldn’t think you’d be this shy.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Musashi VS Kojiro!
A Battlefield of Truth and Love!!
Acerola, wanna be the Island Queen?
Next time
Musashi VS Kojiro!
A Battlefield of Truth and Love!!
No.