Alola!
I’ll be giving you today’s PokéProblem!
The ship at the port
The Pokémon Center
Hapu'u’s house
-
The Altar of the Sunne
Where do we go for
a sleepover today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The end draws near for Satoshi and his friends’
research projects on Poni Island.
It seems Hāpu'u came to see them
at the Pokémon Center today.
Why, is this not...
A Flying-Z!
Kaki’s new Z-Move was so cool!
I wish I got to see it, too!
Your, um...
Final Dive Crash!
Yesterday, I surpassed myself!
Does this mean you have conquered
Kapu-Rehire’s Trial?
I wish dearly that I may be
accepted as Island Queen soon.
It’s all thanks to my grandfather.
Grandfather?
During my battle with Kapu-Tetefu,
I recalled my late grandfather’s words.
And then our power welled up...
Sandy, stop!
Togedemaru!
Are you all right?
This old man... Kaki!
Look, it’s the guy we met yesterday!
You’re right!
Is my grandfather familiar to you?
“My grandfather”?!
You mean the Island King
before the last one-roto?!
No, look, we met this guy yesterday!
Can’t it have been someone else?
I mean, Hāpu'u’s grandfather is already...
But I know it was this old guy!
He was doing crazy well, too!
That must be Kapu-Rehire’s power.
The Guardian Deity at the Ruins of Paradise,
Kapu-Rehire...
...possesses the mystical power to grant the living
audience with those who have passed.
So it was true...
My brother, Gladio, said that his reason
for coming to meet Kapu-Rehire...
...was to meet our departed father.
I understand.
Hāpu'u, do you believe that Kapu-Rehire
will let us meet our father?
I very well understand
how you feel...
But you must be cautious.
Some have found themselves unable to return
from the world within Kapu-Rehire’s mist,
where this world and the next intersect.
When they finally reunite
with those they wish to meet,
the inevitable second parting to be faced
becomes all the more painful.
The ones who cannot
endure this pain...
...will be forever trapped
within the mist.
Sorry, I... I’m just going
outside for a bit.
Did Mao have someone, too?
Back when Mao was little,
Maomama fell ill, and...
I’ll go with you.
It’s all right.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Within Kapu-Rehire’s Mist
Mao, do you want to see Maomama?
I’m sure you do...
I don’t!
Oh...
I’ve been looking forward
to taking this walk for so long!
I’m so sorry I haven’t been
able to go with you.
You didn’t have a choice.
You were in the hospital, after all.
I’m sorry for getting sick...
Don’t be sorry! I get sick, too.
Oh, that’s right! I got a cold not too long ago,
and went to the hospital with Dad!
I know. Your father told me.
I’m so proud of you! He told me
you can finally take your own medicine, too?
Yup!
I’m so sorry...
I wish I could have been there for you
when you had a cold.
Mom, look!
It’s a Pokémon!
That one is called Amakaji.
It’s so cute!
Shall we catch it?
We can do that?!
Perhaps, if we’re lucky.
A Monster Ball!
Go!
Please...
We got it?!
We’re so...
...lucky today!
Pleasure to meet you, Amakaji.
So cute!
She’s my...
...little sister!
Oh, your little sister?
Not too long after that,
she had to go to the hospital again...
Every time I went to go see her,
she’d apologize more and more...
“I’m sorry,”
was just about all she’d say...
I didn’t like that side of her...
I mean, it wasn’t her fault
that she was sick...
Now, I feel like I finally
understand how she felt...
Mao...
But back then...
All you ever say is “I’m sorry” this
and “I’m sorry” that... I hate you!
Mao...
I hate you!
That ended up being
the last time I ever spoke to her...
I don’t want to see her...
I can’t, not after I was
so cruel to her...
It has been a very long time
since having so many guests stay over.
This is quite exciting!
We’re happy to be here!
I’m sorry, Amajo.
Did I make you worry?
Sorry to all of you, too.
Oh, it is nothing to fret about.
That’s right!
Indeed.
Hey, what sort of games
will we play at your house?
Playing games will have to wait until after
we’ve helped her plant the Poni Radish seeds.
Oh, of course...
May you grow into
excellent Poni Radishes!
And the next assignment is...
I can’t believe she does this
on her own all the time...
Hāpu'u is incredible!
Ready, and...
Silvuddy! Air Slash!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Could this perhaps be...
Kapu-Rehire’s mist?!
Are you all there?!
Heed my call!
Hāpu'u, where are you?
I’m over here!
Don’t move!
We’re coming to you!
The weather was so nice
until just now...
This is just like the mist
from yesterday.
Where are the rest?
Mao! Lilie! Satoshi! Can you hear my voice?!
Respond to my call!
Kaki! Māmane!
Hey!
Where are you, everybody?
Mao!
Suiren!
This is odd... The field outside of Hāpu'u’s house
wasn’t this big, was it?
Oh, thank goodness...
I was afraid I’d gotten lost in the mist!
Lilie?!
Big Brother!
What are you doing here?
I could ask you the same...
What are you doing in this forest?
Forest? I thought
I was at Hāpu'u’s house...
I had gone to visit Hāpu'u
with the others!
What?!
Is this Kapu-Rehire’s mist?
Mao!
Satoshi!
Lilie, where are you?!
They have been trapped
within Kapu-Rehire’s mist.
The world within Kapu-Rehire’s mist...
...is a mystical place where
our world and the next intersect.
Mao and the others could be near,
yet at the same time beyond our reach.
Somewhere they may reunite with one
who has departed this world...
Lilie said she wanted to see
her father, didn’t she?
And Mao must have wanted
to see Maomama!
Then, what about Satoshi?
Does Satoshi have somebody
he wants to meet in this mist, too?
Wait, Nyaheat!
Where are you going?
What’s wrong?
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kapu-Rehire
Type:   Water/Fairy
Mooland?!
It really is Mooland!
I don’t believe it-roto!
It’s been so long, Mooland!
Well, doesn’t matter how.
You got to see Mooland, after all!
Right, Nyaheat?
Fire Fang-roto?!
Now a Nitro Charge-roto?!
Now Ember-roto?!
Nyaheat wants Mooland to see
all the moves he knows!
Awesome!
Mooland’s punch caused Ember to
become Great Blaze-roto!
Mooland’s training him!
Are you somewhere
in this mist, Dad?!
Father, it’s me, Lilie!
I would very much like to see you...
Dad! If you’re there,
then show yourself!
Dad!
What do I do...
I’m lost.
Mao.
Mom...?
Mom?
Mom...
Mom!
You’ve grown so big, Mao.
And Amakaji, you’ve evolved
into such a beauty!
Mao?
I’m so sorry, Mom!
I’m sorry I said I hated you!
It’s okay, Mao...
It’s fine.
But... But...
It was my fault.
My mistake.
That’s not true!
You didn’t do anything wrong.
Listen, Mao.
I shouldn’t have said “I’m sorry”.
What I should have said was...
Thank you.
Thank you, Mao.
Thank you for being my daughter.
Thank you for bringing me,
your father and your brother...
...so much love and happiness.
Mom...
Thank you for taking
such good care of Amakaji.
Thank you for doing such a great job
looking after Aina Cafeteria.
Thank you for growing into
such a cute, sincere girl!
Thank—
Mom!
I’m trying again.
So forget I said “I’m sorry” just now.
Mom... Thank you...
...for being such a warm,
kind mother to me!
Thank you for making
delicious food for me every day!
Thank you... The walks we went on
together were so much fun!
Thank you for catching Amakaji
so I wouldn’t be lonely!
Mao...
Thank you for
giving birth to me!
Suiren, Kaki, Māmane!
Wait here for the others
to come back!
Banbadoro!
It split just a little-roto!
Hang in there, Nyaheat!
Nyaheat’s Ember has evolved
into Great Blaze-roto!
You did it, Nyaheat!
Banbadoro, wait here for me!
Kapu-Rehire!
I request that you give
Lilie, Mao and Satoshi back to us!
Kapu-Rehire!
I beg of you! Bring them back
while they can still return!
This is no time to
be idly dancing!
If you have no intention
of letting them go...
Then I shall reclaim them
by force, if I must!
Let us go, Golugh!
Luster Cannon!
What is this?
Hāpu'u.
Grandfather!
Hāpu'u. Kapu-Rehire has accepted you
as the Island Queen of Poni Island.
Truthfully?!
The Luster Cannon you fired
to save your friends...
...moved Kapu-Rehire’s heart.
Congratulations.
Kapu-Rehire,
does that mean...?
The fog’s...
Mao.
I’m always with you.
Mom...
You may not see me, but my heart is always
with you, your father, and your brother.
Mom!
Mooland!
The mist is clearing-roto!
Huh?
Are we...?
Lilie! Gladio!
Satoshi!
Look!
You’re okay!
We were worried about you!
Everyone!
Mao!
What a relief!
That’s the Mythical Pokémon,
Xiemi-roto!
Xiemi?
Xiemi. Gratitude Pokémon.
Grass type.
When it curls up its body,
it looks like flowers.
When Gracidea flowers
are in season,
it changes its form and flies off
to deliver feelings of gratitude.
Will you stay with me
until you fly off?
Thank you!
Xiemi is so cute!
Suiren... I met Mom!
That’s great!
We met Mooland!
We...
Why didn’t Dad appear?
Is it not because he still lives?
The fact that you could not see him,
despite your strong desire to do so...
...means that your father still lives...
...somewhere within
this unbelievably vast world.
Somewhere in this...
...unbelievably vast world...
We have to tell Mom!
Yes! As quickly as possible!
Silvuddy!
Gladio!
When you next set foot on Poni Island,
you may undertake my Grand Trial!
Doesn’t that mean...?
Kapu-Rehire has accepted me
as the Island Queen.
The explosive birth of
an Island Queen!
Congratulations, Hāpu'u!
Congratulations!
Well, then, please let me take your
Grand Trial right now, Island Queen!
Oh, Satoshi,
you truly are a hasty one...
The Grand Trial must wait until I have completed
the ritual to become the Island Queen.
Okay, after that, then!
I accept your challenge!
In Kapu-Rehire’s mist,
Mao met her mother...
Nyaheat met his old master, Mooland.
With these precious experiences in their hearts,
they now take another step towards the future.
And for Satoshi, the Poni Island
Grand Trial awaits!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
We went to Hāpu'u’s house!
The Gratitude Pokémon Xiemi
is a Grass type.
Apparently it can dissolve
toxins in the air...
...to instantly transform ruined land
into a lush field of flowers!
Perhaps I was able to say “thank you” to Mom
because of you, Xiemi.
It appears you cannot sleep...
You, too.
Next episode
What am I gonna do?!
My research project isn’t finished!
It’s the final day already!
What have you been doing?!
You must stick to the plan
with your research project!
It’s because you made
the Grand Trial your project!
Why not do something else?
A picture diary, for example?
Great idea!
Rotom, tell me the weather!
It was sunny every day-roto.
All right! I’m gonna draw our trip
from the first day!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
An Island Queen is Born!
Satoshi’s Grand Trial!!
Oh, no! I don’t remember anything!
Just take Hāpu'u’s Grand Trial-roto.
Next time
An Island Queen is Born!
Satoshi’s Grand Trial!!