Guess who got a haircut?
Eevee! V!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Gladio’s Lugarugan
Zoroark
Satoshi’s Lugarugan
Pikachu
Who is the last Pokémon standing
in today’s battle?
Blue: Gladio’s Lugarugan?
Red: Zoroark?
Green: Satoshi’s Lugarugan?
Or Yellow: Pikachu?
Get the answer at the end!
The Alola Pokémon League finals...
The match between
Satoshi and Gladio...
...started with Meltan’s evolved form,
Melmetal, facing Silvuddy.
Melmetal’s raring to go!
All right!
Use Double Panzer!
Here it comes!
What?!
Multi-Attack!
Using superior technique,
Silvuddy broke through Melmetal’s powerful moves,
before falling to Pikachu’s
Electroweb tactic.
Go!
Iron Tail!
And the second Pokémon Gladio sent out
was Lugarugan.
100,000 Volts!
But that was actually just an assumed form
Zoroark had used to disguise itself.
Here it comes, Pikachu!
Zoroark! Night Burst!
100,000 Volts!
Shadow Claw!
Use Iron Tail!
Attack with a flurry
of Shadow Claws!
Now strike!
Pikachu!
Night Burst!
Pikachu! Leap over it!
Shadow Claw!
Now!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Rise of
Alola’s Champion!!
Now!
Competitor Gladio
unleashes a Z-Move!
On the night of the new moon,
you shall become
an eternal wanderer,
forever lost in
the blackest of darkness!
Call of the Endless Night!
Something’s coming!
Run, Pikachu!
Shake it off with Lightning Speed!
You waste your time!
None can escape Zoroark’s
Call of the Endless Night!
Who cares?
Pikachu, stop right there!
We’re not gonna run!
Here we go, Pikachu!
Go! This is our full power!
Ultra Dash Attack!
Pikachu and Zoroark are
both unable to battle!
Pikachu!
Zoroark!
This is unbelievable!
It’s a double KO!
Thanks, Pikachu.
Thank you, Zoroark.
Now both fighters are
down to their last Pokémon.
The next match-up will decide
the Alola Pokémon League’s first Champion!
You were in perfect sync
with Zoroark, Gladio!
Nobody but you could have broken through
Call of the Endless Night like that, Satoshi!
Oh? What could have befallen
Competitors Satoshi and Gladio?
What’s going on?
Good question...
Seems like they’re having fun.
Gladio...
This is the best!
Yeah.
Let’s keep going!
Of course!
Lugarugan, I choose you!
Come forth, crimson glare.
Lugarugan!
I don’t need a suitcase, photos or a guide on this journey
Both sent out Lugarugan!
This should be interesting!
but I’ll keep the warmth of everyone I’ve met as a souvenir!
Back when you were Iwanko,
you didn’t stand a chance
against Gladio’s Lugarugan.
I had some really harsh memories along the way, too
but they must’ve fallen out of a tear in my backpack!
I don’t know what exactly you saw in
that Iwanko who couldn’t stand losing, but...
...you didn’t hold back against it.
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Even when you evolved into Lugarugan,
that one was with you.
Little by little... Type: Wild!
It may have accepted you
as a rival back then.
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...so much more! Type: Wild!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
Thanks to those guys
showing us battling styles we didn’t know about,
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
we were able to grow.
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Let’s settle this now,
Lugarugan!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lugarugan
..                         (Dusk Form)
Type:   Rock
Stone Edge!
The two break the silence
with Stone Edge!
The final battle has begun!
Lugarugan! Accelerock!
Counter!
We’ll have to do something
about that Counter!
Now it’s our turn!
Stone Edge!
Run around it!
And then use Bite!
It’s already preparing a Counter?
Stop, Lugarugan!
Too soft! Stone Edge!
He dodged that?!
All those battles must’ve
improved his reflexes!
It won’t be easy to get close...
Then let’s try this!
Attack, attack and
keep attacking, Lugarugan!
I won’t let you set the tempo!
Stone Edge!
Dodge!
Accelerock!
Lure them into a Stone Edge!
Jump!
That didn’t have
enough momentum, huh?
You used the Stone Edge
as footing?
But I won’t let you
use that tactic again!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Dodge to the left
and use Accelerock!
Again!
Dodge to the right
and charge in!
Counter!
Lugarugan!
How’s that?!
Hang in there, Lugarugan!
Competitor Satoshi’s Lugarugan
managed to get back up!
You can still stand up
after taking that Counter?!
Incredible!
This is so much fun, Satoshi!
Yeah! I’m having fun,
too, Gladio!
Well, how’s this?
Swords Dance!
Competitor Gladio’s attack power
is sharply boosted!
Let your crimson fury
hit its boiling point!
Reversed Scale!
Stone Edge!
It means nothing
in the face of Reversed Scale!
Advance!
Be careful! Here it comes!
What’s this?
Competitor Gladio’s
Lugarugan bit itself!
Why?
Is it because of its
post-Reversed Scale confusion?
Here’s your chance!
Attack with Bite!
Counter!
It...
...bit its own arm
to snap out of confusion!
Exactly!
That’s the equation Lugarugan and I
came up with to attain victory!
Incredible!
How much training
did they have to do to pull that off?!
A relentless drive to win!
He’s cool-headed, but the flame burning
inside him is blazing hot!
Can Competitor Satoshi’s
Lugarugan still fight?!
Can you stand, Lugarugan?!
One last rush! Stone Edge!
Bite attack!
Keep using Stone Edge!
Give them
a full power Accelerock!
Go!
Finish them with Counter!
It’s not over!
Lugarugan, fight Counter
with Counter!
What?!
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is...
...Competitor Satoshi!
It’s over!
He made it through a brutal struggle, and now takes
the throne as the Alola Pokémon League’s first Champion...
Competitor Satoshi!
Satoshi won!
The explosive birth of
a Champion!
That was a burning battle!
Gladio sure was strong...
Satoshi, Big Brother...
You’re both incredible!
Oh, my! The Alola
Pokémon League Champion!
Well done, Satoshi!
Congratulations!
I’m so happy for you, Satoshi!
V! V!
I really felt the romanticism
in that final match!
I so envy him for getting to
challenge Royal Mask!
Gladio... That was
a magnificent battle!
Why are you spacing out?
Did I... win?
Sheesh...
Congratulations... Champion!
Thanks, Gladio!
That was a magnificent battle!
It was a dazzling and powerful battle,
shining as brightly as the Alolan sun!
Give our finalists a big round of applause
for the incredible spectacle they showed us!
Satoshi.
Let’s fight again sometime.
Of course!
Ouch! That hurts!
‘e ‘on?! Th’ bra’d boy?!
So, how’s it coming along?
Just have to put in
this part, and...
Yes! It’s done!
It’s complete, meow!
Now we can nab loads of Pokémon!
We poured our entire budget into it!
The plan will succeed, for sure!
We Team Rocket will remake
Alola in our image, meow!
Yay!
After many intense battles, it’s finally time for
the Alola Pokémon League’s award ceremony!
Oh, come on! How could Kukui
miss such an important moment?
Watched over by the competitors
who fought in the final tournament,
Royal Mask is now handing over the trophy
to the first Champion: Competitor Satoshi!
Congratulations, Satoshi!
Thank you!
Pikachu, check it out!
I guess you wouldn’t get it...
Royal Mask, I’m really looking forward
to tomorrow’s exhibition match!
As am I, Satoshi.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Satoshi is so cool!
Indeed.
Satoshi, let’s immortalize
this moment-roto!
Say “Namakobushi”!
Bad news! I’m getting
an Ultra Hole reaction!
At what coordinates?!
It’s very close... No...
It’s right above us!
W-What?!
It’s an Ultra Beast!
Watch out!
What?!
Akujiking?!
A massive Ultra Beast
appeared out of nowhere!
Is it friend or foe?!
To be continued in
the next exciting episode!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thanks for waiting! V! V!
The last one standing
was Satoshi’s Lugarugan!
Satoshi, congratulations
on winning!
Gladio was struggling
until the last second, too...
That truly was
a final match to remember!
And then Akujiking showed up
just when the mood was so nice...
Talk about awful timing!
Next episode
We will now begin the “How Many Z-Moves
Can You Name” challenge, meow!
Sounds fun!
I won’t lose!
Ready, go, meow!
Full Power Peerless Fists of Fury!
Ultimate Dragon Burn!
World’s End Fall!
Raging... Geofreeze!
Nyarth, now you!
What?!
Um... Black Hole E—
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Akujiking Invades!
A Grand Z-Move Showdown!!
Now Team Rocket... or, no...
Next time
Akujiking Invades!
A Grand Z-Move Showdown!!
I become a legend!