Alola, meow!
Here’s your PokéProblem, meow!
Sakaki
Matori
Musashi
& Kojiro
Persian
Who leads Team Rocket elite force
that appears today, meow?
Get the right answer
at the end of the episode, meow!
The festival of the eclipse,
the Manalo Festival, is coming up.
I went to the Pokémon School
just like on any other day,
but the grown-ups were acting strange
for some reason.
While that was going on,
we Ultra Guardians...
...were asked by Ms. Lusamine
to come to the Altar of the Sunne.
There, Lunala emerged
from the Ultra Hole.
But a creature that we’d never seen before
appeared with it...
Is that an Ultra Beast, too?
It came from the Ultra Hole...
So it must be.
The one absorbing Ultra Aura
from across Alola...
...was that Ultra Beast, then.
It’s still absorbing Ultra Aura
from Lunala as we speak.
Melemele Island is
over in that direction!
Oh, no!
You must protect Lunala!
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
We have to go after them, too.
I suppose...
What a pain...
Yeah...
Lunala has suddenly appeared in Alola...
...pursued by a mysterious Ultra Beast.
What will become of Lunala?!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection-start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection-don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Lunala VS UB: Black!
A Full Moon Battle!!
Will you stop sighing already, meow?!
But we’re not selling anything...
Maybe I’ll just quit this job...
What?
That’s the Legendary Pokémon,
Lunala, meow!
What?!
Hey, look, meow!
What’s that?
It might be a mega rare Ultra Beast...
In any case,
we gotta contact HQ, meow!
Gozu, what’s going on?
What do you mean?
Ever since we arrived in Alola,
I’ve been feeling hopelessly lax...
Yeah... Me too...
Wanna go back?
Big news, meow!
Wait, what?!
Matori, what’s with that outfit, meow?!
Where are you right now, meow?!
It doesn’t concern you.
Anything the matter?
Lunala and a black, mega rare Ultra Beast
have appeared over Melemele Island, meow!
Oh...
“Oh...”? You’re not
surprised at all, meow?!
Gozu.
Gozu!
Set a course for
Melemele Island, full bore!
What a pain...
We’re not gonna catch it?
Yes, we are.
But when I say “we”,
I mean Team Rocket’s elite unit...
...the Matori Matrix.
Matori Detox?
Matori Matrix!
I see.
You guys stay out of this.
Just go home.
That’s an order.
Wait... Hello?!
Hello?! Hello?!
She hung up on us, huh...
What’s with that bowl-headed four-eyes?!
“Matori Matomatomato”...
How in love with yourself
can you get?!
Myahoo! Musashi’s back
to her old self, meow!
Not really...
Ah, what a pain...
Let’s just stay out of this
and go home...
No, meow! If Matori catches Lunala
or that mega rare thing,
she’ll get promoted even further,
and be able to boss us around even more, meow!
I thought the wind seemed
unusually rowdy...
So this is why.
If a battle breaks out here,
there’ll be trouble for sure...
Kapu-Kokeko!
What is that creature?!
There they are!
Lunala!
Onvern, hurry!
Good!
Keep it up!
It vanished?!
That was Phantom Force-roto!
Lunala’s putting up a good fight!
Well, it is a Legendary Pokémon!
So cool!
Gladio!
Yeah!
Satoshi?! Big brother?!
Gaburias! Dragon Pulse!
Onvern! Blast Waves!
Lilie!
Thank you, Lunala!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Tyltalis, are you all right?
Lunala, thank you
for saving Lilie!
I have to give
my thanks, too.
Lizardon! Flamethrower!
Flygon! Great Blaze!
Metang! Luster Cannon!
Hakuryu! Ice Beam!
Go!
That move is too dangerous!
We gotta fall back!
Got it!
What’s up, Bebenom?
Satoshi! Look at
that Ultra Beast’s back!
It looks just like the drawing
Bebenom made-roto!
You’re right!
And since it was
on that mural too, that means...
...it’s probably linked to
the Radiant One in some way-roto!
What is happening?!
It’s absorbing Ultra Aura
directly from Lunala-roto!
And not just that-roto!
It might be trying to
possess Lunala itself-roto!
You mean like
what happened with Mother...?
Not happening!
Gladio!
Onvern! Blast Waves!
Use your Bite attack!
Let Lunala go!
Big brother!
Are you all right?!
Yeah.
Lunala is...!
Lunala was...!
...possessed by that thing?
What?!
An electromagnetic net-roto!
Electromagnetic net?
It came from there!
No way!
Optical camouflage?!
Pocket Monsters.
Sun & Moon...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Lunala
Type:   Psychic/Ghost
Begin pulling it up...
Open the hangar doors...
What a pain...
It’s being taken away!
Cut it out!
Solgaleo?!
That’s...!
Solgaleo, I’ve missed you!
Solgaleo!
Hang in there!
All right!
But Lunala is...
What about the Ultra Beast?
It broke apart and fell.
The aircraft again?!
What’s their deal?
Don’t mess it up this time.
Yeah... Maximize the
electromagnetic net’s power.
But that might damage them...
Don’t care. Do it.
What a pain...
Stop it!
Silvuddy! Air Slash!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
We’re hit...
Retreating...
Not good! Here it comes!
Solgaleo!
Now it’s possessed
Solgaleo-roto!
It’s running away?!
Wait! Give Solgaleo back!
It vanished,
still possessing Solgaleo...
Build Up!
I’m filled with poweRokon!
I’m full of energy!
Remembering that bowl-headed four-eyes
made my stomach churn!
Myahoo! At last, Musashi and Kojiro
are back for real, meow!
We’ll catch those things,
for sure!
Our targets are Lunala and
the mega rare thing!
Well? Do we give up?
Yeah... Let’s just relax on the beach
with a Pile Juice or something...
We will never give up!
We’ll await our
next opportunity!
Indeed!
Activate optical camouflage!
Roger!
How’s Lunala?!
We’re giving it first aid.
Have a Full Restore.
Eat this.
It’s an Obon Berry.
Hang in there!
It’ll need
emergency transportation.
The nearest place is the
Pokémon School’s underground base!
Let’s carry it there.
Sauboh!
Yes!
Mom... The Ultra Beast that
consumed Solgaleo...
What was that?
I don’t know. For now,
we’ve decided to call it “UB: Black”.
UB: Black...
Everyone!
Professor Kukui!
Principal Okido!
You’re not hurt, are you?
We’re fine!
Amazing... So this is Lunala?
Professor Kukui is back
to his old self!
Yeah... The dark cloud over my mind’s
cleared up like a Clear Skies!
I’m fully energizeDangoro!
Dumbball! Darumakka!
Come to think of it,
Mother, you’re also fine.
Yes. It’s ironic...
It seems we got better thanks to UB: Black
absorbing Solgaleo’s Ultra Aura.
I hope Solgaleo’s okay...
Professor Burnet, how’s Lunala?
The treatment’s complete!
Now we’ll just have to wait for it
to recover its strength.
Lunala...
UB: Black, huh...
Come to think of it, the mural we found
at the Altar of the Sunne...
...had a picture of UB: Black on it.
Yes.
It seems there’s a deep connection
between the Radiant One and UB: Black.
If we want to solve that mystery,
we’ll have to decipher the writing on the mural!
One question still remains-roto...
Why did you draw the same image
that was on the mural-roto?
I can’t tell what it’s saying
at all-roto...
Everybody!
We’ve verified the data of the aircraft
that tried to capture Lunala and the others!
Who were they?!
An organization that operates from Kanto...
Team Rocket!
Them again!
Their elite force,
the Matori Matrix.
Matori Matrix...
I say we get right to working on a plan
to deal with them as well as UB: Black.
Got it.
Children, stay with Lunala.
Yes!
Ult-Roger!
Let’s get going, too.
Yes.
It’s begun...
The day of the eclipse,
and the Manalo Festival...
The emissary of the sun,
Solgaleo, has been taken away,
while the emissary of the moon, Lunala, has been robbed of its power...
What is about to happen
here in Alola?
Hey, Radiant One...
I know this is ancient history and all...
But the emissaries of the sun and moon
saved you, didn’t they?
So, mind saving them in return this time?
Ya know... Repay the favor?
You’re saying it all wrong again!
You have to make it a proper prayer!
So that our feelings of gratitude...
...will reach the Radiant One.
Get well soon, Lunala.
When I touched Lunala’s back,
it was warm, just like Solgaleo’s.
I felt the power of the moon.
Solgaleo saved Mom...
Lunala saved Lilie...
Now it’s my turn to save it.
Solgaleo, we’ll save you for sure...
...using our full power!
Yeah!
Full power-roto!
Lunala!
All right! It’s back to full strength!
Everyone, get back!
Satoshi and the others have witnessed
Solgaleo get taken away by UB: Black.
And Lunala has regained its power.
How will this end?!
To be continued...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting, meow!
The leader of Team Rocket’s elite force
was Matori, meow!
We’ve gotta catch the mega rare, pitch-black Ultra Beast
that was chasing Lunala, meow!
We can’t let Matori and the others
beat us to it, meow!
How bad are the damages?
Check it immedia-
T-They’re already fixed?
You sure work fast.
Well then... What now?
Um...
Next episode
It’s been a long time since the Island Kings
and Queens have gathered like this.
But why’s the one
from Poni Island not here?
It’s complicated.
Complicated how?
You see...
Gonyonyo...
What do you mean,
“Gonyonyo”?
Gonyonyo. The Whisper Pokémon.
Normal type.
If it starts to cry loudly,  it becomes startled
by its own crying and cries even harder.
When it finally stops crying,
the Pokémon goes to sleep, all tired out.
Say that again?
Gonyonyo...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
A Prism of Light and Darkness,
Its Name is Necrozma!
A Prism of Light and Darkness, Its Name is Necrozma!