Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
PokéChorus
PokéMarathon
PokéDance
PokéVault
What is the slightly unusual lesson
that’s held today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Professor, what are you doing?
I thought I’d have you all
participate in PokéDance.
PokéDance?
Could you be talking about something like
a dance performed by Pokémon?
Each of you choreograph a dance
for your Pokémon to perform.
Simple, isn’t it?
Sounds fun!
Are we allowed to use props?
Of course.
Use whatever you want, as long as it
helps draw out your Pokémon’s unique charm!
Charm, huh...?
All right, Garagara!
Let’s show them the spirit of Wela with a dance!
Ashimari, do your best!
All right, Pikachu! We’re gonna come up with
an amazing dance, too!
Amamaiko,
let’s give it all we’ve got!
The performance will be in three days.
Practice hard until then!
Yes!
With that said,
everyone’s got dance fever today! Yay!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Won't You Give Us a
Dance Dance Evolution?!
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Have some Kiteruguma brand Honey Doughnuts
right out of the oven, meow!
I’ll have one.
I’ll have five, please.
Thank you for your order, meow.
We’ll bring them out right away!
Looks like they’re in the mood for doughnuts today, meow!
They’re selling like crazy, meow!
The way things are going,
we might even have a chance to expand our menu!
Yeah! With us getting this much money,
I’m sure even HQ will be pleased with us!
In that case, should we try to
advertise a bit more flashily?
Sing, dance,
and make it all sparkly!
After all,
I am a singing and dancing actress!
So...
Bravo! Bravo!
Then let’s have a
marketing strategy meeting, meow!
That’s...
The brat girl’s...
That means...
What?
Amamaiko!
Don’t run like that!
It’s dangerous!
The green brat girl!
Amamaiko!
Sheesh... You came here again...
Alola, you two!
You’re as lively as ever,
little Ama!
Here, have a treat.
I’m so sorry, Ms. Moani.
It’s fine.
Amamaiko, aren’t you glad
you got a treat?
Oh, my!
You said “Thank you” in Alola Hula?
Alola Hula?
I guess most young people
don’t know it.
Alola Hula is
an ancient Alolan dance.
“Hula” means “Dance”.
I’m sure you’ll understand
if you see this.
Come out, little Dori!
Now you try too,
little Mao!
Yeah!
What are they doing?
Makes me wanna dance too
for some reason, meow.
I want it.
I want that Pokémon!
Point!
“Odoridori, Hula-Hula Style.
Dancing Pokémon. Psychic/Flying type.
“One of the Odoridori types
found in Alola.
“It increases its Psychic powers
through dancing at its own pace,” apparently.
I want it!
I want it to be my backup dancer,
I tell you!
Well then, I’ll show off
some sharp steps, too!
I want to dance, too, meow!
That was fun!
Hey, Amamaiko, why don’t we try
competing with Alola Hula?
Competing?
Yeah.
There’s gonna be a PokéDance recital
at the Pokémon School.
Thank you for telling me
about Alola Hula, Ms. Moani!
All right,
let’s continue shopping!
Sorry to have
taken up your time!
Take care!
Hey, did you hear that?
Sure did.
I finally know the name of that
old lady at the market, meow!
No, not that!
A chance came up to turn not just Odoridori,
but all the brats’ Pokémon into my backup dancers!
I get it! So you’ll target their recital
and catch all their Pokémon in one fell swoop?
Exactly!
Here we go!
One, two! One, two!
You’re good!
Would it perhaps be better if
I made it a bit more elaborate?
I suppose so...
How about adding some
Pokémon moves to it?
Moves?
I see. I hadn’t thought of that!
Thank you very much!
Ashimari, fire two Balloons
in succession!
Good, Ashimari!
You’re using Balloons?
That’s so Ashimari!
We’re still only 50% done.
You’ll be seeing a lot more soon!
I look forward to it.
I’m sure this dance will impress everyone,
Togedemaru, Denjimushi!
What sort of dance, Māmane?
It’ll be a surprise!
Wait for the performance!
Garagara, the flames of Wela
burn within us...
Let’s make them flare up
with a dance!
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
Don’t play with fire.
Yes, sir...
Satoshi, what kind of dance
are you thinking of having them do?
Pikachu! Nyaheat! Lugarugan!
Mokuroh! Bebenom!
Let’s show him our
full power dance!
Photo op-roto!
Is this... a PokéDance?
Huh? It isn’t?
Failure-roto...
How about you,
Mao, Amamaiko?
We’ve chosen Alola Hula!
Alola Hula, is it?
Looks like you’re onto something there.
I look forward to seeing it!
Thank you!
Let’s do our best, Amamaiko!
Is that Alola Hula?
Yeah! It’s for the
PokéDance project.
It’s coming along nicely.
Wait a moment.
I’m almost done.
Mao, I’ll handle the rest here,
so go practice with Amamaiko.
Thank you, Dad!
You’re such a hard worker,
Amamaiko!
That went well, meow!
We’ll name it
“Operation: Team Rocket Dancers”!
Now all that’s left is
to wait for the main event!
I’ll definitely get those
Pokémon backup dancers!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Odoridori
..                  (Hula-Hula Style)
Type:   Psychic/Flying
Yay! PokéDance! PokéDance!
Dance! Dance! Dance!
Calm down,
or I’m sending you home.
Ho and Sui are dancing, too?
That’s a secret.
It’s a secret
even to Big Sis’s boyfriend!
Secret! Secret!
H-He’s not my boyfriend!
Is everyone here?
All right, let’s start the
PokéDance recital!
First off, a demonstration from
the master of Alola Hula!
Master?
It’s Odoridori!
That’s its Hula-Hula Style,
is it not?
Huh?
The lady from the market...
Ms. Moani was famous?!
I haven’t danced in so long,
but I guess I still have it in me!
Thank you, little Dori!
Thank you very much.
Everybody, try putting your own feelings
into your dance, okay?
I’m looking forward to seeing it!
Thank you!
And now that we’ve seen that wonderful example, it’s finally time for the main event!
First up is... Lilie!
Yes, sir!
Well then, Snowball,
let us begin!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
Awesome!
She’s figure skating!
A dance befitting of
the Ice-type Snowball!
Snowball, finish it!
That was a wonderful ice dance.
Thank you very much.
Next up is Suiren!
Yes!
Yay!
I see, so Ho and Sui
are part of the dance, too.
Looks kinda fun.
We will do a dance
befitting of Ashimari!
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Two Balloons!
Ho, Sui, go inside.
Yeah!
Yay!
Ashimari, jump!
Ashimari’s bouncy dance!
Thank you very much.
Very much!
They’re pretty good!
Yeah! Everyone’s bringing out
their Pokémon’s strengths!
We can’t let them beat us,
Amamaiko!
It’s Kaki’s turn next!
I’m so excited!
They’re dancing together!
They’re in perfect sync!
This is our burning hot
Wela spirit!
Awesome!
He’s like Lizardon!
Oh, my!
Little Dori’s got the fever, too!
Good, Garagara!
Hotter! Faster!
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
Our burning... hot...
Are you all right, Kaki?!
Didn’t I tell you
not to play with fire?
Yes...
C’mon, Denjimushi!
What’s that?
Change! Denjimushi Car!
What are they doing?
Go, Togedemaru!
Toge-Denji Robot
Perfect Form DX!
So cool!
So what kind of dance
are you going to do?
Well, I didn’t have time
to program in that part...
All right!
It’s our turn next!
Let’s go, everybody!
Brat girls and brat boys!
It’s showtime!
Showtime?
I hadn’t heard about this...
Could this be a surprise from
Principal Okido-roto?
Pokémon,
enter the Pokémon frame.
Trainers,
enter the trainer frame!
Ashimari, you go over there.
What’s going to happen?
This must be another
guest appearance.
What if it’s Royal Mask?!
I doubt that...
Today’s all about PokéDance.
It’s starting!
It’s time to begin
a wonderful dance show!
It’s a Pokémon-getting fever!
The pop-stepping
fan favorites! There!
Everyone’s beloved...
...Team Rocket!
Team Rocket!
You’re not “beloved”!
Doesn’t matter!
Everybody’s gonna love us in a moment!
What are you here for?!
Isn’t it obvious?
We’re here to dance!
Wrong!
We’re here to snatch you all
in one fell swoop, meow!
How do you like our flawless plan?
We’re gonna get a bunch of Pokémon backup dancers
and form Team Rocket Dancers!
To that end, we’ve snuck in here
night after night...
...and worked on this contraption!
These are the fruits
of our labor, meow!
That’s not fair, Team Rocket!
You can say
we’re not acting fair...
...but now that you’re caught,
you’re at our mercy!
Wait!
Why is that one still outside?!
You’re right!
Amamaiko!
To think they’d find a weakness
in our flawless plan...
Very impressive, meow.
Catch that thing, now!
Yes, meow!
Amamaiko, run!
Now its hands and feet are
completely restrained, meow.
Looks to me like its feet are
poking out...
T-That’s no problem at all, meow!
Just give up and roll over
on the floor, why don’t you?!
Exactly! It’s impossible to release your friends
from those sturdy catching devices!
That’s right, meow!
We’re never gonna tell you that
the top of the catching devices is really fragile, meow!
Amamaiko, up top!
Get on top of the cages and attack!
What?! How did she know
their weakness, meow?!
Glare...
I won’t let you, meow!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
You waste your time, meow.
Stop that, meow!
Amamaiko, be careful!
What’s that?
It’s getting stronger!
It’s Stomp! Amamaiko is
trying to learn Stomp!
Amamaiko...
It can’t be...
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Amamaiko... You’ve evolved?
I gripped my small palms tight
Rotom, what is that?
Amajo. Fruit Pokémon.
Grass type.
Its specialty is kicking attacks
using its powerful legs.
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
In victory, it shows off by
trampling the defeated under its feet.
The brat Pokémon...
...became a queen Pokémon?!
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
It... It evolved right before
our eyes again, meow...
In this world I wandered into all alone
Amajo! Finish him off!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
It... It’s strong!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Great job, Amajo!
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Team Rocket! Now it’s our turn!
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
This isn’t good...
My backup dancers...
What?
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
What even is this feeling?
Thank you, little Mao!
You should thank Amajo for working so hard!
Right, Amajo?
Evolution is incredible!
Incredible! Incredible!
It’s my first time seeing an Amajo!
Mine, too.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Oh! Little Dori, you’re saying
“Thank you” to little Amajo, too?
Well then, let’s begin Amamaiko’s,
or rather, Amajo’s PokéDance!
You can do it, right, Amajo?
Fatal Moku Shot
Neo Fatal Moku Shot!
Amajo, thank you.
Amamaiko has undergone a
dramatic evolution into Amajo.
She’s sure to show us some incredibly
exciting dances from now on, right?
To be continued! Yay!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The slightly unusual lesson was
Green: PokéDance!
The Fruit Pokémon Amajo
is a Grass type.
Her kicks seem to have gotten a lot stronger
than when she was an Amamaiko.
The move she used to kick Nyarth away
was Tropical Kick!
Let’s stay friends, Amajo!
All right, Amajo!
Time to help out in the cafeteria!
Oh, right...
The apron’s too small for you now.
I’ll have it refitted for you.
Next episode
I wish I could use moves, too.
I can use Flamethrower!
Though I kinda messed it up today...
Well, that’s neat,
but I want something cooler!
Maybe Teleport, like Nebby!
Or how about Shadow Clones?
It’d be really helpful!
Or Minimize!
That definitely wouldn’t be possible!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Satoshi Minimizes
Next time
What?! For real?!