Alola! Kukui here!
I’ll be giving you today’s PokéProblem!
The shopping mall
The Pokémon Center
Its old home
The TV station
Where does Satoshi take Mooland today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
You’ve got your hands full
with shopping bags-roto.
I’ll carry some for you-roto.
They’re really heavy!
That will not be a problem!
Alola!
Alola.
Out doing chores?
Yes!
Here.
Thank you so much!
Nyabby! Long time, no see!
Wait, Nyabby!
Hey!
Nyabby!
What’s up, Pikachu?
Nyabby! This is where he was?
Mooland’s there, too-roto.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
It’s Time for Nyabby to Set Off!
That move...
It’s Fire Fang-roto!
Mooland! Have you been well?
Satoshi and Nyabby...
Satoshi was concerned about Nyabby,
who was living out in the wild.
Then he learned that Nyabby was living
with an elderly Mooland.
But Nyabby did not seem interested
in forming any sort of bond,
and has kept his distance
from Satoshi.
Nyabby, you’re practicing
Fire Fang now?
Are you okay, Mooland?
I know!
I just bought some berries.
I’ll share some with you.
You sure haven’t changed...
Well, this is unusual!
Two Pokémon of different types
practicing moves together...
Rotom, freeze it there!
Pausing-roto.
You see how they’re both
arching their backs, right?
That’s how they
concentrate their energy.
Now that you mention it,
they struck that pose a few times.
Mooland seems to care a lot
for Nyabby.
Huh?
Pikachu, let’s go visit Nyabby!
We’ll bring him some berries.
What are you doing?!
When asked “What are you doing?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
What’s up, Nyabby?
Did something happen?
Sheesh!
Don’t get in our way!
Is that the honcho?!
Pikachu! Electric Ball!
Huh? They vanished with a poof!
Like a villain!
Man, what a waste of time.
Retreat! Retreat!
Nyarth, come on.
You go on without me, meow.
Nyarth?
Mooland!
It looks to be in pain-roto!
Is this what you wanted
to tell me, Nyabby?
Don’t worry.
We’ll get it right to
a Pokémon Center.
You’ll carry it-roto?
Of course!
It’s light...
But still really big!
I knew you couldn’t do it-roto...
Don’t worry, Nyabby!
Mooland will get better in no time!
Nyabby!
Ms. Joy.
Is Mooland all right?
It’s not injured or seriously ill
or anything like that...
You see, Mooland is just...
Does Nyabby understand that?
He can probably sense it.
I understand.
You should stay with him for the day.
Thank you, Professor.
The fact that Nyabby
came to you...
...proves that he sees you
as a human he can trust.
Don’t let him down.
I won’t!
Nyabby, Mooland,
I brought some...
Oh, no-roto!
Mooland can’t have gotten far
in its condition-roto!
It probably went back to its home!
Nyarth!
I got something
I wanna say to you, meow.
Nyabby is a real
hard worker, meow.
I want you to look after him, meow.
Where’s this coming from?
That’s all I wanted to say, meow.
What’s gotten into him?
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Mooland
Type:   Normal
Nyabby?
Where’s Mooland-roto?
Don’t ask.
Nyabby...
What’s gotten into him?
He’s been sighing non-stop
since he came back.
I’m not in the mood
for that, meow.
Bring these to the little one.
Thank you.
I hope Nyabby cheers up.
Tell him he’s
always welcome here.
You’re hungry, right?
I got these from the lady
at the market.
She said you’re
always welcome.
I’m here if you
want to talk, meow.
Talking things out
can help you feel better, meow.
Nyabby.
I’ve decided to stay here
‘til you start eating again.
Professor Kukui gave me the go-ahead,
too, so you’re stuck with me!
Brat boy...
Today’s what yesterday—
yes, yesterday called tomorrow
Now, shine down on us from above
Oh rising, rising, rising, sun!
I’m smiling, and they’re smiling
We’re smiling,
smiling without even thinking
Smiling when we’re happy
Smiling when we’re sad
United by our smiling
Tomorrow, we’ll still be smiling
Spinning when we’re sad
United by our spinning
Tomorrow, we’ll still be spinning
For me?
You eat first.
Go ahead... Here.
I said...
Hey, Nyabby,
wanna come with us?
I’ll help you perfect
your Fire Fang!
You can join us.
Oh, my!
He’s saying he’ll join
if you prove your strength in battle, meow.
He doesn’t want
your pity, meow.
All right, I get it.
Pikachu!
Then, we’ll give you a peek
of how we battle!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Lightning Speed!
What?!
It’s Fire Fang-roto!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Lightning Speed!
Electric Ball!
Come with us!
Go, Monster Ball!
I got Nyabby!
This is for the best, meow.
But now we’re enemies, meow.
I won’t show you any mercy, meow.
Come out, Nyabby!
Play nice with these guys,
too, Nyabby.
I know.
We should eat together!
Satoshi has caught Nyabby.
Overcoming the parting
with Mooland,
and now aiming towards
perfecting Fire Fang,
Satoshi and Nyabby’s
new challenge begins!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was the Pokémon Center!
The Big-Hearted Pokémon Mooland
is a Normal type.
It also serves as a Ride Pokémon
here in Alola!
Nyabby.
Work hard so you can make the Fire Fang
Mooland taught you your own!
Next episode
Awful news! Satoshi was swallowed
by Shirodeathna!
What happens
when it swallows you?!
You turn into a Deathkan!
What?! A Deathkan?!
Come on...
Everyone believed you again...
Everyone! While you’re talking,
Satoshi’s gonna...
We’re not falling for that again.
Next time...
on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Beware of Shovels...
Next time
Beware of Shovels!!!
What?! You’re kidding!