Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Yowashi
Ohrot
Larantes
Dekagoose
Which of these is the Totem Pokémon
that appears today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
All right, Pikachu!
Use an even stronger 100,000 Volts!
Don’t be in such a rush,
Mokuroh.
Everyone’s buzzing with excitement-roto!
Of course they are.
The Alola League’s right around the corner.
Hey, look what I found!
Burnet has found a photo...
Who could this boy be?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Satoshi — A Timeless Encounter!
So cute! This is you, right?
How old were you?
About five, I think?
Where’d you find this?
I was sorting through things in the closet,
and found it stuck in this book.
Oh! My starting point!
The Super Pokémon Move Index!
You sure had done your research!
Yeah. This really takes me back.
I loved it so much,
I’d bring it with me wherever I went.
It was like my textbook for whenever
Mr. Hala let me see his battles.
Heavy Bomber!
Heavy Bomber! The more the user outweighs the target,
the greater the move’s power!
That hit real hard!
Use Ice Ball!
Ice Ball... The move’s power
increases each time it hits!
Dodge and use Infight!
He won again!
I really wanna go on
the Island Pilgrimage, too...
You’re still a tad
too young for that, Little Ku.
Don’t treat me like a kid!
I even have my own Fire-Z!
Is that Nyabby yours?
Oh, well,
it belonged to my parents...
We were always together,
so I guess we were like siblings?
Here we go, Nyaheat!
Great Blaze!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Such power-roto!
Oh no-roto!
Satoshi and Nyaheat are gone!
Satoshi!
Gao... huh?
Ow...
Lugarugan, that was
one crazy strong Stone Edge!
Huh? Lugarugan? Pikachu?
Where are you? Hey!
Pikachu! Mokuroh! Lugarugan!
Meltan! Rotom!
It’s a Nyabby!
Nyaheat!
Right, good...
Come here.
What’s wrong?
Let’s be friends!
It’s all right, Nyaheat.
Oh, are you...
Nyaheat’s trainer?
That’s right.
A Z-Ring! That’s awesome!
You’re on the Island Pilgrimage?
Yup.
This is an Electric-Z, right?
I have a Fire-Z!
That’s awesome!
I don’t have that one!
Really? Yay, I win!
I wanna see a Z-Move!
Show me a Dynamic Full Flame!
You have a Z-Ring!
You can do it, right?!
You wanna see it, too,
right, Nyabby?
What to do...
Can’t you?
Right! Let’s give it a try!
We’ll aim for that rock.
Huh? But was that giant rock
there before?
Whatever.
Um...
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Well, I’ll just give it my best shot!
Let’s go, Nyaheat!
This is our full power!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Cool! That’s a Dynamic Full Flame?!
We did it.
Wasn’t that cool, Nyabby?
You can have this back.
Thank you.
That was my first time seeing
the Fire Z-Move!
Aw, man... My book got singed.
Oh, sorry!
Guess the move was
just that powerful.
Was that really your first try?
Oh... Yeah.
Amazing!
You were like the Island King!
I know! You’re the Move King!
Move King, huh? Cool!
Now let’s have a Pokémon Battle!
I wanna see more moves!
Okay, let’s do it!
All right!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ohrot
Type:   Ghost/Grass
Nyaheat,
try to hold back a bit.
When I say Nitro Charge,
use Sizzle Charge.
And for Great Blaze,
make it a Medium Blaze.
Those moves aren’t real!
Don’t treat me like a kid!
“Like a kid”? Uh...
Give it your all, Move King!
Got it! If that’s what you want,
then we’ll use our full power!
Let’s go, Gao!
“Gao”?
You’re wearing
a Gaogaen hat, right?
So, Gao.
Whoa! That’s so awesome!
Nyabby, I’m Gao!
Here I come, Move King!
Nyabby! Use Ember!
What? No way!
How’s this for a Fire move?!
Nyaheat! Nitro Charge!
Nyabby!
Great Blaze!
Um... Bite!
Nyabby, you did your best.
Let’s battle again sometime, Gao.
Using Great Blaze is no fair!
What?
You wanted me to
give it my all.
I didn’t want to lose!
Don’t worry if you lose.
Just try to win next time!
Really?
Yeah.
I see!
Nyabby, let’s keep getting stronger,
and then beat the Move King someday!
You were watching us?
Come over!
This is crazy!
They’re all my friends.
H-H-Huge!
Even Grandpa Oh is here!
Grandpa Oh?
Yeah!
He’s an elder Ohrot, so he’s Grandpa Oh!
He’s the Totem of the forest!
There’s a Totem Pokémon
in this forest, too?
Grandpa Oh gave me my Fire-Z.
Really?!
Yeah! Awesome, right?
Again, Grandpa Oh?
“Again”?
Hang on, Grandpa Oh.
Nyabby, use Scratch!
That’s less Scratch
and more Tickle...
This is what we need.
What?
Grandpa Oh...
...sometimes gets an itch on his back,
and then he can’t stop sneezing.
We tried lots of stuff and found that
Nyabby’s claws work best.
Oh, I see.
You wanna try, too, Nyaheat?
No!
Nyabby can do it
because of its tiny claws!
So he says, Nyaheat...
Are you okay now?
Oh, no!
Looks like it’s gonna pour down...
It did!
You’re awesome, Grandpa Oh!
Thank you, Grandpa Oh!
Thank you!
You like that book?
It’s the Super Pokémon Move Index.
It’s got all sorts of info
on Pokémon moves!
Really? Sounds fun!
But seeing them in person
is something else!
How’d you pull off
that amazing Great Blaze?
I’m not sure what to say...
You can do it, too,
if you and your Pokémon keep at it!
I see!
What’d you think of our battle?
It sucks that I lost, but it was fun!
Right, Nyabby?
You’ve battled lots, yeah?
Yup. Before I came to Alola, I’d go to
the Pokémon Gyms in all sorts of cities,
and battle the Gym Leaders there.
Gym Leaders? Are they strong?
Yeah, they’re super strong!
When you beat a Gym Leader,
you get a Badge,
and if you gather enough of those,
you can enter the Pokémon League!
It’s like a Pokémon Battle festival!
The Pokémon League?!
So what happens
if you win the Pokémon League?!
I have a dream.
Dream? What kind?
To be a Pokémon Master!
Pokémon Master?!
I’ve never heard of that before!
That sounds awesome!
I’ll be a Pokémon Master, too!
Thanks for the help, Grandpa Oh!
Thank you, Grandpa Oh!
Huh?
What’s wrong, Grandpa Oh?
Nyabby, use Scratch!
It’s not stopping.
Why?
Nyaheat!
Something’s wrong.
I’ll go!
Right! I’m on it!
Awesome, Move King!
Thank you, Heracross!
Abuly!
The rain got their wings stuck.
All right! I’ll help you, Abuly.
Stay still.
That’s the last one.
Let’s have our partners dry them.
I see!
That worked great, Gao.
Yeah!
Feel better now, Grandpa Oh?
A Fire-Z!
It’s your reward!
I got this from helping him, too!
I see!
Thank you, Grandpa Oh!
Let’s have another battle, Move King!
With everyone here!
Okay! I’ll be right there!
Huh? Nyabby,
where’d the Move King go?
Grandpa Oh, do you know?
What’s that light-roto?
Wait-roto!
Owww...
Huh?
Gao? Nyabby?
Where are they?
Grandpa Oh, do you know?
That tickles!
Stop it, it really tickles!
What happened to you?
You’re all dirty...
Sorry... I don’t understand.
Found you-roto!
Rotom!
We’re home!
Welcome back.
Is lunch ready?
I just finished it.
Wash your hands,
then go get Kukui, okay?
Got it!
Professor Burnet!
What?
I made a huge discovery-roto!
Wait, isn’t that a Celebi?!
Celebi in Alola!
A grand discovery-roto!
They say Celebi appears
in beautiful forests...
It must have been drawn to
Alola’s beautiful nature...
Hey! Wipe your hands!
Sorry!
They’re dry now, though!
Professor, I’m back!
Oh, welcome back!
Food’s done.
Got it. I’ll be right there.
A most mysterious meeting
made possible by Celebi.
And that meeting back then...
...now paves the way
to the Alola League.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
The Totem Pokémon was Ohrot!
The Elder Tree Pokémon Ohrot
is a Grass/Ghost type.
It’s really nice to
all the creatures who live in the forest.
Through its roots,
it exerts control over other trees.
Wait...
So that’s what happened when
we were seeking shelter from the rain!
Whoa, this looks great!
It’s like they’re brothers...
Next episode
“Where did Satoshi go?”
Satoshi and Nyaheat suddenly vanished
right in front of Pikachu and the others.
“Hurry! Hurry!”
“Wait! Don’t leave me behind!”
They dash through the forest
in pursuit of the two.
“All right, leave this to me!”
They advance,
overcoming countless obstacles...
When shared,
joy is doubled and sorrow halved.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Pikachu’s Exciting Expedition!
“I found sumthin’ real nice!”
Next time
Pikachu's Exciting Expedition!