Alola!
It’s me, Kukui!
I’ll be handing out today’s PokéProblem.
Alolan Ishitsubute
Gantle
Kapu-Tetefu
Dainose
The Pokémon Ms. Lychee sends out in battle
are Lugarugan and... who?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Let’s go, Mokuroh!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Huh? Nothing’s happening.
Wrong!
Come on... I spent so much time
teaching you yesterday!
Stretch out your arms like this!
Match with the example given: 53%-roto.
Slump!
You know how to Focus Energy,
but that’s not enough.
Satoshi, will you be okay
for the Grand Trial?
I’ll be fine!
I do better at the main event.
I hope you’re right...
This is my first time
seeing a Grand Trial!
I can hardly wait!
Same!
Oh, Iwanko! You wanna train, too?
You sure are riled up...
Keep it up, and let’s
blast through that Grand Trial!
Satoshi! Don’t underestimate her.
I won’t! I’ll give it my full power!
Today it’s finally time for Satoshi’s Grand Trial.
His opponent is...
O Kapu-Tetefu, God of Life who
watches over Akala Island...
I am the Island Queen, Lychee.
I now go to face the Island Pilgrim.
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Lychee’s Grand Trial!
The Hardest Pokémon Battle!!
These are the Ruins of Life.
This is where the Grand Trial will be held.
Ruins of Life...
These ruins are home to
Akala’s Guardian Diety, Kapu-Tetefu.
Today, we’ll be watching
Satoshi’s Grand Trial.
Cheer him on as best you can.
Yes!
Well, then, off I go.
Please leave the recording to me-roto.
Ms. Lychee!
So there you are, Satoshi.
Please give me a good fight!
We will now begin the
Island Pilgrimage ritual of the Grand Trial!
Wela Volcano,
nurturer of Akala Island!
God of Life, Kapu-Tetefu!
Watch over me and the young Island Pilgrim,
and give us strength!
Ms. Lychee’s so cool!
She’s like a different person...
So, are you ready?
There’s the usual Ms. Lychee.
Yes!
Iwanko!
Not yet! Calm down!
Ouch!
Iwanko seems pretty aggressive.
What could be wrong?
We will now begin
the Grand Trial battle!
Both fighters, send out
your Pokémon!
This will be your hardest
Pokémon battle on Akala Island.
I’m going all out!
I’ve been waiting for this!
My partners are all adorable,
rugged little Rock types!
Go, Dainose!
Dainose!
I’ve never seen one before!
Dainose. Compass Pokémon.
Rock/Steel type.
It freely controls three small units called Mini-Noses
using magnetic force.
All right, then I’ll use...
And also...
Lugarugan!
This Grand Trial will be
a Double Battle!
A Double Battle?!
It was one-on-one
when she fought me.
What? Really?
Why did you make it
a Double Battle?
Satoshi has already conquered
Hala’s Grand Trial on Melemele Island,
and owns no less than
three Z-Crystals.
It means that the Alolan wilderness
has already recognized his strength.
In order to draw out his full power,
this is the least I could do!
I’m honored!
Let’s have a Double Battle!
I can see it, Satoshi.
The blue flame blazing inside you!
I got hungry from being so nervous...
Then I choose...
Moku—
Iwanko’s acting
far too wild today-roto.
Iwanko,
I like your eagerness!
And Mokuroh! I choose you!
He’s awake!
Even Mokuroh’s eager!
Cheer them on, you two.
It’s all right.
We’ll definitely win!
Let’s do the Grand Trial!
Satoshi,
show me your full power!
Let the battle begin!
Grand Trial
Mokuroh, use Leafage
on Lugarugan!
Iwanko, you use Rock Throw!
He’s giving them both orders
at the same time?!
That’s what a Double Battle is!
They test the trainer’s judgment.
Seems difficult.
Assume formation!
Lugarugan, use Rock Slide!
Mokuroh and Iwanko
both took damage?!
Yeah. That’s what’s scary
about Rock Slide.
Mokuroh, Iwanko,
are you all right?
That frightened me.
This is bad for my heart.
Stealth Rock!
What? What’s that?!
Wait, Iwanko!
Iwanko!
They’re surrounded!
This Stealth Rock is
really troublesome.
Ms. Lychee really is good.
Lugarugan attacks, while Dainose provides support.
She has their Double Battle roles
clearly defined.
This Grand Trial will not be easy.
In that case, Mokuroh,
carry Iwanko and fly!
If you’re airborne,
there’s no need to fear the Stealth Rocks!
Mokuroh,
use Leafage on Dainose!
Well done! But how long
can you keep that up?
Magnet Bomb!
It’s the Mini-Noses!
There’s no point in running!
Don’t underestimate
the Mini-Noses’ formation attack!
Iwanko, use Rock Throw!
Mokuroh! Iwanko!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Dainose
Type:   Rock/Steel
If even a single Magnet Bomb hits its target,
it deals massive damage.
You’d better hope you can
predict their path,
or you won’t be able to
clear this Grand Trial.
Lugarugan, Dainose
and the Mini-Noses...
It’s five on two, placing Satoshi at an
overwhelming disadvantage.
Even so, Satoshi has to win!
This truly is a Grand Trial.
This is getting interesting!
Breaking out of situations like these
is what make battles so intense!
You’re burning hotter
than Wela Volcano!
Satoshi, challengers like you
are the best!
Dainose, use Zap Cannon
on Mokuroh!
Lugarugan, use Accelerock
on Iwanko!
Mokuroh! Grab on to Iwanko and fly!
Then use Leafage on Lugarugan!
Lugarugan!
Watch out!
They can even do that?!
Collecting data! Collecting data!
Collecting data!
Now! Use Zap Cannon!
Watch out, Mokuroh!
Iwanko’s so cool!
Well played!
Good work, Iwanko!
Iwanko?
He’s been acting strangely
for a while now.
Yeah... I hope nothing’s wrong.
Iwanko! Mokuroh!
Let’s fight back!
Launch the Mini-Noses!
Surround Mokuroh and Iwanko!
Lugarugan, here we go!
A Z-Move?!
That’s it!
Mokuroh!
Fly up with Iwanko!
Roar, heartbeats of life!
O, echoes of the bedrock,
piercing through heaven and earth!
Stop there, Mokuroh!
Go!
World’s End Fall!
Danger-roto! Danger-roto!
Mokuroh, above you!
Get out of the way!
What are you planning, Satoshi?
Now, Mokuroh!
All right!
Oh, my! The Stealth Rocks
are gone-roto!
Satoshi’s so lucky!
No, that wasn’t luck.
Satoshi was aiming for this.
He’s one crazy guy!
I see. You’re good.
We’re not done yet!
Dainose,
use Giga Impact on Iwanko!
Lugarugan! Rock Slide!
Mokuroh! Leafage!
Iwanko, use Bite
on Lugarugan!
What amazing fighting spirit!
Good, Iwanko! Don’t let go!
Mokuroh, provide backup!
Dainose, use Magnet Bomb
on Mokuroh!
Now, Mokuroh!
I won’t let you!
Dainose, use Giga Impact!
Take this, Dainose!
This is our full power!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Dainose is unable to battle!
He pulled it off!
Satoshi, you’re amazing!
You fought well, Dainose.
Well done.
Lugarugan, now it’s all on you.
You did it, Mokuroh!
Now only Lugarugan is left.
All right, let’s go, Iwanko!
Mokuroh,
grab on to Iwanko and fly!
Mokuroh!
Mokuroh! Mokuroh!
Mokuroh is unable to battle!
Iwanko made a terrible mistake...
Was he so riled up that
he couldn’t think clearly?
You fought well.
Take a good, long nap.
Iwanko, remember this?
What’s that pose?
The pose from the
Rock Throw training-roto?
Let’s beat Lugarugan!
I’ll fight alongside you!
I see...
You’re an interesting one,
Satoshi.
What does he mean,
fight alongside him?
Let’s go, Iwanko!
Use Rock Throw!
Just standing around waiting
won’t get us anywhere
Lugarugan, use Accelerock!
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl
all turn to look in awe
Bite!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing,
naturally endless journey
Rock Slide!
Things to find here and there and everywhere,
it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on
and on and on and on!
Jump!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint
with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Now, Iwanko!
Use Rock Throw!
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage
will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul,
give it all you’ve got
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
Therefore, the winner of
this Grand Trial battle...
...is the challenger, Satoshi!
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Iwanko!
That was a narrow victory.
Thanks, Iwanko.
Thank you for a heated battle,
Lugarugan.
That was super cool!
So intense!
It was a good battle!
Thank you, everybody.
Satoshi, jumping up the Rock Slide
was an inspired strategy.
Ms. Lychee...
Congratulations on
clearing the Grand Trial.
And this is a present
from Akala Island.
A Rock Z-Crystal.
Have Iwanko use the
Rock Z-Move whenever—
She’s all over the place...
Dancing, tripping, battling...
Let’s try that again. Here!
Thank you very much!
I got a Rock-Z!
The fourth Crystal collected-roto!
You did it, Satoshi!
Congratulations!
Iwanko, this is all thanks to you two
working so hard.
Satoshi.
Yes?
After watching him battle today,
it occurred to me...
...that your Iwanko
might be about to evolve.
What?
Yeah. When Iwanko’s evolution
draws near,
its disposition grows
wilder and more aggressive.
Rotom mentioned that
earlier, too.
Indeed-roto!
Iwanko, you’re gonna evolve?
Will he become Midday Form,
or Midnight Form?
I can’t help but wonder-roto!
I think either one would be cool!
Become whichever one you want!
That’s...
Kapu-Tetefu.
Satoshi has overcome Lychee’s Grand Trial
and gotten the Rock-Z.
And Iwanko is showing
signs of evolving.
The extracurricular lessons
are drawing to a close!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Dainose!
The Compass Pokémon Dainose
is a Rock/Steel type.
Its attack where it controls the three Mini-Noses
is quite troublesome to deal with.
It and Lugarugan had a perfect balance
of offense and defense in their Double Battle!
What?! You think Satoshi’s Iwanko
will become the Midnight Form?
Yeah. He’s more active
during the night.
He seems to be looking up to my Lugarugan,
so I think he’ll become the Midday Form!
Well, whichever it is...
I can’t wait!
Next episode
Pokémon evolution
truly is mysterious.
When our Dorobanko evolve into Banbadoro,
it’s always so moving!
I’ve evolved!
Satoshi! Humans don’t
evolve like Pokémon do!
Yes I did! Right, Professor?
Indeed!
You were able to use the
washing-machine for the first time!
Washing machine?
Well done, Satoshi!
He’s acting like...
A doting father...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Iwanko and the Guardian Deity From the Ruins of Life!!
Iwanko and the Guardian Deity
From the Ruins of Life!!