Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Kekking
Koiking
Akujiking
Nidoking
Who’s the Pokémon with a name ending in “-king”
who battles us today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi and Pikachu were battling Kapu-Kokeko
to prepare for their Grand Trial on Poni Island...
...when the shock of a fierce Spark
flung them to a ruined city.
There they encountered Akujiking,
a beast who would eat anything...
...as well as Dia and Zeraora,
who were fighting in solitude.
What’s wrong?
Isn’t that...
...the Pokémon School?
I knew it...
This is our Pokémon School.
“Our”?
That’s right.
I was here just yesterday.
A parallel world?
Para... what?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Fire!
The Twin Sparking Gigavolt of Friendship!!
Parallel worlds.
Suppose you reach a crossroads...
Call this path A, and this B.
You’d like to take both paths,
but you can’t go both ways at once.
But if you could...
These paths would be
parallel worlds.
The paths would split up further after that,
and even further still later on,
giving birth to more and more
parallel worlds.
You and I existed in
two disconnected worlds.
But some sort of accident occurred,
bringing you to our world.
I don’t get it at all!
Well then,
I’ll tell you about this place.
Ten years ago, an event took place here on Melemele Island
that would alter the course of the future.
The land was bought up, and reckless construction work
destroyed the once lush nature.
The forests, the ocean,
and even the air became polluted.
Then there was the fateful day
that Akujiking appeared.
If you pick the wrong path,
then the same fate might even
befall your world.
Feeling homesick?
No. I was just remembering
everyone from the Pokémon School.
That’s what being homesick is.
I’ve had so much fun
at the Pokémon School...
Playing, laughing and battling a lot...
Want some food?
Thank you!
Dinner time!
Delicious!
Wait... What about Zeraora?
Hey, Zeraora!
Come eat with us!
It prefers being alone.
But you’re partners, right?
I never caught it,
if that’s what you mean.
I don’t know what it’s feeling.
“I want to send Akujiking
back to its own world...”
It was that wish
that brought us together.
It’s over!
Get back in the Ultra Hole already!
What?!
Before long,
we ended up fighting together.
I see.
Akujiking’s one and only weak spot...
...is the second face
above its gigantic mouth.
All we have to do is hit that with Plasma Fists
and push it back into the Ultra Hole...
Or so we thought.
It didn’t work?
We couldn’t break through
its defenses.
If only you could use Z-Moves...
This place used to have Z-Moves, too.
But when the nature was destroyed
and Kapu-Kokeko disappeared,
our Z-Moves stopped working.
The Guardian Deity of Alola
has abandoned us.
Dia...
Don’t worry.
Even if the Guardian Deity has given up on us,
we won’t ever give up.
Right, Pikachu!
Let’s do some training!
Pikachu, try aiming your attacks
at this can!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
And then a 100,000 Volts!
What are you playing at?
It’s training for hitting its weak spot.
If we use Electroweb to
stop Akujiking from moving,
we can hit its weak spot
with a 100,000 Volts!
Don’t you think that could work?
I never asked for your help!
But we’re free to do battle training
if we want, right?
Right! Pikachu, one more time!
Zeraora’s telling you
to knock it off, too.
That’s wrong.
It’s saying it’ll help us train!
Zeraora, let’s go!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
See? Zeraora’s raring to go!
You guys provoked it!
Thanks, Zeraora!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
100,000 Volts!
Use Lightning Speed!
Pikachu!
We’re not done!
Let’s try that one more time!
You...
I’ll help you until sunrise.
Now you’re talking!
See if you can hit Zeraora!
Lightning Speed!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu, are you okay?!
Akujiking won’t give
you any time to rest.
Lightning Speed!
Now! 100,000 Volts!
You did it, Pikachu!
An Obon Berry?
For Pikachu?
Thanks, Zeraora!
When you locked your aim just now,
you and Pikachu were one.
I could say the same for you!
Oh come on,
you know what I mean!
You two are perfect partners!
That’s...
Akujiking!
Pocket Monsters!
...and...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Akujiking
Type:   Evil/Dragon
Hey, Dia! Let me help you
send Akujiking back!
Looks like I have no choice.
All right!
Now, then...
First we have to lure it out!
This way!
We’ll lure it to the Ultra Hole,
break its guard with Electroweb,
and then simultaneously hit its weak spot
with 100,000 Volts and Plasma Fists!
Got it!
To the right!
Satoshi!
Hold still...
I’m fine.
All right, let’s move.
It’s the Ultra Hole!
It’s shrinking.
If that entrance disappears...
Don’t tell me...
We won’t be able to send that monster
back to its own world.
We have to pull this off, no matter what!
Yeah!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Let’s go! Plasma Fists!
100,000 Volts!
Go!
Satoshi!
Zeraora! Infight!
Dia! Zeraora!
It’s hopeless.
Run away, you two.
Get going!
No!
We don’t stand a chance now.
We don’t know that!
Think of how I’d feel...
...if you got killed
by that monster, too!
I said I won’t give up,
no matter what!
What’s happening?
Kapu-Kokeko!
You’ve come back?
It’s got a different color...
I think we might be able
to use Z-Moves now!
Yeah, let’s give it a try.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Zeraora!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
All right!
You finally did it!
Yes... At last...
What’s wrong, Dia?
Aren’t you happy?
Of course I’m happy.
It’s just... I can hardly believe
that it’s finally over.
Dia...
Pikachu, you did great!
Zeraora, you’re amazing!
You did great!
Where’s Kapu-Kokeko?
Satoshi! Pikachu!
Kapu-Kokeko?
What is it trying to do?
Of course...
This still isn’t over.
Now it’s time to send you
back to your own world.
But how?
Together, maybe we can
make a miracle happen...
That’s how I feel.
Oh, I get it.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Lightning Speed!
Zeraora!
Good... You’re evenly matched!
Infight!
Iron Tail!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Plasma Fists!
Pikachu!
Satoshi!
Dia.
I swear we’ll restore Alola
to how it once was.
So you take good care of
your Alola, too...
Sure! Leave it to me!
And then let’s have another battle!
Of course!
Are we...?
Satoshi!
Rotom!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Oh, right...
What about the others?
Satoshi, you forgot this!
Everyone!
Satoshi, did something happen?
It was insane!
Come on, tell us what happened.
Oh, right... Kaki. Sorry I broke my promise
to battle you yesterday.
Yesterday? That was for today!
Huh? Today?
So if today is yesterday...
Then when is today?
What are you talking about?
Alola sure is beautiful.
Satoshi and Dia...
Pikachu and Zeraora...
Even in separate worlds,
they will live together.
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon we battled was Akujiking!
The Junkivore Pokémon Akujiking
is an Evil/Dragon type.
It’s a crazy strong Pokémon that’ll eat
even mountains and buildings!
Let’s hope that, now that Akujiking is gone,
Dia’s world will go back to normal.
All right, Pikachu...
Use Plasma Fists!
Plasma Fists?
I’ve never heard of that move-roto!
Hey, Satoshi!
Let’s fight!
Yeah!
Next episode
Dear Suiren...
I’m happy to say that
we do have time.
It looks like Takeshi
can come, too.
Let’s hope our surprise works out!
I’m looking forward to
meeting your new Pokémon, Sandy, too!
Wait for us!
Best regards, Kasumi.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Alola, Alola! Takeshi and...
...Kasumi!!
I can’t wait!
How about you, Sandy?
Next time
Alola, Alola!
Takeshi and Kasumi!!