Alola!
Yeah! I’ll be giving
today’s PokéProblem!
Yamikarasu
Gänger
Kosokumushi
Alolan Nyarth
The Pokémon that steals our Dark-Z
in today’s episode is...
Blue: Yamikarasu?
Red: Gänger?
Green: Kosokumushi?
Yellow: Alolan Nyarth?
Which one?!
Our recent activities have been
pretty mundane, don’t you think?
Yeah, it’s been quite a while since
the last time we caught anything.
We gotta get some
proper work done soon,
or else the doughnut stand will end up being
our primary source of income, meow!
All right,
so let’s think of our next plan!
But first, let’s have snacks!
Yay, I found a cream puff!
That’s mine!
Time for a snack!
What are you doing?!
My cream puff!
That move was
Knock Off, meow!
Hidoide has learned
a Dark type move, meow!
Really?
That’s incredible, Hidoide!
If we have both a Pokémon
that can use a Dark move and a Z-Crystal...
...then all we’ll need is a Z-Ring,
and we can use Z-Moves, meow!
Super Hyper Z!
Zoom and Smash!
Sounds great!
Sounds cool!
I’m dying to try one, meow!
A call from HQ.
It appears your progress has come to
yet another standstill.
You’ve been showing
far too few results.
Yes, we’ve very sorry.
It’s like this every time,
but what an awful feeling.
It can’t be helped, meow.
I can’t take it anymore!
I’m gonna set the record straight!
May I have a moment?
Musashi!
We are terribly busy
at the moment.
You see, we have made plans
to add Z-Moves to our arsenal.
Z-Moves?
W-Well, yeah...
But from what I hear,
such moves require a Z-Ring,
and one can only obtain those from
an Island King or Island Queen.
Do you have any leads on those?
W-Well...
Go to Ula'ula Island.
Its Island King Kuchinashi and I
have known each other for a long time.
You might be able to
get one from him.
I expect great results from you.
Leave it to us!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Team Rocket's Island Pilgrimage?!
Get a Z-Ring!!
And so Team Rocket trio and Sonansu
headed straight for Ula'ula Island.
Great results... The boss expects
great results from us, meow!
If we can just live up
to his expectations...
We’re sure to get
a special bonus!
And then I’ll get Sakaki’s lap, too!
What a very, very, maximum great feeling, meow!
Today, we’ve even taken
anti-Kiteruguma measures!
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
What a great feeling.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
That ought to buy us
plenty of time.
All right, let’s go all out
and get that Z-Ring!
Yeah!
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for...
Alola, Big Sis Acerola!
Alola!
Which book should I read you today?
I wanna hear “The Greedy Lapoo”!
Read it for us!
A long, long time ago,
in a forest on this island,
there lived a ghost
that nobody liked at all.
The ghost was very violent,
and liked to frighten people.
What’s more, the ghost was very greedy
and would run off with anything that struck its fancy.
The people named the ghost “the Greedy Lapoo”,
and were quite scared of it.
What kind of guy do you think
this Island King Kuchinashi is?
I hope he’ll give us
a Z-Ring quickly.
No problem.
I’ve prepared a secret weapon, meow.
Ta-daah!
Could that, by any chance, be our new product,
the mixed fruits malasada?
The plan is that we’ll use this to
befriend the Island King in no time at all, meow!
Well done, Nyarth!
There, there...
Now we just have to find
the Island King.
I found something nice!
What? A police station...
A police station?!
It’s fine.
We just have to put on a disguise.
‘Scuse me!
Ah’d like ta ask sumthin’!
Why are there
so many Alolan Nyarth here?
What an awful feeling, meow.
I’m sure these guys are up to no good, meow!
What, meow?
I knew it...
They made quick work of us...
What’s with all the noise?
Those Pokémon stole
our precious malasada!
Tough luck.
This is the Nyarth’s hangout.
We’ve lost our present
for the Island King...
We’ll have to think of
something else.
You’re here to see
the Island King?
‘s true!
Da boss asked us to!
Yeah! We came ‘ere in a jiffy
ta see ‘im!
Yeah? But sorry to say,
that’s not happening.
Why’s dat?
Ula'ula Island’s Island King went on a journey
to do some martial arts training or something.
M-Martial arts trainin’?
He might be back in ten days,
or a month...
...or perhaps a year...
A... A year?!
What’s he mean,
martial arts training?
He’s plenty strong already, isn’t he?!
I mean, he’s the Island King, isn’t he?!
Complaining won’t help, meow...
Go home.
I don’t want anything to do
with those loudmouths.
The Greedy Lapoo was
sealed away by the Island King,
and peace returned to the island.
The end.
The Island King is so cool!
I love this story!
I don’t really like it...
I’m not too fond of violent ghosts.
Besides, the mound Greedy Lapoo
was sealed in is kinda scary...
Really? Just think of it as a fairy tale.
Nothing to be afraid of!
Yeah, it’s fine!
Let’s go take a look!
So, what do we do now?
We can’t get anywhere if
the Island King isn’t here, meow.
I really wanna try
firing off a Z-Move.
I wanna use
the Dark-Z already, meow!
We can’t go home
empty-handed!
We have to get a Z-Ring,
no matter what it takes!
Huh?
You’re too fired up, meow.
Big Sis Acerola, look!
Something came out!
T-The Greedy Lapoo?
It wasn’t a fairy tale?
Who’re you supposed to be?!
You scared us!
That’s...
...our Dark-Z!
Give it back!
Let’s get out of here,
Big Sis Acerola!
Stop it! Can’t you see that
you’re scaring them?
Be nice to people,
or they’ll hate you!
What?
What?!
Big Sis Acerola!
That Mimikkyu just flew, meow!
Is it a Flying type?
This is no time to be asking questions!
Let’s chase them!
Yeah!
What do we do?
Big Sis Acerola got taken away...
Let’s go! We gotta tell
the Island King!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun!
Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Gänger
Type:   Ghost/Poison
Hey, let me down!
Those belong to Jijilong!
Won’t somebody
show up already?
No, Greedy Lapoo!
You there, run!
Give me back my Gold Orb!
I’m sorry!
Hey!
Stop!
Sheesh!
I told you, no!
What a troublemaker...
Mimikins, you’re here?
I lost sight of them...
Our Z-Move is on the line here!
There’s no way we’re giving up!
You said it, meow!
There they are!
Mimikins!
Get back, Mimikins!
It’s too dangerous!
Mimikins!
Owww...
I’m so glad you’re all right.
Um... Are you worried about me?
I’m fine! Look!
Maybe the book was
wrong about you.
Say, Greedy Lapoo...
I really should go home.
I’m sure everyone’s worried about me.
What’s all this?
Greedy Lapoo...
Hey, what is it doing?
It looks like it likes that girl, meow.
It’s saying “I’ll give you anything you want,
so come with me!”.
Huh?! How full of yourself can you be?!
That thing makes me sick!
You’ve really collected
a lot of treasure, haven’t you...
No, I can’t accept it.
Because I can’t go with you.
My work at the library and
my storytime with the kids...
...are my most precious treasures.
Greedy Lapoo...
Hey! Stop!
All right!
Perfect shot, Mimikkyu!
Mimikkyu?
I got our Dark-Z back!
Just as planned!
We beat you real good,
right in front of the girl!
The girl you liked saw you
looking super lame!
So pathetic, meow!
Bye!
Acerola!
Are you all right?
Uncle Kuchinashi!
Here it comes!
It caught us off guard before,
but not this time, meow!
Taste my finely honed Chaotic Scr—
It vanished?
No, that’s not it...
Wait, it can’t have...?!
He’s been possessed?!
I had no idea it could do that!
Mimikkyu, do something!
Nyarth!
When did it...?
I won’t let Nyarth’s sacrifice
be in vain!
I will avenge h—
Impossible! Even Musashi?!
I have no choice...
Come out, Hidoide!
No, not me!
What do I do? If we fight all-out,
we’ll just end up hurting each other.
I have to drive that thing
out of Musashi.
Of course! Knock Off!
Dark-type moves are strong against Ghost types,
so it might drive Gänger out!
Hidoide, your move is
going to save Musashi!
All right! Use Knock Off, but gently!
Are you all right, Musashi?!
Ow... What’s going on?
My body feels all stiff, meow...
It’s so much angrier than
it was just a second ago, meow!
Of course it is.
That counterattack of yours hurt.
You’re that guy from before!
I heard what’s going on.
I thought you guys
were just pests...
...but I must say,
you’re pretty good.
So, you might as well
finish the job properly!
Is this a Z-Ring?!
Hidoide should be able to
use the Dark-Z, meow!
It’s all up to you, Kojiro!
Gotcha!
Let’s go, Hidoide!
The three of us will stand together,
even if all we can share is our drive!
This is our...
...first Z-Move!
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Romanticism”!
The “ke” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Keenness”!
Black Hole Eclipse
The little “c” in “Team Rocket” between the two stands for...
“‘Course, we’re villains!”
“Come on, come at us!”
“Clearly, Pikachu’s too strong, meow!”
“What an awful feeling!” we scream as we blast off,
and beneath us we see a little, tiny earth,
forests, mountains and Pokémon...
They all blend together!
So this thing was a troublemaker
that’d been long sealed away by the Island King?
You’re pretty mean, wanting to
get your hands on anything you see, meow...
Is it really just greedy?
It offered all the treasure
it had collected to me.
Maybe it’s just been
lonely all this time...
...and just wanted to feel
appreciated by someone?
Hey, Gänger,
will you be my friend?
I can’t go with you,
but if you come with me,
we can play anytime!
You weren’t greedy,
you were lonely!
You never cease to amaze me.
Huh? So everything’s fine now?
It’s friendship, meow!
What a great story!
Really?
Greedy Lapoo.
If you do anything bad again,
I’ll seal you up real good, got it?
So he says.
The Island King is really scary,
so be nice.
Hang on a second!
Island King?!
Yeah. Uncle Kuchinashi is
Ula'ula’s Island King.
Whaaat?!
So my cover’s blown...
What’s your deal?!
We came all this way on Sakaki’s orders
just to see you!
Sakaki?
Does that mean you’re
in Team Rocket?
We are.
Any problem with that?
We want a Z-Ring, meow!
Fine.
You can have the Z-Ring.
Really?!
Take it as thanks for
helping Acerola.
I’m her guardian, you see.
By the way,
that Mimikkyu is flying, isn’t it?
Yeah. Mimikins is an actual ghost.
Oh, so it’s a ghost, is it?
...Wait, what’s that mean?!
Oh? That’s a Mimikkyu-Z.
A special Z-Crystal
that only Mimikkyu can use.
It looks like Mimikins
wants your Mimikkyu to use it.
Mimikkyu’s Z-Crystal...
And the Z-Ring!
A double win,
and more than ever before...
What a great feeling!
And thus, Team Rocket obtained
a Z-Ring and a Mimikkyu-Z.
And onboard this ship
headed for Ula'ula Island,
we find Satoshi, Pikachu
and the team!
Let’s do this, you guys!
It’s finally time for
our third Grand Trial!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
This jerk was the one
who stole our Dark-Z!
What an extremely
bothersome Pokémon!
Hey, Musashi!
You forgot to give a profile!
Huh? Oh, right.
Then you take care of that.
What? H-Hey, Musashi!
The Shadow Pokémon Gänger
is a Ghost/Poison type. Over!
Now, let’s go home
to the secret base!
Yeah!
The wind’s too strong for us
to launch the balloon, meow...
Won’t Kiteruguma come?
Next episode
Oh! You’re playing
with the kendama again!
Junsa! I’m on break, you see!
Here, why don’t you try it, too?
It’s a nice way to relieve stress.
It is? All right,
I’ll take you up on that.
Nightingale!
Earth turn!
Whirlwind!
Cup to spike!
Airplane!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
This Nasty Old Guy is the Island King?!