Alola! V! V!
I will be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Babanom
Bibinom
Bubunom
Bebenom
The Ultra Beast who appears in
today’s episode is named...
Blue: Babanom
Red: Bibinom
Green: Bubunom
Yellow: Bebenom
Which is it? Get the answer
at the end of the episode!
What’s this? There’s something faintly glowing,
hovering above the seaside.
It could be a Pokémon.
Let’s move in a little closer.
Now! 100,000 Volts!
What’s wrong-roto?
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
The Lover of Light!
Twirling Bebenom!!
All these photos were taken by
the director of Ula'ula Island’s Hokulani Observatory,
who is my cousin!
I started looking at the stars when I was little,
after getting a telescope as a gift.
The stars in Alola are
as clear as can be!
They are absolutely
perfect for stargazing.
That’s right!
Big Mu told me people come to Hokulani Observatory
from all over the world to see the stars!
Oh, and when I say Big Mu,
I’m talking about my cousin here—
Speaking of which,
Māmane’s cousin, Mullein,
is a talented Pokémon Trainer, and my best friend!
An observatory, huh.
Sounds neat. I wanna go too!
I’m sure you’d like it!
Professor, let’s all go there sometime!
We could make it an extracurricular trip!
Sure!
Hey!
Māmane’s presentation isn’t done yet!
Please refrain from making comments!
We’re sorry...
Big Mu’s always saying that there’s gotta be
undiscovered Pokémon in outer space!
I sure hope I’ll get to meet
those Pokémon someday!
When you do, I hope you’ll let me
record them in my Index-roto.
I want to be the Pokémon Index
who records the first-ever data on a new species-roto!
Of course, Rotom!
Well, that concludes my presentation.
Thank you, Māmane.
That was a fine presentation!
W-Well... Yeah...
All right! It’s time for lunch!
I was so nervous,
it made me super hungry!
Well done.
Good job!
Thank you.
Looks delicious!
Wow! A Pikachu burger?
It’s so cute!
I’m sure Hoshi would be happy
if I made one for her.
Isn’t this...
Professor Burnet
made lunch for him today-roto.
Professor Burnet’s so feminine!
This is for the Pokémon.
Wake up, Mokuroh.
It’s time for lunch.
You, too... Nyaheat, Lugarugan!
Huh? Pikachu?
Pikachu!
Where are you-roto?
You must be so worried,
Togedemaru.
Pikachu never just
wanders off on his own...
Yeah...
Perhaps he’s gone somewhere
off the school grounds?
Mokuroh!
All right! I’m gonna go search
outside the school too!
Wait-roto!
Let’s keep looking.
Yes.
Welcome!
Welcomeow!
Have some delicious...
...Kiteruguma brand doughnuts!
The secret to their
deliciousness is honey!
They’re naturally sweet,
and good for your health, too!
Huh? What?!
Mimikkyu! Wood Hammer!
W-Was that...
who I think it was?
Probably.
Who else could it be, meow?
Here, one plain with honey.
Thank you.
Thank you very much!
What’s wrong, Mimikkyu?
The brat boy’s Pikachu,
that other one, and...
What’s that purple pointy-head?
Dunno...
Huh? Did it say something?
Hey, what’d it say?
I can’t understand it, meow.
What do you mean, you can’t understand?
It was talking, wasn’t it?
It was going “Bebebe”
or something like that.
Of course I heard it talk, meow.
But I can’t understand it, meow!
That thing isn’t listed in here either.
Which means it’s
a pretty rare Pokémon, huh?
Yeah.
It might even be an Ultra Beast,
the rarest of the rares, meow!
We’re gonna get it!
Yeah!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nyaheat
Type:   Fire
Tired, are we?
When asked
“Pika?” “Moroh?” “Bebe?”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Oh, dear... Did I really just introduce myself
to a bunch of Pokémon?
It just laughed at us, meow!
You can understand it now?!
Even I can tell
that we’re being laughed at.
You’re pretty rude
for one so cute!
Anyway, with all of you here...
Now’s our chance!
Roger!
Stop!
What?!
We didn’t plan for this, meow!
Is that...
Honcho...
I see... So you’ve evolved
into a Nyaheat, honcho!
Are you all right,
Pikachu, Mokuroh?
Who’s this?
Leave it to me-roto!
No data?
Well, of course.
It’s a super rare Pokémon!
Huh?
We’re gonna offer it up
to Sakaki, meow!
So yeah! We’re gonna catch
that purple pointy-head!
Counting on you, Hidoide!
For crying out loud...
Mimikkyu! Shadow Claw!
Pikachu, dodge it
and use Iron Tail!
Hidoide! Spike Cannon!
Lugarugan! Use Rock Throw!
Mimikkyu! Shadow Ball!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What even is this feeling?
All right, that should do it.
Mokuroh has made a full recovery from the poison.
Mokuroh has recovered 100%-roto.
Thank you, Lilie.
I am glad to have been of help.
Although I was quite surprised
when Mother contacted us.
It’s definitely a Pokémon
I’ve never seen before...
That’s right! Rotom said
it had no data on it either!
Here. Pikachu said that tickles.
It really seems to like the Z-Ring.
So it seems.
Sorry. This Z-Ring means a lot to me.
I got it from Kapu-Kokeko.
I can’t give it to you.
Mokuroh’s better now?
Glad to hear it!
Mother!
After analyzing the
photos and footage Rotom sent us...
we’ve concluded that
that really is an Ultra Beast.
We’ve also decided on a name;
Bebenom. The Poison Pin Pokémon.
Rotom, you take care of the update.
Do you mean that it’s an
undiscovered Pokémon-roto?!
Yes.
I’ll be the first to record data on
an undiscovered Pokémon-roto!
It’s a mission befitting of an Ultra Guardian, isn’t it?
We’re counting on you.
Ult-Roger-roto!
Bebenom! Poison Pin Pokémon! Poison type!
Ultra Beast registration complete-roto!
We’d like you to update the data on this Pokémon
through daily observations.
Please cooperate with Satoshi.
Of course, I’ll help out as well.
Does that mean...?
Until we can figure out where the Ultra Hole materialized, we want you to be Bebenom’s partner.
Ultra-get it, Satoshi!
Ult-Roger!
It will be living with Satoshi?
That’s wonderful!
Um... Where are the Ultra Balls?
Thanks, Pixie!
I want you to be my partner! Um...
That means you’ll live with me.
That we’ll be family.
Look. Me, Pikachu, Mokuroh,
Nyaheat, Lugarugan and you.
All right, here we go!
One more time!
D-Does this mean...
It doesn’t want to be caught?
Perhaps Bebenom
is simply playing?
It might not understand that
it’s supposed to go inside the ball.
Oh, that’s it!
Look carefully, Bebenom.
Return, Mokuroh!
Come out, Mokuroh!
Return! Come out!
Return!
Get it? You’re supposed to
go inside the ball.
All right!
Let’s do this, Bebenom!
Bebenom, I ultra-got you!
All right, you can come out now.
Bebenom, it’s nice to meet you.
Stop it!
Bebenom is quite a prankster!
Yeah! You know what I think?
That they look like one big family!
That’s fine, isn’t it?
I love big families.
It’s Pikachu!
That’s really good, Bebenom!
Do you like drawing?
Satoshi ultra-got Bebenom,
the mischievous Pokémon who likes Pikachu.
What sort of life
lies in store for them?
Their hearts race with anticipation...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
This one’s name was
Yellow: Bebenom!
Bebenom, whom Satoshi got,
is the Poison Pin Pokémon, a Poison type.
We don’t know where the Ultra Hole
Bebenom came from is,
so we thought we’d look after it with Satoshi
for the time being.
I’ll record Bebenom’s biology
as best I can-roto!
Next episode
Line up and say your numbers!
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
Um... Uh... Eight!
Too slow! You’ll never be
a full-fledged nurse like that!
Next exercise: Running!
Welcome to the Pokémon Center!
We’ll be taking care of your Pokémon!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Work Experience! A Day at the Pokémon Center!!
Next time
Work Experience!
A Day at the Pokémon Center!!
What sort of experience is this?!