Alola!
I, Joy, will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Larantes
Yareyutan
Dodekabashi
Kapu-Kokeko
Which Pokémon does Mao
meet in the forest today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode.
Class is in session at the Pokémon School.
What are they studying today?
Professor Kukui!
It’s almost time,
so I’ll be going home early.
Oh, of course!
Aina Cafeteria is going to
be on TV today, isn’t it?
What? Really?
Yeah! We’ll be on
“Local Famous Gourmet Restaurants Feature”!
Awesome!
I wanna be on TV, too!
Wait until classes are
done for the day, okay?
All right! In that case I’ll work extra hard
to end them faster!
The classes won’t get any shorter
just because you work extra hard-roto...
All right, guys, see you later!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
The Runaway Mao
and Yareyutan!
Hey Jun, are you sure having Dekagoose
keep watch alone was a good idea?
Dekagoose is guarding the outside.
I have to keep things under control on the inside,
to make sure the recording goes well.
You say that, but you actually
just want to be on TV, don’t you?
Really? Are you sure you’re not
talking about yourself?
Of course not!
I just came here to
promote the delicious food!
I’m home!
Welcome home!
Ms. Joy... Ms. Junsa...
Welcome!
Mao! Sorry to rush you,
but please help me out!
What a lovely apron!
It’s custom ordered! Since you’ll be on TV,
you gotta look your best!
Isn’t this great, Amamaiko?
Well first off, have a little snack!
Come on over, come on over!
Have some delicious Kiteruguma-brand
Honey Doughnuts, meow!
Nobody’s coming.
These are super good, though.
Hot hot hot hot hot!
But so delicious!
Coming up next:
“Local Famous Gourmet Restaurants Feature”.
Over to our drive-by reporter, Ana!
Hi there! I’m the ever-cheerful
idol reporter, Ana!
Time to fill your stomach!
And with that, we’ll be introducing
another great restaurant today!
“Great restaurant.”
Yeah, right!
Oh! There’s a really
great-looking place right over there!
Alola!
This must be the rumored
gourmet restaurant.
What’s this? I’m on TV?
Oh my gosh!
Alola!
Alola from me, too!
Film me, too, meow!
Um...
Yahoo! Everybody watching?
Ana, that’s wrong!
Please calm down!
It’s obviously not this cheap place!
It’s over there!
What?! Really?! I’m so sorry!
Wow! They all look delicious!
What an adorable little waitress!
Right?
Please have some of
our pride and joy, Pile Juice!
Don’t mind if I do!
Delicious!
Of course! Aina Cafeteria is
all about flavor!
I particularly recommend our stew! Would you like to give it a try?
Sounds great!
Mao, another stew, please!
All right!
Right... Right... Right...
Mao! Some gratin, please!
And a pilaf!
Understood!
What about your work, Jun?
Mostly done for the day,
so I’m taking a break.
Um, stew, gratin, pilaf,
and sweet rolls...
Please,
order as much as you want!
Geez, won’t Dad
come over here soon?
Are you all right?!
You’re not hurt, are you?
I’ll clean this up,
so could you get me a dustpan?
Oh no!
It’s ruined...
Mao!
Oh, Dad! Please, help—
Ms. Ana said she wanted
to try the gratin, too!
Make it quick!
The sweet rolls look good, too!
Mao, add some sweet rolls
to her order!
Excuse me!
One Pile Juice, please!
A Pile Juice for me, too!
All right! Two Pile Juices!
Mao?
I’ve had enough.
Mao!
Sir, may we have
a comment from you?
Oh, of course!
Amamaiko truly is your cafeteria’s
poster idol, isn’t she?
Eh? Uh, yeah, I guess...
Idol, huh...?
If only we had an idol.
Isn’t that...
What?
The green brat girl, meow!
And now Amamaiko, meow!
Amamaiko?
The poster idol?
We’re closing up for the day!
What we need is an idol.
We’ll get that one,
and rake in the cash!
Why only me?
Pocket Monsters!
Junsa &...
...Joy!
I choose you!
Name: Yareyutan
Type:   Normal/Psychic
Yeah, thanks to my hard work,
the class ended sooner!
Time to be on TV!
Huh?
Hey, don’t tell me...
Thank you very much!
Looks like it’s already over.
Shock!
Alola!
Oh, it’s you... Welcome.
Good timing. Did you see Mao?
The last time we saw her was
when she left school.
Oh... How troubling.
Did something happen to her?
Oh, it’s just...
It seems I made her angry,
so she just ran off.
She ran away-roto?!
Amamaiko left with her, too.
I was just about to go
looking for them.
Do you have any idea
where they might be?
Mao might have gone to the forest.
I agree.
She often goes there
to look for ingredients.
All right! Let’s go look!
Where am I?
I came to the forest,
then I tripped and...
What’s this?
Who’s there?!
A Pokémon?
Yareyutan?
That’s your name?
Were you the one who...
What?
For me?
It’s delicious!
This Pile Juice tastes
like the one Dad makes.
Mao! Where are you?
Please answer!
Mao!
Amamaiko!
Please come out!
They might have gone further in.
But it’s already getting dark.
If we just blindly look for them,
we’ll get lost ourselves.
That’s a good point.
Then maybe we should
consult my master.
“Master”?
Some sort of forest expert?
Yeah.
Someone who knows the forest
better than anyone.
And then Dad got so excited
about appearing on TV,
and pushed all the work
off on me!
Yare Yare...
Good grief...
What’s more, he leaves all
the cleaning and laundry in the house to me,
and doesn’t help with anything
aside from the cafeteria!
I did tell him...
but when Dad tries to clean,
he just makes things messier,
and the laundry just
ends up all wrinkly,
and he’s bad at folding it, too.
It’s not like I have a problem with
doing the cleaning, laundry and cooking, but...
Thank you.
But really...
I wish he’d praise me.
“Well done. Thank you.”
Just every now and then,
you know?
Amamaiko?
Got the idol...
Amamaiko!
There you are,
green brat girl!
What are you doing?!
When asked “What are you doing?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket!
Give back my Amamaiko!
What are you talking about?
We went to great lengths to get this idol!
If you want it back, why not try to
beat us in battle and take it back?!
Huh? You don’t have any
other Pokémon?
I guess that means
we win by default!
What? What?!
What a creepy thing.
Yareyutan!
Yareyutan? Oh, here it is.
Sage Pokémon.
Normal/Psychic type.
Known for its extreme intelligence,
this Pokémon will look down on inexperienced trainers...?
W-We’re being looked down on, meow.
Yareyutan, you’ll fight for me?
Whatever-yutan?
If you don’t wanna get hurt,
then back off!
Yeah, yeah!
Hidoide, get it!
No, you’ve got it all wrong!
Was that Mindpower?
Hidoide, use Spike Cannon!
W-What?!
Ow ow ow ow!
No! Absolutely not! Stop that!
Well? We win.
Now give Amamaiko back!
As if!
Try using Mindpower or whatever again,
and you’ll pay dearly!
That’s low!
Thank you!
“Low” is a compliment to us!
Nyarth, take them out
while we have the chance!
The secret killing technique of these claws,
which I have polished each and every day...
Have a good taste of it, meow!
Chaotic Scratches!
Why?!
Amamaiko!
Hey, what are you doing?!
It got away!
It’s not my fault, meow!
My body moved on its own, meow!
Wasn’t that the move Instruct?
Apparently it instructs the target Pokémon to repeat
whatever move they last used.
Now it’s our turn!
Round-Trip Slap!
You’re too soft, meow!
What?! That’s low!
That’s my line!
Let’s do it, Amamaiko!
Kiteruguma?!
This has gotta be the first time I’ve ever felt like
I can actually count on Kiteruguma!
Now, use your freakish strength
to beat Yareyutan!
Hang in there, Yareyutan!
That’s honey, right?
Is that... Pile Juice?
Hey...
What even is this feeling?
Thank you, Yareyutan.
I’m sorry, Amamaiko.
But how did you know
where I was?
I see!
Owww...
Dad! Everybody!
Mao?
Mao, we looked all over for you!
Sorry I made you worry!
A Pokémon?
It’s Yareyutan-roto!
Mao! I’m so glad you were here.
Mao?
I’m sorry. Please cheer up.
Your knee...
Yareyutan treated it for me.
Oh, you did, Master?
Your “Master” was Yareyutan-roto?!
Long ago, when I’d only just
opened Aina Cafeteria,
I was having trouble
working out the menu.
I didn’t pay attention,
and ended up getting lost.
Master looked after me
when I was injured,
and listened to my worries.
What’s more, the Pile Juice he served me
was absolutely delicious!
I realized that this was what
my menu had been missing,
and ever since,
Yareyutan has been my master.
Then, rumors about my master
spread throughout the city,
causing the islanders to come here,
hoping to soothe their spirits.
And together, we made the place
what it is now.
I keep getting helped out by you,
Master.
Thank—
Oh, of course.
Mao.
What?
Thank you.
You’re always doing such a great job
with the cleaning, the laundry and the food.
Thank you so much.
I’m so sorry!
It’s all right.
Heartfelt expressions of
“I’m sorry” and “Thank you”...
Be sure to say them too, everyone!
So my Dekagoose totally thinks it’s a gumshoe...
I mean, a detective!
Well, know what my Cuwawa did?
It just went and picked the flowers in my garden
that I’d been growing so carefully!
Without permission?!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was Yareyutan!
The Sage Pokémon Yareyutan
is a Normal/Psychic type.
It’s a very intelligent Pokémon
who can even use human tools adeptly.
The fan-like object it holds in its hand
is made by weaving leaves together using its own fur.
Thanks for the drink!
Master, see you later!
I feel so much better!
Me, too!
I got to vent my frustrations,
so tomorrow,
I can do my best again!
My mood’s done a Yu-turn!
Next episode
Thank you for coming
to Melemele Aquarium today!
The wait is over!
Our resident idols Ashimari and
Oshamari’s striking show begins!
People on the front row,
beware of splashing water!
Well then, it’s showtime!
Suiren, are you really doing this?!
Just kidding!
Oh, Suiren, come on!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Ashimari, Oshamari and the An-chor-y Dadarin!