Alola!
I, Kaki, will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Yatoumori
Alolan Garagara
Guardie
Boobur
Which of these Pokémon
does Bakugames fight today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi and his friends are taking extracurricular classes
on Akala Island, home of Wela Volcano.
What kind of class will they have today?
There’s so many people and Pokémon!
They’re really lively-roto!
The Wela Fire Festival...
...is a traditional festival
dating back over a hundred years.
Enjoy this festival to its fullest,
and learn about Akala’s history and culture.
That’s today’s assignment.
Everybody, this way.
Kaki’s really into this.
Apparently he comes here every year.
Satoshi, don’t you want to
make Nyabby even stronger?
Make Nyabby stronger?
Yeah, I do!
Then this festival
will be perfect for you!
Everybody, today is the long-awaited
Wela Fire Festival day!
Oh, Ms. Lychee!
Let’s turn up the heat today to show our gratitude
to Wela Volcano, the nurturer of Akala Island!
Yeah!
This is pretty awesome!
Wela! Wela! Wela!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
A Fire Battle!
Garagara Appears!!
So Ms. Lychee was doing her job
as Island Queen today.
She’s so cool!
What’s that she put on its head?
A cluster of rocks-roto!
That’s the Crown of Wela.
It’s said that when you put a lava crown
on a Pokémon’s head...
...that Pokémon will become as
noble and strong as Wela Volcano itself.
They say it’s super effective on
Fire Pokémon in particular.
I read about this in a book.
In recent years, talk of the festival has spread to other regions,
and trainers from all over come here to partake.
I thought this would be perfect
for your Nyabby.
Awesome!
Nyabby, we gotta have you
wear that Crown!
It’ll make you stronger!
Of course, you gotta
wear it too, Pikachu.
Let’s all go!
Well, since we’re here...
Yes!
Wait!
Have you had Bakugames
wear the Crown?
Yeah, last year.
Your grandfather was
the Island King, right?
Did he put that Crown on
people’s Pokémon?
Yeah.
Back when I was younger,
it was my dream...
...to have Grandfather put the Crown
on my own Pokémon.
I see.
I’m sure your grandfather is happy that
you’re coming to the festival with your own Pokémon!
Yes.
All right, I’m up next!
So you’ve come, Satoshi.
Yeah!
Thank you for this, Lychee.
This way.
Nyabby, here you go.
May Wela Volcano protect you.
What?
What’s that thing?
Leave it to me-roto!
Here’s its data-roto.
Garagara: Alolan Form.
Fire/Ghost type.
The bone in its hand is extremely precious to it,
and it can also make it its greatest weapon...
...by lighting it on fire
and attacking with it.
An Alolan Garagara, huh?
Hey, give that back.
That doesn’t belong to you!
Give it back!
Hold it!
Why, you...
Cut it-
That little...!
It’s kinda obnoxious.
Either way, we must catch it!
Stop, Garagara!
Calm down!
Hey!
Stop right there, Garagara!
Ms. Lychee, first we need to
calm everybody down!
But...
I’ll get it back!
Bakugames, come with me!
Oh, wait, Kaki!
Pikachu! Nyabby! Let’s go!
Be careful!
Go, Kuitaran!
Wait, Garagara!
Satoshi! This way!
Which way?
Odds that it went right: 50%.
Odds that it went left: 50%-roto!
So where do I go?
What’s wrong?
Hang in there, Boobur!
Are you all right?!
Oh, hi there! Are you planning to
chase after Garagara as well?
I wouldn’t recommend-
Oh, hi there! Are you planning to
chase after Garagara as well?
Where did it go?!
I wouldn’t recommend-
Oh, hi there! Are you planning to
chase after Garagara as well?
I wouldn’t recommend-
Where did it go?!
Garagara went that way!
What was that?
Give the Crown back quietly!
You mean you wanna battle me?
Fine!
I’ll win and take it back!
Flamethrower!
Dragon Tail!
What?!
Bakugames!
We’ll finish this right now!
Let’s go!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Bakugames!
Are you all right, Bakugames?!
Where are you, Garagara?!
Oh no-roto!
Kaki! Bakugames!
I can’t believe
Kaki and Bakugames lost.
We couldn’t get
the Crown of Wela back.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Garagara
..                     (Alolan Form)
Type:   Fire/Ghost
I see Bakugames is doing better.
Yeah.
He’s 100% recovered-roto.
I’m sorry, Bakugames.
I was in such a rush
to get the Crown back...
...that I didn’t pay attention
to the opponent.
I failed to read Garagara’s actions...
...figuring I’d win
if I just used the Z-Move.
Grandfather told me that battles are about
watching and understanding your opponent, yet I...
I wanted to become...
...a truly strong trainer like Grandfather, who could
understand the hearts of Pokémon and protect everyone.
When you became my partner,
and got to wear the Crown of Wela...
I felt as if I’d gotten stronger.
But I wasn’t good enough.
Even if I have you wear the Crown...
Even if we can use Z-Moves...
I can’t be satisfied with just that.
I need to strive to be stronger and hotter,
just like Wela Volcano.
I have to keep on burning.
Like Wela Volcano, huh?
That’s a huge goal.
It’s a goal I’m not sure
I can even accomplish.
That’s fine! You gotta dream big!
Let’s chase our dreams together!
I’ll run full speed towards
becoming a Pokémon Master!
You run too much-roto.
You’re right...
I’d hate to stay the loser forever.
I’ll defeat that Garagara
and get the Crown back!
Now we’re talking!
Then let’s do some training!
Yeah!
Hang in there, both of you-roto!
Let’s go, Kaki!
Yeah!
Bakugames!
Let’s find a way to beat that Garagara!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Bakugames, get in position!
Watch out for
the spikes on his shell!
He avoided the Trap Shell-roto!
You’re good!
Run, Pikachu!
You just have to avoid the spikes.
Now! Iron Tail!
Electric Ball!
Flamethrower!
Pikachu, run again!
Iron Tail!
Hang in there, Bakugames!
Outspeeding will be difficult.
This is what lost us
the battle with Garagara, too.
You can’t win just by guarding!
Let’s go! Use 100,000 Volts!
Bakugames!
He’s right. We can only
tank attacks for so long.
But then, what do we...
Bakugames?
Normally he takes a firm,
unmoving stance...
...but on the inside,
he’s burning bright...
I got it!
Show me...
...the Wela Volcano inside you!
Boobur!
Ms. Joy, please help Boobur!
Yes, it’ll be all right.
Hang in there, Boobur!
So the Crown is still...
Yes.
Garagara beat him,
just like it did those guys.
I wonder why that Garagara
took the Crown.
So do I.
It must have had a reason.
But the Crown of Wela is
an important treasure to Akala Island.
I can’t leave the matter be.
Will you go after Garagara?
It’s my duty as Island Queen.
I’ll be back.
Wait!
Ms. Lychee, I have a request.
Kaki?
Please let me go take the Crown
back from Garagara!
Can you do it?
I can!
Then, I’ll leave it to you!
Thank you very much!
What? Really?
Kaki seems different from yesterday.
Yeah. He and Bakugames
both have a good look in their eyes.
It’s because they trained!
This time, the two of you
can do it! Right?
Yeah!
There it is!
Garagara! Fight us again!
Dragon Tail!
It’s like it’s toying
with Bakugames!
He can’t attack if this goes on!
If only he could
keep up with Garagara somehow...
But how...?
Flamethrower!
Are you all right?
This is a pretty hot battle...
literally!
Garagara’s...
Bakugames, behind you!
Good!
They’re gonna blow it away
with Trap Shell!
It dodged it!
Amazing!
We can still do it!
Now, Bakugames!
Shell Smash!
A move that makes one more vulnerable to damage,
but raises both speed and attack power-roto!
That’s such a risky move!
Yeah! But it’s the only way
to win against Garagara!
Bakugames!
He has no strength left-roto!
It can’t be!
You can still go on, right?!
Dragon Tail!
Let’s do it, Bakugames.
My full body...
...soul...
...and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Kaki!
You did it!
Incredible!
You did well, Bakugames.
You wanted to become even stronger
by putting on this Crown, right?
It did?
I figured it out by battling it.
It’s got a burning heart,
just like us.
What? Really?
I can understand that feeling.
You can understand each other
through battle!
It reveals your heart.
Garagara must have returned the Crown
because they understood each other.
You mean that you want to...
All right!
Got it!
Come out!
Glad to have you with me.
Is it saying “I’ll win next time”?
It really hates losing, huh?
What are you doing?
Be careful.
The Crown of Wela has
returned to us in one piece!
Let’s start the festival over!
Yeah!
Here.
Now it’s your turn.
May Wela Volcano
protect you too, Garagara.
From now on, let’s keep growing stronger
together with Garagara, Bakugames.
I will take a picture to
commemorate the occasion-roto!
Say cheese!
Kaki has caught Garagara,
a Pokémon who burns as hot as Wela Volcano itself.
With more friends, things are sure
to get even more lively.
The extracurricular lessons
on Akala Island will go on!
See you!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Sorry I kept you waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem...
...was this one! Garagara!
The Bone Keeper Pokémon Garagara’s Alolan form
is a Fire/Ghost type.
It rubs its bone against its forehead,
building up friction to light it like a match...
What an interesting Pokémon!
Still, that Garagara really hates to lose.
Cut it out already!
Next episode
Satoshi, will you take on my Trial?
Mao’s Trial?
To make the most delicious curry!
First, you must gather
the necessary ingredients.
A Mago Berry.
A Revival Herb. A Miracle Seed.
A Matoma Berry. A Big Root!
A Zuri Berry! Delicious Water!
I’ll be in charge of eating it!
He who does not work,
neither shall he eat.
Huh?!
Going without food would be a Grand Trial!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
An Elegant Curry Battle! Larantes’s Dance!!