Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s
PokéProblem, meow!
Alola Limited Edition Ice Cream
Pudding à la Mode
Lum Berry Juice
Fluffy Shaved Ice
What do I have hidden
in the refrigerator today, meow?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode, meow!
Do you all remember...
...the creatures that were on the boat
Satoshi and his friends rode home from Poni Island?
Yes...
Such strange, strange creatures...
What could they be doing now?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Landfall in Alola!
Melty Metal Panic!!
Man, I love how cheap
that store is!
It really is a Happy Island for
us poor folk, meow!
Just look at these bolts!
Wouldn’t think they’re junk parts,
would you?
What are you doing, meow?!
Stop complaining
and help pick them up!
Guess I gotta, meow...
Ta-daah!
Found it!
I can’t believe Nyarth was trying to eat this behind our backs,
yet he hid it in such an obvious spot!
He’s as soft as these sweets!
We’re back, meow!
Were you doing
something, meow?
Not really?
This is very suspicious, meow.
Nyarth! Never mind that,
help me with this!
Did I really buy this many?
It’s gone!
My Limited Edition Ohana Town
Special Pudding à la Mode is gone, meow!
Musashi!
Why are you looking at me?!
Besides, you were the one
hiding it to eat it behind our backs!
What?! Is that true?!
There it is, meow!
Give it back, meow!
Oh, come on! Gimme half!
Share some with me, too!
Today’s class will be on building
electric appliances.
We’ll be building the Pokémon training machine
Māmane designed, together!
All the tools we need are here!
Whoa... Looks fun!
How professional-roto!
I’m getting fired up!
I haven’t really built anything before.
Can I do this?
Of course you can!
You’ve got me with you!
Māmane’s shining today!
Listen up! First, you have to take apart
the pre-built model.
You need to understand
how it’s made!
Yes!
Satoshi, hand me
the ring spanner.
Okay.
Um...
Which one’s the ring spanner?
This?
That’s a wrench.
Okay, this, then!
That’s an adjustable wrench!
It’s gotta be this!
Correct!
Suiren, you’re amazing!
All right, then, Lilie,
can you get me some nuts?
Certainly!
Um...
This?
Yup!
But I don’t remember using
any nuts that big...
Really?
Something’s attached to it.
Yeah, what is this?
It’s squishy.
Let me touch...
Me, too!
It’s true!
It feels kinda nice.
What’s this ball?
What material is this?
It’s heavy!
Amazing!
Was that Luster Cannon?!
You mean it’s a Pokémon?!
I’ll check its data-roto!
No data! No data!
I’ve never seen this one,
either.
Could it be an undiscovered
Pokémon species?!
If so, it’s a huge discovery-roto!
Hey, look at this!
There’s loads more over here!
You’re right!
Where’d they come from?!
Sandy, no!
Watch out!
Pikachu! Electric Net!
Thank you, Satoshi, Pikachu.
I have to record its traits-roto!
So it’ll attack if provoked...
Be careful, everyone.
You can leave this to me! Working on the farm
has trained me in dealing with wild Pokémon!
Oh, aren’t you a little cutie?
There, there...
Nice Pokémon...
It’s electrifying!
It can use Electric moves, too?
This is a new discovery!
Right? And it’s all
thanks to me, you know!
The tips on
the screwdrivers are gone!
All the nuts and screws
I brought are gone, too!
Maybe these Pokémon
ate them, or something?
It eats metal?!
You think it could be a Steel type?
Where did you come from?
Will you eat this?
They’re eating it!
Could that red cable they’re
wagging in the air be a tail?
If it is,
that means they’re happy!
That black ball in their nuts...
Think it’s an eye?
Let me see!
The ball’s floating! Why?
Magnetism?
Oh, right! There’s an electromagnet
on the machine’s motor!
Switch on!
It really is a Steel type.
They seem happy!
What’s happening?
This is a welcome dance!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Meltan
Type:   Steel
Snack time!
It doesn’t even feel like
I ate anything, meow...
That’s why you and I should’ve
just taken half each!
Having it all to yourself
is what makes it good, meow!
Now, now, don’t fight!
Anyway, did you get the parts?
Yeah, I got some great ones
at a low price!
Look at all of this!
What?!
They’re gone! Gone! Gone!
All the parts I bought are gone!
That’s impossible!
You probably just
dropped them somewhere!
No, I didn’t!
I know they were here!
Huh?!
What?
Who did this?!
A Pokémon?
That’s who, meow!
Sheesh...
Here we go...
What?
My precious crown collection!
Here it is!
My beloved crown
is half melted!
Why?!
This must be
the intruder’s doing, too, meow.
Sheesh... Where is it hiding?
Who did this?!
It makes no sense!
Why is it melted?!
Are you here, you little...?!
This is awful, meow...
The entire machinery has melted, meow.
And that means...
This is a nut, isn’t it?
Is this one of
the parts you bought?
No, it’s not.
Hey! Were you the ones who melted
our machinery and my crowns?!
Say something!
Hold it, meow!
Where did they go?
If that really was an undiscovered Pokémon species,
then I have to record it in my Index-roto!
All right!
Let’s split up and search!
Yes!
Hold it!
Get back here, meow!
You!
I will avenge my crowns!
And I will avenge
our machinery, meow!
What are they saying?
It’s all nonsense like
“Will you eat this?” and “Good Pokémon!”, meow.
You know, if we sell these as some new Pokémon species,
we’ll make a killing, don’t you think?
Well, whatever the case...
It’s time to make them
feel some pain!
Hidoide!
Not me! Them! Over there!
Mimikkyu, use Shadow Ball!
Tiny!
That Shadow Ball is tiny!
Mimikkyu doesn’t have the drive to fight
if it’s not against Pikachu, meow.
Hidoide!
Use Spike Cannon!
We’ll catch every last one
of you, meow!
Toss!
Here comes another, meow...
Kiteruguma!
Hah! How’d you like that?!
Try again never!
But now we’ve lost our ticket
out of our life of poverty, meow!
After them, meow!
What even is this feeling?
All the way up there?!
You’re right!
Resuming recording-roto!
What are they doing here?
You can’t eat this bell!
Hey, what are they doing?
Resonating?
Another new discovery!
How strange. Won’t that
make them dizzy?
What are they trying
to accomplish?
They’re gone...
But you got
quite a bit of data, didn’t you?
Loads-roto!
Mokuroh, sorry I’m late!
Let’s go home!
I’m home!
Professor Okido!
Oh, Satoshi!
Why are you so excited?
I think we may have found
something amazing!
Rotom’s gonna send you
the data right now!
What is this?!
It’s a new Pokémon
species, isn’t it?!
I see... It likes eating metal...
It sticks to magnets,
wags its cable tail when it’s happy...
It freezes up when surprised,
and will sometimes spin its head to generate sound...
It attacks from the ball in its head,
and can use Electric moves, as well...
Could potentially be a Steel type...
I’m impressed that you managed
to gather so much data!
Heh-roto!
Yes, this might just be
the discovery of the century!
I’ll get right to work on
analyzing the data you sent me!
All right!
Roto!
Please do!
Oh? One of the mysterious
Pokémon tagged along.
And here, too...
There are so many of them...
What to do?
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting, meow!
I had Pudding à la Mode
hidden in the refrigerator, meow!
What were those things that
broke into our secret base, meow?
They melt metal,
they fire beams...
We’ll be sure to catch them
the next time we see them, meow!
Everything’s... almost...
back to normal... meow...
I’m so sorry, my crown...
Come on, you help out, too.
Forget that bottle cap.
It’s not a “bottle cap”!
Really...
Next episode
I’ve made a new type
of doughnuts!
Its name is
Mitsuhoney Doughnuts!
How is that any different
from Honey Doughnuts?
Well, you see, you put three of them together
in the shape of a Mitsuhoney!
You’re right!
This’ll sell like crazy!
Yeah! The Alolan doughnut industry
belongs to Team Rocket!
Aim for national distribution!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
New Species Discovered! I Got Meltan!!
Next time
New Species Discovered!
I Got Meltan!!