Alola!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Diancie
Volcanion
Magearna
Hoopa
Which of these is the Pokémon
I encounter today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
That should do it...
Breakfast’s ready!
Oh? It seems everyone at Satoshi’s home
is starting the day as energetically as ever.
But Mokuroh and Meltan
are nowhere to be seen...
Hey! It’s time for breakfast!
Breakfast!
Alola!
Hey, do you know where Meltan is?
Meltan! No eating this!
Your breakfast’s over there.
Oh! An Explosion of smiles, I see!
Um, listen, Meltan just
went for the frying pan...
It ate another one?!
Burnet’s gonna be so disappointed when she hears...
This is the fourth one-roto...
Don’t worry!
We saved it just in time!
Don’t scare me like that!
Speaking of,
where is Professor Burnet?
She’s at Aether Paradise.
Ms. Lusamine had a request for her.
Be careful with that!
And that!
Young Master Gladio,
please treat my documents with a bit more care!
Are the documents from Dad’s
experiments really here?
Absolutely!
After the accident, I carried all of
Professor Mohn’s documents down here.
The President attempted to have
all of his research sealed off!
Why would she?!
Mom tried to seal off all his data on Ultra Holes?
I can’t believe that!
It was understandable. The shock and sadness
from the professor’s death made her—
Father is alive!
Dad is alive!
O-Of course!
You cannot imagine my joy
when I heard...
I need a tissue...
Isn’t this...
Oh, how nostalgic!
Father...
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Lilie and the Secret
Mechanical Princess!
Professor Mohn was
an outstanding scientist.
With his exceptional talent
and leadership,
he led our research team.
Dear!
Mohn...
Where are you now?
Come in.
Excuse us...
We’ve had the Aether Foundation branches in each region
look into missing person cases...
And what were the results?
Unfortunately, we’ve received
no helpful information as of yet.
I see...
The search has only just started.
I suppose so.
What about you? Did you find
Professor Mohn’s research documents?
Sauboh is looking for them for me.
Gladio and Lilie are helping him, too.
The two of them are eager to find them.
Of course they are.
Mom!
Dad is alive! He’s still alive!
Hāpu'u... The Island Queen
on Poni Island told me...
...that the reason we didn’t meet him
inside Kapu-Rehire’s mist...
...was because he’s still alive!
I’d never seen Gladio that happy before.
That was when I realized
how wrong I had been.
What do you mean?
Ever since that accident,
I never told Gladio or Lilie
anything about Mohn.
It never even occurred to me just
how dearly they longed for their father.
Mother.
Come with me.
There’s something I want to show you.
We’ll handle this. Right?
Indeed.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
What is this?
Mohn’s...
Your father’s room.
It was this room...
Mohn was very passionate...
As researcher, father
and husband alike.
He was an admirable man.
He was also quite the dreamer...
The kind of person who’d believe in fairy tales.
Gladio. Lilie.
I’ll entrust you with this room,
until he comes back.
Us?
That is a splendid idea, Madame.
Thank you.
Big Brother!
A Z-Ring!
I was told he received it from
the Island King, Mr. Hala...
...back when he moved to the Alola Region
to work on his Ultra Hole research.
Dad?
The master was an incredibly gifted
Pokémon Trainer, as well.
Mother, where is
Father’s Pokémon now?
Well, it disappeared
after the accident.
If only I’d taken better care of it...
You had just gone through
a terrible shock at the time.
It is not your fault.
But it had gone through
a shock, too.
Its partner had just vanished
without warning, after all.
And yet, I was so caught up
in my own sadness...
...that it clouded my judgment.
If I’d paid better attention,
it might not have taken me so long to realize
that Mohn might still be alive.
Mother.
I was still but a baby,
so I don’t remember anything
about Father or the accident...
But now I understand how you felt!
Please, don’t blame yourself so harshly.
Thank you...
You two really saved me back then...
My little troublemaker, Gladio...
...and my cute little baby.
I’m not a baby anymore!
Geez! Why do children
have to grow up?
Lilie, I think you should keep this
until we find Dad.
Me?!
Oh, that’s a great idea!
You should consult
the Island King.
V-Very well...
Snowball,
I might be getting a Z-Ring.
What do you think?
Oh, she seems to be
quite excited at the prospect!
What a relief! I will go speak with Mr. Hala
as soon as possible tomorrow.
What seems to be the matter?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Magearna
Type:   Steel/Fairy
Why, if it isn’t the Magearna that
the master had been looking after!
Magearna?
Indeed.
She is an artificial Pokémon created long ago
by the scientists in a foreign land,
according to the master.
Artificial Pokémon?
When Mohn first met this one
on his travels,
it was rusting in the corner
of an antique shop.
Hey, Lilie...
Why did you open this door
all of a sudden?
Hmm... I’m not quite sure...
Supposedly, Magearna was created
to look after the princess of that kingdom.
So apparently, when Mohn
first met her, he thought...
...that this was fate.
Fate?
Since we’d just gotten
our own little princess, too.
Mohn tried his best
to get Magearna to move,
but it didn’t work.
So he had to give up on this
present for his little princess.
A present to me...
...from Father...
So this is your dad’s Z-Ring?
Awesome-roto!
I hope you’ll find your dad soon!
Thank you!
Lilie is going to see Mr. Hala
about that Z-Ring today.
Why?
I wish to request that he let me
use this Z-Ring until we find Father.
That’s a great idea!
I don’t know if I’m really
qualified to do so, but...
I’ll come with you to cheer you on!
Me, too!
And me!
I’m coming, too, of course!
Count me in, too!
Well, then,
let’s all go right now!
This is plenty cause for
an extracurricular lesson!
I remember the day I gave
this Z-Ring to Mohn very well.
He gave calm, precise orders...
But when push came to shove,
he provided a most passionate battle.
I would very much like to battle him!
If he makes it back,
we will hold a feast in his honor here.
Please do!
Now, Lilie...
Hit Mr. Hala with your wish,
like an Aurora Beam!
Yes, sir!
U-Um...
Hang in there!
We’re here for you!
Relax, relax!
Be yourself!
You can realLilie do it!
Mr. Island King, Sir... Yesterday, I was shown
my father’s room for the first time.
I do not remember him,
but yesterday,
I could feel his love for me.
I felt elated.
And so, I thought...
I wish to find my father,
whatever it takes!
In order to accomplish that,
I wish to become stronger!
I’m certain that Snowball
understands my feelings.
Before my father returns,
I wish to grow stronger
with his Z-Ring!
And with this Ice-Z, I wish to
master a Z-Move alongside Snowball!
What must I do to
receive your blessing?
Your feelings have
touched my heart.
This is what we will do...
You will attempt to unleash the Z-Move,
Raging Geofreeze, before my eyes.
Already?!
Very well! I will try!
Let us do our best, Snowball!
That’s the spirit, Snowball!
Be quiet! Lilie can’t focus!
Sorry...
Are you prepared?
I am!
Snow silently fluttering down
from the heavens...
Countless glimmering crystals of ice...
O, freezing Z that covers the land...
Along with my heated soul,
return now once more to the heavens!
Raging Geofreeze!
So close...
She almost had it...
Don’t worry, Lilie!
If you just train and become stronger,
I’m sure you’ll be able to pull off a Z-Move!
Satoshi’s right.
The Alola League’s drawing near, too,
so we’ll all train every day!
I’ll do my best, too! Seeing you
made me want to use a Z-Move myself!
You managed to make Z-Power manifest!
That’s amazing in itself!
Right, Xiemi?
Everyone...
No, Snowball... It wasn’t your fault
that the Z-Move failed.
I simply wasn’t strong enough!
It’s true!
So, I will do my best!
I will become stronger, so...
Please bear with me, Snowball.
You almost had it.
But, young Lilie... I most certainly did see your Z-Move,
incomplete though it may have been.
I will give you special permission
to wield that Z-Ring.
I suppose you may call it
a provisional license.
Thank you so much, Island King!
I promise I will master
the use of my father’s Z-Ring!
All right!
I’m so happy for you, Lilie!
The Island King is so generous!
The Z-Ring must have chosen Lilie.
You do have some pretty great lines
now and again, Satoshi.
When your training bears fruit,
and you’ve mastered your Z-Move,
come seek me out again.
Yes, sir!
Magearna... I’ve been granted permission
to use Father’s Z-Ring!
I will do my best so that
Snowball and I can become stronger!
And, Magearna...
I wish to become friends with you.
The wish Father had for me...
I wish to make it reality,
on my own.
If all goes well, when I reunite with Father,
you will be there beside me...
Is something the matter?
What is this?
Father...
I thought you’d be here.
Mother... Big Brother...
What did the Island King say?
He gave me permission.
Though it’s only temporary,
for now...
I see!
Train hard.
Yes! I wish to master the Z-Move
as quickly as I can!
What is that?
I just found it in here.
It appears to be Father’s research notes
regarding Magearna.
He wrote in it daily, at great length...
You might call it a Magearna journal...
I never knew he had that...
Mother.
Please let me take care
of Magearna!
Perhaps it will never move,
no matter what I do...
Even so, I wish to make it move,
if at all possible.
Just like Father wanted!
All right.
You really have become strong.
Have I really...
“Today, I stopped by
a small antique shop,
“and for a moment,
I doubted my own eyes.”
A Magearna was lying there
in a corner of the shop.
It was covered in rust,
but I could tell it was a Magearna.
It’s said that Magearna was created...
...over five hundred years ago,
by the genius scientists in a distant land.
Just then, Lilie’s cute smile
came to mind.
I thought this must be fate.
I will give Magearna to Lilie
as a present...
To my little princess...
Father...
Through Professor Mohn’s Z-Ring
and her meeting with Magearna,
Lilie is starting to feel
a strong bond with her father.
And now...
Lilie’s new dream has
been put into motion.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you very much for waiting!
The Pokémon I encountered
was Magearna!
It seems the Artificial Pokémon Magearna,
which was created hundreds of years ago,
is a Steel/Fairy type.
Magearna, I should very much like
to talk with you someday.
I do believe the first part is fine...
But after the “Freezing Z that
covers the lands” part...
I may have been mistaken to
follow it up with “My heated soul”.
Ice isn’t hot, after all!
Young Lady, I do not believe
the wording is the problem...
I will try my best to
make it work next time!
Next episode
Hey, where in Malie City
do you want to go?
We’re only there for two days and one night,
after all... We’d better plan proper—
I want to try some of
their Octan-yaki!
What’s that?!
I want to try some, too!
Their sweets appear to be
famous as well.
Such as their dango
or their botamochi.
Sounds great!
Let’s go try all of it!
I told you, we have to
lay some proper pl—
Kaki, isn’t this Tosakinto yōkan the one that
Hoshi had said she wanted to try?
It is! Let’s go!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Xiemi, Meltan, and Sandy! Lost Explorers!!
Next time
Xiemi, Meltan, and Sandy!
Lost Explorers!!