Alola!
You all doing good?
I’ll give you today’s PokéProblem!
Today’s episode features Koratta’s natural enemy.
Which of these is it?
Tsutsukera
Alolan
Nasshi
Youngoose
Nyarth
That means the one Koratta
really can’t stand.
Get the answer at the end!
Satoshi and Pikachu started
living in the Alola Region.
At the Pokémon School,
they’ve met new friends and Pokémon.
Every day is filled with
learning and excitement!
Go, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Activating!
Right on schedule-roto!
Now to wake up
Satoshi and the others...
Satoshi’s awake-roto?!
What’s wrong?!
What happened-roto?!
I wanna get to
use a Z-Move again!
I’ve made up my mind!
I’m getting a Z-Crystal, for sure!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Totem Pokémon is Dekagoose!
A Z-Crystal, huh?
I wanna keep getting stronger,
and battle Kapu-Kokeko again!
I see.
We wanna try
using a Z-Move again, too!
Don’t we, Pikachu?
You’re Blast Burning, Satoshi!
You can get Z-Crystals by doing
that Island Pilgrimage thing, right?
Yeah. It’s not the only way to get one,
but undergoing the Island Pilgrimage...
...and clearing the Island Kings and Queens’
Grand Trials is the most certain way to do it.
How do I clear those?
Leave it to me-roto!
A Grand Trial is a Pokémon battle
with an Island King.
Win that battle, and you will have
cleared the Grand Trial-roto!
Sounds fun!
“Sounds fun”? It’s the Island King
you’ll be up against!
Underestimate him
at your own risk!
Besides—
According to my data,
the right to face a Grand Trial...
...is only given to those who have cleared
a Trial given to them beforehand-roto.
A Trial followed by
a Grand Trial, huh?
In any case, we should go see Melemele’s Island King,
Mr. Hala, sometime soon.
Sure!
See ya later!
Watch the house
while we’re out, Iwanko.
What a mess!
What’s that?
An accident-roto?
Attention, everyone! You may not use this road
until we’ve cleared away the timber.
Please take another road.
You’re not hurt, are you?
What’s going on, Ms. Junsa?
Professor Kukui.
A herd of wild Ratta and Koratta
ravaged the fields.
While they were fleeing,
they jumped onto the road and caused this mess.
Ratta and Koratta?
Are you a Pokémon School student?
Yes! My name is Satoshi!
This is my partner Pikachu,
and this is Rotom.
Pleasuroto to meet you!
I’m Junsa.
The pleasure’s all mine.
I graduated from
the Pokémon School myself!
What, really?
Awesome!
They make it look easy!
That’s Mr. Hala,
the Island King.
I’ll help.
Me, too!
Oh, that is much appreciated.
Thank you very much,
Island King.
Think nothing of it.
Solving trouble that befalls the island is my duty.
Reinforcements
should be here shortly.
Speak of the devil...
Your cooperation is
most appreciated!
Mr. Hala, I’m here for
the Island Pilgrimage...
I know.
What?
I’ll be waiting for you. You and the Professor
can come visit me any time.
We will.
All right!
You’re here already?
Now, come on in.
Excuse us.
Data updated-roto!
Those are...
I was the one who made
the Z-Ring on your wrist.
You, Mr. Hala?!
But I got this from Kapu-Kokeko...
I assumed as much.
I noticed one day that
a Ring had gone missing, you see.
It then occurred to me that
it must be Kapu-Kokeko’s doing.
Does this happen a lot?
This was the first time it
took a Z-Ring from me.
It seems Kapu-Kokeko is
quite interested in you, indeed...
Oh, I’m just thinking out loud.
Mr. Hala...
I really wanna get a Z-Crystal.
So that I can
battle Kapu-Kokeko again!
“Again,” is it? I see.
Young Satoshi,
may I ask you a question?
A question?
You are aware that a herd of wild Ratta and Koratta
are causing trouble for the islanders, yes?
Yes.
If you were to resolve this situation...
What would you do?
Huh?
I’d have Pikachu, Mokuroh and the others
battle the herd and—
Young Satoshi.
Do you know why the Island Pilgrimage tradition
was started in Alola so long ago?
It was not merely to
make one strong in battle.
They say it was to raise young people
who would love and protect...
...Alola’s islands, Pokémon,
and of course its people, as well.
“Love and protect”...?
Try to seek out answers
besides simply battling.
We can discuss the matter of your Z-Crystal
after I hear your answer.
Come to think of it, Mr. Hala’s question
put me in a bind many years ago, too.
Really?!
Yeah.
Oh, yes, indeed!
Young Satoshi, I will not rush your answer.
You may take as much time as you need.
Lilie, you’ve gotten completely used to
taking care of the egg!
Oh, not at all.
I’m always on edge.
I wonder, what’ll I do
if it breaks?
No, that’s where you’re wrong...
What?
Before, you were nervous because
you were afraid of the egg!
Hey, Satoshi?
What could be wrong?
That was his 786th “Hmm” since returning
from Mr. Hala’s house yesterday-roto.
His 786th?!
Satoshi’s been
lost in thought all day?!
Unbelievable!
What did Mr. Hala say?
Tell me.
Perhaps I can help.
Please tell us, as well.
Yeah! We’ll hear you out.
You’re all lifesavers!
So, there’s this herd of Ratta and Koratta
that’s been bothering the people in town...
I know them!
They raided our neighbors’ pantry!
I was afraid they’d
raid our refr—
Stop!
Satoshi’s talking right now.
Sorry...
So, Mr. Hala asked me
how I would resolve it...
And he told me to find a solution
that wasn’t battling...
I see.
If you knew more about the Ratta’s biology,
you might find some hint.
That’s my cue-roto!
Are these Ratta and Koratta?!
They’re a little different from
the ones I know!
Koratta, and its evolution, Ratta.
Mouse Pokémon. Evil/Normal type.
They form groups and will sometimes
steal food from people’s homes.
Long ago, they snuck into a ship’s cargo and came to Alola,
where they eventually assumed Alolan forms.
When the population of
Ratta and Koratta grew out of control,
Youngoose and Dekagoose were brought in
from another region to drive them away.
That’s it!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Youngoose
Type:   Normal
It’s not following us, yeah?
Hello, freedom!
Farewell, life as
Kiteruguma’s roommate!
Byesy-meow, healthy life with no food but
berries and honey!
Thinking back on it...
It was sweet and delicious,
but it was getting kinda old, yeah?
But why was that Kiteruguma
so doting?
Could this be...?
For the first time in Alola, it’s...
Ready, and...
What an aw—
Talk about impressive
athletic skills!
Huh?!
What even is this feeling?
I see.
You believe you could solve this problem
with the aid of Youngoose and Dekagoose?
Yes!
That is a fine idea, young Satoshi!
You are absolutely correct!
All right!
Bingo-roto!
The truth is, I posed this question to test
whether or not you were worthy of taking my Trial.
What?
Um... My friends helped me think of
the answer to the question.
Can I still take the Trial?
But of course!
If you find yourself at a loss, do not brood alone.
Seek the counsel of others.
That is incredibly important.
Now, let us be off.
Of course!
Youngoose and Dekagoose
live in this cave.
They are most powerful.
One of the Dekagoose in particular
is a fearsome beast known as a Totem Pokémon.
Totem Pokémon?
There are Pokémon referred to as such
here in the Alola Region.
Most of them carry out the will of the Guardian Deity
Pokémon, assisting with the Island Pilgrimage.
Young Satoshi...
My Trial for you is to defeat the Totem Pokémon
in a Pokémon battle.
Then, with his aid,
drive the Koratta and Ratta out of the city.
But...
How do I get his aid?
It will be fine.
Once a Totem Pokémon has recognized
the strength of its opponent,
it will gladly lend its strength
to said opponent.
I will be the referee for this Trial.
It’s huge!
Totem Pokémon Dekagoose!
An Island Pilgrimage
challenger has come!
Please test his skill in a Trial!
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
Please battle me!
I hear something-roto.
I-Is that the Totem Pokémon?
It is not.
They are the Totem Pokémon’s tribe.
You will, however, need to battle them.
We shall now commence
the Trial Pokémon battle!
Rotom, give me their data, please.
I’m on it-roto!
Youngoose. Prowling Pokémon.
Dekagoose. Stakeout Pokémon.
Both Normal types.
Youngoose possesses
sharp fangs and jaws,
and when it evolves into Dekagoose,
it grows even more tenacious and resilient.
In that case...
Pikachu! I choose you!
Mokuroh, you’re up!
He’s asleep-roto...
Wake up!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Mokuroh! Tackle!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Mokuroh, fly!
Mokuroh! Leafage!
Now it’s our turn
to blind them!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Mokuroh!
Huh?
Impressive...
He snuck up on it silently.
Right!
Mokuroh, use Tackle!
Youngoose and Dekagoose
are both unable to battle!
All right!
Here he is!
He is the Totem Pokémon himself!
H-Huge!
Unbelievable-roto!
He’s three times the size
of that other Dekagoose-roto!
Pikachu, jump back
and use 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
His speed is too fast
to measure-roto!
Tackle!
Thank you for saving Pikachu,
Mokuroh.
Take a nice, long nap.
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
Pikachu!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
What?!
There’s no way Lightning Speed will work
on that thing-roto!
Pikachu, take advantage of
the Sand Attack!
What?!
Pikachu is blending into the sand
from the Sand Attack-roto!
Now, Pikachu!
Let’s end this, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
That’s enough!
Challenger Satoshi
wins this battle!
All right!
You did it-roto!
Dekagoose!
Danger! Satoshi,
that’s dangerous-roto!
Are you all right,
Dekagoose?
Is that for me?
Thank you.
Oh, my! Is that...
I got a Z-Crystal!
A spectacular victory-roto!
Totem Pokémon do not often
hand over Z-Crystals...
Young Satoshi is
a mysterious lad indeed...
Say, Dekagoose...
Could you help me drive
the Ratta and Koratta away?
Are you ready, Satoshi?
Yes.
I’m counting on you guys.
We’re opening the door...
Impressive! Especially that one
with the sharp fangs!
That went just like my data
suggested-roto!
Thank you very much!
Oh, not at all. It was all thanks to
Dekagoose and Youngoose!
Young Satoshi...
As Melemele’s Island King,
I declare your Trial complete.
Thank you, Sir!
You did it, Satoshi!
You will be challenging
the Grand Trial next, yes?
I look forward to it!
I cannot wait to see
your Z-Move for myself!
I’m super excited, too!
Aren’t you, Pikachu?
Under the watchful eye of Hala, Melemele’s Island King,
Satoshi and his Pokémon have cleared their first Trial.
Next, it’s finally time for their Grand Trial
against Island King Hala!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Youngoose!
Did you all get it right?
The Youngoose were strong, too,
but that Dekagoose really had me struggling!
But the Totem Dekagoose was
the most amazing of them all!
That one was intense!
What did it eat to grow that big?
It was huge, but it was super fast, too...
I can’t believe we won!
You with the sharp fangs!
Hang on a second!
Would you like to join me?
That’s an “Okay,” right?
Thank you!
I’d been wanting a partner!
Next episode
Come out, Mokuroh!
I choose you!
Mokuroh’s fired up-roto!
We’re finally gonna battle the Island King, after all!
We’re training like crazy!
Mokuroh! Go back into
your Monster Ball!
Huh?
Come out, Mokuroh!
Return!
What kind of “training”
is this-roto?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Will the Z-Move Work?!
Challenging the Grand Trial!!