Hi, hi, hi!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Two times
Five times
Eight times
Thirteen times
How many times are Z-Moves used
in today’s episode?
You’ll get the answer at the end,
so just watcHuntail!
Intense battles unfolded one after another
in the Alola Pokémon League.
Satoshi and Gladio
clashed in the finals.
It’s not over!
Lugarugan, fight Counter
with Counter!
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is...
...Competitor Satoshi!
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Akujiking?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Akujiking Invades!
A Grand Z-Move Showdown!!
Akujiking?!
The Ultra Beast you battled
in a parallel world?!
Yes!
Wait, how do you know that?
K-K-Kukui...
Professor Kukui told me.
If Satoshi was telling the truth,
it’s a pretty dangerous Ultra Beast.
First, we have to
evacuate the audience.
Ult-Roger!
Switch on!
Standing by!
O-Oh, sorry I’m late.
It’s fine.
Everyone, that Ultra Beast
is incredibly dangerous.
Please evacuate to the port
in a calm and orderly fashion.
I repeat:
Please evacuate to the port
in a calm and orderly fashion.
You heard what she said.
Satoshi, will you help me lead it away?
Of course!
We’ll help, too!
Yeah!
Me, too!
Thank you, everyone!
What’s that?!
The time has come...
...for Team Rocket to...
...nab loads of Pokémon!
Team Rocket?
We Island Kings and Queens
will fend off this beast!
You help with the evacuation.
Hang on!
I know its weak spot!
What?!
Akujiking’s one and only weak spot...
...is the second face
above its gigantic mouth.
The second face above its mouth...
That’s right!
If you focus your attacks there...
Very well!
Good to know.
We leave the spectators
in your care!
Got it!
It’s some Pokémon I’ve
never seen, meow!
Don’t fuss about this or that!
We’ll catch that Pokémon,
and all the others, too!
Here we go! Desperate Tackle!
It did nothing, meow!
Wait, is it trying to eat us?!
Kojiro, don’t you have
any other moves, meow?
Um...
Baby-Doll Eyes!
That had no effect either, meow!
Kiteruguma!
Such power!
We should head up there, as well!
This way!
Head for port!
No need to rush!
There’s room on the ships
for all of you!
You’re almost there!
Calm down-roto!
This way!
Is everyone out?
Please leave your luggage here!
Oh, no!
Another Ultra Hole is opening!
A-Another?!
Location?
Um...
Above the shopping mall!
Is that...?
An Ultra Hole?!
What’s going on?!
Another Akujiking?!
I’ll hold it off.
You two get to safety!
What are you saying?!
I can’t just run and leave a friend behind!
That’s right!
Have it your way!
Two Akujiking have appeared
at Manalo Stadium.
Connecting to the stadium’s
surveillance cameras.
How’s the evacuation going?
Almost everyone has boarded.
Are you sure you’ll be fine?
Yeah!
We’ll make sure to send Akujiking
back through the Ultra Hole!
I’ll accompany him.
But...
I-Is that...?!
An Ultra Hole-roto!
Which means...
Another one?!
Akujiking!
This one’s massive, too!
Now the ships can’t leave!
Let’s go, Satoshi!
Sure!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Akujiking
Type:   Dark/Dragon
Good! Keep it up, meow!
Hold the phone!
At this rate, we’re just gonna get dragged off by Kiteruguma
without catching any Pokémon, again!
That’d be bad!
Our master plan
would be for nothing!
This is our chance
to escape, meow!
Yeah!
Soft steps... Quiet steps...
Torideps...
Kiteruguma!
Kiteruguma is so set on protecting Nuikoguma
that she’s willing to risk her own life!
I’m shaken to my core, meow!
How can we claim to champion the evils of
truth and love if we let this be?!
Yeah!
When you say
“AAAAAAAAAAAAAA!!!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
What even is this feeling?
Everyone, here we go!
I’ll knock Akujiking off balance.
Got it. Then Hau and I...
...will aim for the weak spot
on its face.
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Bakugames! Flamethrower!
Ju'niper! Razor Leaf!
We’ll have to deal with those arms!
Ju'niper’s Spirit Shackle
might be able to stop them.
In that case, Bakugames’s Focus Blast
should come in handy, too.
Got it. Then I’ll use Lugarugan’s Z-Move
to blast that thing back into the Ultra Hole.
Wait, you’re kidding!
What’s wrong?
The Ultra Hole...
Hey, look at that!
The Ultra Hole is shrinking!
Ju'niper! Spirit Shackle!
Bakugames!
Fire off a flurry of Focus Blasts!
Here we go, Lugarugan!
Amajo! Magical Leaf!
Ashirène! Sparkling Aria!
Kuwagannon! Zap Cannon!
Are you all right?!
Lilie!
Māmane! Suiren! Mao!
Thank you! You saved us!
We’ll fight...
...together!
Yeah!
Banbadoro! Use Bulldoze!
Lugarugan! Rock Slide!
Persian! Evil Pulse!
Hariteyama! Arm Thrust!
Still not sufficient, is it?
Kapu-Kokeko!
Kapu-Tetefu!
Kapu-Bulul!
Kapu-Rehire!
In Alola’s time of need,
all four Kapu have gathered!
Hey, Kapu! Hate to ask,
but we need your help!
Will you stop Akujiking
from moving?
Then we’ll focus our Z-Moves on it
and send it back into the Ultra Hole!
It stopped!
Here we go!
I am he who shares the will of Melemele Island
and the Guardian Deity, Kapu-Kokeko...
The Island King!
The time has come
to unite our strengths as one!
Full Power Peerless Fists of Fury!
Roar, heartbeats of life!
O, echoes of the bedrock,
piercing through heaven and earth!
Go!
World’s End Fall!
May the full power of darkness
consume you.
Black Hole Eclipse.
Vast roots spreading through
Poni Island’s soil...
Bestow upon us your power!
Rising Land Over!
Let’s all go at full power!
Yes!
Vividly shining light,
take flight!
Engrave into the battlefield...
...the name of the ultimate fighter!
Ultimate Dragon Burn!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
How long has it been since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
Lord of the silent forest,
Ju'niper!
I’m kinda proud of that
Here we go!
Shadow Arrows Strike!
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
Snow silently fluttering down
from the heavens...
Countless glimmering crystals of ice...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
O, freezing Z that covers the land...
Along with my heated soul,
return now once more to the heavens!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
Raging Geofreeze!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
Feel the sprouting grass and trees,
and the breath of the forest!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Embraced by our mother,
the sea...
Echo...
...beyond the horizon!
Sea God’s Symphonia!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
All of our systems
are in perfect sync!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
Full Power Program... Run!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...so much more! Type: Wild!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Absolute Predatory Spin-Out!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
We did it!
Yes, we did!
We won!
Yeah!
“Hello, my dream”
There’s no time.
We’ll finish this here, Satoshi!
Yes!
The bell’s rung!
Lucario?!
First, Lucario will attack
and draw Akujiking’s attention.
While we’re doing that...
Pikachu and I
will stop it from moving!
Lucario! Infight!
Now, Pikachu! Electroweb!
Lucario! Use Dragon Pulse!
Lucario!
Push it back with Infight!
No way...
Not even Lucario’s attacks
are strong enough to push it back?
I’m sorry. I have no Pokémon
who can use Electric moves.
The Ultra Hole is...
Now we cannot
send Akujiking home!
Wait!
What’s that?
Are you... Bebenom?!
Awesome! You’ve evolved!
Is that...
the Bebenom from back then?
Bebenom came back
as an Agoyon-roto!
Watch out, Satoshi!
You’ve learned 100,000 Volts?!
If so, I might be able to fire
a Sparking Gigavolt as well!
Agoyon,
please lend me your power!
All right!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Here we go, Agoyon!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
All right!
You did it-roto!
Royal Mask!
I should be the one
thanking you, Satoshi!
Royal Mask’s true identity
has finally been exposed!
What is Kukui to do?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting!
Z-Moves were used
no less than thirteen times!
The Junkivore Pokémon Akujiking
is a Dark/Dragon type.
A dangerous Ultra Beast,
it appears to be eating constantly,
but they sent them all back through the Ultra Hole,
so it’s all rightta! Koratta! Meloetta!
This is paradise...
You can say that again...
Somehow, this is a really...
...great feeling...
Next episode
Enjoy!
To all the kids in front of the TV!
Are you all still enjoying
the Pokémon League today, as well?
Now that the Champion has been crowned,
it’s finally time for me, Royal Mask, to make an appearance!
Please cheer me on!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
The Final Battle! Satoshi VS Kukui!!
“Kukui”?
Oh, right! My cover’s blown! What do I do?!
Next time
The Final Battle!
Satoshi VS Kukui!!