Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Zubat
Yatoumori
Fukuthrow
Dustdas
My opponent in today’s episode is Hau.
Who’s his partner Pokémon?
The answer’ll be at the end of the episode!
Fukuthrow! Razor Leaf!
Great work!
Fukuthrow, you’re doing great!
This young man is Hau.
He’s currently training on Melemele Island
with his partner, Fukuthrow.
Let’s keep it up, together!
And then let’s beat my gramps
at his best, Fukuthrow!
What are you doing?
Hello-roto...
Alola...
A Z-Ring!
Wow...
W-What?
Can you use Z-Moves?
Did you take
my gramps’s Grand Trial?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Artisan Fukuthrow!!!
The Sleeping MokurohZZZ
I see.
So Mr. Hala’s your grandfather.
You’re so lucky to have
taken his Grand Trial.
I wanna battle my gramps
at his best, too.
If he’s your grandfather,
then I’m sure he’d battle you if you just asked him.
No, not at all.
He says that, as we are now,
he can’t give his best against us yet.
Right, Fukuthrow?
I see.
I’ve been living away from Alola with my dad
for a long time now.
We came back not too long ago,
and now I can finally take the Island Pilgrimage!
Really? You can do it!
And since I really wanna do
my gramps’s Grand Trial first, I’m training here.
Did you come to train, too?
We’re exploring.
There’s still loads of places on Melemele Island
that we haven’t been to.
Then we found you two.
Fukuthrow was so cool that I forgot to say hi,
and just stopped to watch.
Isn’t it?
I’m really proud of Fukuthrow!
Fukuthrow is
Mokuroh’s evolved form, right?
Stop right there!
This is where I come in-roto!
Fukuthrow. Blade Quill Pokémon.
Grass/Flying type.
It throws sharp feathers called blade quills
at enemies or prey.
A bit of a dandy, it spends its free time
preening its wings.
Let me introduce...
...my partner, Mokuroh!
It’s sleeping soundly!
This is his favorite spot.
Mokuroh’s as heavy a sleeper
as they come-roto.
Hey, Mokuroh, wake up!
It’s your evolved form,
Fukuthrow!
What’s going on?
My Fukuthrow
can’t stand bed hair.
It’s a fashionable Pokémon,
after all.
See? A heavy sleeper, right?
He’s out of the ordinary, that’s for sure.
He’s the Sleeping Champion!
Say, Satoshi. Did you use Mokuroh
when you beat gramps at his best?
Yup. He beat his Makenkani.
Makenkani?!
He snatched victory
from the jaws of defeat-roto!
A-A-Amazing!
Fukuthrow didn’t stand a chance
against that one!
So cool!
I really respect you two!
In that case, let’s battle!
Really?
Sounds great! I’d be happy to!
Let’s give it a try, Fukuthrow!
Fukuthrow says
it wants to try, too.
All right!
Mokuroh... Fukuthrow says
it wants to battle you.
I wanna battle with you, too!
Fukuthrow,
let’s make this a fun battle!
All right, let’s go,
Mokuroh!
I’ll be the referee-roto!
Let the battle between Mokuroh
and Fukuthrow begin-roto!
Fukuthrow! Leaf Blade!
Here it comes, Mokuroh!
What?!
Wake up, Mokuroh!
Are you awake now?
Mokuroh’s a funny guy, huh?
I’m counting on you,
Mokuroh!
Use Razor Leaf!
My Mokuroh
pulls through when it counts!
Then we’ll use
Razor Leaf, too!
I knew the evolved form’s attacks would be far stronger,
even when using the exact same move-roto!
Impressive, Hau, Fukuthrow!
Amazing, isn’t it?
Another Leaf Blade,
and let’s make this one count!
Then I’ll use a Z-Move to...
Oh, no!
Got it!
Mokuroh is unable to battle!
Fukuthrow wins-roto!
We won!
You did it, Fukuthrow!
We beat an opponent who
beat my gramps...
This is the best!
Sorry, Mokuroh...
I was too slow.
Its speed and power were on
an entirely different level-roto!
The battle’s over,
Mokuroh...
Mokuroh’s finally gone into
Serious Mode-roto...
What, really?
He sure is easygoing, huh...
I’m sure you’re upset,
Mokuroh...
All right, Hau!
Let’s have another battle!
Sounds great!
Let’s do it!
...Or so I’d like to say,
but I’ve got an appointment with my dad.
I gotta get going.
Huh?
Sorry about that!
Let’s have a rematch
here tomorrow!
I wanna battle you
some more, too!
Sure! It’s a promise!
Yup! It’s a promise!
Mokuroh,
let’s do our best tomorrow!
Pocket Monsters...
...and...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Fukuthrow
Type:   Grass/Flying
Sounds like you had quite a day!
Hau and Fukuthrow
were both really cool!
We’re gonna battle again
tomorrow!
You made a promise?
Yup! I’d hate to stay the loser,
and they were super fun to battle!
I see. So that’s why
Mokuroh’s been so...
Mokuroh!
I won’t mess up again!
So let’s win tomorrow!
Don’t you think it’s exciting to
retaliate with a new move in situations like these?
New move?
Searching available moves
for Mokuroh... Searching...
The tale of how Royal Mask and Gaogaen
learned Cross Chop brought a tear to my eye!
For real? Let me hear it!
Well, the root of their Cross Chop
was Brick Break, but...
Hang on. Right now,
we should focus on Mokuroh.
Sure...
But it’s true...
Royal Mask got stronger by following the motto of
“When in doubt, return to your roots”.
“Return to your roots”?
It means to go back
to the beginning.
That’s right. Like a place or event
that was important to you and Mokuroh.
Then I know just the place!
Mokuroh!
Tomorrow,
let’s practice a new move!
Mokuroh, this was where
everything began for us, right?
In the forest where I caught you.
All right...
Then he can learn a new move!
What’s your basis
for that claim-roto?
Basis? What’s that?
You don’t have one-roto?!
That’s illogical-roto!
It doesn’t matter, does it?
We might find a hint of some kind here.
That Kerarappa...
It was in Mokuroh’s nest-roto!
Found it!
Here they are!
Long time, no see,
Dodekabashi!
I wanted to see you!
I thought you might...
This is a trait often seen
in bird Pokémon-roto.
Huh? What is?
There are bird Pokémon who
can’t properly digest things they eat whole-roto.
So they’ll eat tiny rocks that grind down the food
in their stomachs to help with digestion-roto!
How strange...
You mustn’t try to imitate them,
Satoshi, Pikachu-roto.
We get that.
Right, Pikachu?
Hey! Rotom just said not to,
Pikachu!
That was Seed Machine Gun-roto!
That’s some power!
Satoshi, look at this-roto!
Their Seed Machine Gun attacks
use rocks-roto!
The ones they just swallowed!
Depending on a Pokémon’s habits and habitat,
they might use different things as ammo for Seed Machine Gun...
This proves the conclusion
my research yielded-roto!
Awesome!
Are Dodekabashi and the others
trying to teach Mokuroh Seed Machine Gun?
But Mokuroh shouldn’t be able
to learn Seed Machine Gun-roto.
What?! Really?
Well, he’ll break that limit with fighting spirit!
After all, he’s got Dodekabashi teaching him!
That’s not how this works-roto...
Hang in there, Mokuroh!
You can’t expect it to work the first time!
Okay, I’ll do it with you!
Here I go!
Juthd wadch be...
Satoshi,
that was awesome-roto!
Not bad, right?
The trick is to focus your power
in your belly!
And one more trick:
Never take your eyes
off the target!
Well done, Pikachu!
Got it?
Focus your power here, okay?
Thank you for the great hint,
Dodekabashi, Kerarappa!
We were right to come here!
That stone is...
What, Rotom?
It’s probably an Everstone-roto...
An Everstone?
A stone that prevents Pokémon
from evolving-roto!
Huh?!
Mokuroh, spit it out!
You should have him use Seed Machine Gun
to get it out-roto!
Oh, right...
Focus your power in your belly...
Ready, go-roto!
What a relief...
Hey, Mokuroh!
He swallowed it again-roto!
Think it tastes good?
This’ll mean Mokuroh
won’t evolve-roto!
This looks less like Seed Machine Gun,
and more like Seed Bomb-roto!
Seed Bomb? I see!
Amazing, Mokuroh!
You’ve perfected Seed Bomb!
Just like that-roto?!
Sorry to have
kept you waiting, Hau!
Alola, Satoshi!
Sorry I had to leave
so soon yesterday.
Let’s enjoy this
to the max today!
Yeah! We’ve been
looking forward to this!
You’ll be amazed when you
see our super special move!
Really? Amazing!
Let me see!
All right, let the battle between Mokuroh
and Fukuthrow begin-roto!
Look! This is our new move...
Seed Bomb!
What was that?!
Was that how
Seed Bomb worked?
It’s our own,
original Seed Bomb!
What’s that mean?
I guess it takes something special
to clear a Grand Trial!
We’re not done yet!
Use Peck!
Don’t lose, Fukuthrow!
Razor Leaf!
Mokuroh!
Now! Leaf Blade!
Another Razor Leaf!
Now Mokuroh
can’t get away!
Mokuroh! Seed Bomb!
I knew you’d do that!
Send it back with Leaf Blade!
This’ll end it!
Leaf Blade!
Mokuroh, let’s clear away
the Razor Leaves!
A Z-Move?!
But he can’t move!
What?!
This is our full power!
Bloom Shine Extra!
Fukuthrow is unable to battle!
Mokuroh wins-roto!
All right!
Fukuthrow,
you did your best.
I’ve never felt like this before...
Is this what frustration
feels like?
Hau.
The two of you are amazing!
We wanna use that Z-Move, too!
Don’t you?
Using your full power is great!
Satoshi! The next time we battle,
it’ll be after I’ve beaten my gramps’s Grand Trial!
Right! I’ll be waiting!
Then, we’ll duke it out
with Z-Moves!
Yeah!
Mokuroh...
He swallowed
the Everstone again-roto!
Well, whatever...
A friendship is born. Satoshi and Hau
promise to meet again.
And now, what sort of future
lies in store...
...for the unevolving
Mokuroh?
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thanks for waiting!
Hau’s partner Pokémon
was Fukuthrow!
The Blade Quill Pokémon Fukuthrow
is a Grass/Flying type.
It’s really sensitive to the presence of others,
and can even hit opponents behind itself with its feathers!
Hau’s Fukuthrow noticed our
presence right away, too!
Okay, it’s time to eat,
everybody.
Is that an Everstone?
Mokuroh really likes it!
Next episode
I’m disappointed
in you-roto, Satoshi!
What do you mean?
I already know-roto!
You mean, how I broke that vase
while playing with Pikachu and the others?!
Or that I was snacking on the candy in the house
and ended up eating all of it?!
Or...?
Professor Kukui!
I’ve figured out who did it-roto!
It was Satoshi-roto!
Oh...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Duo Splits Up?! Satoshi and Rotom
My deductions never miss the mark-roto!
Next time
The Duo Splits Up?! Satoshi and Rotom
But you didn’t deduce anything.