Alola!
Today’s PokéProblem is from me,
and it’s about Odoridori!
Mai-Mai Style
Flare-Flare Style
Hula-Hula Style
Clap-Clap Style
What form does Odoridori turn into
when it sips Yellow Nectar?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Aina Cafeteria,
which is run by Mao’s father.
What’s this? Everyone’s here.
What could they be up to?
I can’t wait!
I wonder what she’ll be serving!
You guys!
Thank you for coming to my tasting party
for the new menu item!
Oh, finally!
Don’t rush me.
You won’t have to wait
that much longer!
I skipped lunch today...
I can’t wait much longer!
Thanks, Amakaji!
Y-You’re helping out at work?
How impressive!
Don’t bother her when
she’s working, Mokuroh.
Smells great...
Māmane’s spellbound
by Amakaji, too...
No! Not by Amakaji!
It’s coming from the kitchen.
You’re right!
Pikachu, can you give me a hand?
W-What?!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Seriously?!
Mao’s Cooking Master Plan!!
Mao, why do you look so...
Are you all right?!
I’m just fine!
Ta-daah!
The Mythical Alola Stew
is complete!
Mythical?!
Alola Stew?!
Looks great!
It’s kinda burnt...
And you all get
some special Pokémon food!
Time to eat!
What’s going on-roto?!
Well? Surprised? Is it good?
Mao... Just what is this dish?!
That tingling aftertaste is
totally addictive, right?
That aftertaste is what
defines the Mythical Alola Stew!
“Tingling”... More like...
Shocking...
It’s like I got zapped
by Pikachu’s electricity...
You can’t have...!
Yeah! I added a 100,000 Volts
to the stew as a finishing touch!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Maybe it was a bit too intense...
I must ask, what is
this “Mythical Alola Stew”?
Well...
Oh, welcome!
Dad!
I hope we’re not a bother.
Maopapa!
What is Mythical Alolan Stew?
Where’d that come from?
Well...
Long ago, they would always make it
for festivals and ceremonies,
but as the years flew by,
it was gradually forgotten.
So that’s why it’s “Mythical”...
Did you know?
No, I’ve never heard of it before.
If so, then how were you
able to make it?
Well, you see...
What’s this?
The recipe for Alola Stew.
My big brother sent it to me.
Your brother? The one who’s traveling
to hone his cooking skills?
That’s right! And on his journeys,
he happened across an old document...
...that had the recipe
for Alola Stew in it!
He copied it for me!
I see...
The recipe says you need Yellow Nectar
to complete the stew.
It’s a vital ingredient.
It’s what gives that tingling aftertaste.
Yellow Nectar...
But it’s out of season,
so how would you...?
Yeah! That’s why I thought
I’d use a 100,000 Volts as a substitute...
I don’t get it. Not at all.
Why?! Why a 100,000 Volts, of all things?
It makes no sense at all!
I really wanted to perfect it,
and make it a featured
Aina Cafeteria menu item...
You’re right.
Let’s keep trying, Amakaji!
More, please!
This is great!
I can’t get enough of
that spicy electric shock!
The power of skipping lunch...
All right,
I’ll make you something else.
My treat!
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Our reputation is on the line here!
All right!
You’re still not full-roto?!
Time to eat!
Thanks for the food!
Thank you for coming.
I am most satisfied!
Take care on your way home.
Of course!
Later.
See you at the Pokémon School.
Bye bye!
Hey, Mokuroh!
Sheesh...
C’mon, we’re leaving.
Thank you for coming today,
Satoshi.
It should be me thanking you.
Say...
What does the Yellow Nectar
being “out of season” mean?
Oh, well, you see...
Allow me to explain it for her!
If it’s not the right time of year,
you can’t find Yellow Nectar...
...with a few exceptions.
What? Exceptions?
Definitely!
Well, according to my grandpa.
How vague...
Mao, let’s go looking tomorrow!
I’ll help you out!
But...
I really wanna try
that Mythical Alola Stew!
All right!
At last...
At last!
Team Rocket’s secret base
is complete!
We did it, meow!
After X weeks of hibernation!
Now, we can finally
get back to our original mission!
Brat boy’s Pikachu,
we’re finally gonna get ‘chu!
We’re gonna get all the Pokémon
of Alola, too, meow!
Then let’s waste no time!
Team Rocket, move out!
Yeah!
...but I’m tired,
so let’s do it tomorrow.
Yeah...
All right,
where do we start looking?
Are you sure about this?
Dad’s info was pretty vague.
I don’t know if we can find it
just by searching blindly.
Heh heh heh!
This is where I shine-roto!
Commence search for
Yellow Nectar-roto!
Odoridori, Clap-Clap Style.
Why Odoridori?
My data indicates that
Odoridori loves Yellow Nectar-roto!
So if we find and follow Odoridori...
It might lead us to somewhere
we can find Yellow Nectar?!
Exactly-roto!
But our current chances
of finding one are just 8%-roto...
8% means it’s still possible!
Let’s go looking for Odoridori!
Yeah!
Anything?
Nothing...
Doesn’t look like it.
Anything?
Nothing...
We’re not getting anywhere...
The search has lasted five hours.
The probability of finding one
has dropped to 0.3%-roto...
I won’t give up!
I will find a source of Yellow Nectar!
So I can make the Mythical Alola Stew
a featured dish at the Aina Cafeteria!
You’re really fired up.
But why are you so set on
making it a featured dish?
I mean, you’ve got plenty of
super good dishes already.
My dream is to make Aina Cafeteria
the best diner in all of Alola!
Best in Alola...
I want to use the featured dish
to get the word out about Aina Cafeteria,
so that everyone can get to
taste Dad’s cooking!
I see! That sounds great!
Once it’s done,
you’ll get the first taste!
You’re on!
We’ll find that Yellow Nectar, for sure!
Yeah!
A mythical dish?
The best in Alola!
Yellow Nectar! I get the feeling
it’d sell for a lot, meow!
Change of plans!
We’re gonna nab that Yellow Nectar!
Yeah!
Let’s go, everyone!
I’m not sure if they
get along or not...
Oh, I just had a brilliant idea, Mao!
Huh? Brilliant idea?
I know how to find Odoridori!
Odoridori is
a bird Pokémon, too, yeah?
So if Amakaji releases
plenty of Sweet Scent,
one might come flying here
like Mokuroh does!
That could work!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Amakaji
Type:   Grass
Counting on you, Amakaji!
Awesome!
Hang in there, Amakaji!
Whoa, here they come!
See any?
No...
Look over there-roto!
It’s Odoridori!
It’s leaving!
Let’s follow it!
Amakaji, come on!
Wait!
Please stop, Odoridori!
No, don’t go!
It’s back!
Oh, no!
W-Wait...
Amakaji! Oh, look at you...
Thank you!
Leave the rest to us!
Over there-roto!
What’s this place?
Is that Yellow Nectar?
Amazing! We really found it!
It’s a miracle-roto!
It’s Odoridori’s
Flare-Flare Style-roto!
Rotom, what happened?
It turned from Flare-Flare Style
into Clap-Clap-style!
Um... Um...
Odoridori’s typing and appearance change after
sipping special kinds of Nectar found in Alola-roto!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
Look at this!
What’s this?!
When asked “What’s this?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket!
Operation successful, meow!
We’ll be taking the Yellow Nectar!
Do your thing, Nyarth!
Sure, meow!
Here’s my Almighty Treasure
Suction Machine, meow!
That’s so cool, Nyarth!
Just do it!
I got ya, meow!
Oh, the Yellow Nectar!
Just twiddle your thumbs
as you sit and watch!
Oh, no!
Stop!
What even is this thing?
No thanks. Totally not my thing.
‘Kay.
Hey, your face!
Look sharp, Nyarth!
That’s right! You’re not gonna
beat Persian like that.
That was nothing!
No big deal at all, meow!
Amakaji...
...evolved!
The totally-not-my-thing...
...got cute!
Amamaiko. Fruit Pokémon.
Grass type.
The sepals on its head
developed to protect her body.
These are quite hard,
giving its Round-Trip Slap considerable power.
All right!
This is...
That was nothing!
No big deal at all, meow!
Mokuroh, use Peck!
Amamaiko! Round-Trip Slap!
Retreat! Retreat, now!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
What even is this feeling?
Thanks for waiting! The Mythical Alola Stew
is finished... for real, this time!
Thanks, Amamaiko!
Thank you.
It looks like she’s having even more fun
helping out after evolving.
All right, dig in!
Don’t mind if we do!
W-Well?
Delicious!
All right!
That tingling aftertaste
has quite the impact!
Mythical taste!
More, please!
It tastes amazing, Mao!
Yeah, this is nothing like the last one!
I thought the last one was great, too.
Thank you all! This is all thanks to everyone who
helped me find the Yellow Nectar:
Satoshi, Pikachu, Rotom, Mokuroh,
and especially Amamaiko!
I hope you’ll keep
being my friend, Amamaiko.
I mean, I mean... I thought this would be
the last time I’d get to eat this...
And that made me sad...
Oh, Māmane...
Your stomach rumbled
because you were sad?
Getting Yellow Nectar when it’s out of season
would be a bit too tough...
But don’t worry!
I may not be able to make it a featured dish,
but I’ve decided to leave it up
as a seasonal item!
All right!
I see!
But I still have my goal of
making a featured dish for Aina Cafeteria!
I’ll have plenty more
tasting parties later,
so look forward to those!
Yeah! Sounds promising!
Amakaji’s strong feelings toward Mao
have let her evolve into Amamaiko.
Mao’s efforts to make
a featured dish will continue,
together with her
partner Pokémon!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem was
Clap-Clap Style!
Odoridori’s Clap-Clap Style
is an Electric/Flying type.
What an amazing Pokémon, changing its appearance
and typing based on its preferred Nectar!
We found the Yellow Nectar
thanks to it.
Thank you!
Mao, should we call it a day?
Sure!
Good job, Amamaiko.
You can relax now.
Oh, you’re such a baby...
Next episode
Today, I’ll be training with Māmane!
Yeah! First we’ll have some
steaming hot malasada!
Whoa! Training with malasada?!
Delicious! Hot!
It’s hot, but it’s great!
Next up: Alola Pancakes!
Training with Alola Pancakes!
Delicious!
How is this training?
This is just snack time-roto!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Intense Electric Training!
A Rematch with Kapu-Kokeko!!
Next time
Intense Electric Training!
A Rematch with Kapu-Kokeko!!