Alola, all nice little kids
who love Team Rocket!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Dekagoose
Alolan Ratta
Dodekabashi
Kiteruguma
Who is the Totem Pokémon
appearing today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Today’s class will be
a refresher on Z-Moves.
Got it!
All right!
Z-Moves?
What are those sparkly things?
What pretty gems, meow!
Now then, Satoshi, Kaki!
Let’s see some serious Z-Moves!
Of course!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Assume position, Bakugames!
They’re doing
some weird poses, meow!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Both moves were
immensely powerful-roto!
Truly a Trump Card!
Team Rocket has gotten
their first look at a Z-Move.
What will their next move be,
in response to this shocking revelation?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Battle For the Crystal!
Team Rocket VS Team Skull!!
So, I spent the past
couple of days researching it...
Apparently you activate Z-Moves
by equipping a Z-Ring with a Z-Crystal,
and striking this
“full power pose” thing.
Like this, meow?
And Z-Crystals are found in
special veins of rock in the Alola Region!
Guess we just gotta
go look for some, then!
Agreed!
I really wanna fire a Super Nyarth Beam
from my Charm, meow!
What an awful feeling!
Good, good... Spectacular!
And to that end,
I have prepared...
...this Z-Crystal
Detecting Machine!
Isn’t that just the worn-down Dowsing Machine
you bought at the pawn shop the other day, meow?
Does that... even work?
Of course! I’ve made some
special modifications to it!
Now, let’s get searching!
It found something?!
It’s surprisingly close!
Move out at once, meow!
We’ll be talking about
Z-Crystals again today.
Has anyone seen any Crystals
besides the ones Satoshi and Kaki have?
A boy in my neighborhood
has a Grass-Z!
I see. Anyone else?
Looks like...
...they haven’t-roto.
But worry not, because I’ll show you
the Z-Crystals for every type today!
Awesome! Are these all real?
I’m afraid they’re all replicas.
But seeing them all lined up
like this is exciting, yeah?
Can anyone tell which
Crystal is which?
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground,
Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost,
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice,
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy.
There you have it-roto!
Absolutely correct!
Knew you’d get it, Rotom!
Where is that Crystal, meow?
Where?
Hang on! The response came from
around here somewhere...
What?!
Over there?!
A grand discovery!
That’s the Evil-type Crystal!
It’s perfect for Team Rocket!
Let’s go get it, meow!
Ratta and Koratta, meow!
What is that?!
A Ratta... Or is it?!
It’s way too big, meow!
Run!
Bro, I’m pretty sure
we’re totally lost.
Is there really an “evil candy shop
that’s just right for us” in here?
Are ya guys sayin’ ya don’t believe me,
yer great Bro?!
The map wasn’t no help,
so I’m leadin’ the way with my brilliant instincts!
But we ain’t gettin’ nowhere!
I’m starvin’!
Now ya guys listen up!
Of course ya hafta get hungry before ya get any!
That’s what makes it evil candy!
Just quit yappin’ and follow me!
I know what I’m doin’!
O-Oh, I get it now!
Yer the best, Bro!
Pardon!
Ho!
Run!
What was that?
A giant Ratta!
C-Cut it out! Cut it out!
We ain’t done nothin’!
We ain’t with those guys!
That thing was huge...
It ain’t no pushover.
Maybe it’s the Totem Pokémon
rulin’ these parts?
I getcha.
That would explain the size.
Bro, how ‘bout we
catch that thing?
If we had somethin’ that big on our side,
we’d be the strongest in Alola, for reals!
Right on!
I was just thinkin’ the same thing!
Of course ya were, Bro!
Yer so smart!
Sure am!
The really interesting thing
about Z-Crystals,
...is that they don’t correspond
with the type of the Pokémon,
but rather the type of
the move used.
Take Pikachu for example.
It may be an Electric type,
but it has Normal-type moves, too, yeah?
So it can activate
the Normal-type Z-Move as well,
if you use the Normal-type Crystal.
Satoshi’s Pikachu can also use
the Steel-type move Iron Tail-roto!
Yeah, and?
So if you had the Steel Z-Crystal,
he could use the Steel Z-Move, too-roto!
Of course!
Do you wanna try it, Pikachu?
Question, Professor!
What is it, Suiren?
What’s the pose for
the Water-type move?
Well, you see...
Hey, isn’t that the Ratta’s nest?
They’ll make it hard to
get the Crystal, meow.
Maybe if we climb up from
the back of the rock?
That’s it!
Yer gonna bleed, Totem Ratta!
Bro, Bro! Look at that!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
That’s, like, the thing, yeah?
Ain’t it a Z-Crystal?
Yeah, that’s just what
I was about to say!
Oh, Bro, ya know everythin’!
Sure do!
All treasure in Alola
belongs to Team Skull!
Startin’ today,
I’ll be a Z-Move-user!
But Bro, didn’t ya hate Z-Moves?
Don’t go bringin’ up
the ancient past like that!
What do we do about Ratta?
Keep yer eyes on the Crystal,
not Ratta!
Good point!
Yer the best, Bro!
S-Sure am!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Dustdas
Type:   Poison
Who are you?
Ya guys’re...
the guys from earlier!
When you say
“Ya guys’re... the guys from earlier!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Lame.
We’re not “lame”!
So friggin’ cute!
I’m totes in love with
this talkin’ Nyarth!
Hey... What are you doing
with our Nyarth?!
I seriously want that talkin’ Nyarth!
Quit praisin’ it! Quit fallin’ in love with it!
Yer not makin’ sense!
Those lame uniforms ain’t Alolan.
Where’re ya guys from?
We hail from Kanto!
Where’s that?
You don’t know?!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
I really like
the Water Z-Move pose!
Listening to Professor Kukui’s lecture
made me want to give it a try!
Look at this!
It’s the Grass Z-Move pose!
Don’t you want to get to
use a new move, Pikachu?
Satoshi. That’s not a real pose.
What were you guys
doing over there, meow?
Don’t tell me you were
after the Crystal!
Huh... So yer after it, too?
Now ya listen up, outsiders!
Alola belongs to...
...Team Skull!
So that Crystal belongs to us, too!
This Nyarth belongs to me, too!
You little...!
Cut it out already!
What do we do about them?
They’re so obviously
mooks, meow.
They mocked our nice uniforms.
That cannot stand!
We can’t let some
friggin’ outsiders beat us.
Let’s show ‘em
the power of the locals!
Right on!
We’ll use those guys as Ratta bait
while we go get the Crystal. Ya got that?
I wanna get
the talkin’ Nyarth, too!
Ya can leave that to me.
I got a plan.
Bro, yer the best!
How about we compete to see
who gets the Crystal?
Very well... On one condition!
Whoever loses becomes
the winners’ subordinates!
Sounds good, meow.
We were thinking the same thing!
That settles it, then.
Yeah! I’m gettin’ chills!
Li’l Nyarth,
yer gonna be mine!
It’s on!
They sure can eat, meow.
First we gotta get
the Koratta away from the nest...
Shouldn’t ya get that
away from yer head first?
Don’t worry about it...
Ya can just keep on
lazin’ about, I guess...
Let’s go.
See ya, Li’l Nyarth!
What an awful feeling.
Let’s enact our own plan, meow!
A trap filled with
a mountain of berries, meow!
And if I sprinkle on this powder I bought on mail order,
which brings out a delicious scent of the berries,
those Rattarars will be lured by the scent,
and get completely trapped!
I can’t wait!
Will this scent really lure them here?
My nose is burning, meow.
That’s so much better!
All right, here they come!
It lured them in!
But the huge Ratta isn’t here.
That one’s special.
Switch, meow!
Hey, they’re gnawing on
the cage... Is that bad?
It’s fine.
We’ve bought ourselves some time.
Let’s attack the huge Ratta
while we have the chance, meow!
We’re gonna get it away
from the Crystal, meow!
Yeah!
Yo, they do some
pretty great work.
Go on ahead, ya guys.
I’ll back ya up.
Leave it to us, Bro!
Countin’ on ya!
All right, off we go.
The talkin’ Nyarth belongs to me!
The Spike Cannon hit!
Let’s go get that treasure!
It... It didn’t work?!
Don’t chicken out!
Dustdas! Venom Shock!
Zubat! Supersonic Waves!
Here it comes!
They might as well
not even be here...
Look, meow!
That guy!
He tricked us!
Mimikkyu, you’re up!
Leave this to us, meow...
Hidoide, you help Nyarth, too!
Be nice to each other!
We will take you on, meow!
Yeah, that’s it...
Not good!
We’re not letting you
have the Crystal!
I ain’t givin’ it to
no stinkin’ outsiders!
Hurry and take it,
Yatoumori!
That’s ours!
Mimikkyu!
Hidoide, use Spike Cannon, meow!
Li’l Nyarth!
Hang in there,
my Li’l Nyarth!
Nyarth!
We’re coming!
Awesome!
Now the Crystal is mine!
Dustdas!
Don’t get distracted, Yatoumori!
Oh, fine! I’ll do it myself!
Got it!
Nyarth!
My poor Li’l Nyarth
got beaten...
He’s not yours, though!
Nyarth, are you okay?
Hang in there!
Where’s Bro?
Your Bro was using you.
You were just bait
so he could get the Crystal.
I get ya! Bro, yer so smart!
Our plan’s workin’ great!
Well... I guess it is...
Mimikkyu!
All right!
A Wood Hammer!
No way...
You did it!
That one’s amazin’!
So strong!
Thank you, Mimikkyu, meow!
Absolutely no way...
The Crystal!
Bro!
Come loose already!
Oh, ya guys!
They got out of the trap?
Ow!
I got the Evil Crystal, meow!
All right! Team Rocket wins!
Yeah!
Now you’ll have to
become our underlings!
Geez... I hate ya, talkin’ Nyarth!
If ye’ll excuse us...
Later...
What?
Did they finally realize
our greatness and freak out?
Well, the outcome of that match
was clear from the get-go, meow!
We can go home on our own,
you know!
What even is this feeling?
See you tomorrow!
Bye bye!
See you!
Have a nice day, and take care!
You, too.
Super Aqua Tornado!
Looking good, Suiren!
I really like it!
Pikachu,
let’s give the Steel Z-Move a try!
Here we go!
Wait-roto!
You got it all wrong-roto!
Move your arms like this-roto!
No, it’s like this!
Satoshi, you suck-roto!
No way!
Come forth, Z-Move!
Super Nyarth Beam: Fire!
Nothing’s happening.
Maybe the pose is wrong?
I think the Z-Ring you made
is no good, meow.
The Ring is just for show, right?
So it is the pose?
The brats were just
doing whatever, meow.
I think what you lack
is fighting spirit!
No, you lack evil!
It’s the Evil Z-Crystal, after all!
Just give it a good “Grrrr!”
I’ve got evil to spare, meow!
Come forth, Z-Move!
How’s this?!
Team Rocket has clashed with Team Skull
and gained a Z-Crystal as a result.
Will they be able to
unleash a Z-Move someday?!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Alolan Ratta!
That thing was way too big...
Alolan Ratta is
an Evil/Normal type.
Apparently the reason it’s so fat is because
it makes its underlings gather food, while all it does is eat.
Since it’s an Evil type, it would be a good fit
for Team Rocket, but...
It would be crazy expensive to feed,
so no thank you!
Next episode
Māmane’s acting strange.
Did he sleep too much?
Eat too much?
Diet too much?
Could it be... his first love?
There’s no way...
What do I do?
I can’t tell everyone that
I have to leave them!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Farewell, Māmane!
What do I do?!
I don’t want to leave!
Next time
Farewell, Māmane!