Are you all doing well-roto?
I’ll be presenting
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Laplace
Mooland
Gaburias
Kentauros
What Ride Pokémon
do Pikachu and the others ride today-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
Here we go, Nyaheat!
Great Blaze!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
During Nyaheat and Lugarugan’s
sparring match,
Satoshi and Nyaheat were swept up
by Celebi’s time travel powers and sent to Alola’s past.
Despite that, Satoshi managed to get back
and reunited with Pikachu and the others.
All’s well that ends well.
But why were Pikachu and the others
so dirty and tattered?
What could have happened
while Satoshi was gone?
Today, let’s find out!
Here we go, Nyaheat!
Great Blaze!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Such power-roto!
“That was scary...”
“Are you all right?”
“What?”
“Satoshi! Where did you go?!”
“Satoshi!”
Oh, no-roto!
Satoshi and Nyaheat are...
Satoshi!
Pikachu and the others
search for Satoshi in the forest.
“Satoshi!”
“Nyaheat!”
“Where did they go?”
Satoshi!
Where’d you go-roto?!
“Satoshi!”
“Did you find him?”
“No, I don’t see him anywhere.”
“What should we do?”
“Satoshi?”
“You’re right! It’s Satoshi!”
“Where are you going?”
“What’s this?”
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Pikachu's Exciting Expedition!
“Satoshi!”
“Wait!”
“Everyone...”
“What are you doing?!
Don’t scare me like that!”
“Geez... Hmph!”
Oh? So that wasn’t Satoshi,
but an Usokki!
Too bad!
“Satoshi...”
“Maybe he isn’t
in the forest.”
“At home, maybe?”
“Or with his friends?”
“What do you think?”
He’s asleep?!
“Oh, come on... Wake up!”
“Wh-What?!”
“Good grief...”
“Hey, Pikachu... Maybe he’s there?”
“You might be right.”
“All right, let’s go.”
“Let’s go!”
“Wait!”
Huh?
Now Pikachu and the others are gone, too-roto!
Pikachu, where’d you go-roto?!
Pikachu and the others’ search for Satoshi has
led them out of the forest and into the Pokémon School.
“Satoshi! Satoshi!”
“He’s not here, either.”
“He’s not in the school yard, either.”
“What?”
“What’s this?”
“I have an idea!”
“Listen up!”
“Ultra Guardians, move out!”
“Alola!”
“Alola! It’s just you? How unusual.”
“Oh? What’s going on with the hat?”
“Oh, I see.”
“They’re still multiplying!”
“That’s right. I don’t even know when
all these new ones showed up.”
“Wanna come in?”
“Oh! No, stop!”
“You have to stop them!”
“Assemble!”
“Well done.”
“What?”
“Amazing!”
“Here you go.”
“Thank you.”
“Say, have you seen Satoshi?
He’s disappeared!”
“No, I haven’t seen him.”
“We want help from the Ride Pokémon
to look for Satoshi!”
“I understand!”
“Ultra Guardians, move out!”
“Ult-Roger!”
“Thank you!”
“Counting on you.”
“Huh, it’s just you guys today?”
“Don’t complain if
I go too fast for ya!”
“So...”
“How far do y’all want me to go?”
“We want to go
somewhere with a good view.”
“Well, I know just the place!”
“Hang on tight, y’all!”
Where will Gaburias, with Pikachu and company in tow,
go in search of Satoshi?
“Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!”
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Celebi
Type:   Psychic/Grass
“There ain’t no place with
a better view than here!”
Pikachu and the others
find themselves...
...at the best vantage point
in all of Alola;
Lanakila Mountain on Ula'ula Island.
“All right, then, I’m goin’ back now.”
“This place is awful for my skin.”
“Thank you!”
“Don’t catch a cold!”
“Ya for real?”
“So, what do you think?”
“I’m so sleepy...”
“Wake up! Don’t fall asleep!
Come on!”
“I’m back!”
“Come on,
let’s go find Satoshi!”
“Yeah, let’s go!”
“This is a little too fast,
don’t you think?”
“Not at all!”
“Look out!”
Pikachu and the others
are rolling down...
How far will they go?
“We came all the way to the ocean...”
“Pikachu!”
“Are you all right?”
“Yes.”
“I’m soaked...”
“Everyone...”
“What’s wrong?”
“Meltan’s disappeared!”
“What?!”
“I couldn’t see it...”
“...anywhere.”
“I’ll search from the air!”
“Let’s look underwater.”
“Sure.”
“Meltan might be in this cave!”
Are you sure you should be
diving this deep?
“Hey, Meltan!”
“I was looking for you!”
Oh, my! What Pikachu and the others thought was a cave
was actually a Whaleoh’s mouth!
And now they’ve been sent flying again...
Where will they land?
“Where are we?”
“Give that back!”
“This is my shelter! I found it!”
“It belongs to Satoshi!”
“I dun’ care! It’s mine now!”
“Give it back!”
An unexpected rival appears!
Pikachu faces a tough challenge!
“Hey, what’cha doin’?!”
“Meltan, that was amazing!”
“Pikachu!”
“Meltan!”
“Everyone!”
“I’m so glad you’re all right.”
“All this worrying’s made me tired...”
“Are you all right?”
“So lucky...”
“I’m hungry, too...”
“Me, too.”
“And me.”
“There are berries up this cliff!”
“Really?!”
“Berries!”
Owww...
Huh?
Gao? Nyabby?
Where are they?
Grandpa Oh, do you know?
That tickles!
Stop it, it really tickles!
What happened to you?
You’re all dirty...
Sorry... I don’t understand.
Found you-roto!
Rotom!
I see! Pikachu and the others were
so tattered and dirty...
...because they’d been on
a grand adventure!
Seriously,
what happened to you guys?
Thank goodness they all managed to
reunite with Satoshi.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
You called?
Here I am-rotototo!
The Ride Pokémon
Pikachu and the others rode...
...was Gaburias-roto!
The Celebi I saw in the forest is the Time Travel Pokémon,
and a Psychic/Grass type-roto.
It has the power to travel across time,
but it is said to appear only in peaceful times-roto.
Next episode
They’re finished!
The new doughnuts,
the Manalo Doughnuts!
They’re triangular, meow?!
I shaped them to
look like Manalo Stadium.
Oh, come on! Doughnuts gotta be
round and with a hole in them!
That’s not true! They can be
triangular and without a hole, too!
Round and with a hole!
Triangular, with no hole!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Gladio and Lilie!
Chasing the Father’s Illusion!!
Can’t you compromise and make them
triangular with a hole, meow?
Next time
Gladio and Lilie!
Chasing the Father's Illusion!!