Alola!
You’ll need to make a prediction
for today’s PokéProblem!
Try to predict which Pokémon
wins the Pokémon Pancake Race today!
Kiteruguma
Pikachu
Nekkoala
Raichu
We’ll announce the results
at the end of the episode!
What’s this? Amakaji is doing
something rather odd.
What could she be up to?
Looking good, Amakaji!
It looks like Satoshi and his friends
are also confused.
What has Amakaji been doing-roto?
Who knows...
Mao!
Don’t talk to me right now!
Got it...
Keep it up, Amakaji...
One last push!
Goal!
And you were pretty quick!
If we keep training every day until the race,
you can get even better!
Race?
Oh, right. You don’t know.
I’m talking about Melemele’s traditional
Pokémon Pancake Race.
Pokémon Pancake Race?
Never heard of it-roto.
I know!
You should enter, Satoshi!
Anyone can join the race,
and the rules are simple!
It’s fun!
Guess I’ll give it a try!
It’s like a festival
on the day of the race!
Really?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Great Alola Pancake Race!
Let’s see... That should be
all the shopping taken care of.
Do you really need to
buy this much?
I’ve got a gluttonous freeloader
in my house, see.
All right,
let’s take a quick break.
Yeah!
“Freeloader”? Who-roto?
Welcome, Professor Kukui.
Hey, Noa!
It’s that time already?
It’s the Pokémon Pancake Race!
You know about it, Satoshi?
Mao told me.
She invited me to participate!
You should! It’s a lot of fun!
Huh? Aren’t you
the lady on the poster?
You can call me Noa.
Raichu!
This is my partner.
Noa and Raichu are
last year’s champions.
Champions?!
Awesome!
This one looks
completely different!
It’s floating in the air...
That’s so cool!
Raichu, Alolan form.
Mouse Pokémon.
Electric/Psychic type.
It uses psychokinesis to
control electricity.
It hops aboard its own tail, using psychic power
to lift the tail and move about while riding it.
It’s not just Electric,
but a Psychic type, too?
Here you are!
Our store’s special
Alola Pancakes!
They look as delicious as ever!
Amazing!
The stacks you have to carry during the race
are this tall, too.
Sounds great!
If the stack crumbles or the pancakes fall off the plate,
you’re disqualified on the spot.
It’s really fun!
Pikachu, let’s join!
A rival appears, Raichu.
Noa, please teach me about racing!
Okay.
Just wait ‘til lunch time is over.
All right!
All right! Then let’s pray
that you and Pikachu perform well...
...and let’s eat!
It’s great!
So good!
You want some, too, Pikachu?
You, too, Iwanko.
Keep it up, Pikachu!
Go, Pikachu!
He’s gradually speeding up from
a starting point of 5 kilometers per hour-roto!
Hey, look at that.
What’s that floating Pokémon over there
that looks kinda like a Raichu?
Actually, you know what?
It’s pretty cute, isn’t it?
Is it? Let’s see...
It actually is a Raichu.
It seems that Raichu in the Alola Region
look like that.
What a fascinating place Alola is,
changing the appearances of Pokémon, meow...
One last push, Raichu!
You got this, Pikachu!
His speed’s risen to
15 kilometers per hour-roto!
The brat boy and Pikachu
are here, too, meow.
Oh, you’re right.
And the talking Index.
Great run, Raichu!
Looks like we might have
a shot at victory this year, too!
The pancake stack
is perfectly intact.
For your next attempt,
try to cut your time by at least three minutes-roto.
You gave it all you had, Pikachu.
There they go again. Oh, Raichu...
Pikachu ran so well that
I could hardly believe it was his first go.
He didn’t drop the plate
or any of the pancakes, either.
If you just keep practicing,
you might rank pretty high in the race.
Really?! All right, Pikachu!
I see...
The Pokémon Pancake Race, huh?
What’s that?
This, meow.
This is that Raichu and trainer
from before, meow!
You’re right!
They were last year’s champions?
The winning pair receives
a one-year gift card...
...for free pancakes
anywhere in Alola, meow!
Free pancakes?!
We’re entering
the Pokémon Pancake Race, too!
What?!
Listen up!
Whatever it takes, we will win...
...and get that one-year gift card!
R-Roger...
Beneath the shining blue sky,
the day has once again come for
Melemele Island’s traditional Pokémon Pancake Race!
Alola TV will be broadcasting this race
to the entire Alola Region!
Now let me show you
today’s race course!
The competitors will start out
clearing various obstacles...
...such as inclining hills and balancing beams,
to meet up with their partner Pokémon.
Then the Pokémon
will get into a wagon,
at which point the trainer must
pull them to the next point.
From that point on,
the Pokémon must compete on their own.
If they use any moves or tricks to hinder other Pokémon,
they will be disqualified instantly.
We’ve got plenty of participants ready
at the start line this year, too!
Have fun!
Do your best!
Yeah!
Got it!
Cheer us on!
Of course!
Here’s Competitor Noa,
who won last year!
How are you feeling?
I hear this race was established long ago,
for the enjoyment of Melemele’s people.
So my first goal is to have fun,
the second is that nobody get hurt,
and the third is to win the race...
I suppose?
Noa’s really confident.
She’s that good?
She swept the competition
last year!
Satoshi, that wasn’t fair!
I told you about this race,
and then you get to go off
and practice with Noa!
W-Well it just
kinda happened... Sorry.
I’m just joking.
Her partner, Raichu,
is full of confidence as well-roto!
Pikachu and I have
just as great teamwork as they do!
Amakaji and me, too.
Togedemaru and I are
one in spirit!
Bakugames and I
have hearts hotter than fire!
Wait, Ashimari.
I’ll be right there!
I’m glad everyone
on the race tracKimawari...
...seems to be so gleefuLizardon!
And everyone’s off!
First, the trainers fight it out!
Pocket MonsTattsu!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Raichu
..                 (Alolan Form)
Type:   Electric/Psychic
H-Hey, wait up, everyone!
Oh, my! Competitors are getting
disqualified in droves!
Thank you, Betobeton!
Just like every year, Betobeton are feasting
on the fallen pancakes!
Thank you...
One-year gift card...
Free pancakes!
All I can eat, for free!
One-year...
...What’s this awful feeling?
No, don’t!
Hey... Wait, wait, wait!
Don’t run away, pancakes!
Noooo!
Pikachu, once we’re
past these obstacles,
it’ll be time for the
Pokémon-only race!
I’ll circle around to the goal and cheer for you!
Give it all you’ve got!
Principal Okido’s partner
is Nekkoala-roto?
Nekkoala. Drowsing Pokémon.
Normal type.
A Pokémon perpetually asleep
thanks to its ability, Hyper Sleep.
The log it holds was given to it
by its parents at birth.
Its actions are thought to be
its tossing and turning due to its dreams.
Heavy...
Well of course, meow, Kojiro.
This is the turbo engine-powered mech,
Champion Racer Kid, meow.
No, you’re too heavy,
even taking that into account!
I think you guys may have put on some weight
since we started living with Kiteruguma!
Because you’ve just been
eating and sleeping!
Gulp!
No, that’s not true, meow!
It’s all right, Bakugames...
It’s just... fine...!
I’ve had... an epiphany...
We are...
...not cut out for the
Pokémon Pancake Race!
I’m so sorry, Togedemaru.
I’ve already been disqualified.
Let’s go cheer on the others.
Ow! Sorry! Sorry!
I said I’m sorry!
Using Pokémon moves to attack other racers
is against the rules!
Mimikkyu! Don’t!
Amakaji!
Mimikkyu!
Ashimari!
Oh, my goodness!
Amakaji, Mimikkyu and Ashimari...
...have all been disqualified
almost simultaneously!
Why, that Mimikkyu!
I can’t keep my balance, meow!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Double your speed-roto!
Are you having a nice dream,
Nekkoala?
Keep it up, Raichu!
Just a little further, Ny—
I mean, Kiteruguma!
All the Alola Pancakes we can eat,
for a whole year!
Come on! It’s all on you!
The one running at the front of the pack
is Raichu, the favorite to win!
Following it are Pikachu,
Kiteruguma, and then Nekkoala!
Raichu and Pikachu are locked
in an intense dead heat!
Good, Pikachu!
Impressive.
This is getting interesting.
Pikachu, Raichu,
both of you give it your all!
Snowball?
We’ve been outrun, meow...
This bear costume
is too hot, meow!
But this is when we make
our last stand, meow!
Nya— I mean, Kiteruguma
still isn’t here?!
If he doesn’t win...!
Champion Racer Kid,
prepare turbo!
Engage, meow!
Excuse us, meow!
Now we just have to outrun
that pesky Raichu and Pikachu, meow!
Turbo engine max power, meow!
H-Here he comes!
Go! Go! Kiteruguma!
Blast on through!
Leave ‘em in the dust!
O-Oh my! Kiteruguma pursues
with frightful momentum!
It’s nearly caught up
to Raichu and Pikachu in the lead!
I see them-roto!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Don’t give up, Raichu!
We got this. We can win, meow!
Victory shall be ours, meow!
What, meow?!
O-Oh, my! The front runner, Kiteruguma, seems to have been a fake!
Rule breakers are
promptly disqualified, of course!
What even is this feeling?
The winner is Nekkoala!
Following it, Raichu and Pikachu dive across the goal line at the same time,
winning a shared second place!
Quite an unexpected conclusion!
This is what makes the
Pokémon Pancake Race so fun!
Oh, thank you, thank you!
ArigaTosakinto!
That was a great run-roto!
You really did great, Pikachu!
That was a fun race,
wasn’t it, Raichu?
Now, now... Don’t look so down.
We’ll try again next year!
I’ll try not to drop
the pancakes next time.
So please
cheer up, Togedemaru.
Ashimari, hopefully you’ll learn to make balloons
that won’t pop quite so easily.
Say, Lilie! You should join the race next year
along with that baby!
The one in the egg?
Huh? Hey, where are
Kaki and Bakugames?
Where indeed-roto?
I will never... I will never...
I will never...
...admit defeat!
O-Oh, no!
What’s wrong, Lilie?
What?
It’s Snowball...
Snowball?
That’s what I’ve been calling the egg
while looking after it.
Because it’s white
and rolls around like a ball...
It’s glowing!
The egg has hatched...
...into a beautiful Pokémon
with white, fluffy fur.
Now then...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for your patienCelebi!
The answer to the PokéProblem was Nekkoala!
Did you get it righTamanta?
Well done, Nekkoala!
Last year’s winner of the
Pokémon Pancake Race was Raichu!
It’s an Electric/Psychic type.
It focuses psychic energy into its tail and
rides it like it’s surfing. It was quite the formidable foe!
I didn’t think Nekkoala stood a chance,
to be honesTabunne!
I got a one-year gift card!
Nekkoala... The race is over...
GeeZoroark...
Next episode
It’s hatched!
It’s a pure white Rokon!
All Alolan Rokon are white!
Really? I didn’t know!
Isn’t this great, Lilie?
I...
What’s wrong?
I... can’t touch her!
What?!
What should I do?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Proof of Courage: Lilie and Rokon!
Next time