Alola!
You all doing all right?
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Good luck!
Gyarados
Starmie
Koduck
Tosakinto
Which Pokémon battles Pikachu today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi and the others have left the Alola Region
to go on an extracurricular class in Kanto.
Today they’ll get to experience
a Gym Battle at Hanada Gym.
Huh? There’s something there.
It’s Koduck!
It’s so cute!
Koduck, good job looking after
the place while I was out.
Welcome to my Hanada Gym!
I haven’t felt like this in a long time!
Now I really want to
get right to the battle!
Let me introduce you again.
This is the Hanada Gym Leader,
the Water-type Pokémon user, Kasumi.
Nice to meet you!
The former Nibi Gym Leader,
the Rock-type Pokémon user Takeshi.
A pleasure!
I want your battles with these two
to be as intense as a Blast Burn!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way! (We’re waiting!)
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Gym Battle!
Z-Moves VS Mega Evolution!!
Pokémon Trainers
in the Kanto Region...
...travel from Gym to Gym
to battle the Gym Leaders there.
If they win those battles, they receive a Gym Badge
as a symbol of their victory.
The Hanada Gym gives out
the Blue Badge!
And this is the proof of victory
against the Nibi Gym, the Gray Badge!
It’s so beautiful!
Yeah!
You collected the Badges
from Kanto, right?
Sure did!
I got all eight of them!
Ours he got out of pity, though.
Yeah, I guess that did happen.
Is that true, Satoshi?
Once you’ve gathered eight Badges,
you can challenge the Pokémon League!
Pokémon League?
It’s a Pokémon battle tournament
where plenty of strong trainers gather!
Well then, let’s get right into some
mock battles with Kasumi and Takeshi!
Who wants to go first?
Me!
I want to fight Kasumi!
Okay! You’re on!
One more for Kasumi!
I want to face Takeshi.
So do I!
I wanna battle both of you!
I... I don’t know...
Hang on! Well then,
how about this?
Now, let’s do this!
Yeah!
Guys! She may not look it,
but Kasumi’s pretty tough!
Give it your full power!
What do you mean, “pretty tough”?
Suiren, Mao!
Don’t hold anything back!
Leave the recording to me-roto!
All right, let’s do this!
Amamaiko!
Magical Leaf!
Ashimari!
Bubble Beam!
All right!
That did the trick!
Koduck!
Water Gun!
You’re kidding!
Amazing, Ashimari!
She absorbed the whole thing!
Pretty interesting, Suiren.
But what now?
Launch the balloon!
When Suiren and Ashimari get to use their balloons,
they’re absolutely incredible!
Impressive. But my Koduck
is really strong in tight spots!
Use Mindpower!
Huh?
Why isn’t it using the move-roto?
Kasumi’s Koduck is a bit slow.
Another Magical Leaf!
Oh, I’m sorry!
That was a nasty sound!
Oh, don’t worry about it.
Here it comes!
What? What’s happening?
Mindpower? Why now?
Koduck, that’s enough.
Let Amamaiko and
Ashimari down.
Guess that’s that.
Kasumi and Koduck
sure make a great team!
You’ve both got
great battle instincts.
Really? That makes me so happy!
I feel a bit more confident now.
What’s wrong?
Oh, he’s noticed the damage
he took from hitting his head.
How dense can you get-roto?
Koduck is so cute!
I know, right?
He’s such a little cutie!
Now, we’re up next!
All right, Togedemaru!
Use Shocking Prickles!
Huh? It didn’t work at all!
Indeed.
Why? Ishitsubute is
a Rock/Electric type!
Electric moves should work!
Oh, I think you’ve got it confused
with Alolan Ishitsubute.
Kantonian Ishitsubute are
Rock/Ground type.
They’re immune to electricity!
Oh, of course, regional forms!
What a blunder...
Māmane, leave this to us!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Ishitsubute, use Gyro Ball!
Awesome!
What? Gyro Ball is
an offensive move, isn’t it?
If you train right,
you can use it like this, too!
That isn’t even in any of my books.
Gym Leaders are incredible!
I can’t beat that.
Mind you, I learned to battle this way
from a certain challenger of mine!
Well, everyone?
Did you feel some of the
complexity of Pokémon battles?
Yes!
A Pokémon’s type and
the moves it learns...
Those, and the way you raise them,
can create infinite ways to battle!
I’ve gotta know the opposing
Pokémon properly, too,
or else I’ll just make mistakes
like the one I just did.
Well, now it’s
Satoshi and Kaki’s turn!
Professor, I want to fight!
I want to have a serious battle with Takeshi!
I want a serious match
with Kasumi, too! Can I?
I wonder, can you really beat me?
Don’t regret this later, Kaki.
What an unexpected development.
Well then, don’t hold back!
First, Kaki VS Takeshi!
I’ll be the judge.
It’ll be a one-on-one battle.
When one side’s Pokémon can
no longer fight, the battle is over.
I’m pretty confident in
my battling skills.
Sounds promising. We Gym Leaders want to see
teamwork between Pokémon and their trainers!
That’s more important than
who wins and who loses.
All the more reason for me to
be confident! Bakugames!
This is my partner!
It’s huge!
Oh, it’s Haganail!
Haganail. Iron Snake Pokémon.
Steel/Ground type.
Tempered underground under high pressure and heat,
its body is harder than any metal.
Um... Steel types are weak
against Fire types,
so Bakugames has an advantage!
But Fire types are weak
against Ground types,
so you could also say that
Haganail has an advantage.
So in the end,
it’s fifty-fifty, huh?
Kaki, Takeshi!
Show us a good battle!
Let the battle begin!
Bakugames, let’s go!
Flamethrower!
Haganail, use Gyro Ball!
What?!
I just showed you this, didn’t I?
Go! Attack with Bind!
Trap Shell!
Wow, you’re good!
You, too!
Use Dragon Tail!
Dig!
Bakugames,
it’ll come at you from below!
Awesome...
Bakugames, we’ll be in trouble if this drags on.
Let’s finish this at once, with a Z-Move!
I see. So you’re using one of those “full power” Z-Moves
I’ve heard so much about!
In that case, I’ll fight with
my full power, too!
I’m a strong, rugged rock man!
What’s that?
Here I go! Mega Evolution!
Mega Evolution?!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Mega Haganail
Type:   Steel/Ground
Mega Haganail!
Gotta record this-roto!
What’s this? It got even bigger!
So cool!
This is Mega Evolution?
That’s right. Mega Evolution is a
mid-battle power-up phenomenon,
achieved through a Pokémon and their trainer
making their hearts one.
Now show me your Z-Move!
Sure! I won’t lose!
Let’s go, Bakugames!
My full body, soul and power!
Dynamic Full Flame!
What?!
I-Impossible!
It withstood the Z-Move!
That Z-Move was
amazingly powerful!
It looks like it hurt
my Haganail pretty badly.
But you couldn’t quite
finish the job.
Stone Edge!
Bakugames, use Dragon Tail!
Bakugames!
It’s over! Bakugames is unable to battle!
Haganail wins!
They lost!
Bakugames did his best,
but even so...
This is a Gym Leader...
This is getting archived!
This is getting archived-roto!
Huh?
Mega-evolved Pokémon return to
their normal forms when the battle ends.
Good work, Haganail.
Come back!
Are you all right, Bakugames?
Garagara, I know you’re upset that they lost,
but they put up a commendable fight!
What do you all think?
My palms were sweaty
from the tension!
I’m still so excited!
Right? Battles are so much fun!
Kasumi, we’re up next!
I know. Don’t be in such a rush.
Awesome! It’s a water arena!
Now this is what Hanada Gym
should be like!
The battlefield can change
depending on the Pokémon.
Does he realize that this
puts him at a disadvantage?
Where are his Pokémon
supposed to stand?
It’s all right, Māmane!
Pikachu, counting on you!
I figured you’d choose Pikachu.
Yeah, of course!
Kasumi is a Water-type trainer-roto!
The Electric-type Pikachu
has the advantage-roto!
Kasumi VS Satoshi. The rules are the same
as the last battle. One-on-one!
Are you ready, Satoshi?
Yeah!
The world-class beauty:
the tomboyish mermaid!
Go, my steady!
Gyarados, huh?
Gyarados! Atrocious Pokémon!
Water/Flying type!
A tale is told of a town
that angered Gyarados.
Before the sun rose the next day, flames utterly
consumed the town, leaving not a trace behind!
Gyarados VS Pikachu! Begin!
Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
Hydro Pump!
How’d you like that?
We’re blocking your Electric moves with water!
Does not compute...
Lightning Speed!
Follow it up with an Electro Ball!
Rain Prayer!
It’s raining.
But how? We’re inside the Gym!
It feels great!
Don’t worry about it, Pikachu!
Gyarados!
Hurricane!
Such power!
Well, Satoshi?
You can’t escape, can you?
A Hurricane in the rain...
Good strategy, Kasumi!
She’s even shutting down the Electric moves
that you’d expect her to struggle with!
This is Kasumi’s anti-Pikachu strategy!
Pikachu, are you all right?!
Satoshi, pay attention!
Well? Looks good on me, doesn’t it?
You, too?!
Strongly, valiantly, beautifully!
My blue sweetheart!
Mega Evolution!
I’m having fun, Kasumi!
Me, too!
Hydro Pump!
We’re not letting you get away!
Crunch!
Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
There’s no way,
in their position!
Jump on to Gyarados!
Now! Iron Tail!
Amazing! It hit!
You two don’t disappoint.
Here it comes again, Pikachu!
Hurricane!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
The combo of Rain Prayer
and Hurricane!
No challenger who’s come here
has ever broken through this!
Glad you told me, Kasumi!
Busting through stuff like that
is what makes battles fun!
What are you talking about?
Pikachu, can you hear me?
Climb the Hurricane!
What?
Does not compute...
Use Lightning Speed
to run on the electricity!
He’s using the electricity
as footing?!
He’s out!
Yeah, that’s just like you.
Pikachu, time for our Z-Move!
Go, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Gyarados is unable to battle!
Pikachu wins!
All right! We did it, Pikachu!
Gyarados, you did well.
You’ve gotten stronger, Satoshi.
Of course I have!
You’re still as childish
as ever, though.
What do you mean, “childish”?!
See? You’re proving my point.
Well... Calm down.
They were burning like
Wela Volcano!
That was amazing!
Yes!
I’ve decided!
I’ll be a tomboyish mermaid!
I’m sure the battles today filled you
with all kinds of emotions.
Don’t forget these special experiences,
even after you go back to Alola!
These are replicas, but take them
as a commemoration of today.
All right! Thanks!
Hanada
Cerulean, the color of water.
Such a mysterious color.
It truly is beautiful.
They’re so well made,
I’d never guess they were replicas!
The next time we battle,
I’ll get a real one!
Bring it on, any time!
Kasumi, can I come back?
Of course!
This gives me some confidence.
I will make the Pokémon League culture
take root in Alola, too!
Of course! Hang in there!
Let’s think of some Badges together,
buddYorterrie!
Satoshi...
It was fun.
It felt like the old days.
You guys should
come to Alola sometime!
Sure!
We will!
It’s a promise!
And so the Pokémon School’s
extracurricular lesson in Kanto came to an end.
Will Kukui be able to realize
his dream of a Pokémon League?
Perhaps only the skies of Alola know!
Are we in Alola yet, meow?
We’re almost there!
It’s been running for
three days already...
What even is this feeling?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Gyarados!
Gym Battles are great!
All-out battles are
the best kind there is!
Still, I didn’t expect Kasumi
to use Mega Evolution!
Mega Gyarados’s Hydro Pump
was really strong!
And its Rain Prayer and Hurricane combo
really gave us trouble, huh, Pikachu?
So that’s a Z-Ring?
That’s what it looks like, huh?
Yeah! Cool, isn’t it?
Let me have it!
Just kidding!
Next episode
Satoshi said he caught a Pokémon!
He caught Solgaleo!
What?!
Just kidding.
Is it an Electric type?
Or maybe the Fairy type, Pippi?
Oh, Satoshi!
What Pokémon did you catch?
So exciting!
Solgaleo!
What?!
It was an awesome dream!
A dream?
It was all just a dream?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Satoshi and Nebby! A Strange Meeting!!
Next time
Satoshi and Nebby!
A Strange Meeting!!