Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
The Pokémon School
The Shopping Mall
The Pokémon Center
The TV Station
Problem: Where does the Ultra Beast
first appear?
Blue: The Pokémon School? Red: The Shopping Mall?
Green: The Pokémon Center? Yellow: The TV Station?
The sun is shining again today.
The students at the Pokémon School
are on the grounds taking PE.
Mao!
Yes!
All right!
100 points-roto!
Mao, you’re so cool!
I knew you could do it.
That was a fine demonstration!
Thank you, Amajo!
Next up, it’s Lilie’s turn!
Yes! I have prepared for this.
If I use the momentum from running
to jump on the springboard, I should be successful!
Here I go!
You can realLilie do it!
I failed...
Try harder next time.
Now it’s Māmane’s turn!
I’m no good at vaulting...
You can do it if you try!
Huh?
I got over?
You did it!
That was ultra!
W-Well... Yeah...
Thanks, Togedemaru!
Now it’s Satoshi’s turn!
Yes!
Right... Rotom,
raise it up by two stacks!
Eight stacks-roto!
This is my full power!
Are you all right?
Yeah, I’m fine...
Try to focus more on
where you’re stepping next time.
Now it’s Kaki’s turn!
Eight stacks?!
I will aim far higher!
Ten stacks-roto!
It’s amazingly tall.
You can do it, Kaki!
I will surpass
the mountain of Akala!
Awesome!
How’s that?!
This is my Wela spirit!
Suiren has conquered
twelve stacks-roto!
Amazing!
I might even make it to fifteen!
That’s far above
my highest heights!
Professor Kukui,
I’ll try for twenty stacks next!
I’ll go for thirty!
Hey, hey...
We don’t have that many-roto.
I’ll prepare some for later.
Today, just practice
until you can jump properly.
Yes!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Leap 'n' Climb,
Tsundetsunde!
That’s why he wants to jump
a thirty-stack vault?
And since he wants to try,
I’ll just have to make it happen.
I’ll jump over ‘em, for sure!
Calculating the probability
of Satoshi clearing that jump...
0.001%-roto!
Huh?! Why is it so low?!
My calculations are perfect-roto.
You should start by practicing
with a lower number...
Hey! What’cha doin’,
doodlin’ on my wall?!
Oh, I’m sorry!
I’ll erase it right...
Who were you again?
Royal Satoshi!
I remember!
Onigawara Lightning!
Who’s dat supposed ta be?!
Name’s Bourgain! Got it?
President o’ da super luxurious, high-class
Rainbow Happy Resort Company!
What are you doing here?
What I do with my own land’s
my business, ain’t it?
I’m here ta build da
astonishing Bourgain Tower!
Bourgain Tower?
Dat dere’s da
finalized concept drawin’!
A high-class boutique, a high-class restaurant, and a high-class hotel...
My high-class Bourgain Tower!
And the crown jewel’s gun’ be
da high-class Bourgain statue shinin’ in th’ reception area!
It’ll be an entirely different world
from the one ya kids live in!
...Hey, what’cha doin’?!
That’s him, all right.
It ain’t even close!
Satoshi, let’s go!
Wait!
And stay out!
Get back ta work, ya slackers!
The Bourgain statue’ll be ‘ere tomorrow!
Y-Yes, sir!
What’s this?
Awesome!
That’s Professor Kukui for you!
He prepared a vaulting box
bigger than we could’ve imagined!
Can we leap over this?
I think I’ll just watch.
Me, too.
I’ll go first!
Satoshi, are you all right?
Well... I should be fine...
I’m up next!
I will surpass
the mountain of Akala!
Amazing!
He just might do it!
Easy!
He did it!
Kaki!
What happened?
Eyes...
So many eyes were...
Don’t... Don’t look at me!
Pull yourself together.
Amajo.
Don’t look at me!
Don’t look at me, eyes...
Amajo, that’s a bit much...
But he’s back to normal.
What could have happened?
Could this vaulting box be...?
Everyone! It’s an emergency dispatch call
for the Ultra Guardians!
Emergency dispatch?
Alola, Ultra Guardians.
A new Ultra Beast has appeared.
What kind of Pokémon
is it this time?
We’ll send you
all the information we have.
Rotom!
Ult-Roger!
Downloading data...
Tsundetsunde. Rampart Pokémon.
Rock/Steel type.
Block-shaped Pokémon have gathered together
to form a rampart. They stay perfectly still.
Isn’t this...?
This is the Ultra Beast?!
It’s not moving at all.
Maybe it’s a docile Pokémon?
What are we gonna
do about this?
Let’s just Ultra-get it!
It dodged-roto!
Now it’s my turn!
Like the mountain of Akala...
Dynamic Full Flame Ball!
It’s dodging our throws
with ease.
It might be better to
exhaust it a bit through battle.
All right!
Let’s all attack together!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Now, go!
Yes! Snowball!
Powder Snow!
Togedemaru! Shocking Prickles!
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
Amajo! Tropical Kick!
Garagara! Bone Boomerang!
Our attacks aren’t working?!
It’s tougher than we thought.
Then how about this strategy?
Operation:
“Surround It and Ultra-Get It”!
Lilie, you’re a genius!
Great idea!
I’ll hit it for sure.
Okay!
All right, let’s go!
Ready, and...
It expertly dodged them-roto!
I am so sorry...
We’re not done!
Yeah!
It’s hopeless...
Why...
...can’t we hit?
I am sorry, Mother.
We tried everything we could think of, but...
I see... I suppose we’ll just have to keep an eye on it.
Thankfully, it seems fairly docile at the moment.
We’ll try to think of our own plan,
so let’s try again tomorrow.
Yes.
Well done. On that note,
see you tomorrow.
Yes!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Tsundetsunde
Type:   Rock/Steel
All right! All right! All right!
Be careful.
If ya break it, ye’ll pay dearly!
Understood!
But whaddayaknow,
even ya guys can impress me sometimes.
How nice of ya ta
prepare da pedestal in secret.
I’ll pay ya a bonus later.
Thank you, Sir!
Th’ plan was to put it up after th’ tower was done,
but I guess we might as well do it now.
Were you the one
who prepared the pedestal?
No... You?
I don’t know.
We should’ve thrown a whole bunch of Balls at once,
instead of one at a time.
One of them is bound to hit!
How will you throw them-roto?
We’ll hold them like this and...
Satoshi! It’s terrible!
What?
Tsundetsunde’s gone!
It was gone by the time
we got to the School.
Did it go back to the Ultra Hole?
That would be nice...
But there is one thing
that bothers me.
Bothers you?
What’s this?
Could these be footprints?
Footprints?
Did it even have feet?
It didn’t.
Then, what is this?
Everyone! They’ve picked up
an Ultra Aura reaction from the city!
Stop-roto!
This is where the reaction
came from-roto!
Isn’t this...
Bourgain Tower?!
Did you say Bourgain?!
So Tsundetsunde is in here?
Crackle crackle crackle!
Let’s go have a look!
Right!
All right! All right! All right! Yes, there!
Be careful, now!
Dat’s it... Lower it slowly.
Hey!
You need permission to enter!
We’re the Ultra Guardians!
Huh?! Yer da kid
from yesterday, ain’t ya?!
I told ya t’ never come back!
Scram!
Listen, Bourgain,
there’s an Ultra Beast here!
Yer such a cheeky runt...
If ya wanna play house,
find somewhere else ta do it!
What do we do? The Ultra Aura reaction
was coming from here, right?
What is it, Bebenom?
Don’t tell me...!
Yes, very suspicious-roto!
What’re ya doin’?!
Da pedestal fer da high-class
Bourgain statue’s in dere!
Pedestal?
‘s right!
It’ll be done in a sec.
Put it down already!
Got it!
All right! All right! All right!
Get a good look...
Dis is da high-class,
sparklin’ gold Bourgain statue!
What’s this?
How tacky...
Who?
They’ve slimmed him down
a bit too much...
Well?! Makes ya wanna
take a picture, don’t it?
Fine, go ahead.
I’ll do ya a service, just fer today!
I knew it!
Tsundetsunde!
What’s dat? What’s goin’ on?
Tsundetsunde stood up!
What’s goin’ on? Cut it out!
My Bourgain statue’ll fall!
Watch out!
Are you all right?!
‘Preciate yer concern...
What is that thing?!
I told you, it’s an Ultra Beast!
Ultra?!
Why’d it start rampaging
all of a sudden?!
I don’t know!
Ms. Lusamine!
Ultra Guardians! We’ve discovered
another aspect of Tsundetsunde’s biology.
Tsundetsunde intensely hates having anything
on top of itself, and will try to shake it off!
So we just gotta knock
that Bourgain statue off?
W-What?!
Garagara!
Garagara, Bone Boomerang!
Aim for that Bourgain statue!
Don’t put a scratch on it!
Oh, no, we missed.
Return, Garagara!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Satoshi!
Togedemaru!
Watch out!
Thanks, Māmane, Togedemaru...
Are you all right?
If we try to climb its legs,
it will just shake us off.
Then why don’t we leap
on top of it or something?
How would we do that?
I know! Vaulting!
Vaulting?
Bakugames!
We’ll use this
as a springboard!
Oh, I get it!
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Hold on tight, Pikachu.
Go!
All right! He made it!
All’s well that ends well, huh?
It’s stuck with glue.
Pikachu, Iron Tail!
Aim for its soles!
You did it!
All right, it came loose!
Why are you still rampaging?!
It’s because you’re on top of it!
If he falls from that height,
he’ll be in trouble!
You...
Please, calm down!
It stopped...
Eyes! Loads ‘a eyes’re watchin’ me!
Please, stop!
Did Tsundetsunde listen to me?
It could be that it will calm down
in response to one who has successfully ridden it?
I see...
It’s just like
a rampaging Mooland...
Tsundetsunde’s data
has been updated-roto!
Hey, can I Ultra-get you?
I promise to send you back
to where you came from.
Go, Ultra Ball!
Tsundetsunde...
I Ultra-got you!
All right!
What’s dis?!
My Bourgain statue’s...
It looks just like you!
No, it don’t!
I’m scrappin’ Bourgain Tower.
Instead, I’ll form a Poké Baseball team and build a Bourgain Stadium!
Yes, sir!
Now, Satoshi,
return Tsundetsunde to its home.
Yes!
Come out, Tsundetsunde!
Take care on your way home!
You really were
the star today, Satoshi.
By jumping on Bakugames,
you can easily clear thirty stacks.
All right... Forty stacks!
No, I’ll even leap fifty!
Let’s do this, Bakugames!
Satoshi and the others have
returned Tsundetsunde to its own world.
The Ultra Guardians have successfully
carried out another mission!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The first place Tsundetsunde
appeared in was...
...Blue: The Pokémon School!
The Rampart Pokémon
Tsundetsunde is a Rock/Steel type.
Each one appears to be made up of
many life-forms stacked one on top of each other...
Wait, is that why it had
all those eyes glaring at me?!
So anyway, Ashimari...
Tsundetsunde’s come back?!
We have to
contact the others-roto!
That stone wall’s
been there for ages.
Next episode
Welcome! Welcome to the
Pokémon Paradise Resort!
Sure to make any Pokémon
a hundred times happier!
And that’s not all! Just for now,
entry is at a 30% discount, meow!
All right, customers keep coming!
Let’s keep up the pace and
lure in the brats, too!
Hey, newcomers! Clean the floor!
Refill the soap dispensers, too!
Yes! Right away!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
I Choose This Place!
The Pokémon Steam Paradise!!
Infiltrating an establishment
is no easy task, meow...
Next time
I Choose This Place!
The Pokémon Steam Paradise!!