Alola!
I, Hala, will be presenting
the PokéProblem this time!
Pheroache
Massivoon
Tekkaguya
Tsundetsunde
Which Ultra Beast
features in today’s episode?
Get the answer at the end!
A guest, maybe?
Hariteyama!
What is this creature?!
Satoshi, wake up!
There’s been an
emergency dispatch call!
Did an Ultra Beast emerge-roto?!
Hariteyama!
What do you intend
to do with that?
Mr. Hala!
Satoshi!
What?
Lizardon!
It’s gone already!
It was too quick for me to
get any data on it-roto!
Totally out of focus...
What was that?
Are you all right, Mr. Hala?
Indeed...
However, my Z-Crystal
was taken from me.
What?!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Beauty and the Nyarth!
The Ultra Guardians suddenly got
a dispatch call in the middle of the night.
Now, the sun has risen,
and it’s time for class!
However...?
That was quite the
long yawn, Satoshi...
Well, of course... We had to go on a mission
in the middle of the night...
I’m totally sleep-deprived...
We didn’t even find
the Ultra Beast, either...
Alola!
Alola...
You all did well last night.
We weren’t able to do any—
I-I wasn’t sleeping!
Ultra Guardians,
just hurry to the base!
Of course!
Alola, Ultra Guardians.
Alola!
We’re sorry we sent you out
on such short notice last night.
So, what kind of
Ultra Beast was it?
Burnet.
What is this?
The Ultra Beast was so fast,
I couldn’t gather any data either-roto.
We tried to analyze the data
to make some sense out of it...
Here.
So that’s what it looked like!
Do you have any other leads?
There have been several other cases of
people being attacked by that Ultra Beast since then.
What’s more, the targets are all
trainers who have Z-Crystals.
It seems they all
had their Crystals stolen.
Just like what happened
with Mr. Hala!
We’ve named
this Ultra Beast “Pheroache”.
Pheroache may have been drawn to
the energy the Z-Crystals radiate.
Energy?
Does that mean Z-Power?
Whatever the case, I won’t stand for
it stealing people’s precious Z-Crystals!
We will catch it and get them back,
whatever it takes!
Yeah!
Requesting permission to download
Pheroache’s data-roto!
Of course!
Pheroache. Lissome Pokémon.
Bug/Fighting type.
Successfully added to
the Index-roto!
If you don’t find Pheroache quickly,
it’ll cause more damage.
We’re counting on you all!
Of course!
Leave it to us!
It’s the Meltan herd!
Are you doing okay?
Your assistance is
most appreciated!
Great job!
Well then, here we go!
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Yes! Perfect!
Well done.
Another huge batch of berries
ripe for eating today, meow!
A Pokémon?
What beauty, meow!
Do you need something, meow?
You can have this
if you’d like, meow.
What a cool gaze!
If you keep staring at me
with those eyes, I...
Nyarth, what’s wrong?
Wait, Alola had
a Pokémon like this?
Hey! Give those b—
Wait, meow! Cool Beauty!
Wait, meow!
Never before have I met
a Pokémon as beautiful as you, meow!
This is fate, meow!
Please, tell me your name, meow!
I’m not getting through, meow...
Could you be shy, meow?
Well, then, since you’re so beautiful,
I’ll just call you Beauty, meow!
I just can’t live on
without you, meow!
You’re collecting Z-Crystals, meow?
Well, then...
Grin...
I know someone who
has loads of them, meow!
I will aid you, meowphe!
It’s not here...
Where did Pheroache go?
Huh?!
What?!
Hey, brat boys!
Down here, meowche!
That’s Team Rocket’s...
Nyarth! What’s he up to now?!
Welcome, meowphe!
What sort of dirty tricks
are you up to this time?
Something vile indeed,
meowphe!
If you wish to stop me, you’ll have no choice
but to fire off your Z-Moves, meowche!
“Phe”?
“Che”?
What’s that about?
Come on, now, just try
using your Z-Moves on me, meowphe!
All right, have it your way!
Now, meowche, Mademoiselle!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
It’s faster than
Pikachu’s Lightning Speed?!
I knew you would be,
meowche!
This is so annoying!
Where’d Nyarth go?!
He does tend to
fall in love a lot...
There he is! Found him!
Meowphe?
Huh?
Why do you look so weird?
I have become a Monsieur befitting
of my dear Beauty, meowphe!
Who’re you calling “Beauty”?!
Give us back our Z-Crystals!
Huh? It stole the
Team Rocket’s Crystals, too?
Looks like it.
Forgive me, meowche...
But I have learned what
true love means, meowphe!
I have sworn that I will do
whatever it takes for Beauty, meowche!
Drop the delusional babble!
And drop the weird verbal tics, too, while you’re at it!
Isn’t that an Ultra Beast?
You really better give it up.
That doesn’t matter,
meowche!
Hand in hand, we will elope together
on a flight of love, meowphe!
A flight of love...
How romantic...
Really?
Now, Mademoiselle,
let us share in a sweet romance...
Please, wait, meowche!
We’re going after them!
Yeah!
Do you even realize
how messed up this is?!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moo—
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pheroache
Type:   Bug/Fighting
And then it got away?
We can’t keep up with
Pheroache’s speed-roto.
No way.
What are we to do?
If you can’t keep up,
then you’ll just have to catch it when it shows up.
Perhaps we could set up a trap?
Sauboh!
Yes, Chief!
This is the Ultra Beast
containment device I have invented:
The Sticky Stuck Soles
Sauboh Special!
You leave the Z-Crystal
here in the center as bait,
and flood the surrounding area
with a powerful adhesive gel.
When Pheroache approaches,
its soles get stuck in the adhesive gel, and...
...which... gives you the
perfect chance to catch it!
We’ll send you the
spare device right now!
Chief, help me!
Oh, come on!
What are you doing?!
Chief... Chief!
It does seem powerful,
all right...
I guess...
That should do it.
Have my Ice-Z, as well.
I’ll let out the adhesive gel.
Stand back so you don’t get stuck!
No, Togedemaru!
All right! Let’s hide!
Yeah!
There they are!
Looks like the brats’ plan...
...is to lure in the Ultra Beast
using their own Z-Crystals.
Well, then, why don’t we sneak in there and
steal all of those Z-Crystals for ourselves?
We’ll regain ours,
and get some spare change!
I’m counting on you, Hidoide.
Please, wait, meowphe!
What seems to be
the matter, meowche?
Z-Crystals out here?
It’s a trap, meow!
W-What is this?
Hold it, Pheroache!
I knew it was a tr—
We caught Nyarth...
Fail.
Pikachu!
Now we’ll just have to
face it head-on!
Yeah!
Lugarugan!
Bakugames!
Let’s do this, together!
At full power!
So fast!
I couldn’t see it!
Now, Mimikkyu!
Shadow Ball!
Wrong target!
Hidoide! Spike Cannon!
Musashi! Kojiro!
Stop it, meow!
These guys are my friends, meow!
Nyarth!
That lousy...
My... dear... Beauty!
It cannot be!
My dear Beauty!
It was just using Nyarth?
Oh, my!
That’s awful!
So, what do we do?
This is all kinds of bad...
If you’re here, that means...
It really is Kiteruguma!
She doesn’t seem like herself...
Is it just me,
or is Kiteruguma...
...fuming with rage?
So strong...
It’s got the Ultra Beast
backed into a corner...
Whoa!
My eyes can’t keep up!
Kiteruguma wins
by a landslide-roto!
I’m...
What even is this feeling?
Satoshi! Now’s your chance to
ultra-get Pheroache-roto!
Oh, of course!
Go, Ultra Ball!
All right! Pheroache...
We ultra-got you!
...Though we owe it
to Kiteruguma, this time...
Don’t say that...
That just ruins it!
Everything’s ready.
Right!
Come out, Pheroache!
Don’t come back!
Take care of yourself
back home!
Ms.ion complete-roto!
It’s over!
Now, let’s go home, too.
No, it’s not over yet.
We’ll still have to
give these back to their owners.
Oh, right...
Let’s split up and
hand them over!
One last spurt!
Hang in there, all of you.
Of course!
Come to think of it,
what happened to Sauboh?
My Sticky Stuck Soles Sauboh Special
is powerful indeed!
Why don’t you just
take off your clothes?
What a disgrace...
Musashi...
I don’t...
No need to be so humble.
Musashi!
Kiteruguma got those berries
for us, so just eat!
Yeah!
We’ll have some, too.
Thank you, meow...
This is where I belong, meow...
Tell us something we don’t know.
Yeah.
It’s delicious, meow...
Pheroache has successfully been sent back
through the Ultra Hole to its own world,
and Nyarth, too, has gone back
to Musashi and Kojiro.
All’s well that ends well!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
So, the Ultra Beast that appeared
was Pheroache.
The Lissome Pokémon, Pheroache,
is a Bug/Fighting type.
It seems as though it senses some
uncleanness to the items of this world.
Pheroache moves too fast
for the naked eye...
Its eyesight must be
incredibly well attuned!
Should Pheroache appear again,
these will come in handy...
Goggles that lock on to life readings
and attune themselves to their movement!
Now, then, time to
test it on Aburibbon.
Next episode
Alola! It’s Ana the reporter!
Today, I’d like to deliver a
drive-by report on Professor Kukui!
Professor Kukui!
Is it true that you intend to make a
big announcement at this conference?
Yes!
I see that you have invited the
Island Kings and Queens, too...
What is it you have planned?
Sorry! I just got Amnesia!
Meaning you want us to
wait for the conference, I see...
Well then, next time,
on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Guzma, Emperor of Destruction!
Next time
Yeah! Look forward to it!