Alola!
I will be presenting
the PokéProblem this time!
Tupper
Plumeri
Kuchinashi
Guzma
Today’s episode features
Team Skull’s boss. Who is it?
Blue: Tupper?
Red: Plumeri?
Green: Kuchinashi?
Or Yellow: Guzma?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Pokémon School is
as peaceful as always.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
In the school yard...
This is our full power!
Super Spiral Combo!
It worked!
Amazing!
So that’s the Steel-type Z-Move!
You did it, Pikachu!
That was so intense!
I got it all on video-roto!
Now, Pikachu knows
three types of Z-Moves!
Electric, Normal and Steel!
Looking at them made me
want to use a Z-Move, too!
I know, right?
Hey, everyone!
It’s almost time!
Huh?
Oh, that’s right!
Professor Kukui told us to assemble
at Aether Paradise, right?
He claimed to have an important
announcement there...
What could it be?
You’ll just have to wait and
hear it from hiMikaruge!
Gänger!
Gamale!
Hey, wait for me!
Mankey! Metang! Mantine!
Look at all these people!
Everybody!
Over here!
Professor Burnet!
We’re terribly sorry to
have kept you all waiting!
The presenter for this event
is finally here!
Professor Kukui, everyone!
You can do it, Kukui!
Now then, it’s time for
my announcement...
I’d like to officially announce
the Alola Pokémon League!
Awesome!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Guzma, Emperor of Destruction!
The Pokémon League
is easy to explain.
It’s a tournament to crown the Champion,
the strongest here in the Alola Region!
But the most important thing isn’t
who becomes Champion.
What matters is that all the trainers
and Pokémon participating fight as one...
...and clash against their opponents with all their might,
helping everyone grow!
Competitors learning
from each other...
...is the true appeal
of this tournament!
Their heated battles are sure to bring dreams,
hopes and awe to the people!
So whoever wins this tournament
is Alola’s first-ever Champion, huh?
The Champion’s, like,
the most powerful person of all, right?
If that were us, we could do
whatever we wanted here in Alola!
Yeah! We could even give the islands themselves
as a present to Sakaki, meow!
These esteemed individuals have
lent their support to my project!
The Island Kings,
Mr. Hala and Mr. Kuchinashi!
The Island Queens,
Ms. Lychee and Ms. Hāpu'u!
As well as President Lusamine
of the Aether Foundation!
I had no idea!
Hey, Hāpu'u!
Oh, Satoshi!
Don’t disturb!
R-Right...
First of all, we must thank
Professor Kukui!
We, the Island Kings and Queens,
were deeply moved by his passionate message.
and therefore we have chosen
to aid him however we possibly can!
As I’m sure you are all aware,
the proud custom of the Island Pilgrimage
has been passed down in the Alola Region for generations.
But there used to be another custom,
which has since been abandoned.
Namely, having those who have
completed their Island Pilgrimage...
...battle at the summit
of Lanakila Mountain.
I believe this truly was a battle to
determine the Champion of Alola!
Putting it simply, Professor Kukui is reviving that custom
and opening it to everyone.
Trainers and Pokémon who wish to strengthen one another,
competing to prove their might...
We wish to make the League
that kind of tournament.
Hearing their wishes, we at the Aether Foundation
decided to fully back this tournament!
Look at this!
This is the main stadium!
It’s not quite finished yet,
but we wish to make this the symbol of
the Alola Pokémon League... A stadium of dreams!
It will soon be time for
the long-awaited Alola Pokémon League!
Let’s all have fun and
build it up together!
En...
...ter, please!
We’re waiting for you!
The Pokémon League is the best!
Yeah! Truly the stage of dreams!
I’ll win, for sure!
As if I’d lose! Now I’m fired up!
Would you all like to participate, too?
What?
Yeah! The more, the merrier!
Great idea!
Yeah! It sounds fun!
Serious battles are great!
You get to go all out
against your rivals!
Yeah!
I hope I don’t get put up
against Satoshi or Kaki...
What’s this?
You feel like joining, Māmane?
W-Well... Yeah...
Kuwagannon just evolved,
after all!
You can do it!
Lilie, you can do it, too!
You did well in that
Double Battle, after all!
What should I do...?
What will you do, Mao?
I’m not sure, either...
Suiren?
I will win!
Classic Suiren!
Well, I’m super happy! I can’t believe
I get to fight in a Pokémon League in Alola!
Right, Pikachu?
Hey, yo! We’re Team Skull!
Numskulls! The boss is back!
Let’s get high!
Yay! Mr. Guzma!
I can’t handle this stupid world!
Beat down and smash this rotten world!
Smash! Trash! Wreck! Break!
Enough with being nice!
Let out steam with destruction!
Full power! Blue skies!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
We’re the famous Team Skull!
Put your hands up, y’all!
Yeah!
My foulest, greatest brothers,
how are you doing?!
As foul and blue as can be!
My irritation’s as great as can be!
That’s life.
Nothing you can do about it.
Yeah!
Mr. Guzma!
Big Sis Plumeri!
Big news, yo!
Man, you’re noisy...
Pipe down!
Huh?! Oh, I’m sorry...
Well, ya see, there’s gonna be
a Pokémon League in Alola!
Pokémon League?
Even the Island Kings’re in on it!
It’s all they’re talkin’ ‘bout on TV...
All of Alola’s all festive ‘bout it!
Didn’t we have
a half-broken TV over here?
Huh?
The trick’s to hit it
at a 45 degree angle.
Today, we’re running
a three-hour special to commemorate...
...the announcement of
the Alola Pokémon League!
The Pokémon League is
easy to explain.
It’s a tournament to crown
the Champion...
You look great on TV, too!
Oh, stop, you’re embarrassing me...
Your performance was really cool!
Hey, do you think Royal Mask
will participate in the League, too?
Huh?!
W-Why are you asking me?
What? “Why”?
What a naïve question-roto.
Well, you know... He’s a mysterious,
anonymous masked man...
His actions are
shrouded in mystery, too.
I can’t say if he’ll participate or not.
Still, I can’t wait!
Everyone! Starting tomorrow,
we’ll train for the League!
We Island Queens and Kings...
...will be acting as referees
to ensure the battles are fair.
I am most pleased to be able to
partake in this event!
Isn’t this enough?
Mr. Hala has a message to wrap this up.
Pokémon battles enable
both trainers and their Pokémon to grow!
And this goes for both sides,
as they all aid in each other’s growth as well!
I wish for the Alola Pokémon League
to become a place of learning for all involved.
Battlin’ sure is complicated...
Yo! Sounds fun, don’tcha think?
“Fun” how, yo?
It ain’t got nothin’ to do with us!
Silence!
What’s the plan?
It’s obvious, isn’t it?
I’ll destroy that miserable
Pokémon League!
Get ready! We’re heading
to Melemele Island!
Yeah!
Feels great!
Training!
Whoa, they’ve already put up posters!
All right! Let’s do some training
for the League, Hidoide!
Again, you’re...
...doing it... wrong...
If you wanna train,
then train with me!
Not used to seeing you
this motivated, meow.
I’m gonna be the first-ever
Pokémon League Champion!
Yo, yo!
“Pokémon League”?
“Champion”? Get real, yo!
I can’t handle this stupid world!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
Smash!
Trash!
Wreck!
Break!
Enough with being nice!
Let out steam with destruction!
Full power! Blue skies!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
We’re the famous Team Skull!
What’s this? A rap battle?
We can’t let ‘em beat us, meow!
To protect the world
from devastation!
To preserve world peace!
Championing the evils
of truth and love!
We’re the lovely, charming villains!
Musashi!
Kojiro!
And Nyarth, meow!
Team Rocket
soars through the galaxy!
protects us from devastation!
Space out...
And get a kick in the back!
Blast off!
Yo, they’re good!
They look kinda familiar...
Ya wanna fight us?
Who are you?
But fine! Bring it on!
What a waste of time.
If you’re so hyped up about that dumb Pokémon League,
then I’ll take you on myself!
Boss, leave this to me...
Nah, this’ll make a perfect
warm-up before Kukui.
Who’s this high-and-mighty guy?
Ya guys don’t know?!
Destruction in human form!
The king of outlaws!
Team Skull’s boss,
Mr. Guzma!
Bring it on, all of you at once.
You said it, not me!
Don’t cry when we’re done, meow!
All right! Leave this to me!
I’ll destroy you.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Sonansu
Type:   Psychic
It only took him a second
to take out Hidoide...
Nuikoguma...
And that means...
What even is this feeling?
So, the first Pokémon League...
Yo! Yo! Yo! Yo!
Yo, Kukui!
Yo! Yo! Yo!
Team Skull?!
Get down here, Kukui!
We wanna talk with ya!
Everybody,
wait in the classroom.
But...
I’ll be fine.
I don’t know what you want with me,
but class is in session.
Save it for later.
You sure are cold.
Guzma!
Yo! Yo! Ya scared?!
Why are you here?!
We’ll let you all see it, too!
The special match between
Kukui and Team Skull boss!
Oh, you’ve come to battle me?
You think too small. I’ve come...
...to destroy you.
I get that you want new stuff...
...to replace those stuffy old customs,
like the Island Kings or the Grand Trials...
But a Pokémon League?
That’s no good.
‘Cause everyone already knows
who the strongest trainer is!
Yeah! Mr. Guzma’s
the greatest, yo!
If you think so,
then just join the League yourself.
Prove in battle that you really are the strongest,
and that it isn’t just talk.
I won’t fall for that trick!
If you refuse to back down,
then I’ll just wreck your League!
I won’t let you do that!
And that’s why I came to
destroy you first.
You haven’t changed one bit, Guzma.
Hey! That’s Mr. Guzma to you!
If you want a Pokémon battle,
then you can fight me!
We’re talkin’
important stuff here!
Don’t interrupt us, yo!
You use Z-Moves?
Yeah! And I’ve cleared
four Grand Trials!
This kid has the same stench
Kukui does.
I love your foulness!
Fine! I’ll take you on!
Wait, Satoshi!
Let me do this, Professor!
All right.
But I’ll be the referee.
Before I destroy you,
I’ll destroy everything you care about!
And what’s that
supposed to mean?!
Satoshi is strong.
It won’t be that easy.
It won’t be that easy...
for who?
Satoshi! You gotta win this!
Sure! Leave it to me!
Pikachu, I choose you!
I choose this one!
Who’s that Pokémon?
Gusokumusha. Hard Scale Pokémon.
Bug/Water type.
The shell covering its body
is as hard as diamond.
Its claws, which it can extend and retract at will,
are its greatest weapons.
Electric-type moves are
super effective on Water types-roto!
This is a good match-up
for Pikachu-roto!
Begin!
First Impression.
Pikachu!
What was that move?!
That was First Impression!
Nobody’s ever dodged it!
Use Iron Tail!
It’s like it didn’t do anything!
Use Pin Missile.
Electroweb!
Use 100,000 Volts!
It deflected the super effective
Electric move-roto!
Then let’s show
the results of our training!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
A Z-Move!
Go! Go!
This is our full power!
Super Spiral Combo!
It bounced right off?!
Aqua Break!
Pikachu!
Lightning Speed!
Use Poison Jab!
Pikachu was poisoned-roto!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Use Iron Tail!
Pin Missile!
Pikachu!
He beats ya down and beats ya down
and never lets up!
That’s Mr. Guzma for ya!
Are you okay?!
All right! We’re not done!
Lightning Speed!
You waste your time.
Use Poison Jab!
Well done!
Gusokumusha says you’re so weak,
it lost interest.
What?!
Are you throwing the match?
I have no interest in battles
where the outcome’s obvious.
You can’t say that for sure
unless you finish the fight!
Gimme a break.
What’s even the point?
Try asking your Pokémon, too.
Pikachu!
Satoshi!
Eat this.
Now that you’ve seen
Gusokumusha’s power,
you realize that Z-Moves
are unnecessary, right?
How about you join Team Skull, too,
instead of hanging out with that loser Kukui?
As if!
The Pokémon League will be nothing but
schoolyard fights between weaklings.
I’ll wreck the League itself
while all of Alola’s watching!
Mr. Guzma, yer the best!
I got chills, yo!
Are you just going to
run away like that again?
Just like you ran from the Island Pilgrimage,
and the Island King?
I’m done. I almost let this loser
throw me off again.
I came here to destroy you,
but that brat spoiled my mood.
So long.
Satoshi!
What kind of relationship does Kukui have
with Team Skull’s boss, Guzma?
And will he be able to hold
the Pokémon League without trouble?
Huh? Big Sis Plumeri...
Where’s Mr. Guzma?
He’s making destruction plans
in his room.
He’s so awesome!
Are you just going to
run away like that again?
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
Team Skull’s boss was
Yellow: Guzma!
Guzma’s partner, Gusokumusha,
is the Hard Scale Pokémon, and a Water/Bug type.
With a flashing slash of its giant sharp claws,
it cleaves seawater—or even air—right in two.
It’s got really high defenses, too,
so Pikachu wasn’t able to smash its shell.
Pikachu! If we wanna land that Z-Move properly,
we’ll just have to strengthen your Iron Tail!
Now, let loose on this frying pan!
T-That was awesome...
Pikachu...
Next episode
I’m so happy!
Oh, come on, Mother,
can’t we eat in peace?
But it just makes me so happy
to have breakfast with my family!
I’ve brought some
sweets for dessert.
What is this?!
Oh, my!
I ordered loads.
Cream-coated malasadas!
Crushed Pile gelato!
Alola Pancakes, and Berry Chocolate!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
Lilie and the Secret Mechanical Princess!
Next time