Alola!
I, Mao, will give today’s problem!
Ashimari
Nyabby
Mokuroh
Mimikkyu
Which of these Pokémon
does Satoshi catch today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Here you go, little Nyabi!
Oh, dear...
It’s a flock of Tsutsukera!
It’s that time again already?
It’s quite all right.
They only come here at this time of year.
The blessings of nature
are to be shared equally between all.
That’s the law for
those who live in Alola.
So feel free to come here
whenever you feel hungry, too!
Satoshi and Pikachu are trying to catch
their first Pokémon in the Alola Region.
They are right in the middle of
a Pokémon Battle as we speak!
Agojimushi. Larva Pokémon.
Bug type.
Its strong jaw enables it to
scrape trees and slurp out the sap.
It normally lives underground.
Satoshi!
Did you get that-roto?
Sure did!
Thanks, Rotom!
Pikachu, jump!
100,000 Volts!
To catch wild Pokémon, you first have to wear them out
in a battle before throwing the Monster Ball.
That’s a basic of
Pokémon Battling-roto!
All right!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Enter Mokuroh!
I Caught a Pokémon in Alola!!
Will he manage to get it?
He can do this!
Too bad...
You almost had it...
Pikachu!
When Agojimushi comes out,
you hit it with Lightning Speed!
Y-You’re such a scaredy-cat...
I-I-I most certainly am not!
I love Pokémon,
as a subject to learn about!
Pikachu!
Beware its sturdy jaw-roto!
Are you all right?
Damage confirmed!
Damage confirmed on Pikachu!
I’m so sorry!
I’ll show you to
the Pokémon Center.
There’s a Pokémon Center here?
That’s great! Please do, Mao!
Lilie, don’t worry about it.
Satoshi, we’ll go back to the School
and explain the situation to Professor Kukui.
Thanks, Kaki!
This time, for sure!
C’mon, Mimikkyu!
You offered to help us out,
so let me catch you!
It hasn’t been weakened at all,
so of course it’d be hard to catch, meow.
I’m trying to catch Mimikkyu because none of you
can stand up to that Kiteruguma, remember?!
If we don’t get out of here already,
we’ll be that thing’s dinner before long!
Its... dinner?!
A Gorgeous Ball?
Perfect!
D-Don’t!
It’s a valuable part
of my collection...
Collection?
You know, Monster Balls are worthless
if you don’t use them!
Wait! Please!
Do anything but—
Oh, sheesh, be quiet already!
What?!
It went in!
I did it!
You got Mimikkyu, meow!
That ball was meant
for my collection!
H-H-Hey! Let go of me!
Kiteruguma’s saying
it’s dinner time, meow!
No way!
Mimikkyu! Save us!
Mimikkyu! Mimikkyu!
What’s this?
It’s so sweet! Delicious!
I’m filled with energy!
Th-This is Mitsuhoney honey, meow!
It’s so sweet, meow!
You’re right!
This is really nice
somehow, isn’t it?
Welcome to the Melemele Island
Pokémon Center!
Please take care of him,
Ms. Joy.
Don’t worry.
Your Pikachu will be better in no time.
Happinus, if you please...
The Pokémon Center is a place where Pokémon can
recover their health and be treated for any ailments-roto.
Ms. Joy. Updated.
Information updated.
Say, Rotom, who’s that Pokémon?
Roger that! Leave it to me-roto!
Cuwawa. Posy Picker Pokémon.
Fairy type.
It releases a soothing aroma
from the flowers it’s plucked,
which heals the stamina and ailments
of both itself and other Pokémon.
It’s the perfect Pokémon to be
Ms. Joy’s assistant!
Happinus is perfect for her, too!
An accurate assessment-roto!
Happinus. Happiness Pokémon.
Normal type.
When Happinus senses sadness
with its fluffy coat of fur,
it will rush over, no matter the distance,
to share a Lucky Egg that brings a smile to any face.
We’ve restored your Pikachu
to full health.
Pikachu!
That’s great, Pikachu!
Testing-roto...
Full health restoration
confirmed-roto!
Today is the day...
I’m 100% gonna catch
a Pokémon today!
The forest behind the Pokémon School
currently has an 89% chance of Pokémon appearing!
That could be good!
I met Amakaji in that forest, too.
Wh-What Pokémon is that?
Leave it to me-roto!
Mokuroh. Grass Quill Pokémon.
Grass/Flying type.
It stores up energy during the day
using photosynthesis.
Silently it glides, drawing near its targets.
Unnoticed, it starts pelting them
with vicious kicks.
Not only was it noticed by its target,
but it utterly failed to pelt it with vicious kicks...
Quite the contrary,
it took a vicious attack-roto...
Amakaji is used to this, after all.
Used to it?
You see, Amakaji’s scent—
Leave the rest of that explanation
to me-roto!
Amakaji. Fruit Pokémon.
Grass type.
A delectable aroma pours from its body.
There are many bird Pokémon who are
lured in by this aroma, mistaking it for an actual fruit.
Wait! Here it comes again-roto!
It might be really hungry...
Are you all right?
That’s good!
What an appetite!
It’s consuming a frightening amount
at an alarming speed-roto...
Want this, too?
Ouch!
It’s got really strong legs!
Was it good?
I see. Glad to hear it!
So soft!
Say, Mokuroh.
Is it okay if I catch you...?
Hang on!
Will you catch it-roto?
Yeah!
Let’s go!
Roger that-roto!
Pocket Monsters-roto!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Mokuroh
Type:   Grass/Flying
The coast is clear!
We can get away now!
I’ve got the Gorgeous Ball
Mimikkyu went into!
And my belly’s full,
thanks to Kiteruguma, meow!
H-H-Hey, w-what are you...?!
Those jerks!
They took Kiteruguma’s
stockpile of food!
What a bunch of villains!
We’re getting it back!
What?
We owe Kiteruguma a debt for
the lodging and food!
If we ignore these jerks here,
it would go against our path of righteous evil!
Y-Yeah!
Musashi’s so manly, meow!
There it is!
It’s my turn-roto!
Tsutsukera. Woodpecker Pokémon.
Normal/Flying type.
It can peck at a rate of 16 times a second
to drill holes in trees.
It uses the holes for
food storage and for nesting.
Kerarappa. Bugle Beak Pokémon.
Tsutsukera’s evolved form.
It eats berries and
stores their seeds in its beak.
When it encounters enemies or prey,
it fires off all the seeds in a burst.
Dodekabashi. Cannon Pokémon.
Kerarappa’s evolved form.
The temperature of its heated beak can exceed
100 degrees, causing severe burns when it hits.
Oh? It’s not warm at all-roto.
How odd! This contradicts
my explanation-roto!
You had this many friends?
Wh-What?!
When asked “Wh-What?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
It’s you people from yesterday!
Team Rocket!
Let the Tsutsukera go!
Not gonna happen,
brat boy!
These jerks stole
Kiteruguma’s food!
We will take it back, to show our gratitude
for the lodging and food!
Fire, meow!
And then we’re giving Pikachu to Sakaki
as a present, too, while we’re at it!
Mimikkyu! It’s all on you!
Mimikkyu, pummel them!
I don’t even care how you do it!
A Shadow Ball, meow!
Pikachu! Electric Ball!
Mokuroh, now’s your chance!
Go save your friends!
Use Iron Tail, Pikachu!
It broke through that net
with a single kick-roto!
When...?!
One of their friends, meow?
Mimikkyu! Attack again!
That’s Mimikkyu’s
Play Rough, meow!
Pikachu!
Mimikkyu, finish them off!
That’s Shadow Claw, meow!
It can even use Shadow Claw?!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
That move... It’s Leafage!
Well done, Mokuroh!
Pikachu, are you all right?
Right! Use 100,000 Volts!
Mimikkyu!
Is this what they call...
...déjà vu?
It is Kiteruguma!
Hey, wait!
We were trying to repay our debt
for the lodging and food!
What even is this feeling?
They’re off...
Yeah...
Mokuroh looks happy.
You’re right.
Mokuroh.
Thank you. Everyone’s safe,
thanks to you.
That was a vicious kick-roto!
Later.
Let’s go home,
Pikachu, Rotom.
Go home? Weren’t you
going to catch Mokuroh-roto?
It’s fine.
Really?
Does not compute.
I mean...
Mokuroh’s got all of
these friends here!
They’re family.
So, it’s fine.
Mokuroh! Why?
Mokuroh...
You mean you want...
...to come with me?
Roto?!
I see!
I wanted to be with you, too!
Mokuroh?
What’s it doing-roto?
Isn’t it obvious?
You’re telling me
to catch you, right?
All right! Let’s go, Mokuroh!
Here’s the Monster Ball!
I got Mokuroh!
I-It’s possible to catch
a Pokémon like that-roto?!
Of course it is!
Well, I guess that’s just
Satoshi’s style!
All right, Mokuroh...
Come out!
You really like my backpack, huh?
Some Mokuroh love backpacks...
Data updated-roto...
His first new Pokémon
in the Alola Region...
A carefree glutton...
Yet someone who can display
tremendous power to protect its friends...
Satoshi has caught Mokuroh!
With a new friend by his side,
his adventure in Alola...
...has only just begun!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Mokuroh!
The Grass Quill Pokémon Mokuroh
has strong legs and is great at kicking!
Even its Tackle attack uses its legs!
Oh, yeah, and it seems like Mokuroh really likes Satoshi’s backpack.
It looks really cute
peeking out from there, doesn’t it?
Mokuroh’s asleep again...
Oh, dear...
Next episode
Today’s class is on fishing!
I’ll be the teacher!
Got it!
Suiren’s great at fishing, you know!
All right, do as I tell you.
As a matter of fact, you can even fish up
the Legendary Pokémon Kaiogre here!
What?!
Let’s go, you guys!
We’re gonna get that Kaiogre, for sure!
Come on, Suiren...
The boys are actually serious about this!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Ashimari, Do Your Balloon-est!