Alola!
I, Joy, will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Zubat
Cuwawa
Yatoumori
Dustdas
Which of these Pokémon helps me today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Thanks for the food!
Bebenom really does
like Pikachu a lot, doesn’t it?
All right, me, too!
Satoshi, are you sure
you have time for this?
Today’s the job experience day, right?
Oh, that’s right!
As usual, Satoshi is heading
to the Pokémon School in a hurry.
What’s this?
Where is he headed?
Hold it there, you!
It’s you guys!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Work Experience!
A Day at the Pokémon Center!!
Yo! Ya got a Pokémon
I ain’t ever seen before there!
Ya showin’ off?
Who do ya think ya are?
Yer way too young to be braggin’
to us, Team Skull!
I’m not trying to show off!
Satoshi, you shouldn’t bother
with these guys-roto.
You’ll be late-roto!
You’re right.
Hey!
Once yer eyes meet ours, we battle.
Ain’t that how trainers do things?
Oh, you’re so annoying...
Fine, I’ll take you on!
Pikachu!
Yatoumori!
Zubat!
Dustdas!
Yatoumori, use Scratch!
Zubat, finish ‘em off
with Leech Life!
Dodge, Pikachu!
Now, Dustdas! Venom Shock!
Looks like it’s got
a clot or somethin’...
What’re ya doin’?!
...Ew! What’s this stench?!
Now, Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
They beat us!
Dustdas, what’s goin’ on?
What’re ya doin’?!
Hey, that one smells pretty strange.
Maybe you should let
Ms. Joy have a look at it?
Mind yer own business!
Hey, let’s go!
Wait for me!
We’ll get ya for this, kid!
Will it really be okay?
Satoshi!
We’re definitely not okay-roto!
We’ll be late-roto!
Oh, no!
I’m sorry I’m late!
You cut it way too close, Satoshi.
I totally thought
you were playing hooky.
No way! I was really looking forward to
the job experience day.
Bebenom!
You’re already taking it around
with you, huh.
It didn’t get a chance to
say hi yesterday, after all.
Bebenom, these are my friends
from the Pokémon School.
It was just as rowdy
yesterday-roto.
They’ve already become
quite good friends, it seems.
They’re acting a bit
like Ho and Sui...
Isn’t it fun to have
more family members, Satoshi?
Yeah, I guess.
Does it like electricity?
Anyway, Ms. Joy sure is late.
Alola...
I hope I didn’t keep you waiting...
Ms. Joy, what’s wrong?
I just caught a cold, that’s all.
I’m completely fine...
You’re not fine at all!
Thank you, Happinus, Cuwawa...
You should get some rest,
right away!
No... I can’t take
time off from work!
Ms. Joy, please leave the
Pokémon Center to us today!
What? But...
Happinus...
We did come here to work
at the Pokémon Center, after all!
We want to be of use to you!
Please let us pay you back for
all you’ve done for us!
We’ll do our best!
I’m confident in my
Pokémon caretaking skills!
This is more than
I signed up for...
All right...
If there’s anything
you don’t understand,
there’s a job experience manual on this,
so just read that.
May I copy that-roto?
Of course.
Copying data... Copying...
Copying complete!
You can leave the manual to me-roto!
All right, I’m counting on you all...
Get well soon!
Will we really be all right?
We’ll do what we can!
Yes.
If we all work together,
it will be fine!
Well, then,
should we get ready?
Yeah!
So cute!
I’ve always wanted
to wear one of these!
By wearing this,
I will be seen as a grown-up.
I must act with
utmost responsibility!
Is this right?
It can’t be.
Right?
I’ll see if they have
male uniforms.
I’ll go, too. Togedemaru!
If you need to find something, then leave it to
Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
It’s not here... Maybe next door?
Hey, did you guys find any...
Satoshi, look at this!
Ta-daah! How does it look?
Satoshi...
That uniform...
This was all there was.
Are there any other clothes on your end?
Hey, come over here!
What?
Just come along!
Satoshi! Did you find one-roto?
It’s gotta be like this, right?
Is this not the way it should be?
No, this might be it!
Incomprehensible...
Rotom! Lend me your Laki wig!
Be careful with that-roto!
Satoshi...
What happened?
I don’t know either...
We gave him some makeup!
We did our best!
Satoshi, you’re so cute!
Satoshi has undergone
a Forme-Change-roto!
Come on! If I have to wear this outfit,
then so do you two!
No, they had male uniforms.
You have fun being dressed like that.
Alola!
Welcome to the Pokémon Center!
Sure is lively here today.
What happened to Ms. Joy?
S-She appears to have caught a cold.
She is resting in the back.
So, we’re her substitutes for today.
Now, Satoshi,
ask what he needs-roto.
Um... What do I say again?
It’s “Would you like to...”
Oh, right!
Would you like to
rest your Pokémon?
Yes, thank you.
Carry this to the back-roto.
Understood!
I’ll take... your Pokémon... then!
Tell Ms. Joy to get better soon.
Thank you, Snowball!
Alola!
Alola! Welcome to
the Pokémon Center!
Would you like to
rest your Pokémon?
Will you look after this one?
Leave it to us!
Thank you. Also, I’d like to rent a room.
Are there any open?
Room?
There are rooms for trainers
on the second floor-roto.
Māmane and Suiren will
get one ready for you-roto.
Please do.
Understood!
We will prepare one right away.
Togedemaru, let’s go!
Ashimari!
Ms. Joy does
all of this every day?
Yeah... There are all sorts of
different trainers, after all.
Satoshi! Kaki!
There’s work for you-roto!
I want you to
deliver this-roto.
It should be around here...
Isn’t that the place?
Alola!
The doughnut stand is on break right now.
Everyone’s out.
Um... We’re not customers.
We’re from the Pokémon Center.
We’ve come to
deliver some medicine.
Oh, the one I ord...
Brat...
Brat?
No, I mean... Bravo to you
for delivering it so quickly!
Um... This is what you ordered, right?
Moisturizing cream for Water Pokémon?
Yeah, that’s it!
Um, I mean...
My Pokémon needs this,
or else its skin gets all brackish!
You really care for
your Pokémon, huh?
Yeah, it’s really cute, if a bit brash.
Thank you for the cream—
A-Are you all right?
I’m fine...
This is love, you know. Love!
I feel like I’ve
seen that guy before...
C’mon...
Don’t do that, Togedemaru!
Ashimari, will you help me?
All right, hold down this part.
And you hold here.
Ready, and...
I think I understand the Pokémon Center
a bit better now.
Team Skull?!
What are you doing?!
Don’t freak me out like that!
Why are you here?!
N-No reason at all!
Could he be...
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Cuwawa
Type:   Fairy
It’s finally lunch time,
everyone-roto.
I’ll have some mix au lait.
Me, too.
I’ll have some Enecocoa!
Extra extra large!
Very well.
Oh, and ice cream!
Ta-daah! An Amamaiko lunch box!
It’s very well made.
So cute!
But your lunch is...
...something else.
James had it delivered here just now.
So luxurious!
Your lunch has
quite the impact, as well.
That was great!
Pikachu, you full, too?
I think I’ll go have
another ice cream!
That’s the third one!
That Team Skull guy’s still here!
Really?!
Does he want to come in?
Lunch time is over-roto!
Resume job experience day-roto!
Alola! Welcome to
the Pokémon Center!
The market lady!
I brought something
to make Ms. Joy feel better.
You know she’s caught a cold?
Word travels fast
in the marketplace.
Here you go.
Looks delicious!
I’m sure this’ll
make her feel better!
Thank you so much!
I’ll go give it to her.
This is for all of you.
Satoshi, there’s work for you-roto!
Go help Kaki in the back-roto!
OK!
Alola!
Looking after the Pokémon in our care
is an important job, too-roto.
All right. Leave it to me!
It’s tough for trainers to care
for bigger Pokémon by themselves.
Kentauros seems to be enjoying itself.
And I’ll be looking after this one, huh?
Nasshi!
It really is huge!
All right, Pikachu.
Let’s do this together!
Pikachu, use this!
Use that to scrub
Nasshi’s neck, like this!
Yeah, just like that!
Does it feel nice?
Bebenom, that’s...
Thank you for waiting.
Your Chillarmy is back to full health.
Thank you.
You were nervous,
but it looks like you got over that.
Yes.
Getting to interact with so many different Pokémon
is quite enjoyable.
Right?
Satoshi?
Bebenom, it’s dangerous to
touch a Nasshi’s tail!
Huh?
Hey...
I told ya, it ain’t nothin’!
You wouldn’t be here
if it was nothing, right?
Is it about Dustdas?
None o’ yer concern!
Look, just come inside for a bit.
Yer not really makin’ it
easier for me...
Just do it!
Dustdas.
What’s this smell?!
It stinks!
It seems to be in pain.
When did this start?
I dunno! It just got like this
outta nowhere!
What is it, Happinus?
Is there something in there?
It seems there’s poison
stuck in its fingertips-roto.
It might be a poison clog.
I once read that Pokémon who
use poison attacks...
...can have said poison clog up in their veins,
though it is a rare occurrence.
That’s it! When we battled this morning,
it couldn’t fire its Venom Shock.
How little care
have you taken of it?!
Huh? I hadta do somethin’?
A trainer has to
carefully look after their Pokémon!
But that’s so lame!
What would Ms. Joy do
in this situation?
Leave it to me!
Somebody get me an
earpick for large Pokémon, quickly!
Ms. Joy!
You’re all better!
I’m pretty sure
they sell earpicks in the shop!
Plenty of Dustdas get poison clogs.
They tend to live in
unsanitary environments, after all.
It’s clogged up really badly.
Here they are!
Thank you.
We’ll help, too!
Please let us do it!
We want to help it!
Then, take care of
its other fingers.
Yes!
Also, bring me some buckets.
I’ll do that!
Me, too!
Somebody, massage its hand!
Yes!
Me, too!
Massaging it will make it easier
to get the poison out.
Understood!
Buckets! Buckets!
Māmane, a bucket!
There are no buckets left!
Will a washbin work?
This won’t quite come out...
If we can get that out,
then I’m sure...
It stinks!
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
Thanks... Ashimari...
That should do it.
All right!
Looks like it’s all better.
It’s fine now?
Yes.
Look after it regularly from now on,
to make sure this doesn’t happen again.
Mind yer own business!
That’s just lame...
Dustdas, let’s go home.
What a stubborn guy.
Huh?
One earpick for
large Pokémon, please.
Oh, you’ll do it after all?
No! This is just...
Just a souvenir!
Oh, I see!
I’m so glad Dustdas is healthy again.
You can always trust Ms. Joy!
Good work, everyone.
What’s going on?
Oh? You didn’t notice?
My big sister said she was in trouble,
so I came over from Akala Island to help.
It looks like you’re
doing better now.
You were a big help.
Cuwawa, thank you for
looking after me.
You, too, Happinus.
Everybody, how was today?
It was tough, but fun!
Right, Pikachu?
This ends the job experience day.
But I wish I could have
seen you all at work.
It’s all right!
I recorded it all flawlessly-roto!
I particularly recommend
this one-roto!
Not that one!
It seems everyone had a good job experience
at the Pokémon Center.
Now that we’ve all learned
how tough Ms. Joy’s job is...
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting.
The Pokémon that helped me
when I had a cold was Cuwawa!
The Posy Picker Pokémon
Cuwawa is a Fairy type.
It makes bands from the flowers it picks,
and spreads a healing aroma.
Both it and Happinus are mascot Pokémon
for the Pokémon Centers in Alola.
Thank you for today.
You were a great help.
Don’t mention it.
All right,
I’ll be going back to Akala.
What? Right now?!
See you!
Cuwawa’s a Ride Pokémon?!
Take care...
Next episode
Please listen to
this actress’s tongue twister!
Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers.
A peck of pickled peppers
Peter Piper picked.
If Peter Piper picked a pick...
Please listen to
this actress’s tongue twister!
Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers.
A peck of pickled peppers
Peter Piper picked.
If Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled peppers,
Where’s the peck of pickled peppers Peter Piper picked?
The thirty-three thieves thought that
they thrilled the throne throw...
they thrilled the throne throughout Thursday.
I bid a view bamboo grew through ad...
I bid a view bamboo...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Shine On, Starship Tekkaguya!