Alola!
I, Kaki, will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem!
Ashimari
Nyabby
Mokuroh
Sunaba
Which of these Pokémon evolves today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
All right! Nyabby,
put your heart into it!
Nyabby’s temperature is rising-roto!
Bakugames,
make sure you block this.
Good...
Now!
Fire Fang!
You almost had it, there...
Let’s have Kaki and Bakugames
teach us the trick!
I’m your man if you wanna know
about the Fire type!
Wanna give it one more try?
Satoshi’s newest
partner Pokémon, Nyabby.
He’s hard at work training to
perfect his finishing move, Fire Fang...
But...?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Beware of Shovels!!!
Watch closely, Nyabby!
Bakugames! Flamethrower!
Take a deep, deep breath
like he’s doing-roto.
This is the point at which the flames
inside his body build up-roto!
Try to mimic that, Nyabby.
Good, Nyabby!
All right... Fire!
That was really promising, Nyabby.
You’ll get it next time!
What are they doing?
They’re playing-roto.
Hang on. That shovel...
It’s Sunaba!
Sunaba?
I got this-roto!
Sunaba. Sand Heap Pokémon.
Ghost/Ground type.
It takes control of anyone who puts a hand on the shovel
atop its head; humans and Pokémon alike!
Takes control?
Yeah. It’s the Pokémon to watch out for
when you’re on the beach.
When I was younger,
Grandfather would often tell me...
...to beware of shovels
sticking out on the beach.
Lest terror would befall me.
But I...
How’s that?! Not scary at all!
Hey...
Kaki?
What’s wrong?
What are you doing?
Apparently I was wordlessly gathering up sand
all the way till the next morning.
Huh...?
But it’s just sand, right?
Watch out!
Iwanko! Rock Throw!
It’s really mad!
It must be searching
for its shovel!
Um...
We just sent it into the sea...
Well, we gotta find it!
Wait-roto!
It’s said you can substitute the shovel
with other things-roto!
What “other things”...?
I’d like to ask you a favoroto.
Wha...?
W-W-What are you doing-roto?!
Satoshi... Are you serious?
Take the shovel’s place
for a bit, okay?
Oh, no! Stop-roto!
Don’t worry about it!
It’s just for a little while.
A perfect fit!
What?
What’s happening-roto?!
It changed!
What is this?!
Stand back, everyone!
Satoshi!
Rotom!
You can stop now!
Get out of there!
I... I can’t get out-roto!
What?!
Satoshi! Watch out-roto!
Satoshi!
Are you okay?!
I’m all right!
Mokuroh?
Whoa...
Is this really still a Pokémon?
This is Sunaba’s evolved form,
Shirodeathna-roto!
Shirodeathna?
Its category is the Sand Castle Pokémon.
Ghost/Ground type.
The shovel on its head is
said to function like a radar.
So I’m inside
Shirodeathna’s body?
What is going on here?!
Stop it, Pikachu!
You’ll just zap me!
All right!
Oh, come on!
Satoshi! Can’t you get out?
I can’t climb up all the sand!
Just focus on finding the shovel!
Seriously... Did you forget
who blasted it into the ocean?
What is that?
Watch out, Iwanko-roto!
Nyabby!
Are you okay, Nyabby?
S-S-S-Something’s off-roto!
Rotom! What’s wrong?!
Kaki! What is this?
It’s Shirodeathna. It got mad, turned giant,
and swallowed Satoshi and Nyabby.
Rotom’s there, too,
on its head!
Satoshi!
Are you all right?!
Guys! There’s something weird
going on with Nyabby!
Satoshi!
Rotom’s not looking right, either!
H-H-H-Help me-roto...
What’s going on with Rotom?
I have no idea!
I’ve read about this in a book.
Shirodeathna is most likely...
...absorbing energy
from Rotom and Nyabby...
...to maintain its enlarged state.
Pocket Monsters...
...and...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Shirodeathna
Type:   Ghost/Ground
At that size,
it could even swallow a house!
We have to keep it on the beach
and save Satoshi!
Leave it to me.
Fight sand with water.
Ashimari! Bubble Beam!
It’s super effective!
Huh? It hardened!
Water attacks...
...will cause Shirodeathna...
to harden-rot-t-t-t-t-to!
That’s really not good!
Get away, everyone!
Shirodeathna is looking for
the shovel that was on its head!
Shovel?
It just flew into the ocean.
What?!
We can’t search the ocean!
But Ashimari can.
But if you touch the shovel,
you’ll get possessed.
Even Ashimari can’t
get around that...
She has her balloons.
I see! If you encase
the shovel in a balloon...
Yeah.
What is it, Pikachu?
We’re counting on you!
Shovel Search Party:
Move out!
Pikachu...
You’re going to look for the shovel?
Hang in there, Nyabby!
If Water moves don’t work...
Snowball’s Ice moves
might prove effective.
You’ll do it?
Please.
We will use Powder Snow
to freeze Shirodeathna.
Got it.
We’ll draw its attention away,
so you attack it with Powder Snow
from its blind spot!
Yes!
But the Powder Snow will affect
Satoshi and Rotom as well...
We’ll be fine! Do it, Lilie!
I will be per-r-r-r-r-
perfectly fine, too-roto!
I’ll just think back to the situation from episode 7
of Alolan Detective Laki season 3-roto!
If my deduction is correct,
they will definitely show up at this mountain hut.
The fact that people rarely come here
makes this a perfect place...
There’s no way I got this wrong!
I, too, will endure the cold
like L-L-Laki did-roto!
Rotom seems to be having fun.
Let us do this, Snowball!
Lizardon! Bakugames!
Let’s go!
Māmane, we’ll serve as
backup for Snowball!
O-Okay, I got this!
Now! Launch a coordinated attack!
Lilie! It’s all on you!
Yes!
Here we go, Snowball!
Powder Snow!
Hang in there, Snowball!
It’s okay, Nyabby.
We’ll be out of here soon.
There’s no way I got this wrong-roto!
Snowball!
It’s too much for Snowball alone!
That’s why we’re backing her up!
C’mon! C’mon! C’mon!
Thank you, Mao!
Māmane, you fan, too!
Sure!
Me, too!
C’mon! C’mon!
Good, Amamaiko!
C’mon! C’mon! C’mon!
Good going, Togedemaru!
Spin it!
Take a quick break, Snowball.
There’s no way I got th—
got this wrong!
Are you cold?
How’s this?
You’ll heat me up, too?
Thank you, Nyabby.
C’mon! C’mon! C’mon!
Shirodeathna is
starting to slow down!
It’s working!
Just a little further!
Keep it up!
Hang in there, Amamaiko!
Go, go, Togedemaru!
One last push, Snowball!
It stopped!
All right!
A roaring success!
We did it, Amamaiko!
You were great, Togedemaru!
Thank you, Snowball.
You guys did great, too.
Th-There’s no way I got this wrong...
Ashimari...
Mokuroh!
All right! Nyabby,
we’re getting outta here!
Almost there...!
Ow!
I’m not giving up!
One more time!
Nyabby?
You did it, Nyabby!
You pulled off a Fire Fang!
Guys!
Satoshi!
Lizardon,
get Satoshi and Nyabby.
now we gotta get Rotom.
T-There’s no...
Satoshi, be careful!
I know!
Right!
Hurry...
You did good, Rotom.
I am the most resilient
Detective Rotom!
Nyabby, thaw the ice around Rotom
using Ember.
It’s awakened?!
Oh, no! Where’s the shovel?!
Lilie, can you use
Powder Snow again?
Snowball has no strength left...
I... I guess she wouldn’t...
There!
Ashimari!
Pikachu! You found it?
We were waiting for you.
Thank you!
Go!
Togedemaru, send it flying!
All right, Nyabby! Wait for your moment
and pop the balloon!
Now, Nyabby! Ember!
All right!
Lizardon!
Thanks, Lizardon.
Sorry, Rotom.
I still feel chilly-roto...
And that was how the clash with
the dreadful Shirodeathna came to an end.
If any of you ever find a shovel
lying on the beach,
then be careful with it!
That sounds really rough.
But, Professor!
Nyabby perfected his Fire Fang!
That’s how we were
able to escape!
I guess that was your
Fire Pledge with Nyabby?
It got dark all of a sudden...
An afternoon shower?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Sunaba!
Sunaba’s evolved form Shirodeathna has the ability
Water Compact, and it’s a real pain!
Whenever it gets hit by a Water-type move,
its defenses go up, turning it into an impenetrable fortress!
Oh, goodness...
I’m glad it finally left,
but that was a real Sand Hell
through and through!
Thanks for helping out.
Next episode
We have just received
some serious news!
Oh, my! It appears the Dugtrio members of
the popular music unit DugLeo are splitting up!
Splitting up?
But Dugtrio is...
Oh, excuse me!
What could have
caused them to split up?
Stay tuned for more information!
...Does that mean they’re
three Digda now...?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Here’s a Real Shocker!
A Dugtrio Split-Up?!
Here’s a Real Shocker! A Dugtrio Split-Up?!
Huh? What’s that mean?