Alola!
It’s time for the PokéProblem!
Today’s problem is as suChillarmy!
Satoshi’s mom
Kaki’s Mom
Mao’s Dad
Team Rocket
Who comes to the Pokémon School today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Pokémon School is off today.
What are Satoshi and the others doing?
Oh? Is that...?
...Some of them take different forms
than they do in other regions.
This is because Alola is
an island region, so they’ve...
They’ve adopted to their environment...
Adopted? No, that’s not the right word...
I know!
Point is, there are some
seriously different Pokémon here!
Hold it-roto!
Satoshi, be precise-roto!
The differences between Alola’s Pokémon
and those of other regions...
...have been studied for years, and are not something that can be summed up in one word-roto!
This data explains it all-roto!
What’s this? If I read all this...
Read it-roto.
I’ll turn into an old man...
I can’t! There’s no way!
It contains vital information-roto!
Oh, dear, I’ve already
become an old man...
Oh, young Pikachu!
How are you doing?
I see you have it rough.
Professor Kukui,
there’s just no way I can do this!
Shouldn’t you have had
Māmane or Lilie do it instead?
Don’t say that.
Loads of guests will be there
at the open house.
You’ve got the vital task of announcing
the results of your studies to all those people.
Bring out your Superpower.
Superpower won’t help me here...
Reassessing Alolan Pokémon by looking at
the differences to their Kantonian counterparts.
A topic you’re uniquely qualified for.
Principal Okido set it specifically for you.
What sort of guests will be there?
The students’ families and other citizens.
Anyone’s free to come.
All right, I got it already.
I’ll bring some for you, too.
Oh, I’ll get that!
Yes, yes, who...
Hi, Satoshi!
Have you been doing well?
Mom! Barrierd!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Alola!
The First Visitation Day!!
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
I’m Satoshi’s mother.
I hope Satoshi hasn’t been
causing you too much trouble.
Not at all!
Having them around is a lot of fun.
Thank you so much.
So, why are you here?
Did you win another
vacation ticket at the lottery?
No. I came to watch your
Pokémon presentation at the open house.
What?! How’d you know?!
Principal Okido told me.
He said I was free to come.
It’s a great chance for her to see
her son in the spotlight!
I wanted to meet you all, too.
Long time, no see, Pika-chan.
You’ve made new friends,
too, haven’t you?
Yeah, that’s right! Look, Mom!
This is Iwanko.
Mokuroh.
Nyabby.
Pleasure to meet you, I-chan,
Moku-chan and Nyabi-chan.
What’s that?
What’s what?
They’re cute names.
Really?
And this is Rotom,
who’s also my Pokémon Index.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you,
Satoshi’s mother.
Oh, you can talk? Incredible!
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
Index-chan.
Mokuroh’s always sleeping.
It looks like you’re having
a lot of fun here.
Yeah, it’s super fun!
Hey, wake up, Mokuroh.
Oh, Nyabi-chan,
you have such soft fur.
Amazing-roto! I’ve never seen Nyabby
this lax before-roto!
Well... It’s Mom.
We were just about to have tea.
Would you like some?
Oh, thank you!
I’ll go get it.
All right, please do.
My, what’s this?
Oh.
That’s the report Satoshi
is going to be presenting.
Oh, how exciting!
I wonder what it says.
What am I gonna do?
I’m not sure I can pull off that presentation...
Your report is currently 20% complete.
There is currently a 90% chance of failure
at the presentation-roto.
Figured as much...
What am I going to do?
There is a way-roto.
What? Really?!
What a cutie...
There, there...
She’s got you wrapped
around her finger, Nyabby.
I-chan, Moku-chan,
you come here, too.
Such good boys.
Here you are!
Oh, thanks.
Thank you.
Here.
This is pretty grand.
It was open to people in the city, too.
Oh, if it isn’t Little Nyabi!
Oh, you know Nyabi-chan?
She’s been helping him out.
Alola!
Alola.
I figured I’d visit the school.
I’m glad you’re doing well,
Little Nyabi.
He’s a really good boy.
Oh, I know!
Oh, how impressive!
Alola, Satoshi!
Master Satoshi, I bid you Alola.
Alola, Lilie, Mr. James!
“Master Satoshi”?
Mr. James is Lilie’s butler.
This is my mom.
I’m Lilie, and this is Snowball.
Master Satoshi has been
a great help to Young Miss Lilie.
Oh, no, I’m sure you’ve helped
him far more!
Oh, my! A white Rokon?
Snowball is an Alolan Rokon,
so she’s an Ice type.
Meanwhile this Rokon hatched
from the egg we brought here.
Oh, it’s from that egg?
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
Roko-chan.
Alola!
I’m glad you could make it!
Alola, Principal.
Thank you for letting me know.
I hope you’ll see Satoshi’s hard work
with your own eyeSaihorn!
Alola, Lilie, Satoshi!
Alola.
Alola!
Look at all these people...
Wait, is that your mom, Satoshi?
She came here all the way from Kanto?
Yeah, she did...
What about you guys’ parents?
Couldn’t make it because of work.
Mine are working, too.
Both my mom and dad are here.
You’re right!
My mom and sisters are here...
Pokémon School!
School! School!
Pokémon everywhere!
Everywhere! Everywhere!
We wanna study at
the Pokémon School, too!
Sure, once you’re a little older.
Now be quiet.
All right!
You’re gonna do a presentation
in front of all these people?
Will you be okay, Satoshi?
Are you nervous?
Hang in there.
Oh, uh... Yeah, it’s gonna be—
It’s gonna be great-roto!
Because he’s got m—
Is something the matter, Satoshi?
Not at all! I got some great training in
with Rotom, so I’ll do just fine!
Alola!
I know a lot of your parents and
guardians are here today,
but let’s have fun learning about Pokémon together,
just like any other day!
All right!
Well, then, Satoshi. You’re up.
R-Right!
Today, I’d like to talk to you
about what surprised me...
...about the Pokémon in Alola,
after I came here from Kanto.
The first thing that
took me by surprise...
...was how some Pokémon I was familiar with
looked totally different here in Alola!
What do you mean, there is a way?
Be amazed, for I now possess
the feature of voice sampling-roto!
Voice sam...?
Give it a try-roto!
Just say something to me-roto!
“Something”...?
Ah... Ah... I’m Satoshi.
I come from Kanto.
Analyzing... Analyzing...
Analyzing...
Sampling complete!
I’m Satoshi! Nice to meetcha!
That’s creepy!
It’s perfect-roto!
Amazing-roto!
Can I do the presentation
with this-roto?
Huh? Um...
Okay, counting on you!
I got this-roto!
Koratta is about the same size here
as in other regions,
All right! This is going great!
but its coloring and
whiskers are different...
We can do this!
We can do this-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Barrierd
Type:   Psychic/Fairy
Furthermore, we had two eggs
that we were observing together.
One was brought in from Kanto,
while the other was found
on Lanakila Mountain,
and when the two hatched at the same time,
two Rokon of different typing and coloring were born.
Snowball, that was you.
It’s been discovered that, just like this, the same Pokémon
can take different forms based on their environment.
Research is being done,
but there’s still much that we don’t know.
Specialists believe that we may only have
uncovered about 10% of the facts,
Oh, Satoshi studied really hard for this!
Yes.
and they predict great strides
in this research yet to come.
Satoshi knew about
all this complicated stuff?
It doesn’t seem like him.
And at a recent conference,
there was a presentation showcasing the benefits
of the facts that have been verified.
Their work is sure to keep
gathering more attention!
Also, there have been questions as to whether or not
regional forms are a phenomenon exclusive to Alola.
The research on this matter
has sped up in recent years,
They have started attempting to...
Hey, Rotom!
You’re going too fast!
...raise Alolan Pokémon
in other regions.
On the topic of Alolan Pokémon,
the Pokémon School’s very own...
...Principal Okido’s research is well known,
and though normally he says...
I wish you luck! Koduck! Golduck!
...and other such funny lines...
Stare...
I think we’re in serious trouble!
He is, indeed, an esteemed
Pokémon researcher-roto!
“Roto”?
That’s a very good
impression of Principal Okido,
Rotom.
It was an easy task for
my voice sampling feature-roto!
Whaaat?!
Oh, my...
Oh, it was Rotom?
I thought it seemed weird...
That was a great impression
of Satoshi.
And of Principal Okido.
Rotom wanted to do
a presentation, too?
So it seems.
That was a highly informative
report, Rotom.
But no more Nasty Plots,
Satoshi.
I’m sorry...
All right, let’s get back
to Satoshi’s presentation.
What?
Tell us how you felt when you
came to Alola, in your own words.
Let’s hear about all
the awesome Pokémon!
Thanks, everyone!
I can’t do it as well as Rotom, but...
I’ll give it a try!
Yup.
I first just came to Alola for a vacation,
but meeting all the Alolan Pokémon
was so exciting,
I just had to know more!
That’s why I enrolled
at the Pokémon School.
Every day’s been filled with thrills!
Nasshi’s neck was this long,
and Snowball was just shockingly white!
Not to mention,
she covered me in ice.
And then I met Kapu-Kokeko,
the Guardian Deity of the island,
and even got to battle it.
It was crazy fun!
Come here, everyone!
I got to be friends
with new Pokémon, too!
I’m having so much fun every day...
...that I’m really glad I came to Alola!
I hope to learn so much more
about these islands!
I’ll show you even more of
what Alola has to offer!
There’s so much I
would like to know, too.
Let’s learn together, Satoshi.
Let’s go out to sea again.
I’ll be your guide!
I’ll help you in any way I can!
All you have to do is ask.
Thank you, everyone!
I wanted to present
for a little longer-roto...
This seems like a lively and fun class.
I’m so glad he’s found himself
some great friends.
You have a very
sincere son there.
Thank you very much.
For the rest of the day, you’re free to check out
any part of the school area.
Yay! Yay!
Gotta see! Gotta see!
Of course...
Shall we go, too, Dear?
I suppose.
I suppose I’ll have a
look around, too, then.
Don’t you agree,
Bari-chan, Nyabi-chan?
It’s over...
You must be relieved, Satoshi.
You pulled off a proper presentation
in front of your mother.
Yeah!
Oh, my!
The Pokémon School
really is a beautiful place.
Yo, yo! Get outta our way!
We said we’re gonna ride ‘em!
Team Skull’s gonna have some fun!
So ya better get outta our way!
Ow!
Hey! This is the Pokémon School!
You don’t belong here! Get out!
Ya don’t know?
Anyone is free to come today!
We’re visitors!
The only ones causin’ a scene
are you guys!
Dustdas!
Venom Shock!
Kentauros, go!
This rocks!
Yeah! Let’s run around
the whole school!
Stop that!
Huh?
How could you act so violently
when everyone’s having fun?
Leave, now!
What’cha talkin’ about?
Ya wanna fight? Huh?!
Back off if ya don’t
wanna get hurt!
If you won’t listen
to reason, then...
Let’s go, Nyabi-chan!
What’s wrong, “Nyabi-chan”?
Let’s have some fun!
Zubat! Bite!
Dodge, Nyabi-chan!
Hang in there, Nyabi-chan!
Zubat!
Oh, Nyabi-chan,
that was amazing!
Mom?
Mom, what are you doing?
Oh, Satoshi!
These people were causing trouble,
so I was teaching them a lesson!
It’s you guys!
Them again?
They never learn.
Wha-?!
Here come the pains...
W-What do we do?
There ain’t no way
we’re retreatin’ now!
Hey, you two!
Today’s the day we take ya down!
Satoshi’s mother!
This is dangerous, so please get back!
No! I won’t run!
Your mother can battle, too-roto?
Oh, geez...
We’ll take you on!
Wait... huh? Mokuroh?
Little Mokuroh
needs his beauty sleep.
Figures...
Ya mockin’ us?!
Toxic attack!
Dodge!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Iwanko! Bite!
Nyabi-chan! Scratch!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
This is why I hate Z-Moves!
We ain’t done with ya guys!
We’ll still get ya someday!
Fight us fair and square,
without Z-Moves next time!
They’re not on their
motorcycles today?
I guess not...
Why not?
That was amazing, Pika-chan!
It’s called a Z-Move!
Thank you, too, Nyabi-chan.
Z-Moves are so cool!
I kinda want to try one myself!
Oh, Mom...
They really are family!
They’re just like each other!
They’re both just as rash.
And just as kind,
and ready to help others!
Say, everyone...
Can you help me fix this flower bed?
Of course!
Come on!
Yeah!
Let’s go grab some tools!
Okay!
You, too, Satoshi!
All right! Let’s do this!
Well, would you look at that...
Of course! If everyone helps each other out,
the work will soon be oveRunpappa!
We’ll help, too.
All right, take care of yourself, Satoshi.
Sure! You, too.
Nyabi-chan,
wanna come with me?
Absolutely not!
Nyabby is my partner!
Just kidding.
See you, Nyabi-chan.
Everybody,
look after Satoshi for me!
Professor Kukui,
I leave him in your care.
Yeah! You can count on me!
I bought too many souvenirs.
See you later, Mom!
Don’t cause trouble for the Professor!
Satoshi and the others were surprised
by his mother’s unexpected visit.
But he may have been happy to see her
for the first time in a while, don’t you think?
Satoshi’s school life in Alola
will continue!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for your patienCelebi!
The answer was Satoshi’s mother!
Did you get it righTattsu?
Barrierd, the Barrier Pokémon which
Satoshi’s mother brought with her, is a Psychic/Fairy type.
It’s a master of pantomime.
It can solidify the air into invisible walls.
Oh, are you going home?
Yes. I got to see that
Satoshi was doing well.
Little Nyabi sure got
quite attached to you.
I’ll miss him.
Maybe I should take him with me.
Next episode
Alola sure is nice, meow!
I never want to leave, meow.
I know, right?
Huh? Who are those lame guys?
Huh? “The proud Team Skull,
who’ll scare even crying kids to tears!”?
They’re so full of themselves, meow!
We’ll show them what real evil is like!
But first...
More ice cream, please, lady!
Double scoop for me!
With extra topping, meow!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Battle For the Crystal!!
Team Rocket VS Team Skull!!
Next time
The Battle For the Crystal!!
Team Rocket VS Team Skull!!