I will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Meltan
Nyaheat
Mokuroh
Pikachu
One of Satoshi’s Pokémon evolves
in today’s episode-roto!
Who is it-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
It’s the first-ever
Alola Pokémon League.
In the preliminary Battle Royal,
151 competitors fought to qualify
for the final tournament.
Many trainers and Pokémon
put their moves and experience up against each other,
and in the first match of the semifinals,
Gladio defeated Kaki.
In the second match, Satoshi defeated Guzma
and moved on to the finals!
The finals are next.
Who will be Alola’s
first-ever Champion?!
Mom! Professor Okido!
Alola!
Alola-roto!
Satoshi, congratulations on
reaching the finals!
Thanks, Mom.
Have you been doing well,
Pika-chan?
Thank you for coming all this way.
Oh, it was nothing!
Of course, we want to cheer Satoshi on...
But I’ve also been
eager to meet Meltan.
In that case...
Here.
It’s a pleasure to meet you, Meltan!
Are you all right?
Please take utmost care
From its eye it launches a
Most fierce Luster Cannon
This must be Meltan’s unique behavior
that I’ve heard so much about!
What’s this?
Look at all the Meltan!
Oh, my...
So its head-spins were its way of
calling its friends?
A huge discovery-roto!
Look!
What’s going on?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Finals!
Ultimate Rival Showdown!!
Looks kinda fun!
That’s enough!
You’re doing great.
Hard at work, I see.
Mom. Lilie.
The finals are tomorrow.
Shouldn’t you get some rest?
This is an important battle.
I want to be sure I’ve done all I can.
You’re just like him.
Your father.
Whenever he was facing a battle,
he’d get so obsessed he’d forget to sleep!
Even on our wedding day, he was training till morning,
and almost missed the ceremony!
Oh, Father...
I look forward to
your battle with Satoshi.
Me, too.
Meltan?
This is Melmetal.
Melmetal?
This Pokémon is described
in ancient writings.
They named it Melmetal,
but I never would have guessed
it was a fusion of many Meltan.
This is a huge discovery-roto!
Updating data! Updating data!
Professor,
would this count as evolution?
Well, I suppose we can call it a form of evolution,
for convenience’s sake.
Well, here comes a haiku.
Pokémon Haiku
Silver and gold in
A bizarre combination
That is Melmetal
Melmetal! I’m so glad
you got to evolve!
W-What a punch!
It’s an Ultra Twirl Splash Punch!
Two punches launched by
the tank-like Melmetal...
I guess you could call it
a Double Panzer!
Double Panzer?
That’s so cool!
Indeed.
It is a fine move name.
Double Panzer
has been recorded-roto!
Oh, my... A perfect fit!
Fusion! Metalmoroh!
All right! Let’s give it our
full power tomorrow!
The day has finally come!
Today, the Alola Pokémon League’s
first-ever Champion will be determined!
The first to enter the arena
is Competitor Satoshi.
In round one, he beat Competitor Sauboh.
In round two, Competitor Hau.
And in the semifinals,
he qualified by defeating Competitor Guzma!
And Competitor Satoshi’s
opponent is...
...Competitor Gladio!
In round one, he beat Competitor Lilie.
In round two, Competitor Dekojiro.
Overcoming Competitor Kaki in the semifinals,
he climbed his way through the ranks!
They stare each other down
from across the arena.
The final battle will begin
in just a moment!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Melmetal
Type:   Steel
The final match is between the brat boy and
the dark brat boy? What a snorefest!
I was supposed to be
in that ring!
You and Kojiro ended up having to
face each other right off the bat, meow...
Well, Kojiro?
Think you can finish it?
It’ll be done in time for
the award ceremony.
That’ll be our chance to nab
loads of Pokémon, meow!
The brat boy’s Pikachu, and all the other
rare Pokémon running around...
If we can nab ‘em all,
Sakaki is sure to be pleased!
This new robot’s sure
to manage it!
The finals are a three-on-three.
I want a fair, full power battle
from the both of you!
Of course!
Go, sacred beast Silvuddy!
So his first is Silvuddy...
Big brother...
Make sure you capture
every moment, Bari-chan!
I’m sure Gladio will be amazed!
I choose you!
Who’s that Pokémon?!
It’s Melmetal-roto!
Meltan’s evolved form-roto!
Meltan?!
It does resemble it a bit,
now that you mention it...
Steel muscles!
You can do it, Melmetal!
What kind of battle will we see
from Competitor Satoshi’s Melmetal?
This will be truly exciting!
Melmetal... Fascinating!
Let the match begin!
Victory goes to he who
strikes first, Melmetal!
...Uh...
Be careful, Silvuddy!
Melmetal’s raring to go!
All right!
Use Double Panzer!
Here it comes!
What?! Silvuddy, dodge it!
Double Panzer
wreaks havoc!
But Silvuddy regains its footing!
Did it take damage?!
What force!
Good, Melmetal! Keep going!
Double Panzer!
As if! Air Slash!
It’s quite powerful, but that doesn’t matter
if it doesn’t hit us!
Dodge and close in!
If we hit, we win!
Melmetal!
Double Panzer!
Crush Claw!
Now! Luster Cannon!
What?!
Silvuddy!
Double Panzer and
Luster Cannon...
This’ll be tricky.
We nearly had ‘em there!
Let’s keep going, Melmetal!
Amazing...
Melmetal became way
stronger after evolving!
It’s gotten much more
dependable!
They just might win this!
We might see their
victory scène! Ashirène!
Silvuddy!
Run in a zigzag pattern...
...and strike its belly!
Silvuddy demonstrates
elegant footwork!
Can Melmetal follow it?!
Melmetal! Sweep them up
with a Double Panzer!
Now! Crush Claw!
C-Calm down, Melmetal!
Fight claw with claw,
fang with fang,
and fist with fist!
Receive the Fight Memory,
and with it a furious spirit!
Silvuddy changed into
a Fighting type!
Silvuddy! Multi-Attack!
Use Luster Cannon!
Hang in there, Melmetal!
Melmetal demonstrates fearsome toughness!
It’s back on its feet!
What a powerhouse...
How intriguing!
Silvuddy, keep attacking!
You think we’ll lose?!
Use Double Panzer!
Air Slash!
Luster Cannon!
Multi-Attack!
Melmetal!
Melmetal is unable to battle!
Competitor Satoshi’s Melmetal
goes down at last!
All right!
Melmetal, you did good.
Pikachu, I’m counting on you!
Competitor Satoshi’s next Pokémon
is Pikachu!
Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Iron Tail!
Crush Claw!
Air Slash!
Get back, Pikachu!
Crush Claw!
Dodge with Lightning Speed!
Silvuddy won its power battle
with Melmetal.
Now it’s engaged in
a speed battle with Pikachu!
Amazing!
Silvuddy is keeping up
with Pikachu’s speed!
I would expect no less from Silvuddy,
the ultimate Pokémon, created by none other than me!
Its movements are
impeccably precise!
Young Master Gladio
has trained it magnificently!
You’re good, Gladio!
Well then how’s this?
Pikachu, use Electroweb!
Dodge it!
Electroweb covers a wide area,
but with Silvuddy’s speed,
we can still dodge it.
Again! This time,
fire an Electroweb in front of you!
You can try all you want,
but it won’t work!
Go! Use Lightning Speed!
I knew it! Dodge it, Silvuddy!
What?!
Go!
Iron Tail!
Silvuddy is unable to battle!
All right!
Very impressive, Satoshi!
So then, how will you
deal with this?!
Lugarugan, huh...?
Pikachu,
watch out for its Counter!
Counting on you.
Now, what will Lugarugan do?
Night Burst.
Does not compute!
Lugarugan can’t learn Night Burst-roto!
What’s going on?
Night Burst...
Could it be...?
That Lugarugan...
When’d it learn
to use that move?!
Go!
Pikachu! Electroweb!
Shadow Claw!
Behind you!
100,000 Volts!
T-That’s...
Mohn’s...
Amazing! It wasn’t Lugarugan that
Competitor Gladio sent out, but Zoroark!
Zoroark?
Please lend me your strength, Dad.
Awaken from your illusion,
Zoroark!
The Alola Pokémon League finals...
Who will the Goddess of Victory
smile upon;
Satoshi or Gladio?!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting-roto!
It was Meltan who evolved-roto!
Meltan’s evolved form Melmetal
is the Hex Nut Pokémon, a Steel type.
What a shock that all those Meltan
would merge and evolve-roto!
Its power has
risen immensely-roto!
Let’s see, now...
Is it really that incredible?
Pokémon Haiku
Double Panzer is
Like a Brutal Swing from an
Electronic fan
You guys catch Pokémon, too!
Next episode
I am in tears.
The Alola Pokémon League finals...
My heart will not stop trembling at
the amazing battle I have just witnessed.
Thank you, Competitor Satoshi.
Thank you, Competitor Gladio, and...
Thank you, Pokémon!
Next time...
...on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
The Rise of
Alola’s Champion!!
The Rise of Alola’s Champion!!