Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Purin
Cayce
Betobeta
Garura
Which of these Pokémon
becomes Nekkoala’s greatest rival today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Lugarugan, use Rock Throw!
You’re both doing great!
Keep it up!
Satoshi!
Breakfast’s done,
so go get Burnet for me!
Okay!
Namakobushi. Sea Cucumber Pokémon.
Water type.
It lives in shallow seas, such as areas near a beach.
It can eject its internal organs to battle enemies.
I’m sorry I got in the way of your research.
It’s fine. Thanks to you,
I got to see a valuable moment.
And the underwater recording
went perfectly-roto!
Oh yeah, Professor Kukui
said breakfast’s done.
I’m famished!
Time to eat!
Amazing! It ate ten times the normal amount
of Pokémon food in just two seconds-roto!
It’s great!
Yeah, it’s delicious!
Excellent work,
if I do say so myself.
I’ll make dinner.
What? But weren’t you
going on a business trip today?
That’s right!
I haven’t prepared at all!
I’ll give you a Helping Hand.
Thanks, you’re a lifesaver.
All right, Professor,
I’m going ahead.
Sure. I won’t be long.
Have a nice day!
See you later!
Now that Professor Kukui
and Professor Burnet have gotten married,
a new life has started for
Satoshi and the others.
What will today bring?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
A Strong Sleeper:
Nekkoala’s Secret!
Aw, come on, Togedemaru!
This isn’t a game!
Snowball, use Powder...
No... Run!
Stop!
Orders in a Pokémon battles need to be given
clearly and with confidence!
If a trainer hesitates, their Pokémon
will be Dragged Along into hesitating, too!
Got it!
Well then, start!
All right... Nyabby, use Fire Fang!
Garagara,
counter with Iron Head!
It’s Nekkoala!
That was close!
It fell again, huh?
But man, what a weird Pokémon.
How can it be sleeping all the time?
How does it eat?
This is a good opportunity.
Let me show you.
It seems I’ll be able to record
some valuable footage-roto!
These leaves are inedible
to humans and other Pokémon,
but they’re Nekkoala’s favorite food!
Oh! It reacted-roto!
It’s eating while sleeping!
That’s right. Since it spends
its whole life asleep,
naturally, it eats while sleeping, too.
This has been bothering me
for quite some time,
but how can it keep sleeping
without end?
I know, right?
I mean, I like sleeping, but I’ll wake up naturally
when I’ve had enough, you know?
Yeah, you’re right.
Well, you see, eating these leaves
will make you really sleepy.
Apparently, those properties are
what cause it to stay asleep.
Really?
Is that so?
But is it really always asleep?
Well, remember the Pancake Race?
Yeah, it was sleeping the whole time!
All right, I’m gonna wake it up!
Are you sure?!
Zooming in on Nekkoala’s face-roto.
Guess it won’t wake up from that.
But it scrunched up its face!
Does that mean it heard you?
No, it’s just having a dream
that’s fouLugarugan.
Principal Okido...
There are times where it looks like
it’s reacting to what people are saying...
But in fact, it’s simply reacting to
whatever dream it’s having.
Really? So it just happened to experience
something unpleasant in its dream just now?
Incidentally, it gets the log it’s holding
when it’s born.
It’s said that once it clings on to it,
it will never let it go-roto.
But there are rare cases where
it does let go of it.
That was how Nekkoala and I met.
Please tell us!
Very well...
It happened while I was
taking a leisurely stroll...
What a bother.
Yes.
What’s happeneDeathkan?
Oh, Principal Okido.
There’s a Nekkoala rampaging
in the middle of the road.
Oh, that’s quite uncommon.
I see. Quite a shocKokodra,
Kodra, Bossgodra!
What do you mean?
That Nekkoala seems to have lost
the log it usually holds.
Because of that, it tosses and turns
and can’t sleep peacefully.
What? It’s tossing and turning
in its sleep?
Indeed. For now, if we just had
something to replace its log...
Oh! These will do nicely!
By all means, please use them.
Then I’ll take you up on that.
Nekkoala, I’ll make you a proper one later,
so please make do with this for...
Nekkoala’s got a
peaceful look on its face!
I see... But this is troubling...
I can’t... Can’t see...
This’ll do nicely!
Now then, since it’s lost its log,
I must hurry and make a new oNasshi!
Something like this?
Here, your new log is done.
Oh? It’s not to your liking?
It wouldn’t move, but somehow,
seeing its sleeping face put me at ease.
I just left it where it was for a while.
Back then, I rang the School bell every day,
but then one day...
Well done, Nekkoala!
You like it?
After that, Nekkoala kept clinging on to it
and wouldn’t let go, so I let it keep it.
Eventually, Nekkoala started ringing the School bell
at the proper time, all on its own.
Really?
Hey!
Awesome!
Nekkoala can battle?
Of course. It won’t lose to an
unskilled teaMakenkani!
I wanna battle it!
Very well. Kani, Kani!
It’s been a while since we’ve walked
around the woods like this looking for Pokémon.
Yeah. Lately we’ve been
so focused on PetitDogas,
but one mustn’t forget the basics!
Our mission is, and always will be,
catching rare Pokémon to send to Team Rocket HQ.
All is for our boss...
Sakaki!
If we can get a mega rare Pokémon
like an Ultra Beast,
we’ll be promoted for sure!
We’ll get a rank high enough to
order that bowl-headed four-eyes around!
I’ll take the right to cozy up on Sakaki’s lap
from that stuck-up Persian, meow!
Could that be an Ultra Beast?!
There you are!
Let us do our job
for a little longer, meow!
It’s a Purin.
What’s the big idea?
If you’re not gonna take us home,
then let go of us!
It took something out.
A microphone?
Could that Purin be...
Huh? Somehow...
This is a really...
...great feeling, meow...
Let’s go, Nyabby!
Nekkoala, this is a Pokémon battle!
Use Ember!
It dodged it!
Scratch!
It dodged again!
It’s really awake, right?
Nyabby!
Nekkoala is strong!
Nyabby, are you all right?
That’s its special move,
Wood Hammer.
Well? Pretty impressive, right?
My Bakugames is up next!
Go ahead,
give it your best attacKoiking!
Flamethrower!
How can it tell
that it’s being attacked?!
That’s still a mystery.
Dragon Tail!
Amazing!
That was its finishing move,
Rapid Spin.
Bakugames!
That thing’s gotta be awake, right?
How can Nekkoala battle
while it’s asleep?
It’s quite a mystery.
I know! Maybe my Mokuroh
can battle while sleeping too?
Interesting!
Let’s give it a trYonoir!
Okay...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Munna!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Purin
Type:   Normal/Fairy
What kind of battle will this be?
It seems I’ll get to record even
more valuable footage-roto!
Mokuroh, use Leafage!
Tackle!
Peck!
No good, huh?
That Purin! It couldn’t be...
It really did come to Alola!
Not good! If we hear its song,
we’ll all fall asl...
Quite amusing doodles!
Wait, are they on my face too?
And mine?
Hey! Nekkoala’s the only one
who hasn’t been doodled on!
Why?!
Oh! I was able to keep recording
even while sleeping-roto!
Really?
Show us!
It was Purin’s doing!
How awful!
Yes.
What a fiend!
It’s gotta be pretty angry
about this...
Does that mean
it’ll come back?
It seems that’s
exactly what it means.
Purin, cut it out!
Stop!
Why...
...did we get hit?
Hey, Purin.
Please let us hear your song
one more time.
We’ll stay awake ‘til the end this time.
Let us hear a song
with some Spark to it!
Starting recording-roto!
There are even more doodles
on our faces now!
Nekkoala’s still the only one
who hasn’t been doodled on!
Why?
Resolution rate: 100%!
Leave it to Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
And there you have it-roto.
Nekkoala did it again...
Purin will come to
get back at it soon.
At this rate, the same thing
will just keep happening!
If only there was a way to make
Nekkoala and Purin Play Nice...
I have an idea!
You fight fire with fire...
So, let’s fight Sing with Sing!
If we teach Nekkoala Sing,
that ought to lessen any animosity
that Purin Hasuboh!
But how do we teach it?
We let the sleeping Nekkoala
hear a song,
and make it understand
that singing is delightfuLugarugan!
And... begin!
You’re all great!
Wonderful!
You’re so good!
It seems to be getting into it!
It’s started singing!
All right!
Well, it’s good that
it’s started singing...
But listening to it...
Nekkoala, that’s enough.
Now it should be able to
sing with Purin.
Truly, this will be
the battle of the century!
A Pokémon song battle!
What? A battle?
Here it comes!
Wait, Purin!
Let us hear your song again, please!
Your song!
Song!
And... begin!
Is it finally beginning?
But once the song starts, we...
We’ll get to see how it turned out...
once we wake up-roto...
What?! How?!
What about Nekkoala?
It hasn’t been doodled on!
What just happened?
Once again: Resolution rate: 100%!
Leave it to Alolan Detective Rotom-roto!
They’re singing together!
But...
Then why are there doodles
on Purin’s face?
The Pokémon song battle’s winner
is Nekkoala-roto!
Nekkoala was the one who
doodled on it!
Amazing! It can draw while asleep!
But this just makes me suspect even more
that it’s actually awake.
This is not good.
Yeah, when Purin wakes up
and sees the doodles on its face...
It’ll get really mad.
And then this will all
have been for nothing!
Let’s hurry and erase it!
Water! A bucket! Water!
Hurry, hurry!
Here!
Yes!
It should be fine as long as
it doesn’t see its own face.
There are no mirrors
around here, right?
No mirrors, but...
All right... It seems we’ve successfully caused
a Reversal to make them Play Nice.
Indeed. We’ve made it through
that rough patCharem!
Purin! See you later!
If you say that,
it really will come back!
Then it can just have another fun
Pokémon song battle with Nekkoala!
Do you want to
practice singing, too, Ashimari?
Through a Pokémon song battle,
Nekkoala has become friends with Purin.
This kind of battle is nice too,
every once in a while.
Come to think of it,
what happened to Team Rocket?
What’s wrong with your face?!
Yours, too!
It’s Purin’s handiwork, meow!
What even is this feeling?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
Nekkoala’s rival was Purin!
The Balloon Pokémon Purin is
a Normal/Fairy type.
That Purin came from Kanto.
According to Satoshi, it would
always show up at random,
put them to sleep with Sing,
and then doodle on their faces.
Will it come back?
What are you watching?
Rotom, turn up the sound.
Roger that-roto!
Next episode
It’s time for Detective Laki-roto!
I see. This criminal is very smart.
He’s solved it already-roto?!
The criminal washed away all the evidence
using this washing machine!
I see.
In other words, the culprit is someone who has
a deep connection to this washing machine!
Who is it-roto?
It is...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Rotom’s Non-Stop Forme-Changing!
Next time
Rotom's Non-Stop Forme-Changing!
It is you!
Unbelievable!