Alola, meow!
I’ll be presenting
today’s PokéProblem, meow!
Bakugames
Nyabby
Togedemaru
Kapu-Kokeko
Which of these detestable Pokémon
foils our plans today, meow?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode, meow!
Watch this!
Ashimari is incredible!
One day after school,
Satoshi had gone to the beach
to watch Suiren and Ashimari’s balloon practice.
Here we go, Ashimari!
Balloon!
The balloon’s strength,
durability and elasticity...
They all maintain
an impeccable balance-roto!
Awesome!
Isn’t it? Ho and Sui managed to
ride in one, too!
Great work, Ashimari!
You’ve gotten this far?
You’re one step closer
to your dream, Suiren!
Yup!
I’m up next!
I wanna ride in one!
I’m not so sure...
I can’t?
When I tried to go inside one,
it popped immediately.
Well, maybe our Pokémon can!
He’s sleeping again...
Ow, ow, ow!
One at a time.
I think three at once
is still too much for her.
All right, Pikachu goes first.
Ashimari.
Again?!
Whaaaat?!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
A Tiny Trio
on a Big Adventure!
Wait!
What do we do, Suiren?
Come on!
A-All right, I got it!
I can run on my own!
Wait!
Don’t forget your backpack!
I’ve never seen Suiren
like that before-roto!
It’s like a switch inside her flips
whenever Ashimari’s in trouble.
Done setting it up?
All the information in Alola
now belongs to us, meow!
We just gotta attach this!
At last, our secret base
is complete!
Well, then...
Set on!
What are you doing?!
My poor parabola antenna!
Guess it can’t get the part
off its body...
That’s the brat boy’s
Pokémon, meow!
And that Ashimari belongs to
the blue brat girl!
Perfect!
Let’s catch ’em!
We’ll kidnap hostages
to exchange for Pikachu...
Or rather, we’ll Pokénap them!
Hidoide! Spike Cannon!
Wait, meow!
Where could they have gone?
Suiren, has anything like this
happened before?
It’s fine. We’ll find them!
They definitely came here,
at least.
Let’s split up and search!
Yeah!
Ugh, didn’t expect that...
Hey, Nyarth?
He went after them.
We should go, too!
R-R-Right...
Let go of us!
That’s enough, meow!
That’s a great pose,
Mokuroh, meow!
Hidoide, give that Ashimari
some good stings, meow!
What do you want?
No big deal...
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nyarth
Type:   Normal
It’s Nyarth, meow!
Oh? This elderly Pokémon...
Isn’t it the Mooland
who was with Nyabby?
So this is where they settled down
after they left Satoshi behind.
How’d it go?
No good...
I asked around, but...
Nobody had seen them.
Iwanko?
Iwanko is really good at
sniffing things out-roto!
He can track Mokuroh and
Ashimari’s scents-roto!
Nice, Rotom!
That’s it!
You should teach Iwanko
Mokuroh and Ashimari’s scents right away-roto!
Their scents, huh?
What has Mokuroh’s scent...?
Of course!
Iwanko, this is Mokuroh’s scent.
Remember it.
Mokuroh’s always sleeping
in there, after all!
This is Ashimari’s scent.
I’m always holding her.
Learn their scents!
We’re counting on you,
Iwanko!
You found them already?!
Iwanko's tail wag is believed
to signal a find they made-roto!
They’re that way, huh, Iwanko?
Towards the forest?
Thank you, Iwanko!
Let’s go!
It’s finally asleep...
Let’s take this chance to
meet up with Nyarth!
Huh? You lost them?
Iwanko...
Iwanko, you’re the only one
we can count on.
Hang in there!
It’s so late...
We better hurry!
Yeah!
He’s wagging his tail!
Does that mean...
...he’s found them?
That way?
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
It’s all for one and one for all!
And so on and so forth...
Huge success!
Great idea cutting them off,
Musashi, Kojiro!
Of course! Though we may be different people,
we share a single vision!
We were about to finish our secret base,
but you pests completely ruined it!
For starters, let’s have you give us back
that vital component!
Oh? Who’s this?
There’s one more now!
Hmmm...
It’s called Nyabby.
It’s the Fire Cat Pokémon.
That one got in my way
at the worst possible time, meow!
Huh... It got in your way, did it?
What’d it say?
“Let these two go!”
Huh?
What, now?
You wanna play hero?
But your friend...
...is asleep, you know?
Quite the impressive fellow!
I like your chivalry, meow!
Wanna join Team Rocket?
Sounds great!
An instant boost of manpower!
Ow! Ow! Hot!
This heat reminded me, meow!
This guy’s the one
who stole our fruit, meow!
Our fruit?!
I see... Seems he had
a good reason, meow...
I see... I didn’t know, meow...
W-What?
W-What did it say?
This guy’s a real
honcho Pokémon, meow.
Casting the world and his own well-being aside,
all for those weaker than himself,
he’s struggled to be strong
all his life, meow!
Well, that’s...
...so noble!
You’re a beacon of shining light
in the darkness of this cruel world, meow!
All right!
We’ll let your honcho-tier skills
help far more people, meow!
If you join us, you’ll become
far stronger, meow!
That’s right!
And then the fruit thing
will be water under the bridge!
He’s saying he doesn’t mind
joining us, meow!
For real?!
You really are
a true honcho, meow!
I know, right?
You gotta be strong
if you wanna help more friends!
You might even get a bonus
if you work really hard!
Now, then, honcho...
Come over here,
on your own, meow.
Leave Mokuroh and Ashimari
where they are, meow.
What?!
Honcho! I really like you, meow!
I’ll make you join us someday,
for sure, meow!
That said, finally...
For the first time in Alola,
we can say...
Ready, and...
What an awful feeling!
What was that?
You’re all okay!
Ashimari!
I missed you!
What a relief...
Huh?
What’s this on your neck?
Hang on, I’ll get it off you.
That cry...
Nyabby!
That’s the Nyabby who
was with Mooland-roto!
Yeah.
Thank you, Nyabby!
You helped them?
How is Mooland doing?
Nyabby!
There he goes, Satoshi...
Sure you didn’t want him to stay?
What a strange one...
We’ll meet again.
Mokuroh, Ashimari and Nyabby...
Thus, their tiny, grand adventure
came to an end.
Will Satoshi and Nyabby meet again?
Only the Alolan sky knows!
What even is this feeling?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting, meow!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Nyabby, meow!
Wretched Nyabby...
You ruined our chance to get Pikachu!
But I gotta say, that Nyabby was
a real chivalrous guy, meow!
He’s got everything Team Rocket wants
from their members, and then some, meow!
Here you go.
Wait, meow!
Yeah, I’m real persistent, meow!
If you join Team Rocket,
you’ll never have to go hungry... meow?!
Where’d you go, meow?
Hey! Listen to what I’m saying, meow!
Next episode
My dear assistant, Pikachu!
This case is an enigma
wrapped in a mystery-roto!
Prepare yourself!
Wait, my dear Pikachu?
My dear Pikachu?
Where are you-roto?
A master detective and his assistant
are kindred spirits!
They always act in tandem,
solving cases hand in hand!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Alolan Detective Rotom!
The Mystery of the Vanished Crystal!!
Next time
Alolan Detective Rotom!
The Mystery of the Vanished Crystal!!
I found you-roto!