Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Shellder
Peroppuff
Peroream
Berolinga
Which of these Pokémon is my brother’s partner,
which is featured today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Mao! You still working on lunch?
What’s going on-roto?
Dad?!
Oww...
Are you all right?
Mao!
What happened?
Oh, I was carrying
these sacks of flour...
I’m fine.
My back just gave out on me.
Here we...
Are you sure you’re all right?
Are you all right?
Owww...
You really should stay still...
But I have to prepare for
the Alola Bread Festival...
Alola Bread Festival?
Yeah, it’s a...
Hold it!
I can explain it for you!
`Ulu
Big brother!
Huh? B-Big brother?
Grin!
You don’t mean...
The one who had left on a cooking journey,
and who sent the recipe for the Mythical Alola Stew-roto?
Dad, Mao, I’m home!
Welcome home, big brother!
Calm down...
Amakaji! So you’ve evolved!
She’s not Amakaji anymore,
she’s Amamaiko.
I’ve evolved quite a lot
myself, too.
Sure looks like it.
How’ve you two been?
Great!
But Dad’s...
I’m ashamed of myself.
Big brother, this is Satoshi.
He’s a Pokémon School classmate.
Sorry I didn’t introduce myself sooner.
Name’s `Ulu.
This is Berolinga.
Nice to meet you, Mr. `Ulu.
I’m Satoshi.
This is my partner Pikachu,
and these guys are Rotom and Bebenom.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
Berolinga. Licking Pokémon.
Normal type.
It never forgets the taste or smell
of anything it’s eaten.
Anyway, `Ulu, what brings you back
so suddenly?
Dad! Please let me participate
in this year’s Alola Bread Festival.
You came all the way
back here for that?
No, I was coming home anyway.
But I heard about the Alola Bread Festival
in town just now,
and that made me want to let everyone taste the results
of what I’ve learned during my journey!
You don’t mind, do you, Dad?
C’mon! C’mon!
Dad!
Mao’s brother `Ulu
has come back out of the blue.
I get the feeling something big is
going to happen at the Aina Cafeteria!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection-start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection-don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Ta-Dough!
Burn With Passion, Mao's Family!!
The Alola Bread Festival...
...is an annual baking event
taking place here in Alola!
Everybody makes
all kinds of bread,
and then we determine which of them
is the tastiest of all!
The tastiest bread in Alola...
The winner gets
a cruise all around Alola on a luxury liner!
Really?
The theme for this year is...
...delicious bread that both
people and Pokémon can enjoy.
Owww...
All right!
That’s the perfect theme!
My skills have flourished
in my time spent training abroad!
Right, Amamaiko?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Your special lunch plates are done.
Looks great! Time to dig in!
It’s delicious!
Is it good?
I see you’re helping out
in the cafeteria, Mao.
Didn’t I tell you that
I’d evolved too?
What sort of bread are you gonna make
at the Bread Festival, Mr. `Ulu?
Well, of course I’m...
...still figuring that out!
I thought so-roto...
I’ll help, too.
Really?
I was planning
to help Dad bake today, anyway.
Thank you so much,
my sister!
Big brother, I can’t breathe...
Alola!
Is the lunch box I ordered done?
Yes!
Just hang on a second, Noa.
Noa?
The poster girl for
the pancake store, Noa-roto!
Oh, if it isn’t Satoshi!
Alola!
Noa-
It’s been so long, Noa!
`Ulu? You’re back!
It’s been so long!
Indeed it has!
I never imagined we would meet again,
let alone like this!
It must be fate!
Um...
I’m just here to pick up
the lunch box I ordered...
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Hey, big brother!
You’re not making Noa
uncomfortable again, are you?
Come again? How rude!
You always get so riled up
in front of her.
Here you go.
By the way, why did you
come back so suddenly?
To see you, of course!
He’s participating in
the upcoming Alola Bread Festival.
The Alola Bread Festival?
I look forward to it every year!
Your store isn’t
going to participate?
Don’t you know?
Pancakes aren’t bread,
they’re cakes!
Well, then, I look forward to seeing
what you’ll make, `Ulu.
U-Um...
Um...
If I win...
Can I please bake bread for you every morning
forever and ever?!
Thank you!
Congratulations,
big brother!
Big brother! Big brother!
Big brother, can you hear me?
Aren’t you glad, Mao?
You’re getting a big sister!
What?
Sweet?
Ama?
That’s right, Amamaiko!
For the sake of my sweet,
sweet newlywed life with Noa...
I must work hard. I must win!
How naïve...
Amai...
What’s this?
Alola Bread Festival?
The winner gets a cruise
all around Alola on a luxury liner...
I’m in!
That was quick!
Well, duh!
It’s a cruise around Alola!
It’ll be a nice tropical vacation!
Well then why don’t we just
get the old air balloon and-
That’s not the same at all!
It’s meaningful because
it’s on a luxury cruise liner!
Welcome, everyone!
Mr. `Ulu!
Maobro!
It’s been a while!
Have you been doing well?
Yeah! You all seem to
be doing well, too.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
My name is Lilie, and I’m Mao’s classmate.
Pleasure.
Long time no see,
Berolinga.
I heard that `Ulu is gonna be baking
for this year’s Bread Festival.
What sort of bread
is he gonna make?
Cutting to the chase,
would you mind sampling my work?
All right!
I haven’t tasted
Maobro’s cooking in ages!
It looks delicious!
It’s gotta be good!
Let’s eat already!
Let’s eat!
Sour!
Delicious!
Sour?
But it’s so sweet and tasty!
What are you talking about?
It’s unbelievably sour! Right?
Sour... Sour... Sour...!
Big brother,
what does this mean?
Well, I wanted to try making bread
using berries that Pokémon like...
So I picked Ubu Berries,
thinking they’d go well with Danish...
Ubu Berries... I knew it.
What’s that, Lilie?
Ubu Berries can be either sweet or sour,
and you can’t tell which it is from looking at them.
Huh...
First I’ve heard of it.
So Kaki just pulled
the short straw.
Well, then,
how about this one?
Sour!
He might end up serving
the sour bread at the festival...
Isn’t there any way around this?
Times like these are when
Berolinga truly shines!
Counting on you, Berolinga!
All right! Bring it on!
Here!
Give it a taste.
But...
It’s fine.
It’s sweet!
What’s going on?
Berolinga has a very keen
sense of taste,
so it can separate the sweet and sour ones
just by tasting their skin!
But doesn’t that mean...
...you could have made only
sweet Danish from the beginning?
Gulp!
You could, couldn’t you?
It’s true...
So sorry about that.
I just wanted to give
a little deemonstration!
It’s “Demonstration”.
Hard at work, I see.
Dad!
Alola, Maopapa!
Is your back doing better?
Yeah, I’m feeling a lot better.
You’re using Ubu Berries?
Those ones are sour,
so he’s not using them.
That’s such a waste...
I feel like they could be used for something...
Awesome!
These are all bakers-roto?
Isn’t this exciting, Snowball?
Let’s go to Mao’s place first.
Yeah!
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Have some absolutely delectable
Honey Bagels, meow!
They look like doughnuts,
but they’re actually bagels!
Absolutely delicious
Honey Bagels!
Three, please!
I want four!
What’s going on?
Customers are just flooding the stand!
I never would have thought
they’d sell this well, meow!
At this rate,
we might actually have a shot...
...at victory!
All right! Let’s keep on selling!
Now’s our chance to get a cruise around Alola!
Yeah!
Huh?
There’s no bread lined up.
Are they still making them?
Mao!
Satoshi...
Still preparing the bread?
What do I do...?
Did something happen?
At this rate, we might...
...not be able to make
any bread at all!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Berolinga
Type:   Normal
His fire’s gone out.
What happened?
Well, he was just carrying
the ingredients, when...
Once we’ve unloaded them,
we’re getting right to baking!
OK!
Alola, you two!
Noa!
Alola! What’s up, Noa?
I wanted to see
how you were doing.
Y-Y-You wanted to see me?
I mean, if you win,
I’ll get to eat your bread every day, right?
I’m so moved!
Hang in there! You’ve got this!
Sure! Sure!
Thank you, Noa!
Big brother?
It’s settled...
Now that I’ve been blessed by the Goddess of Victory,
my success is a foregone conclusion.
Now Noa and I will get m-m-m-m-
So all the sweet Ubu Berries are gone.
It’s my fault.
This happened because
I got careless.
You could try using
another type of berries.
I can’t make that bread
without sweet Ubu Berries.
I’m out of options.
Aren’t there any left at your house?
Only the leftover sour berries.
That’s such a waste...
I feel like they could be used for something...
I know...
Jam!
We can make jam
with the sour Ubu Berries!
We’ll make them sweet
by turning them into jam!
I’ll go get them right away!
You prepare the bread
in the meantime!
H-Hey!
Mao.
I can go to the cafeteria with Lizardon
to get the berries,
so you stay here and
prepare the bread with `Ulu.
But...
We’ll help, too!
If there is anything we can do,
you need only ask.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
Don’t be shy.
We also want to eat
the bread you two made!
Thank you, everyone!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
I gripped my small palms tight
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
It’s missing something...
Really? I think it’s great.
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
What are you doing, Mokuroh?
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
Sweet Scent again?
Sweet...
Of course, Sweet Scent!
Please, Amamaiko!
I choose you!
Future Connection-start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection-don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
Smells great!
Because all the time, see, we’re shining!
Let’s have a try...
It’s perfect!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
These are perfect, too!
Hurry up!
What’s that?
Looks delicious!
I want some!
Me, too.
Yes, right away!
What’s going on?
Why’d the customers disappear
all of a sudden?
It seems some absolutely amazing bread with jam
went on sale over there, meow!
Bread with jam, huh?
Sounds delicious!
How can you be so carefree?
We’re gonna fight back
with our own special jam!
What?!
But what ingredients do we use?
But of course...
We can just use
everything we have!
Cram it all in!
What a mess, meow.
Yeah, if we just mix a whole bunch
of tasty stuff together...
it’ll obviously result in something
supremely delicious!
Told you so.
I’m very sorry!
Alolan Jam Bread is all sold out!
Thank you very much!
Everybody,
thank you for the help!
Well done!
Well, I’m glad
you sold everything, but...
I really wish I could have gotten
a taste for myself.
I wanted to try some, too.
Everybody!
Ta-dough!
We made sure to
save some for you.
All right!
Delicious!
This is the best!
I could eat these all day!
It’s so juicy!
It really is quite delicious.
Here, some for you, too.
Alola!
Noa!
How did you like the bread?
Oh, it was wonderful.
Your cooking training journey
has paid off.
Oh, you flatter me!
If you win, I’ll get to buy this bread at
the Aina Cafeteria every day, right?
That’s right!
You’ll get to buy it every...
...Buy it?
Hey, Noa!
Over here!
Um, and this is...?
He’s my fiancé.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
Fi... an... cé...
We first met because
he was coming to my shop every day,
and now we’re getting married!
I really hope you win!
See you!
His fire’s gone out.
What could have...?
They’ll be announcing
the results soon.
Really? How exciting!
Let’s leave him alone.
Amamaiko...
That’s right. I’m naïve...
The most naïve dunce around!
All right!
The winner of
the Alola Bread Festival is...
...Aina Cafeteria’s Alolan Jam Bread!
You did it, Mao!
Amazing!
Congratulations!
Please step up here
to receive your prize.
Now, go.
What, me?
Go on!
Congratulations!
Thank you very much!
The exquisite harmony between the Ubu Berry jam
and Amamaiko’s Sweet Scent...
...was what landed them the win.
It was a spectacular idea!
Thank you so much!
That jam bread...
...was made with the cooperation of
my friends and family, so...
Hm? Big brother?
Where is he?
What’s this?
To Mao. I’ve learned that
I still have a long way to go.
I’m going on a training journey again!
From `Ulu!
Sheesh... He really is selfish...
Mao! I saw just how much
you’ve evolved!
I swear I’m gonna become the
greatest cook in the world!
Right, Berolinga?
Thump! Wait for me, Ms.!
`Ulu and Berolinga have resumed
their culinary training journey.
Move forth!
Every misstep you make...
...proves you’re moving closer
to your dream!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some Malasada for my Mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
My brother’s partner Pokémon
was Berolinga!
The Licking Pokémon Berolinga
is a Normal type.
Whenever it sees something unfamiliar,
it always licks the object to figure out what it is.
Isn’t it amazing how Berolinga can
discern sweet and sour berries just with a single lick?
Amamaiko, is this one sweet or sour?
You can’t chew it, Amamaiko...
Next episode
All right!
We’ve reached our sales goal
for the month!
The Mixed Cream Malasada Doughnuts
were the talk of the town, after all!
We worked real hard on them!
However! We mustn’t
be caught unaware, meow!
We have to invent some spectacular Malasada recipes
that our rivals can’t replicate, meow!
Aim for...
...our very own
Malasada store chain!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Team Rocket’s Island Pilgrimage?!
Get a Z-Ring!!
Next time
Team Rocket's Island Pilgrimage?!
Get a Z-Ring!!