Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Hokulani Observatory
Malie City
Ten Carat Hill
Altar of the Sunne
Where do we go to in today’s episode?
Blue: Hokulani Observatory?
Red: Malie City?
Green: Ten Carat Hill?
Or Yellow: The Altar of the Sunne?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I see it now!
Where?
There! See?
It doesn’t look very Alola-like...
I read about this in a book.
It seems the city of Malie was
modeled after the Johto Region.
And in Malie Garden, there are
worker Pokémon who tend to the tourists’ needs.
Really? That’s awesome!
I wanna go check out Malie Garden!
I hear there’s a lot of food stands
selling rare foods, too.
I can’t wait!
Sandy!
Let’s have tons of fun here!
It looks like everyone’s gone to
Ula'ula Island’s Malie City to have fun today.
What kind of place will it be?
Their trip starts now!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Xiemi, Meltan and Sandy!
Lost Explorers!!
So this is Malie City?
A two-day, one-night trip
to Malie City...
I’ll make sure to record it-roto!
The wind’s really strong.
Here.
Thank you.
I wonder if it means
a storm’s coming.
It’s all right. The sea is smiling.
If you say so,
then it’s gotta be true!
Apparently these occasional strong gusts
are a seasonal thing.
It shouldn’t be a problem for our trip.
No problem-roto...
Well, then,
let’s hurry to Malie Garden!
Don’t be in such a hurry.
We have to meet up with our guide first.
Sandy!
Sandy really is quite curious.
Don’t go too far.
Hey! That way is dangerous!
Sandy!
Don’t leap into the road.
It’s dangerous!
Thank you, Xiemi.
Well done!
Xiemi is quite attentive.
It might be thanks to Amajo.
Whenever I have my hands full
in the kitchen and stuff like that,
she looks after Xiemi for me.
It looks like she’s been teaching
Xiemi all kinds of things.
So Amajo is like Xiemi’s big sister?
Really?
Where is Amajo today?
She was all fired up about
helping Dad, so she’s back home.
I’ll have to buy them
lots of souvenirs!
But I have to wonder,
where is the guide?
Right here! Believe it!
Did you say something?
No.
I’ve been here for ages,
believe it!
What’s up, Pikach—
A ninja?!
Ninja spotted-roto!
Um... Could you be...
...the guide?
I am your guide, Ana'aki Chikuwa!
Believe it!
A real ninja?!
So cool!
Since we’re in Malie City, I dress like this
for my job as a guide! Believe it!
“Believe it”?
We’re counting on you today...
Sure! I heard what you were saying!
Believe it!
If you wanna go to Malie Garden,
then you should go get a change of clothes first, believe it!
A change of clothes?
They’ll lend you some clothes here!
Believe it!
Alola!
Pleased to have ya.
Ms. Joy!
She looks gorgeous
in an Asian-style outfit!
Ya flatter me...
But compared to my sisters
an’ their fancy makeup...
I’m awful plain, ya know...
I’m the third o’ the four Joy sisters!
Pleasure to meet y’all!
“Plain”...
She’s got more personality
than any of them, though...
We’ve got Malie City outfits
prepared for y’all in here.
Thank you!
Mokuroh, Meltan!
Wake up, we’re leaving.
Guess I’ll let Mokuroh sleep...
How do we look?
They look great on you, Mao!
I love how you’ve used
your hair ornament!
Is this the right way to wear this?
I think you put the obi too high.
This is hard to move in...
It looks great on y’all!
She says it works.
Believe it.
How about we commemorate
the occasion with a photo-roto?
Here goes-roto!
Say “Namakobushi”!
Namakobushi!
All right! Now let’s go
to Malie Garden!
Awesome!
You can get a clear view of the entire Malie Garden
from this observatory! Believe it!
It’s huge!
What a view-roto!
The wind feels lovely!
Hey, look at that!
What?
Oh, I see them! Awesome!
So those are
the worker Pokémon, huh?
Let me see! Let me see!
Sandy?
What is that?
An Eevee procession!
So cute!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
Gotta record this-roto!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
Sandy! No!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
Well, then, this is where
I depart for now. Believe it!
Thank you!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
He vanished!
A ninja indeed...
He’s remarkable indeed!
All right, I guess it’s time for us to
explore the Garden on foot!
Oh oh!
Yeah!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
I’m really hungry
after all that walking.
What should we eat?
I know!
There’s one thing you just
gotta try in Malie City!
Welcomeow! Welcomeow!
Our super popular three-in-one
Mitsuhoney Doughnuts are on sale, meow!
They’re not selling at all...
This is strange.
Operation: “Tourists have loads of money to spend,
so our Doughnuts will sell like crazy!”...
...worked wonderfully
in our simulations, but...
This might be a tourist hotspot,
but doughnuts don’t match the vibe of Malie City, meow.
If you want proof,
just look at that, meow.
Malie City’s famous Octan-yaki is
a massive hit with the tourists, meow!
I hear there are loads of tourists who visit Malie City
specifically to get those, meow.
Their sublime sweet-spicy sauce!
Its taste has been carried down
through the generations,
and it’s simply to die for, meow!
I’ll have three sticks of Octan-yaki!
Make that five for me!
I’ll have ten!
Brat...
...boy?!
What is the brat boy doing here?!
It’s a tourist spot,
so he must be a tourist, right?
Looking closer, it seems like the other brats
from the Pokémon School are there, too, meow.
This is pretty good!
I wonder what this sauce
is made of!
I’ll have some more!
Twenty sticks!
And two more for me!
Is it good?
Look! It’s not just Eyebee...
There’s some really
rare-looking thing there, too!
That’s...
the Mythical Pokémon, Xiemi!
Who’d have thought
we’d meet one here?!
When did the
green brat girl get...
I’m stuffed!
What will we eat next?
...I mean, where will we go?
The library might be interesting.
Don’t they have
a hot spring or something?
Again-roto?!
It finally calmed down...
That’s some wind!
Yeah...
Huh?
What’s wrong, Mao?
My hair ornament is gone!
Did it get carried off somewhere?
Where did it go?!
Meltan?
What’s wrong?
I can’t find Meltan!
What?!
Come to think of it...
Xiemi’s gone, too!
And Sandy!
This is awful-roto!
We have to look for them-roto!
Lugarugan, I choose you!
Look for Meltan and the others!
Counting on you!
Sandy!
Xiemi!
Meltan!
Did you hear that?
Sure did.
Yeah, I heard, meow.
Now’s our chance!
We’ll nab all three of them!
Yeah!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Xiemi
Type:   Grass
Oh, dear...
That sounds awful!
Y’all can leave it to me!
No worries!
We’ll find ‘em in no time at all!
Please do!
Everyone visitin’ Malie City, we’ve got some missin’ Pokémon to report.
Searching... Searching... Searching...
Three Pokémon belongin’ to Pokémon School students:
Xiemi, Meltan and Sandy the Eevee...
...have gotten lost.
If anyone knows where they might be,
please contact the Malie City Pokémon Center.
I repeat...
Hey! Meltan!
Not here, huh...?
Where did they go?
Please respond if you’re there!
Where are you, Sandy?
Xiemi! Xiemi, where are you?
When asked “Xiemi? Vee? Nnn?”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
You waste your time.
It’ll take a lot more than a Tackle to break this cage!
That’s right! The cage is made from
a super sturdy alloy!
You can’t eat this, can you?
The cage is being eaten, meow!
You can even eat
super sturdy alloy?!
We won’t let you get away!
Mimikkyu!
Hidoide!
Now, give it up!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
Xiemi! Where are you?
Xiemi!
Team Rocket?!
What are you doing?!
Isn’t it obvious?
We were catching these Pokémon!
Why, you...!
Nyah nyah!
Don’t like it? Well then, see if
you can land a single hit on me!
That’s...
The brat boy’s...
Well done, Lugarugan!
Satoshi!
The culprits behind
this particular incident are...
Team Rocket! So it’s you!
I won’t let you get away with this!
Meltan!
Use Headbutt on Hidoide!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
Poison moves don’t affect
the Steel-type Meltan-roto!
Let’s go, Sandy!
Use Desperate Tackle on Hidoide!
Hidoide!
This isn’t over!
Mimikkyu’s still here!
Mimikkyu!
Huh? Wait...
Hey! Where are you going?!
Pikachu is here!
Listen, Pikachu is here!
Pikachu, I leave Mimikkyu to you!
Prepare yourselves,
Team Rocket!
W-What?
Nuikoguma?
It seems to be carrying
some huge thing, meow...
If you’re here, that means...
I knew it!
The kite’s going up, meow!
What even is this feeling?
Meltan, are you all right?
I was worried about you, Sandy!
Xiemi, you aren’t hurt, right?
What’s wrong?
Is this my hair ornament?
You were looking for it for me?
Thank you, Xiemi!
Hey!
We finally found you!
I see you found
Xiemi and the others.
Yeah! Team Rocket
was here, though.
But we kicked their butts!
I’m so glad everyone’s safe!
The relief kinda made me hungry...
M-Me, too...
I’ll have ten sticks!
I’ll have twenty!
Then, ten more for me!
Hey...
You won’t have room for dinner...
I’ve got another stomach for that.
Welcome back!
I heard! Believe it!
Good thing you found them all!
Believe it!
As long as y’all are safe...
Sorry to have worried you!
Sorry!
All right! I’ll show you
a cool place tomorrow, believe it!
A cool place?
The Gym of Kanto! Believe it!
I’m one of the trainers there!
Believe it!
Gym? You mean,
like a Pokémon Gym?!
I really wanna go there!
Right, that settles that!
Believe it!
Yeah!
It’s been a busy day, but the Pokémon were able
to work together and get out of the bind they were in.
That said, Satoshi and his friends will be
sightseeing in Malie City tomorrow, too!
Um... Hello?
Ms. Kiteruguma?
We seem to be stuck here, meow...
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thank you for waiting!
The place we went to...
...was Malie City!
Malie City is full of
worker Pokémon!
Hariteyama pulling rickshaws...
Yukimenoko waiting at the teashop...
Nagetsukesaru carrying the kago...
Did you notice them all?
What do you think, Xiemi?
Does it look good on me?
I wonder what sort of outfit
I’ll get to try tomorrow!
Ninja lady!
What? Really?!
Just kidding!
Oh, just kidding?
Next episode
I haven’t had a Gym battle in forever!
I wonder what kind of Gym this will be!
Mr. Chikuwa is a ninja, after all!
So it’s gotta be different
from normal Gyms!
Maybe it’s a ninja mansion?
Maybe it’s got, like,
hidden doors and pitfalls!
Sounds fun!
Satoshi vanished!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Aim for the Top Floor! The Explosive Dragon Gym!!
Next time
Aim for the Top Floor!
The Explosive Dragon Gym!!
That it is!