Alola!
Yours truly, Island King Hala,
will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Water-Z
Fire-Z
Fighting-Z
Electric-Z
What do you receive if
you clear my Grand Trial?
The answer will be announced
at the end of the episode!
Almost ready.
That should do it.
Sorry for the wait!
Ow... Iwanko,
you’ll make me trip!
Go ahead.
I’m hungry, too...
Oh! There’s an article on
your contributions yesterday.
Let’s see-roto...
“The actions of young Satoshi,
who appeared alongside Island King Hala...
“...were a sight to behold.
“With the aid of the Totem Dekagoose and its herd,
whom he had battled in a Trial,
“he successfully drove off
the Ratta and Koratta...
“...who had been making mischief
out of the city lately.
“Young Satoshi is set to receive
a letter of thanks from Ms. Junsa.”
All right!
I’ll get that!
Coming!
Alola, Satoshi!
Ms. Junsa!
And... Dekagoose?
Oh, what’s this? Ms. Junsa,
when’d you make a new friend?
Thanks to your efforts,
I was able to find an excellent partner.
I’m most grateful!
Really? I’m happy for you,
Dekagoose!
Dekagoose is the tenacious,
resilient Stakeout Pokémon.
It’s 99.7% compatible
with Ms. Junsa-roto!
Satoshi, you’re finally facing
the Grand Trial today, aren’t you?
Yeah!
Would you like me to drive you
to Lili'i Town in my car?
All right! Yes, please!
Thank you. But did you
come here just for that?
I nearly forgot!
The letter of thanks to Satoshi!
On behalf of Melemele Island,
I commend your actions,
and present you with this
to show our gratitude.
Here!
Thank you very much!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Will the Z-Move Work?!
Challenging the Grand Trial!!
You’re not staying
to watch the Grand Trial-roto?
I’m afraid I have work to do.
Melemele is a peaceful island,
but there’s still a lot to do.
It’s peaceful thanks to you!
Well then, take care.
Excuse me.
When will Satoshi and Hala
come back-roto?
Oh, they’ll be done soon.
Satoshi and Pikachu are facing
Melemele Island’s Grand Trial.
Before the battle, they went to the Ruins of Conflict
to pray at its altar with Island King Hala.
Today, I will be facing challenger Satoshi
in a Grand Trial battle.
O, Guardian Deity of Conflict,
Kapu-Kokeko...
Please share with us
the power of Alola’s islands.
Kapu-Kokeko... Please watch my
Grand Trial Battle with Mr. Hala, okay?
The prayer is done.
Um... Could Kapu-Kokeko hear
what you were saying?
Perhaps it could, or perhaps not.
Kapu-Kokeko is quite the capricious
Guardian Deity, after all.
Satoshi, let me just make sure
before the Grand Trial begins.
Do you remember the pose
to use the Normal-type Z-Move?
Don’t worry! We’ve practiced it plenty!
Haven’t we, Pikachu?
It’s true-roto!
I see. You’ve got a firm Lock-On
to the Z-Move already, huh?
I’m so excited!
Using Z-Moves uses up a lot of power
from both the person and the Pokémon.
With the strength you, Pikachu and Mokuroh
have right now, you’ll probably only get one shot.
Meaning I have to be careful
about when I use it?
That’s right.
He’s ready to go, Mr. Hala!
As are we.
All right, it is time to begin
the Grand Trial battle...
...between Melemele’s Island King Hala
and Island Pilgrimage challenger Satoshi!
I expect a fair battle!
Please give me a good fight!
Grand Trial
Mokuroh! I choose you!
I’m sure he’s asleep again-roto.
He’s actually awake for once-roto!
Come out, Makenkani!
Makenkani? Rotom!
I got it-roto!
Makenkani. Boxing Pokémon.
Fighting type.
It has an innate drive
to be number one.
While guarding its weak points with its pincers,
it looks for an opening and unleashes punches.
This is a favorable match-up for
the Flying-type Mokuroh-roto!
All right!
Makenkani! Bubble Beam!
Dodge it, Mokuroh!
And then use Peck!
It’s super effective-roto!
Good, Mokuroh!
Another Peck!
Grab it!
Then use Brutal Swing!
Mokuroh!
Makenkani!
Grow Punch!
Mokuroh’s health has
dropped sharply-roto!
The Makenkani Mr. Hala raised
is as powerful as ever!
He really is motivated.
All right, Mokuroh!
Use Leafage!
Bubble Beam!
It got rid of
all the Leafage-roto!
It’s strong!
My Pokémon have been trained
far harder than most, young Satoshi!
Mr. Hala is quite right. Or, no...
If anything he’s downplaying his strength, Satoshi!
Don’t scare me, Mokuroh!
You always sneak up
on me like that...
All right, Mokuroh!
Use Leafage again!
Freak Makenkani out!
The same move again, is it?
If so, then Makenkani!
Use Bubble Beam!
Peck!
Keep using Peck!
Dodge it, Makenkani!
A successful counterattack-roto!
Right!
Guard yourself
with your pincers!
Grow Punch!
Dodge it, Mokuroh!
Makenkani!
Grab Mokuroh and
use Brutal Swing!
Be careful, Mokuroh!
Use Tackle!
Makenkani is unable to battle!
You did very well.
You did it, Mokuroh!
You were so cool!
A spectacular upheaval-roto!
He’s sleeping in mid-air-roto!
Hariteyama,
I entrust this to you.
Wake up, Mokuroh!
It’s time to battle!
Wake up-roto!
Hey, Mokuroh!
Please wake up!
I see... Worn out after
working so hard, is it?
Mokuroh, you did great.
Now leave the rest to us.
Hariteyama. Arm Thrust Pokémon.
Fighting type.
Its thick body is actually
a hunk of solid muscle.
If it bears down and tightens all its muscles,
its body becomes as hard as a rock.
It can send a 10-ton truck flying
with a straight-arm punch.
T-Ten ton?!
Correct-roto.
That’s no less than the weight of
roughly 1,667 Pikachu-roto!
Counting on you, Pikachu!
I choose you!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Fake Out!
Hariteyama! Knock Off!
Pikachu!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Makenkani
Type:   Fighting
What happened-roto?!
I didn’t expect him to
use Fake Out like that-roto!
Fake Out leading into
a Knock Off, huh?
A spectacular combo.
Pikachu, time to strike back!
Electro Ball!
Hariteyama! Arm Thrust!
Even Electro Ball
won’t work-roto?!
Another Arm Thrust!
Arm Thrusts from
the massive Hariteyama...
It’s dealing considerable damage
to Pikachu.
What will you do, Satoshi?!
Dodge it, Pikachu!
He slipped past-roto?!
Now, Pikachu!
Use 100,000 Volts!
A direct hit-roto!
Not even 100,000 Volts works?!
Now the Z-Move is our only option...
We only have one shot...
Hariteyama!
Use Belly Drum!
Belly Drum is a move that
maximizes a Pokémon’s attack power.
But it cuts down the user’s health.
No mercy, huh?
Always fighting at full power...
You really haven’t changed,
Mr. Hala!
Here we go, Hariteyama!
Is that a Z-Move?!
I am he who shares the will of Melemele Island
and the Guardian Deity, Kapu-Kokeko...
The Island King!
The time has come
to unite our strengths as one!
Here it comes.
Pikachu, use Lightning Speed!
Dodge the Z-Move!
Full Power Peerless Fists of Fury!
Pikachu, are you all right?!
Very impressive.
I can see why Kapu-Kokeko
took an interest in you.
We just gotta do this!
Pikachu! Another Lightning Speed!
Run around Hariteyama!
Keep running and use Iron Tail!
Hariteyama!
They damaged it-roto!
Fight one combo
with another, huh?
You did it, Pikachu!
Right! Now it’s our turn!
I can feel it! Pikachu and I
are becoming one,
and it’s making us
way stronger than ever before!
Satoshi and Pikachu
are shining bright-roto!
Go! This is our full power!
Ultra Dash Attack!
Pikachu, the Z-Move worked!
Island King Hala’s Hariteyama
is unable to battle!
As such, the winner of this Island Pilgrimage
Grand Trial battle...
...is the challenger, Satoshi!
All right!
Satoshi is victorious-roto!
Thank you, Hariteyama.
You fought very well.
Mr. Hala!
That was a magnificent battle,
young Satoshi.
Mokuroh, Pikachu and you
all gave it your full power!
Thank you, Sir!
And that Z-Move was
teeming with the joy of battling.
I felt a magnificent youthful aura
coming from you.
I, Melemele’s Island King, Hala...
...decree that you have
cleared your Grand Trial!
Congratulations, Satoshi.
Guess we’re gonna Celebrate tonight.
All right!
Young Satoshi,
do not forget to take this.
What’s that?
It is a Fighting-Z.
With this, you will be able to use
the Fighting-type Z-Move.
Thank you very much!
Was that... Kapu-Kokeko?!
It flew by so fast,
I couldn’t tell what it was-roto!
What is this?!
An Electric-Z! It’s just like the one
Kapu-Kokeko gave me earlier!
Mr. Hala?
Intriguing!
Most intriguing indeed!
Never before have I seen Kapu-Kokeko
take such strong interest in a challenger!
Perhaps I, too,
will see why that is someday.
Now, accept the Electric-Z.
Of course!
I got an Electric-Z!
Second Crystal collected-roto!
Professor Kukui.
Yes?
You spoke of celebrating just now...
May I host a banquet?
In commemoration of young Satoshi
clearing his first Grand Trial!
Of course you may!
Thank you very much, Island King.
Then it is decided!
I must begin preparations at once.
Mr. Hala!
What is it?
Can I invite my friends
from the Pokémon School?
I mean, I might not have been able
to get the Crystal without their help.
Oh, that is a fantastic idea.
By all means, invite them!
Having faced his first
Island Pilgrimage challenge in Alola,
Satoshi has passed his Trial and Grand Trial
with flying colors!
He and Pikachu have perfected
their second Z-Move.
Kapu-Kokeko, thank you
for watching my Grand Trial.
I swear I’ll pull off a Sparking Gigavolt
the next time we meet!
Please fight me again, okay?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Did you all wait?
The answer to the PokéProblem
was a Fighting-Z!
I meant to give it to young Satoshi,
but Melemele Island’s Guardian Deity, Kapu-Kokeko,
swapped it for an Electric-Z instead!
The Land God Pokémon Kapu-Kokeko
is an Electric/Fairy type,
and so it makes sense for it
to hand out an Electric-Z,
yet I do not believe it did so
on a mere whim.
Let us take a quick break.
Is that... the Fighting-Z?
It actually returned it to me?
Kapu-Kokeko is an honorable
Guardian Deity indeed!
Next episode
Pikachu, let’s go to Kaki’s place!
Satoshi, if you wanna visit me,
you’ll have to help with my chores.
Sure! Bring it on!
We run a farm.
You’ll have to look after the Pokémon.
You got it! This’ll be fun!
“Fun”?!
Show Pokémon farms
their due respect!
Did he get really scary all of a sudden,
or is it just me?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Satoshi Visits Kaki!