Alola!
I will be giving
today’s PokéProblem-roto.
Kaki
Satoshi
Gladio
Suiren
Satoshi and the others enter the
Ultra Beasts’ world in today’s episode.
Who is the first to battle in there-roto?
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
As we were heading off to
try and rescue Mother,
unbelievable things kept happening,
one after another.
The Alolan Guardian Deities appearing...
Nebby evolving into the
Legendary Pokémon, Solgaleo...
The Guardian Deities
remaking Satoshi’s Z-Ring...
But because all of this happened...
This is our...
...full power!
...I made it into the Ultra Hole,
to bring Mother back!
We’re out!
This is the Ultra Beasts’ world?
These gems are so pretty!
I’ve never seen gems like these!
I’m not sure they’re stone or metal.
Warning! Warning!
Multiple Ultra Beasts detected-roto!
What are those things?!
That’s UB01: Parasite.
They’re the same kind of Ultra Beast
as the one that kidnapped Mom.
Where is Mother?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Hurry Up!
Operation: Rescue Lusamine!!
That should do it.
What is that, Burnet?
I fired a marker into the spot where
the Ultra Hole emerged,
so that they won’t
get lost on the way back.
Everybody, please come back safely.
What do we do now?
Should we retreat?
The brats are gone,
after all, meow.
All right, all right!
W-We stay here, right?
I suppose we’ll just have to split up
and search for Lilie’s mom.
Split up?
I’m scared of getting separated.
If you’re gonna head into an unknown world,
normally you’d prepare and investigate first, right?
We don’t even have
any equipment, and-
It’s all right, Māmane.
Where are you getting
that confidence from?!
These guys, our Pokémon,
are with us!
You’re right. Snowball,
share your courage with me!
Come out, Ashimari!
Me, too! Counting on you,
Amamaiko!
Let’s go, Bakugames, Garagara!
Come out, Togedemaru, Denjimushi!
Nyabby! Lugarugan! Mokuroh!
I’m counting on you!
Come forth!
Silvuddy, Blacky, Lugarugan!
That’s...
Mother!
The data matches-roto!
We gotta hurry and help her!
UB01: Parasite...
Is it trying to fuse with Mom?
No, no! Stay away!
Mother,
I’m coming to save you now!
Lilie!
Lilie, wait! It’s too dangerous!
But Mother...
Watch out!
Blacky! Use Evil Pulse!
Is this one of that Ultra Beast’s
abilities, too-roto?!
It must be.
But the way she’s acting...
Hey, what’s gonna happen
to Lilie’s mom?!
Since she’s fused with it,
it might drain her energy away.
We can’t let that happen!
There’s so much we still don’t know
about the Ultra Beasts’ biology.
I’m only saying it’s a possibility.
Anyway, we gotta hurry!
Let’s go, everyone!
They’re getting away!
The more we move,
the more we risk provoking them!
Go away! This is mine!
“Mine”?
I got to meet one!
I finally met one!
Come quickly, Lilie’s mom!
Be quiet!
Wait!
Mother!
What’s going on here?
She’s acting like a child.
Yeah!
Is she being controlled?
Perhaps. But at least in part,
those are her true feelings.
That childish tantrum?
Mom has kept up her research for so long,
because she’s always wanted to meet an Ultra Beast.
And that wish has now come true.
But she’s being possessed!
I’m sure she doesn’t feel that she is.
To her, it’s like getting a toy
she’s wanted forever.
A toy?
Meaning that she just sees us as bullies
trying to take her precious toy away.
I don’t care if she thinks we’re bullies.
We will save her!
Yes. We’ll be sure to
make her see reason!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
No! Stay away!
Whoa...
She can even do this?
Go away! I hate you!
Hate?
Lilie, don’t listen to what she says!
Yes.
What she’s saying right now is illogical.
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
Bakugames, use Flamethrower!
Garagara, you use Bone Boomerang!
Stone Edge!
Still no use?
Mother...
Solgaleo!
Incredible!
Go!
All right! Now, everyone!
Quit bothering me!
If you won’t, I’ll just have to scare you away!
What’s that?
Ennewt. Toxic Lizard Pokémon.
Poison/Fire type. Yatoumori’s evolved form.
Its poisonous gas is filled with pheromones,
which it uses to attract male Yatoumori.
That Ennewt is Mother’s.
Yeah. No doubt about it.
Bakugames, use Flamethrower!
They’re getting away!
Everybody!
Leave this to me, and get moving!
Kaki!
Bakugames, use Dragon Tail!
Garagara, you use Flare Drive!
We’ll be fine. Go!
All right. Thanks, Kaki!
We’ll catch you later!
Solgaleo!
You’ll take us there?
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Utsuroid
Type:   Rock/Poison
That aura Mom’s Ennewt was giving off...
It must be because it’s
being controlled by the Ultra Beast.
I’m sure her other Pokémon
will be, too.
Stop! Stay away!
There’s more!
Dredear, Milokaross and Mumagi!
They’re all Pokémon
very dear to Mother.
Ashimari, use Bubble Beam!
Amamaiko, use Magical Leaf!
Togedemaru!
Well done, Togedemaru!
Everyone!
You can see how it is, Satoshi!
The three of us will hold them off!
You keep going!
I’ll support them, too-roto!
Got it. I’m counting on you! Let’s go!
We won’t let you!
Mumagi. Magical Pokémon.
Ghost type.
It appears as if from nowhere—muttering incantations,
placing curses, and giving people terrifying visions.
Curses? Hah! We won’t lose!
Milokaross. Tender Pokémon.
Water type.
It lives at the bottom of clear lakes. In times of war,
it shows itself, which soothes people’s minds and hearts.
Those eyes aren’t
the least bit soothing!
Dredear. Flowering Pokémon.
Grass type.
The fragrance of the garland on its head has a relaxing effect.
It withers if a trainer does not take good care of it.
There’s nothing relaxing
about this!
Ashimari, use Bubble Beam!
Amamaiko, use Round-Trip Slap!
Hang in there, Amamaiko!
W-What?
It’s using Teeter Dance-roto!
You’re kidding! No, why?!
Why are we dancing, too?!
We can’t do anything like this-roto!
Nyabby!
Mokuroh!
Counting on you,
Nyabby, Mokuroh!
Oh, come on, Mokuroh!
He was seduced by
Sweet Scent-roto!
Garagara, use Bone Boomerang!
Let’s go, Bakugames!
My full body, soul and power!
The zenith of all that I am...
Become a blazing flame that burns
like the mountain of Akala!
Dynamic Full Flame!
You did great!
Absol!
Is this another...?
Yeah. It’s been a sparring partner
to my Blacky many times.
Blacky, use Evil Pulse!
Good, Blacky!
Big brother!
Satoshi!
You and Lilie go on ahead.
All right, you got it.
I promise, we will save Mother!
Absol, I will be your opponent.
Silvuddy!
Mean Look, huh?
Why do you keep bothering me?!
I hate you! I hate you!
I despise you!
Lilie, leave this to us!
No, let me do it.
Out of all of Mother’s Pokémon,
this Pixie was my best friend.
Now, hurry to Mother.
Watch out!
Thank you, Lugarugan!
Great work, Lugarugan!
Will you fight with Lilie?
Satoshi, I leave Mother to you!
Yeah, you got it!
Let’s go, Pikachu, Solgaleo!
Come to your senses, Pixie!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Pixie, look!
I’m not very good at battling.
So this how I will fight!
Pixie, please remember...
...how you used to play
with me and this Pippi doll!
I’ll be the mom.
Pippi will be your big sister.
There.
Oh, you match! You’re like twins!
You’re taking care of Pippi?
Pixie, you’re her big sister?
Every day,
we would play family together.
Pixie, please remember...
My hands... My voice...
Please touch the Pippi doll.
Please feel it.
Even if you have been
possessed by the Ultra Beast,
your body and heart
can’t have forgotten...
...the days you spent
together with us.
I will not let go.
Not of you, nor Mother, nor the Pokémon.
I want to take you back.
I love you, Pixie.
You’ve remembered?
I’m so glad.
Everybody, hang in there!
We’re almost there!
We’ve almost reached
Lilie’s mom!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting-roto!
The first one to battle was Kaki-roto!
The Ultra Beasts’ world
is so beautiful, it’s unsettling-roto.
I did not expect Lilie’s mother to have been
possessed by the Pokémon known as UB01: Parasite.
I don’t know how to save her-roto...
Oh, right! Kukui, send out Warrgle.
Oh, sure. But why?
It got hurt a bit in the battle
with Jarango, didn’t it?
I’m sorry you got hurt
for my sake.
Next episode
You know, Pixie, I was really sad...
...when you evolved
and your appearance changed.
Back then, I didn’t really understand...
...how both Pippi and Pixie
have their own unique charms.
Pixie, I love you.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Shine, Z-Power Ring! Super Full Power 10,000,000 Volts!
Next time
Shine, Z-Power Ring!
Super Full Power 10,000,000 Volts!!