Oh, hello!
I will be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Professor Okido
James
Satoshimama
Hoshi
Who comes to Manalo Stadium today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The Alola Pokémon League has gone on for several days,
with intense battles continuing to unfold.
Gladio won the first match
of round two.
The second match ended with
Satoshi’s hard-earned victory against Hau.
In the third match, Māmane’s Kuwagannon
pushed Kaki’s Lizardon to the edge, but...
Ram them with Wild Bolt!
Kuwagannon is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is
Competitor Kaki!
In the fourth match,
Suiren clashed with Guzma.
Embraced by our mother, the sea...
Echo...
...beyond the horizon!
Sea God’s Symphonia!
I’ll destroy your pathetic Z-Move!
Gusokumusha! Aqua Break!
Ashirène is unable to battle!
The winner is Competitor Guzma!
And at last, we’re down to
the top four competitors...
The semifinals are about to begin!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Semifinals!
Kaki VS Gladio!!
Bakugames! Use Dragon Tail!
Don’t give up!
Nyaheat, use Revenge!
You’re on fire-roto!
Use Great Blaze!
Flamethrower!
You’re really focused, Kaki!
Yeah!
I’m facing Gladio, after all!
I have to use my full power!
A battle between
you and Gladio, huh...
This is gonna be so exciting!
We’re really excited, too!
I want both of you to win!
Yeah!
But who do I root for?
I’ll be rooting for Kaki!
He’s the one that
beat my Kuwagannon, after all!
I will leave cheering for Kaki
to all of you.
Meanwhile, I’ll root for my brother
with everything I have!
Nothing would make a brother happier
than cheers from his little sister!
Oh, right!
We’d better go meet Hoshi.
It’s that time already?
Let’s all go.
Hoshi!
Where are you?
She wasn’t on the boat.
Why?! This makes no sense!
Why aren’t you here, Hoshi?!
Calm down, Kaki!
Kaki!
I just asked them, and they said
the boat got here 30 minutes ahead of time!
I see!
So Hoshi went to the stadium
on her own?
All right!
Your brother will be right there!
Geez...
It’s right there,
but I can’t get down!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
We’re the proud Team Skull!
We’re the famous Team Skull!
Enough with being nice!
Let out steam with destruction!
Full power! Blue skies!
You’re not allowed to do that!
Who’s the kid?
Ya got a problem
with Team Skull?
If ya get in our way,
ya best not expect no mercy!
I said you can’t doodle on
stuff that isn’t yours!
Oh.
Still got gripes?
Well, let’s hear ‘em!
Air Slash!
Hoshi!
Scram.
Yer...
Ya kiddin’ me?!
Ya puffed-up poser!
Bro’s gonna teach ya a lesson!
Y-Yeah!
We’ll let’cha off the hook for now!
What?!
W-Wait!
Bro!
Um...
T-Thank you!
Are you okay?
Yeah!
What’s your name?
Hoshi!
Hoshi?
You see, my big brother has
a Pokémon League battle today!
I’m here to cheer him on!
Are you Kaki’s little sister?
Yup! You know my big bro?
Yeah... This way.
You want to go
to the stadium, right?
Yup!
Something wrong?
No, it’s nothing.
I hope big bro wins!
Big bro is always really worried about me,
and he’s really overprotective,
but he’s real strong
in Pokémon battles!
I see. You care a lot
about your brother, don’t you?
Yup!
Hoshi!
Big bro!
I was so worried!
I’m fine!
I’m so glad you’re not hurt!
Why is Gladio here?
You see, this guy saved me!
From some guys called the School Gang or something!
“School Gang”?
You mean Team Skull?
Yup!
I see! Thank you, Gladio!
You don’t have to thank me.
It was nothing.
Big brother!
Lilie!
Huh? He’s Lilie’s big bro?
That’s right!
Oh, you were with Gladio?
I’m so glad you’re all right!
Yeah!
Um... The boat got here early, see...
I thought I could get to
the stadium on my own...
I’m sorry!
You’d better wait
till I get there next time.
Yup!
Later.
See you on the battlefield.
Huh? What’s that mean?
He’s my opponent today.
What?! Really?!
That cool Mr. Gladio
is facing my big bro...
Don’t worry, Hoshi.
Now that you’re here
to cheer me on...
I’m unbeatable!
I’m not so sure...
Thank you very much!
The Manalo Doughnuts
sold like crazy today, too, meow!
Can you believe they all sold out
before noon?!
Let’s have a toast of Pile Juice!
Cheers!
Nothing beats a drink after a hard day
of honest work, meow!
That’s right.
Honest work is the best!
Wait, was it really?
Of course it is!
We work up a good sweat, sell loads of doughnuts,
and everyone’s happy!
Actually, this does feel a bit off.
Doesn’t it?
I feel like we worked hard at something
“for truth and love.”
Gotta be doughnuts.
Or poking holes in doughnuts...
No!
It was evil!
We championed the evils
of truth and love!
We were so caught up in our work that
we forgot something extremely important!
We were on the verge of
losing our righteous evil,
turning into regular old
Honey Doughnuts salesmen, meow!
We must reclaim our evil nature!
Right! Let’s do some evil!
Righteous evil, meow!
So, what evil do we do?
Well, of course...
We gotta steal the League prizes, yeah?
I’ll have the first prize!
I’ll take the runner-up’s crown!
I can settle for
the third-prize Charm, meow!
...No! We’ve thought small
for way too long, meow!
For our boss, Sakaki,
we ought to...
...nab every single one of
the competitors’ Pokémon, meow!
So evil!
But in order to carry out that plan...
We’ll need a new mech!
And to get the funds for that...
Let’s sell some doughnuts!
Huh...?
We’re the proud Team Skull!
We’re the famous Team Skull!
Boss!
My foulest, greatest brothers,
how are you doing?!
Yeah!
As foul and blue as can be...
My irritation’s as great as can be...
That’s life.
Nothing you can do about it.
Yeah!
Boss! Today’s the semifinals, yeah?
Total farce.
The semifinals...
Even the finals will just be a baby’s game.
Yer the best, Mr. Guzma!
Yer winnin’ this, no doubt!
Wreck those League players!
The whole thing.
Huh?
I’ll wreck the whole League,
players and all!
Yeah!
But, boss...
You shouldn’t underestimate
that Satoshi kid.
It could be bad news
if you let your guard down.
Did you forget?
I am a legendary,
undefeated trainer.
Yeah!
Mr. Guzma’s
only ever tasted victory!
Yeah!
You guys just don’t know...
...why Guzma hasn’t
ever lost before.
The semifinals of the Alola Pokémon League
are finally starting today!
The first match is Competitor Kaki
VS Competitor Gladio!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Eevee
Type:   Normal
The first match of the semifinals is
Competitor Kaki VS Competitor Gladio!
Both of them are
exceptionally skilled!
What sort of battle awaits us?
It’s starting!
Big brother!
Big bro!
Here I am!
Big brother!
Do your best!
Oh! Ms. Lychee is the referee!
We will now begin
the first match of the semifinals!
Clash with your full power,
and refine each other through it!
That is the kind of battle
I wish to see!
You may use two Pokémon each.
You are free to switch at any time.
Once both Pokémon on one side are incapacitated,
that side will have lost.
Now, bring out your first Pokémon!
Let’s do this, Garagara!
Come forth, crimson glare.
Lugarugan!
First off is a clash between the Fire/Ghost-type Garagara
and the Rock-type Lugarugan!
In terms of type match-ups,
Lugarugan has the upper hand,
but you can never tell how a battle
will go before it’s over.
May those who battle
be blessed by Wela Volcano...
Let the match begin!
Victory goes to he who strikes first!
Bone Boomerang!
Dodge it!
That’s not all!
Lugarugan! Swords Dance!
So you’ve powered up
with Swords Dance?
Stone Edge!
If that hits, it’ll be devastating.
Avoid it at all costs, Garagara!
Right! Iron Head!
It won’t be that easy!
Draw him in
and use Stone Edge!
Smash it!
That’s gotta hurt!
Hang in there, Garagara!
So I can’t charge in,
even with Iron Head...
In that case...
Flare Drive!
Oh, my!
How does he intend to use this Fire move,
which has a disadvantage against a Rock type?!
No use! Stone Edge!
What?!
And then...
Iron Head!
Ferocious! Garagara’s Iron Head
makes a direct hit!
Well done, Garagara!
I was waiting for this!
Oh, no! Garagara, dodge it!
Stone Edge!
Garagara!
Garagara is unable to battle!
Big bro!
It’s all right!
Don’t worry, Kaki!
You still have one more!
Thank you, Garagara.
You did well.
Bring out your next Pokémon,
Competitor Kaki.
I’ll entrust our victory to you!
Bakugames!
Competitor Kaki’s second Pokémon
is Bakugames!
Big bro! Baku! Hang in there!
If we want to defeat Lugarugan,
we’ll have to find a way to conquer that Stone Edge.
And you have just the move for it!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Use Dragon Tail!
Dragon Tail breaks through the Stone Edge
and lands a hit!
Lugarugan!
Keep up the pressure!
Dragon Tail!
Use Counter!
Dragon Tail and Counter clash!
Bakugames!
Stand up, Lugarugan!
Bakugames, get on your feet!
Flamethrower!
Another Fire move that
doesn’t do much against Rock types!
Those flames will ignite
Lugarugan’s crimson glare!
Use Reversed Scale!
I was waiting for that!
Trap Shell!
What?!
Bakugames’s Trap Shell hits!
Yes! Excellent work,
Bakugames!
Not bad... However...
It’ll take more than that to stop
our Reversed Scale.
Go!
Counter it with Trap Shell!
What?!
It should be blinded by Reversed Scale...
But it kept a cool head
and made a frontal attack?!
So, that’s the sort of
training they’ve done...
Don’t let them get away!
Bakugames!
Keep your focus and
tough it out!
Focus!
Lugarugan!
Oh, my! Was that a Focus Blast?!
At the last minute,
Bakugames has learned Focus Blast!
It’s super effective!
Bakugames?!
All right! Use Focus Blast!
Lugarugan is unable to battle!
Yes!
He did it!
Amazing!
Now it’s one on one.
That’s incredible, Kaki!
Teaching your Pokémon a new move mid-battle!
You did well, Lugarugan!
Competitor Gladio.
Send out your next Pokémon.
Go, sacred beast Silvuddy!
Competitor Gladio’s second Pokémon
is Silvuddy!
The first match of the semifinals;
Gladio VS Kaki!
Who will win?!
And how will the second match
between Satoshi and Guzma go?!
To be continued
in the next episode!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Thank you for waiting!
It was Hoshi who
came to Manalo Stadium!
Bakugames’s new attack, Focus Blast,
is a Fighting-type move!
It’s super effective against Rock types,
so it was too much even for Gladio’s Lugarugan!
Beat down and smash
this rotten world!
Ain’t no kids to disturb us here!
Let’s wrap this up
before Mr. Guzma’s match!
Whoa!
Hey, lemme down!
Next episode
Go! Fight! Win! Kaki!
Go! Fight! Win! Gladio!
You’re so cute!
All right! We’ll do it, too!
Go! Fight! Win! Kaki!
Go! Fight! Win! Gladio!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Explosive Birth!
Pokémon School Cheerleaders!!
Just kidding!
It’s actually...
Next time
Rising Fire!
There’s More Than One Rival!!
Rising Fire! There’s More Than One Rival!!