Alola! Snip snip! V! V!
I will be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
What type is the newly discovered
Pokémon species seen today?
Flying
Ground
Psychic
Steel
Blue: Flying?
Red: Ground?
Green: Psychic?
Or Yellow: Steel?
Get the answer at the end!
Alola, Professor Okido!
Alola!
The Pokémon from yesterday
is indeed a new species!
Really?!
Indeed.
I’ve named it
the Nut Pokémon, Meltan.
Just as you guys predicted,
it’s a Steel type.
Your observation skills
are remarkable, Satoshi.
Meltan has been recorded
in the Index-roto!
Well then, Professor Kukui...
I’ll be counting on you
and Professor Burnet.
Of course!
Bye bye!
Bye.
Meltan, huh?
I hope we’ll get to meet again today!
Now, now, Satoshi...
It’s almost time to leave.
Are you ready?
Of course!
Everyone, time for
Pokémon School!
Mokuroh, you go in here.
Just my imagination?
See ya later!
Bye.
Have a nice day!
What is this?!
An Ultra Hole?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
New Species Discovered!
I Got Meltan!!
The Pokémon School was all riled up
over the outbreak of Meltan yesterday...
Now, what will today bring?
I see! So it was a new species!
Apparently it’s called Meltan.
Our observations were
well worth it!
It spun its head around, right?
What if there are some
hiding in here right now?
There!
Talk about attention to detail...
Maybe Suiren’s disguise
will make them come out?
They appeared in our classroom yesterday,
so they could still be close by!
Alola, everyone!
Alola, Professor Kukui!
For today’s afternoon classes,
you’ll all be battling each other!
All right!
Satoshi, let’s battle!
Sure! Bring it on!
Mao, let’s fight!
Okay!
Amajo, Xiemi,
let’s do our best!
Oshamari, Sandy, us too!
Māmane, would you like to have
Kuwagannon battle Snowball?
Sure! I won’t lose, though!
Mokuroh, we’re gonna battle!
Guess he’s not waking up...
Oh, well. Let’s go!
This goes here,
and then this goes...
Are the repairs done yet?
We won’t be able to sell our
“Three-in-one Mitsuhoney Doughnuts” like this!
That’s right, meow!
My brilliant idea,
Operation: “Set up shop in front of the cinema
and sell like crazy”...
...has gotta work,
I’m sure, meow!
Even my fortune on TV this morning
said that my luck today would be superb, meow!
Oh, this nut’s broken!
It’s cracked, meow.
We’ll have to get another one.
Well then, use this.
Oh, this’ll fit perfectly!
...No, I can’t use a doughnut
to fix the engine!
It’s an energy replenisher.
We’re not getting anywhere
if we can’t find a nut, meow...
If only one would fall from the sky
right about now, meow...
What?
Will you quiet down, Nyarth...
A nut really did
fall out of the sky, meow...
That’s just nuts!
That’s...
Is it not...?!
Shape, sheen, solidity...
This nut is perfect in every way!
Truly a nut among nuts!
All right, meow! Now we can go sell our
three-in-one Mitsuhoney Doughnuts, meow!
Let’s go sell ‘til
there’s nothing left!
Yeah!
Nyaheat! Great Blaze!
Lugarugan! Stone Edge!
Now, Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Lizardon! Use Turning Swallow Strike!
All right, that’s enough!
Thanks, Lugarugan, Nyaheat!
Battling you really is fun!
Yeah! Thanks!
Oh, by the way, Satoshi.
You’ve cleared all four Grand Trials, right?
What will you do now?
Oh...
What will I do?
Huh?
Hey, Mokuroh!
I’ll go have a look.
Right.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pixie
Type:   Fairy
Welcomeow, welcomeow!
Today we’re selling our mega special
three-in-one Mitsuhoney Doughnuts, meow!
Oh, come on!
We’re not selling anything!
Operation: “Set up shop in front of the cinema
and sell like crazy”? It’s a complete bust!
The screening of that six-hour-long feature film
just started, so nobody’s outside...
I’m done!
Change of plan!
I’m gonna go search for Eyebee!
Eyebee?
The eyebeam Pokémon who
melted my crown cap collection?
The pain they’ll suffer when I find them
will be my crowning achievement!
Kojiro’s turned
into Mimikkyu, meow...
Crowning achievement!
Avenging my crown caps!
But how will we find
that Pokémon, meow?
I figured if we just walked around randomly,
we’d run into it eventually?
You mean, like, “the Iwanko that trots around finds a...”
whatever it was, meow?
If only Eyebee would fall
from the sky about now, meow...
Why’d a tambourine
fall from the sky?
Wrong, meow!
It’s Eyebee, meow!
Eyebee...
But wait...
It doesn’t look quite right...
Hey, that thing’s here, too!
Yeah... It’s that thing
the brat boy’s got with him, yeah?
Who gave you permission
to eat our doughnuts, meow?!
Look! That Pokémon really is
the Eyebee we met yesterday!
Time to close up
the doughnut stand!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
I will have vengeance for my crown caps!
Prepare yourselves!
Are you all right?
What’s it saying?
It’s saying
“You’ll have to go through me,” meow!
Well, I’d like to see you try! Nyarth!
You got it, meow!
I won’t let you go, meow!
Its attacks appear frozen to me, meow!
The fortune show was right.
My luck today is superb, meow!
Eat my Chaotic Scratches, meow!
What are you doing?
Kick its butt already!
You don’t have to tell me, meow!
You’re so stubborn, meow...
This is the end, meow!
Hey, Nyarth?!
What are you doing?!
If you’re here, that means...
What even is this feeling?
Mokuroh!
What’s happened to you?!
Meltan!
Did it get separated from its friends?
You found a Meltan?!
Seems Mokuroh
was looking after it.
Well done, Mokuroh.
We’ll have to find its friends.
But where do we look?
Pixie! Did something happen?
Meltan!
Awesome!
They’re following
Pixie’s commands!
They were
surprisingly easy to find...
It’s gotten really attached
to Mokuroh, huh?
You want to be with Mokuroh?
Then is it okay
if I catch you?
Of course, Mokuroh!
Meltan, starting today,
you’re one of us!
Go, Monster Ball!
Oh, dear...
One more time!
Go, Monster Ball!
I got Meltan!
Be nice to each other, okay?
The newly discovered Pokémon, Meltan.
It looks like it and Mokuroh
will make a great team!
They’ll be together
from now on!
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting! V! V!
Meltan was determined to be
Yellow: A Steel type!
The Steel-type Pokémon Meltan
has been classified as the Nut Pokémon.
Apparently it has a body made of molten steel,
which it uses to absorb metals.
It’s still shrouded in mystery,
so I can’t wait to uncover its secrets!
Meltan, so this was
your doing, was it?
I guess this one’s a lost cause,
but don’t eat the new one, okay?
Next episode
All right, let’s go, Māmane!
I’ll aim for a perfect score!
Hang in there, Māmane!
Question: In the Alola Region, there’s...
Alolan Betobeton!
Correct!
Really?
Question: The Alola Region has...
Chigo Berries!
Correct!
You really got it?
Hey, come on!
Question: The Alola Region’s...
Li’l Koi!
Correct!
Question: Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
A New Series?! A Tiny Koiking’s Melody
What even is this feeling?
Next time
A New Series?!
A Tiny Koiking’s Melody