Alola!
I will be giving
today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Kapu-Rehire
Kapu-Bulul
Kapu-Tetefu
Kapu-Kokeko
Which Pokémon battles Lugarugan
in today’s episode?
Blue: Kapu-Rehire?
Red: Kapu-Bulul?
Green: Kapu-Tetefu?
Yellow: Kapu-Kokeko?
Get the answer at the end-roto!
Training! Training!
Training!
Let’s go to
the Ruins of Abundance-roto!
Yeah!
Wait!
Whoa, it’s huge!
Banbadoro. Draft Horse Pokémon.
Ground type.
Its heavy, mud-covered kicks are
its best means of attack,
and it can reduce large trucks to scrap
without breaking a sweat.
You’ve never been to
the Ruins of Abundance before, have you?
I’ll take you there!
Get on behind me.
Thank you, Acerola.
Banbadoro... Let’s go!
Satoshi and Lugarugan lost a battle
against Ula'ula’s Island King, Kuchinashi.
They now set off for the Ruins of Abundance,
hoping the Guardian Deity Kapu-Bulul will train them.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Kapu-Bulul!
Intense Slacker Training!!
A desert?
The Ruins of Abundance are
on the other side of Haina Desert.
Okay, got it.
Let’s get going, right now!
Up and down, left and right...
Wherever I turn, there’s nothing but sand-roto!
You all right?
Yeah...
Mokuroh!
Bebenom!
What a relief...
Thanks, Bebenom.
When you put your mind to it,
you sure do fly fast!
All right,
we’re almost through the desert.
Hang in there!
Yeah!
The Ruins of Abundance!
I wonder if Kapu-Bulul will train us?
Wait!
If it’s Kapu-Bulul you want...
Up... there?!
What?! S-So quick!
Pikachu...
See you later-roto!
We’ll be waiting up top-roto!
I made it...
All right!
Come out!
Mokuroh?
Satoshi, over there!
Kapu-Bulul!
Ula'ula Island’s Guardian Deity-roto!
Me, too!
Kapu-Bulul!
I’m Satoshi!
We met at
the Altar of the Sunne, remember?
We came here for
the Island Pilgrimage.
But we lost against
Island King Kuchinashi.
So, I’d like you to train us.
Please, Kapu-Bulul!
Kapu-Bulul!
Wake up, Kapu-Bulul!
Mokuroh, you, too-roto!
Mokuroh...
Kapu-Bulul. Land God Pokémon.
Grass/Fairy type.
The Guardian Deity of Ula'ula
is a lazy Pokémon.
It causes vegetation to grow,
and then it absorbs energy from the growth.
Kapu-Bulul!
Bebenom...
I’m sorry, Kapu-Bulul!
You’ll train us?
That’s awesome, Kapu-Bulul!
So this is
the Guardian Deity’s power...
I’ve never seen it in person before!
So this is what they meant by “It causes vegetation to grow,
and then it absorbs energy from the growth”-roto?
Mokuroh?!
Leafage? No, that wasn’t it...
That was Razor Leaf-roto!
When did he learn Razor Leaf-roto?!
I’m sure he got power
from the tree!
I see!
Your Razor Leaf was so cool!
Mokuroh got Razor Leaf-roto!
Pocket Monsters...
Sun &...
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kapu-Bulul
Type:   Grass/Fairy
Over there!
Sheesh...
Man, this sucks! I’m soaked!
We’re saved, meow...
Looks like we’ll have to
take shelter here for a while.
In here?!
But this is kinda relaxing...
Ever since we started living
with Kiteruguma here in Alola,
our bodies have started to
relax more easily in places like these, meow!
Well, Kiteruguma
isn’t here right now.
We’re free to do as we please.
Mimikkyu, come on out.
Let’s take this time to
do some Z-Move training!
So, tell me,
what sort of pose should I take?
Huh? You’re having Mimikkyu
teach you?
There’s no way it’d know, meow.
Why not?
It’s Mimikkyu’s Z-Move, right?
How could Mimikkyu
not know it?
What’s that?
Isn’t that a bit out there?
That pose is gonna
haunt my nightmares, meow...
They’re all soaked and
covered in mud-roto...
But it looks fun, doesn’t it?
Not good!
Lugarugan’s eyes...!
Calm down, Lugarugan!
Doesn’t the rain shower feel nice?!
Don’t you remember,
back when you were an Iwanko?
We’d play in the rain
just like this, remember?
To me, it feels like it was
only yesterday!
Now you’ve done it, Iwanko!
We just kept playing,
no matter how muddy we got!
You may look different
after evolving,
but you’re still you.
Now, Iwanko!
You’re stubborn...
Clingy...
And a little bit clumsy...
But I wouldn’t have you
any other way!
Lugarugan!
Well done, Satoshi!
I knew you could do it-roto!
There, there...
What a good boy...
Kapu-Bulul?
You’ll train us?!
What’s this?
Grass Field!
Satoshi! In Grass Field,
the power of Grass-type moves increases-roto!
Got it! Thanks, Rotom!
Heh-heh-roto!
Doesn’t this remind you...
...of the green flash
we saw on Akala Island?
Back when you evolved
from Iwanko to Lugarugan.
He’s evolving?
All right! Let’s tackle this training session
with our full power, Lugarugan!
You’ve got the powers of both
Midday form and Midnight form...
Two amazing powers!
Don’t forget that!
Dodge, Lugarugan!
Lugarugan!
Rock Throw!
It’s insanely powerful!
Lugarugan!
Thank goodness!
This is Wood Horn-roto!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Use Tackle!
I gripped my small palms tight
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
Is that a Solar Beam?!
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
Dodge it, Lugarugan!
In this world I wandered into all alone
Good!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
W-What’s going on?
A new move?!
I choose you!
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Isn’t this...?
It’s Stone Edge!
Oh oh!
He learned Stone Edge-roto?!
Because all the time, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Kapu-Bulul?
Kapu-Bulul recognized
Lugarugan’s strength!
Oran Berries!
Oran Berries have the effect of
restoring a Pokémon’s energy-roto!
I want one, too!
What?
Delicious!
The training was a success,
right, you two?
It’s all thanks to you, Acerola.
Thank you, Kapu-Bulul!
All right! This time we’ll clear
Mr. Kuchinashi’s Trial for sure!
Lugarugan has grown tougher
thanks to Kapu-Bulul’s training.
What sort of Trial
awaits them?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting-roto!
The one that battled Lugarugan...
...was Kapu-Bulul-roto!
The Land God Pokémon Kapu-Bulul
is a Grass/Fairy type.
It swings large trees around,
manipulates grass and trees to stop its foes from moving...
...and pierces them with its horns.
It is a brutal Guardian Deity-roto!
Yet despite that, it’s also lazy
and loves napping-roto!
Hey, Mokuroh...
Oh, my...
Next episode
W-What is it, Mimikkyu?
I-It seems strangely fired up,
doesn’t it?
What is it saying, Nyarth?
It’s saying “Today is the day
I defeat Pikachu”, meow!
The rest of what it says is
too terrifying for me to ever say out loud, meow...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon...
Next time
Super Showdown!
Pikachu VS Mimikkyu!!
Super Showdown! Pikachu VS Mimikkyu!!
Meow!