Alola!
I shall be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Which Pokémon emerges
from the Ultra Hole today?
Lunala
Massivoon
Tekkaguya
Tsundetsunde
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
I slept great!
It’s the start of
a new morning-roto!
What’s up, Bebenom?
Looking for something-roto?
Time to eat! Time to eat!
Professor! Alola!
Hmm? Something wrong?
That’s what I should be saying!
Why have you buttoned up
your coat-roto?!
Huh? ‘cuz it’s cold.
He’s even wearing a T-shirt!
It’s kinda like there’s a dark cloud
hovering above my mind... or something...
Where’s Professor Burnet?
Right here...
Are you all right?!
Yeah... Just a bit sleepy...
You’re not going to
the ocean today?
I’ll just observe these instead...
Good enough.
What’s this? They seem to be
acting somewhat strange today...
Well... Whatever...
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
A Crisis In Alola!
The Darkness that Eats Radiance!!
Alola!
Alola...
Man, I’m so hungry...
Didn’t you have breakfast?
No.
Mom overslept...
And she never does that!
Really?
Alola!
Hey, listen to this.
Dad didn’t do any of the usual morning chores today,
saying he didn’t feel up for it!
My parents, too. I had to work like crazy to get
all the Pokémon chores done before making my deliveries.
Same. Dad didn’t go out fishing.
He was just lazing about at home.
James was acting
somewhat oddly as well.
For real?! Professor Kukui and Professor Burnet
were acting weird, too!
Weird how?
Well...
‘sup...
Just like that.
Professor Kukui,
it’s not “‘sup”, it’s “Alola”!
Oh, right.
Did something happen to you?
No, nothing.
Um... I was going to hold
a class on the Manalo Festival...
...which will be held during
the total solar eclipse in two days...
Discuss it yourselves.
Huh?!
Okay, keep it up...
Today I’ll just be a slackeRokon...
Very well! I will tell you
about the Manalo Festival!
Yeah! Counting on you!
Once every 21 years,
there’s a total solar eclipse in Alola.
The four Island Kings and Queens of Alola
go to their islands’ ruins on that day...
...and offer a prayer of gratitude to
the Legendary Pokémon described in Alola’s creation myth!
That’s the Manalo Festival, which has been a tradition in Alola
since the region was formed!
What’s “Manalo”?
It’s from the old language.
It means “You and I live together.”
Really? Sounds nice!
I like it, too.
Alola and Manalo...
Hmm? “Alola” and “Manalo”
are quite similar, yes?
“Alola” means “To share”.
Put the two together and you get...
“We share and live together!”
I have a question.
Could you tell us about this Legendary Pokémon
described in Alola’s creation myth?
That’s the Radiant One!
The Radiant One?
You know of it?
Yeah.
This girl named Acerola
told me about it on Ula'ula Island.
We saw this picture
back then-roto!
This is the Radiant One?
Solgaleo and Lunala
are there, too.
Bebenom drew a picture of the Radiant One
not too long ago, too-roto.
Why would it do that?
We don’t really know.
I’ve heard about
the Radiant One, too.
Really?
Back when Mother was still young,
Grandfather would tell her
the legend of the Radiant One to help her sleep.
And in the same way,
Mother told the legend to me and my brother.
I see!
Hey, could you tell it to us, too?
The legend of the Radiant One!
Very well!
The Radiant One appeared on Earth,
and filled the world with its overflowing light.
The light was filled with a mysterious power,
and from it our Alola Region was born.
However, after the Radiant One
had depleted all its light,
it turned black,
and entered a long, deep slumber.
Then the emissaries of the sun and moon appeared,
and shared their light with it.
Awakened from its slumber,
the Radiant One shone once more,
and flew off to
the ends of the sky.
The end.
First time I’ve heard the story.
What are these
“emissaries of the sun and moon”?
They’re probably Solgaleo and Lunala.
They were in that picture, too.
What about
the “ends of the sky”?
The other side of the Ultra Hole!
Does that mean that the Radiant One
still lives on the other side of the Ultra Hole?
That is absolutely possible,
if the story is indeed true.
The Radiant One, huh...
Lunch time!
Māmane, you mean
you don’t have lunch either?!
Yeah... My life is over...
Right! Together, we can
weather any storMaggyo!
Mankey! Mantine!
What are you doing?
That just makes me even hungrier...
It’s Principal Okido’s vaunted
Pokémon gags-roto!
Satoshi, have you lost it, too?
No, it’s Alola! Sharing!
Then, have some of mine as well!
Mine, too.
And mine!
Here you go.
Thank you, everyone!
Well, then...
Lunch time!
It’s great!
Alola, Manalo...
Yeah!
“We share... and live together!”
I’m so excited, meow!
I can’t wait for the eclipse, meow!
Eclipse? Big deal...
It’s just the sun getting covered by the moon
so you can’t see it, right?
It might have caused
a huge commotion in the past...
But to us, it’s just
a well-understood natural phenomenon.
Why are you so cold, meow?
Everybody else is
looking forward to it, meow!
Huh? Dad? Are you here?
Are you ready?!
Bring it!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
We’re gonna counter them,
Garagara!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Huh?
That wasn’t very powerful...
Neither Pikachu nor Garagara stored up enough Z-Power,
the energy used to launch Z-Moves-roto!
Maybe because it’s cloudy?
That can affect it?
What’s up, Bebenom?
What’s this?
Gotta record it-roto!
All the Ultra Aura readings that
have been recorded across Alola so far...
...are rapidly diminishing...
What could cause that to happen?
I’m investigating it right now...
Sauboh...
Yes...
You may only speak after I,
your superior, have done so...
S-Sorry, Chief...
I didn’t mean to
phrase it like that...
I’m just in such a downer mood,
it’s making me say things in a much harsher way...
It’s not just you...
I feel the same way, too...
Could that be due to
the Ultra Aura diminshing, too?
I can’t say for sure yet...
But there might be a connection...
Analysis complete...
It looks like a tiny Ultra Hole
has opened...
...and the Ultra Aura in Alola
is being sucked into it...
Sucked in?
Up until now, whenever an Ultra Beast has appeared,
the Ultra Aura readings have spiked...
But this time, it’s
the complete opposite...
The only possibility I can think of...
...is that there’s a Beast
that absorbs Ultra Aura...
Looks like we’ll need
to investigate this...
What a pain...
Yeah...
How is the situation?
Well, Sakaki, sir...
It seems like an Ultra Hole has indeed opened,
though it is a small one.
Which means there’s a chance
that our target might appear.
I see. So there is a chance that this might be
that “Radiant One” I’ve heard about?
I don’t know.
Figuring that out would be
my mission, would it not?
I expect great things from you.
Yes, sir!
Gozu. How far off is
the Alola Region now?
We’ll be there momentarily.
Do it.
Optical camouflage!
Roger!
What’s wrong, Silvuddy?!
Calm down!
Come on, calm down!
You’re frightened?
Don’t tell me...
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Silvuddy
Type:   Normal
It’s not clearing up...
If anything,
it’s just getting darker.
It’s like a storm is coming.
That’s the Ultra Guardians
dispatch call!
This is usually
where Professor Kukui...
Another day where
I think I’ll just...
...Be a slackeRokon.
Then I’ll do it!
Let’s go!
Huh?
A... Alola...
Ultra Guardians...
Are you ready...?
Yes.
Mother! You should make yourself presentable
before appearing before others!
I guess...
That’s such a pain, though...
Mother!
Everyone, head for the Altar of the Sunne
on Poni Island, on the double.
Has another Ultra Beast appeared?
I’ll tell you the details
when you’re there...
Okay!
Okay... See you there.
Is something wrong?
Where’s the cool line-roto?!
This is my chance!
I’ve wanted to say it!
Ultra Guardians,
move out at once!
Ult-Roger!
Professor Burnet’s there, too!
Thanks for coming!
The seventh one
should be here any moment.
Seventh one?
Satoshi!
Gladio!
Big Brother! But why?
Silvuddy is frightened.
If the cause is an Ultra Beast,
then it could be the most dangerous one yet.
Really?
Don’t tell me...
That’s an Ultra Beast, too?!
Yeah. It’s called Bebenom.
Isn’t it cute?
Ms. Lusamine,
what is our mission this time?
We’ll explain from the top...
And by “we”, I mean Burnet.
Sure...
The Ultra Aura readings in Alola
have been steadily dropping since yesterday.
Maybe that’s why... our motivation
has been rapidly dropping, too.
Is that what happened to
Dad and Professor Kukui, too?
For some strange reason,
it doesn’t seem to be affecting children or Pokémon.
She’s right.
After careful investigation,
we figured out that the Ultra Aura decrease...
...was caused by a tiny Ultra Hole
that opened near here.
The Ultra Aura
is getting sucked into it, you see.
Getting sucked into it?
An Ultra Beast capable of doing that
could be on the other side of the hole.
Is there any chance of
that Ultra Beast appearing here?
It’s possible,
if the Ultra Hole grows larger.
That being the case, we want to confirm
the exact location of the Ultra Hole, but...
Sauboh.
Sauboh!
Oh, yes... Um...
The clouds covering the sky
are in the way...
That’s where this Cloud Dispersing Machine
I invented comes into play.
Your mission this time is to use your Z-Moves
to activate this machine and clear away the clouds.
Z-Moves, huh... We couldn’t
pull them off properly yesterday.
We couldn’t store up
enough Z-Power.
Figures... Our latest research has shown
that Z-Power is closely linked to Ultra Aura.
I see! So it didn’t work because
the Ultra Aura had dropped!
Even if you’ve got
less Z-Power to pull from,
if your four Z-Moves work together,
the machine will activate...
I think.
Four, huh.
The ones that can use Z-Moves are
me... Kaki... Suiren...
And me.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Dynamic Full Flame!
Super Aqua Tornado!
World’s End Fall!
The plan worked!
It’s all thanks to you.
All right, time to
locate that Ultra Hole.
While she’s doing that,
there’s something I want you all to see.
Not too long ago, a new ruin was discovered
deep inside the Altar of the Sunne.
I’ll lead you there.
This is it.
The Radiant One?
It’s the symbol Bebenom
drew yesterday-roto!
It’s true.
There’s a lot of letters, too!
These are from
an ancient alphabet-roto!
Do you remember
the legend of the Radiant One?
Yeah.
Of course.
If we can decipher this text,
we might be able to solve the mystery behind the legend.
Everyone, come up!
Did something happen?!
We located the Ultra Hole, but...
The hole keeps getting bigger!
Where is it?
It’s right in this direction!
The Ultra Hole?!
Silvuddy!
It’s Lunala!
Amazing!
We got to meet
another Legendary Pokémon!
My feelings are roaring as fiercely as
a Dynamic Full Flame again!
Can you believe it? First we got to meet Solgaleo,
and now we meet Lunala, too!
Awesome!
This is the best-roto!
Calm down, Silvuddy!
Big Brother, does this mean that
Lunala was the one sucking in Ultra Aura?
No...
It’s not!
There’s another one coming!
Another one?
Lunala appeared suddenly.
And then another creature appeared
as if it was chasing it.
What could
this beast be?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting!
The Pokémon that emerged
from the Ultra Hole was Lunala!
The Moone Pokémon Lunala is
a Psychic/Ghost type.
Lunala absorbs light
and turns it into energy.
I was surprised by Lunala, too,
but I wonder what that Pokémon that came after it was?
What a pain...
Going home is such a pain...
See you later, Master...
Next episode
Matori. Sakaki says for you to
that the that.
Understood.
How can you understand it
from just “that“?
I’m his secretary.
Of course I understand.
Please tell me, what is that?
That is nothing but that.
This and it can be that,
but as long as that exists nothing but that can be that.
In the event that that is indeed that, then that must act
in a manner befitting of the that that that is.
Say that again?
That is nothing but—
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Lunala VS UB: Black! A Full Moon Battle!!
Next time
Lunala VS UB: Black!
A Full Moon Battle!!
Watch it, or you’ll suffer that!