Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Oshamari
Kapu-Tetefu
Laplace
Milokaross
Which Pokémon becomes
Ashimari’s teacher today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s morning in Alola,
and the Camome dance.
Today, Satoshi and Mao
are at Suiren’s house.
I’m glad Ashimari
seems to be doing well.
Thank you for coming.
Don’t mention it.
What happened yesterday had me worried.
But that sure was unexpected.
Go, Suiren!
You can do it!
Right...
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Super Aqua Tornado!
What? Something’s not right.
This is weird.
Ashimari!
Ashimari! Ashimari!
Ashimari was wobbly
the rest of the day.
She must have gotten sick.
You nearly had it, too...
Maybe we just can’t
picture what to do...
...since we’re not
used to battling.
Don’t worry!
You just gotta learn the trick to it!
Lugarugan managed to
pull it off, after all!
Yeah!
Let’s do our best, Ashimari!
What’s that?
There!
Ah, it’s Oshamari!
Oshamari?
Leave the explanation to me-roto!
Oshamari. Idol Pokémon.
Water type.
It can create balloons in different colors,
and it dances with its friends on moonlit nights.
It’s so cute!
There!
It’s so pretty!
Now, time for the final act.
Darlin’, are ya ready?
All okay, I'a!
That my Darlin’, Kanoa!
Now, goin borrow the power
o’ the Alolan gods...
...ta showcase our love!
What? That stance...
It’s a Z-Move!
Take the Super Aqua Tornado
o’ love and courage!
Thanks, Darlin’!
I climbin’ even higher ‘n usual!
Amazing!
Z-Moves are amazing!
I didn’t know you could
use them like that!
Thanks, y’all!
Thanks so much!
Oh!
Hey, Suiren?
Um...
Please make me
your apprentice!
What?!
Apprentice-roto?!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Ashimari, Oshamari and
the An-chor-y Dadarin!
I was so moved!
You and Oshamari
were in perfect sync!
We want to pull off
a Z-Move like that!
Well...
Go on, teach ‘er.
We be here for a while anyway.
Thank you!
We seafolk,
travellin’ all the seas of the world.
Most o’ our people
work as peddlers,
sellin’ goods wherever
people are willin’ fo buy ‘em.
But not us!
I a treasure hunter!
What do you mean?
I look for treasure!
I snatch up treasures that stay slumberin’
at the bottom of the ocean, all over the world!
Awesome!
I want to see those
treasures of the ocean!
Well, see, I never...
Kanoa still don’t got
nothin’ ta show for his dreams.
That’s why Oshamari and I workin’
ta keep food on the table.
Oh, dear...
Nah, it goin be different this time!
I got a reliable clue!
Look at these
documents I got!
Long ago, a ship wen get caught up
in a storm near Melemele Island.
The ship and its cargo
wen sink ta the bottom o’ the sea.
I wen come here ta find
the treasure on that ship!
I see...
Me and Oshamari
still gotta work...
But I guess I can help ya train
for a little bit.
All right! Training!
Just ya wait for me, I'a!
Have a safe trip!
Well, time ta get started.
Thank you very much.
Ashimari’s really hyped up!
What kind of training
will they do-roto?
From what I heard about when ya tried to use the Z-Move,
Ashimari just ain’t got enough power.
First, we gon train ta
make her moves stronger!
All right!
Oshamari, Balloon!
Try fo burst these sturdy balloons Oshamari made,
usin’ Ashimari’s balloons.
Now give the order, Suiren!
Yes, Master!
Ashimari, Balloon!
Here goes!
Needs more work...
Oshamari, again!
Ashimari, Balloon!
Stronger!
Balloon!
Again!
More!
Yes!
Stronger!
Balloon!
One more time!
All right!
They’re sure working hard...
Balloon!
Ashimari!
I think we should call it a day.
What? All right...
I’m back...
How’d it go?
Went all ‘round the Southern side,
but never find anythin’.
I see.
Ya’ll find it tomorrow, I’m sure!
Yeah!
You’re so kind.
Well, he is my Darlin’.
Me and Oshamari never could
use Z-Moves either, before.
But Kanoa wen keep
cheerin’ us on.
Really?
That Z-Move real nice.
Gentle seas, rough seas,
stormy seas...
It goin help ya cross
any ocean!
Any ocean...
I’d love to go there
with you, Ashimari.
Strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go
Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Ashimari, Balloon!
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Good!
We did it!
Ashimari, you’re awesome!
And you too, Suiren!
I'a, I got vital info!
Someone wen see a wreck like the one I lookin’ for
out in the open sea!
Amazin’! This time,
ya really might find it!
Yeah! I finally goin see that treasure
with my own eyes!
Kanoa, what is that treasure like?
If I remember right,
it supposed ta be a Mysterious Droplet.
Mysterious Droplet?
Is that a treasure-roto?
Yeah. It makes Water-type
moves stronger.
Information updated-roto!
I wanna see it!
All right! We goin
sail out tomorrow!
Let’s all go together!
Yeah!
Well then, we leavin’
early tomorrow.
Trainin’ done for today.
All right.
Did you hear that?
I heard it, meow!
Tailing that simpleton was worth it.
That treasure will be ours.
Of course, meow!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon! Here we go!
I choose you!
Name: Dadarin
Type:   Ghost/Grass
This the place.
Hey, Mr. Kanoa.
How are you gonna
search the ocean floor?
Well, these two goin fo
lend me a hand.
All right, do yer thing.
Okay. Ya up, Oshamari!
I goin find somethin’ great,
just ya wait!
Awesome!
Be careful!
That it?
Yeah, no doubt about it!
That’s...
How it wen go, Kanoa?
I wen find it.
The ship I wen lookin’ for.
What? Then why...
Place was occupied.
“Occupied”?
By a Pokémon named Dadarin.
Leave it to me-roto!
Dadarin. Sea Creeper Pokémon.
Grass/Ghost type.
Swinging its massive anchor,
it can even break solid rock.
My father told me,
“If you see one, stay away”.
Meaning it’ll be hard to
recover the treasure?
We seafolk.
We know how fo handle sea Pokémon.
Dadarin attaches
pieces of ships ta itself...
But it ain’t interested in
anythin’ it can’t integrate into itself.
So if we just approach
without rockin’ the ship itself...
How do you like
the new submarine?
Amazing! It’s so easy to pedal!
That’s an electric assist for you!
We caught up to them easily, meow!
Here we go!
Yeah!
Spotted! So that’s the ship
they’re looking for!
I can’t believe how well it’s going.
What a great feeling!
Let’s ram the thing,
full force!
Yeah, full force!
Hey, what’s the big idea?!
Chains?
Is that a Pokémon?
N-Nyarth?
It seems it’s asking “What do you want
with my ship?”, meow.
Huh? It’s this thing’s ship?
“Don’t come any closer,
or I’ll make you into sea scrap.”
Is it trying to threaten us?
What do you think you can do,
you piece of junk?
Um, apparently
it’s called Dadarin.
It says it’s really hard to deal with when it gets angry,
and that it can KO Whaloh in a single blow!
It’s already angry, isn’t it?
W-What do we do?
You have it all wrong, meow!
We’re completely
innocent here, meow!
We’re only doing this because
those guys up there asked us to, meow!
Let’s take this chance...
to get out of here!
All right, Oshamari.
One more time.
What?!
Dadarin!
It’s angry!
Why?
We gotta get away for now!
Everybody, get inside!
Of course!
It’s dragging us back?
Let’s go, Pikachu!
What a monster, meow.
Nyarth, that was well done.
Yeah! It’s nice and distracted.
Don’t tell me
you’re going back there?
Of course!
Now’s our chance!
There it is. Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
No good, huh?
Then I goin try!
Oshamari! Aqua Jet!
It workin’! Oshamari, again!
You did it!
You’re awesome, Oshamari!
Oshamari!
Hang in there!
Kanoa, get da ship movin’!
We need ta get Oshamari to a Pokémon Center!
Master!
The waves...
A whirlpool?!
Get inside, quickly!
Yes!
Hey, are we there yet?
Be patient!
This is the only equipment we have.
W-What?!
W-What’s going on, meow?!
Careful!
Are you all right?
It wants fo use that whirlpool
ta drag us under?
This ship ain’t got
enough power fo break free...
I’m not letting go!
It’s like being in
a washing machine, meow!
We gotta get outta here,
or we’re doomed!
You pedal, too!
A monster!
What even is this feeling?
This no good...
Master, maybe with the Z-Move...
Fight a whirlpool with a whirlpool.
Spin in the other direction and...
Maybe we can cancel it out!
Please let us try!
But...
Suiren...
All right.
The center stay there.
Aim carefully!
Yes!
Keep a cool head,
and ya can do it!
You trained so hard!
I know you can do it!
Believe in Ashimari!
Yeah!
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Reach... beyond the horizon!
Super Aqua Tornado!
You did it, Ashimari!
Did ya get it?
Yeah!
Awesome!
Beautiful!
This a Mysterious Droplet?
Here, I'a.
Why?
My apology for
all the trouble I’ve caused ya.
I love ya.
Oh, Kanoa!
Why?!
Suiren, congratulations on
masterin’ da Z-Move.
It’s all thanks to you.
Are you gonna continue
traveling the seas?
O’ course.
We seafolk.
All the seas in the world
stay linked together.
We goin meet again.
I look forward ta seein’
how much my apprentice’s grown.
Yes!
Through their meeting with I'a and Kanoa,
Suiren and Ashimari have mastered their Z-Move.
Their dream will continue swelling up,
like a balloon.
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting.
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Oshamari!
Oshamari was so cute!
The Idol Pokémon Oshamari is
Ashimari’s evolved form, and a Water type.
A skillful dancer, it creates
a sequence of water balloons as it dances.
I'a and Oshamari’s balloons
were really pretty, right, Ashimari?
Do you want to be
like Oshamari?
Then let’s make that happen,
right now!
Yep, it’s perfect!
Next episode
Togedemaru, you shouldn’t
force Denjimushi to play.
He’s not good at
playing tag and stuff.
Come over here.
Let’s watch some TV together!
Go!
The Type-3 Kit!
Now in stores!
It’s out! The Denjimushi Fun Kit!
Denjimushi, you’re interested
in Denjimushi Cars?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Dash! Denjimushi