Alola!
I, Joy, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem!
Blue Oceans
Red Buns
Melemele Greens
Yellow Socks
Today’s episode features
the Nagetsukesaru of Melemele Island.
What is their team name?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Kairiky?!
Why are the Red Buns
on this island?
The market is, as always,
bustling with people shopping for dinner.
It looks like Satoshi and Pikachu
also are out doing chores.
Wow, smells great!
Here!
Have one!
Thank you!
Little Nyabi, you’ve grown so big!
He’s not Nyabby anymore,
he’s Nyaheat-roto!
He evolved! Right, Nyaheat?
Oh? Good for you, Little Nyabi!
Here’s your favorite berry.
You all have some, too.
What’s up, Pikachu?
Oh, my!
Mokuroh!
Oh, those are Nagetsukesaru!
Nagetsukesaru?
They live in the woods and
play with fruits.
It’s quite unusual for them
to come all the way to the market!
Nagetsukesaru. Teamwork Pokémon.
Fighting type.
It works with its teammates and
attacks by throwing fruits.
They undergo intense training together,
and their mutual bond is remarkable.
So they just mistook
Mokuroh for their fruit?
Hey! Your fruit is over here!
That’s my Mokuroh!
Here!
Don’t lose it again!
Huh?!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Satoshi and Nagetsukesaru!
A Touchdown of Friendship!!
Are these your friends?
Ow!
What?
Hey, are you all right?!
You’re not hurt, are you?!
Ms. Junsa.
These huge Nagetsukesaru showed up,
and this one got knocked out.
Tiny!
Tiny?
It’s the Nagetsukesaru’s boss.
Satoshi, help me carry it
to the Pokémon Center.
All right.
As long as it stays still,
it should be able to move again by tomorrow.
That’s good.
These are the Melemele Greens,
who live in the forest near Lili’i Town, right?
What happened?
The Red Buns and their leader, Claw,
came here from Akala Island.
Aren’t they infamous
for their brutality?
Yes.
I’ve had to station more guards
around the forest. It’s been rough.
If anything happens, I’ll help you out.
Thank you.
I hope it gets better soon.
I was so surprised yesterday!
Some Nagetsukesaru mistook Mokuroh for a fruit
and almost took him away with them!
Nice pass, Ashimari!
So what did you do?
I showed them the fruit,
said “Yours is over here!” and they caught on.
But then these even bigger
Nagetsukesaru showed up,
knocked down the ones who were
there first with a tackle,
and took the fruit.
They were a bunch of brutes
from Akala, or something.
Akala Island? Kaki, do you know
anything about this?
It was probably Claw,
from the Red Buns.
They went on a rampage
on our farm once.
They broke all sorts of stuff.
It was awful!
But why would it come all the way
to Melemele Island just to steal a fruit?
Is the fruit that tasty?
They were probably deciding
the boss of the troop.
Alola, Professor Kukui!
Professor, what do you mean by
“deciding the boss”?
Nagetsukesaru troops all have a special fruit
that they take great care of.
Whoever owns that fruit
becomes the troop’s boss.
I see...
Then that means Tiny
isn’t the boss anymore!
Is it doing all right?
The Nagetsukesaru’s nest is past here.
You were worried about the one who got injured?
You’re so kind, Satoshi.
It just kinda bothered me.
Be quiet so as to not scare them.
Yeah, got it.
Awesome! There’re so many!
What’s that?
They’re throwing their friend!
The Nagetsukesaru are playing.
They also like to play by tossing berries around
and hitting each other with them.
Seems fun!
Where are those guys?
There!
Hey!
Feeling better?
What’s going on?!
Satoshi, look!
It’s the Red Buns!
Claw really did become the boss!
It looks pretty full of itself!
Of course it is.
It’s the boss of the troop.
But I hear that those three
have been attacking troops on other islands, too.
Hey! Are you just gonna
let those guys win?
Don’t you wanna get the fruit back?
Doesn’t this bother you?!
Isn’t there any way to fix this?
Pocket Monsters!
Sun &...
Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nagetsukesaru
Type:   Fighting
Alola!
What’s gotten into Satoshi?
W-Well, he’s been like this
all morning...
Alola, everyone!
Alola!
Oh! It’s coming along nicely.
Satoshi has been doing this
back home, too?
Yeah. Apparently he wants to
tell the Nagetsukesaru something,
so he’s practicing for that.
That side of Satoshi
really is amazing.
Yeah.
Satoshi! As long as you don’t bother anyone,
you may attend class as a Nagetsukesaru.
He’s saying “Thank you”.
You can understand him?!
Just kidding.
Lunch time!
What a bother...
Here, Mokuroh!
He’s almost starting to
look like a real Nagetsukesaru.
But there’s something missing...
I think he has the gestures
down perfectly, but...
Mao, Suiren, will you help me?
All right! How is this?
Perfect!
Yeah, I think it’s great.
Looking good, Satoshi-roto!
Awesome!
I’m a Nagetsukesaru!
Satoshi, you forgot its cry.
I hope they’ll understand you.
Will this really work?
It doesn’t seem to be working...
Look at that!
He got it back!
It’s not going to eat it?
Amazing!
Looks like they’ve accepted him!
Nagetsukesatoshi...
Oh, sorry!
Awesome!
What?
It’s the Red Buns!
They’re huge!
So intimidating!
Tiny...
Tiny!
I’ll help you, too!
Satoshi’s leaving!
Let’s follow them!
It’s begun!
So quick!
It’s like a match between
kids and grown-ups!
Satoshi, hang in there!
Hang in there!
Great going, Satoshi!
That again, huh!
How are they supposed
to grab it?
If Satoshi and the others give up on catching it,
does that mean they lose?
I have to do something!
I know!
You did it!
Here it comes!
All right!
Y-You...!
You guys...
The entire troop...
...are fighting together?
Did they win?
Yeah! The boss has changed!
I’m so happy for you guys.
Wh-What?
Satoshi is being
taken away-roto!
Why?
Satoshi: The Explosive Birth
of a New Boss.
What?!
What even is this feeling?
Satoshi has become
the Nagetsukesaru’s new boss... maybe.
Can he make it
home safely?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting.
The Melemele Island Nagetsukesaru team
was the Melemele Greens.
The Teamwork Pokémon Nagetsukesaru
is a Fighting type.
Their techniques for throwing fruits...
...are passed from the boss to the group,
generation upon generation.
It’s good that Tiny from the Melemele Greens
got to be the boss again, isn’t it?
Dinner time, everyone!
Don’t worry!
I’m sure he’ll be back soon.
Hey! Pikachu, everyone!
I’m back!
Next episode
Um... Bro, is yer Yatoumori male?
Or female?
He’s male.
What’s this all about?
I heard a rumor...
Apparently males don’t evolve.
What’re ya talkin’ about?!
My Yatoumori’s gonna evolve any day now!
Of course! I’m so relieved.
Yer Yatoumori is
the best, for reals!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Ilima and Eevee
Make Their Ilimappearance!!
Next time
Ilima and Eevee Make Their Ilimappearance!!
-roto!