Alola! Kukui here!
Today’s PokéProblem
comes to you from me!
Satoshi is going to visit a friend’s house
in today’s episode,
Suiren
Kaki
Mao
Mamane
-
but whose house?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
The sun shines again on
the Pokémon School.
Oh? It seems there’s a battle
in progress.
Here we go, Iwanko!
Use Rock Throw!
Dorobanko! Double Kick!
So close!
Iwanko’s on the defense!
Iwanko’s Rock type is a poor match-up
against Dorobanko’s Ground type.
But Satoshi doesn’t seem
to think he’s in trouble.
He seems to be
quite enjoying the battle.
Yeah, he really does!
Iwanko, can you go on?
All right, let’s go!
Time for a Z-Move!
Let’s show them our power!
That’s...
A Z-Move! Go! Go!
This is our full power!
Ultra Dash Attack!
Amazing-roto!
Dorobanko!
All right!
Dorobanko is unable to battle!
As such, the winner is Satoshi!
They did it!
Incredible!
I got every second of
Iwanko’s Z-Move on video-roto!
Thanks, Rotom.
You did great, Iwanko.
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Intense Electric Training!
A Rematch with Kapu-Kokeko!!
That was an amazing move!
I didn’t stand a chance!
Let’s battle again!
Yeah!
Satoshi!
Full power Z-Moves are amazing!
You snatched victory from the jaws of defeat!
Thanks! But I still
wanna get way stronger!
Of course you’d say that.
That’s our Satoshi.
If the trainer becomes stronger,
their Z-Moves become even stronger, too.
For real?!
Yeah! The way Z-Moves work is that the Pokémon
receives the trainer’s power to boost their own strength.
So you should
get stronger yourself.
I get it!
Okay! Let’s do it!
And then I’ll battle
Kapu-Kokeko again!
Give it your all, Satoshi!
I’m a bit envious.
No matter how strong his foes are, he faces them without hesitation.
But Kapu-Kokeko is strong!
Of course it is. It is
the island’s Guardian Deity, after all.
But Kapu-Kokeko’s the one who gave me
my Z-Ring, so I wanna show it...
...how much stronger we got!
The bigger the goal, the better!
So, how are you gonna train?
Kapu-Kokeko is
an Electric/Fairy type.
Perhaps you should
base your strategy off that?
If you need help with Electric types,
then I’m your man!
Māmane?
You should come to
my place today, Satoshi.
I’ve got plenty of data from my studies,
so you can use that to formulate a plan!
For real?
Thank you, Māmane!
This is my house.
Huh...
Didn’t know you lived so close.
I’m home!
Welcome home, Māmane.
Mom, I brought a friend!
Oh, welcome.
How are you?
My name’s Satoshi.
This is Pikachu,
and this is Rotom.
Pleasuroto to meet you!
Oh, my, how cute!
Come on in.
I’ll get you some snacks.
Something smells great!
Here you go.
They’re malasadas.
Help yourself.
Looks great! Thanks!
Hot hot hot hot!
Of course, they’re fresh out of the oven.
Take your time.
But they’re really good!
So good!
Here, Pikachu.
Internal temperature
estimated at 50 degrees-roto.
Freshly baked goods
are remarkably hot-roto!
The ones in the store are good, too,
but nothing beats
Mom’s homemade malasadas!
I’m glad to hear it! Please, eat.
I have plenty more.
Yes!
I’m completely stuffed!
I’m glad you liked it.
Satoshi! You’re forgetting your goal-roto!
I can’t eat another bite...
That’s right!
The plan to defeat Kapu-Kokeko!
Oh, right,
that’s what we were doing.
Oh, my... A plan to
defeat Kapu-Kokeko?
I’m home, Dad!
Welcome home!
You brought a guest, Māmane?
Alola!
Hope I’m not a bother.
This is Satoshi, Dad.
Alola!
I’ve heard a lot about you.
You look exactly like Māmane-roto!
I’m actually
a little bit slimmer, though.
Have you had snacks?
Yeah! They were great!
Yeah, I know, right?
Darling’s cooking is the best in the world!
I can’t help but eat too much of it.
This is Māmane Lab.
Māmane Lab?
A laboratory Dad made for me.
That’s awesome!
Come on in!
What is all this?
There’s so many
fascinating things here-roto!
Don’t touch anything
without asking first.
Some of this stuff
is pretty dangerous.
Shocking!
What are you doing-roto, Satoshi?!
Ask before you touch anything!
S-Sorry...
I noticed during your last battle...
...that Kapu-Kokeko’s Electric Field
is produced by its ability, Electro Maker.
You mean it comes out on its own?
Yup.
In Electric Field, Electric-type moves
become stronger-roto!
Which is good for
the Electric-type Pikachu,
but you’d have to come up with some strategy
for Mokuroh and Iwanko.
Here’s the estimated
conduction rate for its Electric Field...
Then I’ll calculate Iwanko’s chances of
dodging attacks given his speed...
If we then take a closer look
at his electrical resistivity...
Is this data on
the Electric type-roto?
That’s right.
I worked with Togedemaru...
...to record what kind of electricity
a Pokémon will output in different situations.
I then compared my data with that of
people researching other Electric types.
I thought it might be usable
to counter Electric Field.
Truly fascinating-roto!
And this Pokémon data can be—
It’s hopeless!
I don’t get any of what you said!
Huh? This is basic.
It’s far too complicated
for Satoshi-roto.
Looks fun!
Of course! That’s it!
Huh?
Special training
to become stronger!
It’s huge!
Now all of you can
run and train together.
All right! Come out!
We’re gonna train. Got it?
Mokuroh! You do it, too.
Good to go!
Hang on a second!
You, too.
What’s this?
Something to get data
from all of you.
This should give some
vital information-roto!
Oh, I see!
Yeah, looking good!
Show us your poweroto!
All right...
Let’s speed up!
Looking good!
The numbers keep rising-roto!
Can you still go on, Pikachu?
Huh? Are my gauges malfunctioning?
Looking good, Pikachu!
The gauges are correct!
Which means...
Full power!
You’re kidding!
Wh-What just happened?
Amazing! I’ve never seen
numbers like these before!
Satoshi, what did you do?
No idea...
But... I think I just had
some kind of breakthrough.
Let’s try again, Pikachu!
What’s going on?
Oh, you’re covered in soot!
Are you all right?
Listen to this! It’s the greatest discovery
since Māmane Lab’s founding!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Dorobanko
Type:   Ground
So, did you figure anything out
at the Māmane Lab?
Conclusion: Physical activity is
far more effective for Satoshi than theory is.
That sounds like him.
Yup.
But we’ve got a perfect plan
against Kapu-Kokeko!
Right, Pikachu?
...Not listening, huh?
That is good to hear.
I got some fascinating data
out of it, too.
I can’t wait for your battle,
Satoshi.
Same here!
Pikachu! Togedemaru!
Amamaiko,
where are you going?
Let’s follow them!
Yes.
Kapu-Kokeko!
In the flesh-roto!
Amazing!
We got to meet it again!
Kapu-Kokeko might’ve
lured Pikachu out with electricity.
Why would it do that?
Why else? To battle Satoshi!
Kapu-Kokeko!
I wanted to see you, too!
All right! Let’s battle,
Kapu-Kokeko!
So you want to battle
Pikachu, huh?
Fine by us! Right, Pikachu?
Who’s that Pokémon?!
They said Kapu-Kokeko!
For real?!
Is that...?!
Professor Kukui.
Well, things have taken
one heck of a turn!
Right?
Why does Kapu-Kokeko
keep appearing before Satoshi?
This battle might give us
the answer to that.
Now, let's get going!
Such enthusiasm.
It’s fine, Snowball.
Recording-roto!
Here it comes.
Just as I predicted!
Electric Field?
Let’s go! Pikachu,
use Lightning Speed!
So quick!
Iron Tail!
Pikachu, another Iron Tail!
Well done!
Is it just me,
or have they gotten even faster?
The results of the training
are showing!
Their speed is 12% higher
than normal-roto!
Do you think they can win?
If it continues like this,
they might, but...
Good, Pikachu!
Run around and
look for an opening!
All right! Kapu-Kokeko is perplexed
by Pikachu’s speed!
They can win!
No, it can’t be that easy.
Dodge it, Pikachu!
Pikachu!
That was Nature's Wrath.
The damage is severe.
Are you okay, Pikachu?
Thanks, Togedemaru.
Good job!
We were just about
to get zapped.
A Discharge boosted by
Electric Field, huh...?
Even though Pikachu
resists electricity...
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Kapu-Kokeko really is too...
Stand up, Pikachu! Get up!
What could be wrong?
Don’t tell me Kapu-Kokeko...
Yeah. It’s waiting for
Satoshi and Pikachu’s full power.
Their full power...
Good, Pikachu!
My Z-Ring is...
Sorry to keep you waiting,
Kapu-Kokeko!
Pikachu, let’s show
the results of our training!
That’s...
Satoshi and Pikachu
are ready to go.
All right!
Go, Pikachu!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Now! Iron Tail!
Pikachu!
Satoshi!
We’re flying!
Kapu-Kokeko!
Satoshi!
I got an amazing picture-roto!
Kapu-Kokeko,
thanks for saving us.
Are you hurt, Satoshi?
No, I’m fine!
What a relief.
Kapu-Kokeko!
We lost again...
But we’ll keep getting stronger
and challenge you again!
We’ll power up our Z-Moves, too!
Satoshi and the others felt
Kapu-Kokeko’s power once again.
More training will be required
before they can get their revenge!
Hang in there, Satoshi! Pikachu!
To be continued!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Māmane!
Satoshi was supposed to be studying the Electric type
to work out a plan for fighting Kapu-Kokeko...
But it seems it turned into
physical exercise instead.
The battle with Kapu-Kokeko was intense! Even Satoshi’s Last Resort wasn’t enough!
Next episode
Pikachu! Mokuroh! Iwanko!
Didn’t I tell you to wash your feet before going inside
after coming back from the beach?!
Hey! Hold it! Don’t run!
There’s footprints
everywhere-roto...
It was just the two of them
when Satoshi and Pikachu came here...
But now look at
how lively it’s gotten!
Satoshi left footprints too-roto.
What?!
Satoshi!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
The Promise Between Satoshi and Pikachu
Next time