Battling’s intense!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Lucario
Gaogaen
Ohrot
Warrgle
Which is the first Pokémon
Professor Kukui sends out today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Satoshi has become the first-ever Champion
of the Alola Pokémon League.
Now, Pikachu! Electroweb!
Lucario! Use Dragon Pulse!
Together with Royal Mask
and his other friends,
as well as Bebenom’s evolved form, Agoyon,
Satoshi fought a full power battle.
All right!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Here we go, Agoyon!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
Combining their strength,
they finally managed to drive Akujiking away.
All right!
You did it-roto!
Royal Mask!
I should be the one
thanking you, Satoshi!
Kukui’s in quite the bind!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Final Battle!
Satoshi VS Kukui!!
Oh, um, you see...
I’m sorry to have
kept this from you for so long.
Wait, wait!
No way, no way, no way, no way!
He’s Royal... Royal is him...
Professor Kukui is Royal Mask...
Satoshi...
I can’t wait for the
exhibition match!
I mean, this is so cool!
It means I get to battle Royal Mask
and the Professor, right?!
Don’t you think so?
You have a point!
All right!
Let’s do this, Satoshi!
I’ll have the battlefield
usable by tomorrow.
All right!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Satoshi VS Professor Kukui...
This’ll be the hottest battle
in all of Alola!
Alolan Father and Son
Showdown!
We’ll all cheer you on!
We couldn’t possibly not be
excited about this!
Satoshi, let’s make tomorrow’s match
a 6v6 full battle.
That means I can bring
Agoyon too, right, Professor?
Of course! It’s part of our family,
too, after all!
Thank you!
Hey, Agoyon!
Let’s do our best, together!
Let’s give it our full power
tomorrow!
Enjoy!
Yesterday’s award ceremony
was full of surprises!
I am safe! This is Jeekyo.
I will be commenting on
today’s event until the end!
The Alola Pokémon League
has been full of excitement.
Competitor Satoshi has been crowned
its first-ever Champion!
And the one waiting for
this first-ever Champion is...
...the ruler of the Royal Dome,
Royal Mask!
But, shockingly, it turns out
his true identity was Professor Kukui!
This shocking revelation was
the hottest topic yesterday!
Melmetal, let’s keep twirling!
There’s immense centrifugal force
behind Melmetal’s fists-roto!
Fire! Double Panzer!
Both its speed and its force
have never been greater-roto!
I know, right?
That’s the spirit, Melmetal!
Did you all see that?
Wasn’t that an awesome punch?!
What a shocker!
I could feel its immense power!
You’ve got this, Melmetal!
So strong! You can win!
It shook me, too!
Man, I can’t wait to battle!
Nyaheat.
You get to battle Gaogaen again.
Let’s show the Professor and Gaogaen
how much stronger you’ve gotten!
All right! Now it’s Nyaheat’s turn!
I’m a failure as a fan, aren’t I?
I was so close to you,
and yet I never noticed!
Royal Mask...
No, Professor Kukui!
Give us a great battle!
Our apologies for the wait.
It’s time for the exhibition match!
Royal Mask, a.k.a. Competitor Kukui,
and Competitor Satoshi are entering the arena!
I’m super nervous for some reason!
Satoshi! You got this!
Competitor Kukui and
Competitor Satoshi...
...are slowly walking towards the middle,
where Chief Referee Hala is waiting!
Now allow me to
go over the rules.
This will be a full battle.
You may use six Pokémon each.
You are free to switch out
Pokémon mid-battle.
The battle ends as soon as
all Pokémon on one side are unable to battle.
He who still has Pokémon left, wins.
I expect a great battle from you two!
Both fighters, assume positions!
Yes!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
It’s time!
Give it all you have!
Satoshi and Pikachu can win,
for sure!
He’s got a great look on his face.
Satoshi now sends
A heated wind that races
Throughout Alola
There’s the Pokémon haiku!
Everyone, turn your attention
to the screen.
It will display the status of each fighter’s
six Pokémon for this full battle.
It’ll help us keep track
of the battle’s progress.
I already know who I’ll use first!
Oh, sorry, Pikachu. Not you.
You come in later.
Nyaheat! I choose you!
Nyabi-chan!
I knew you’d use Nyaheat.
Then I’ll use...
Gaogaen!
There it is! Royal Mask’s
strongest partner...
His ace hits the scene!
When he says Royal Mask,
that’s Kukui, yeah?
Oh, I’m so glad I married him!
Gaogaen is Nyaheat’s
evolved form.
So that’s Nyabi-chan VS Gao-chan!
It’s time for a showdown
between Fire Pokémon!
What kind of battle will this be?!
Nyaheat’s all fired up!
Yeah! Nyaheat’s emotions
are swelling!
Fire power rising! Rising!
Let the match begin!
Bring it, Satoshi!
Let’s go at full power, Nyaheat!
Nitro Charge!
Gaogaen, take them on!
Build Up!
Go, Nyaheat!
W-Wow! Build Up is a move that
raises the user’s attack and defense!
It used its bulging muscles
to repel Nyaheat!
Gaogaen did not move an inch!
I see... It is well trained!
Keep it up!
It’s like a wall.
Nyaheat, use another Nitro Charge!
Another Nitro Charge!
All right! Faster!
So quick!
Amazing!
Nitro Charge raises the user’s speed
every time it’s used-roto!
DD Lariat!
They dodged it!
All right!
Raising his speed paid off!
Fire Fang!
Too soft!
We’re not done yet!
Another Nitro Charge!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Agoyon
Type:   Poison/Dragon
We’re not done yet!
Another Nitro Charge!
Could Satoshi be...
Yeah. He’s planning to
raise Nyaheat’s speed to the limit.
Nyaheat’s speed
continues to rise-roto!
Round and round!
Run circles around Gaogaen!
Nyaheat is quick!
Gaogaen is stuck in place!
You’ve raised him well, Satoshi.
Throat Chop!
Charge in, Gaogaen!
Great Blaze!
So strong!
You wanted to disorient Gaogaen
by raising your speed with Nitro Charge, yeah?
However...
It regularly battles
multiple opponents at once,
so it can discern a Pokémon’s
movements from any direction!
Gaogaen has no blind spots!
I’ll show you the heat of true fire!
Blast Burn!
So hot!
It’s like being in the kitchen!
Nyaheat!
What?!
I got it, Nyaheat!
You’re taking in
the Blast Burn fires, right?
Let’s try that plan!
Hang in there!
Is this even possible?!
What could have happened?!
Gaogaen’s Blast Burn
vanished without a trace!
What could have happened
to Nyabi-chan?
He most likely absorbed
all the flames from the Blast Burn.
So that he could convert them
into his own power.
He can do that?!
Nyaheat’s body...
...is on the brink of overflowing
with fire energy.
I’m certain it’s burning hotter
by the second.
Hang in there, Nyabi-chan!
The power-up was a success,
huh, Nyaheat?
How’s that, Professor?!
I call it Blast Nyaheat!
Now we can beat Gaogaen!
Blast Nyaheat, huh?
That’s an interesting idea!
I accept your challenge!
The flames haven’t vanished.
They only continue to blaze up!
Blast Nyaheat! So cool!
There’s no Pokémon
with that name-roto!
Just go with it!
I like it!
I’d prefer “Nyaburn.”
I’m not so sure about that...
What is happening?!
Smoke is rising from Nyaheat!
He got burned!
His bell got too hot.
He couldn’t endure it, I see...
Too bad, Satoshi, Nyaheat!
That means you’re not ready
to take in our Blast Burn just yet!
Nyaheat.
Return for now.
Your plan will work, no doubt!
I promise to give you a chance later!
Guess we’ll have to Quash
settling the score with Nyaheat.
But Gaogaen will stay in the fight!
In that case,
I’ll go with this guy next!
Competitor Satoshi’s second Pokémon
is Lugarugan!
After you use Blast Burn,
you can’t move for a bit-roto!
Do your best, Lugarugan!
He’s got an advantage
against Fire types!
But his opponent is
Royal Mask’s Gaogaen.
It won’t be easy.
Let’s do this! Accelerock!
Lugarugan goes in!
Gaogaen still can’t move!
Stone Edge!
They’re keeping up the pressure!
Oh! Gaogaen is back in action!
DD Lariat!
This is it!
Lugarugan! Use the shards!
Throat Chop!
Go!
Good! You got them!
Amazing!
Even though his Stone Edge
was shattered,
Competitor Satoshi used its shards!
An inspired idea!
And Lugarugan pulled through!
Their superb combination
managed to damage Gaogaen!
Impressive, Lugarugan.
All right, Gaogaen.
Return for now.
You did it, Lugarugan!
Satoshi, let’s keep up
the full power!
It’s like you’ve gone back
to your childhood self.
Go, Warrgle!
It’s all on you, Warrgle!
Kukui, show them
how cool you are!
Warrgle, huh?
Competitor Satoshi,
will you switch your Pokémon?
I’ll stick with Lugarugan!
Very well.
Then, let the battle begin!
Competitor Kukui uses Warrgle!
Competitor Satoshi, meanwhile,
is leaving Lugarugan in!
Warrgle, use Rock Slide!
Here it comes, Lugarugan!
The Alola Pokémon League exhibition match:
Satoshi VS Kukui!
The battle has only begun.
It’ll only heat up from here!
How long has it been
since I bid Masara Town farewell?
Got so many cuts, scratches and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Back then, I rushed out to buy these sneakers
because everyone was wearing them
But now you can’t find them anywhere...
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”
Battling’s intense!
The first Pokémon Professor Kukui
sent out was Gaogaen!
Warrgle VS Lugarugan...
I wonder what kind of battle this’ll be!
The Valiant Pokémon Warrgle
is a Normal/Flying type!
Ancient Alolan people respected it,
referring to it as “the hero of the sky.”
Oh, my! That Warr-chan
sure looks strong!
Warrgle spins around
Dancing in the sky above
A proud warrior
Whoa!
Luga-chan! Hang in there!
Next episode
Kukui is Royal Mask...
I didn’t have two princes after all; only one!
I’m a bit conflicted.
There’s no time for that,
Professor Burnet!
Sauboh?
I have started a petition
to ensure that Royal Mask...
...will continue to operate despite
his identity being exposed! Sign, please.
Oh, of course!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Flaming, Seething Full Battle!!!
Royal Mask will never die!
Next time
A Flaming, Seething
Full Battle!!!