You’ll be assisting Ms. Lychee?!
Yeah. Though it’ll just be over the break,
at least for the time being.
Training with your master
is important!
Speaking from experience,
huh, Suiren?
Have you decided what you’re doing
during the vacation, Satoshi?
Yeah.
I’m—
Alola!
Alola, Lil—
Magearna?!
So cute!
Magearna in motion...
Data updated-roto!
You finally did it!
I knew you could!
You gave it your all!
I did nothing.
It was all thanks to Zoroark.
And, thanks to Magearna herself.
Um...
I...
...have decided to go on a journey
with my mother and brother.
What?!
A journey to find Father.
A journey... to where?
To wherever Magearna points us.
When Magearna awoke...
I’m so happy, Magearna!
Lilie!
Magearna?
What is it?
Father?
You mean that light
points to where Dad is?
I’ll call Mother!
Magearna has the power
to sense where Professor Mohn is-roto?!
That’s awesome, Magearna!
Mother decided to
embark on a journey immediately.
And she’s set on not returning
until she finds Father.
Naturally, my brother and I
feel the same.
You will come back when
you find your father, right?
Naturally.
What a relief!
Yeah...
It’ll be lonely here without you,
but if you’re coming back...
We’ll be fine!
Thank You, Alola!
The Start of New Journeys!!
Delicious!
It’s from HQ!
That can wait.
I mean, who wants to look at
that bowl-headed four-eyes’s face while eating?
Or that arrogant
Alolan Nyarth, meow?
Yeah, but...
Hang on, Mimikkyu!
Good morning,
my trusted underlings.
Sakaki, sir?!
Good morning, meow!
I’ll get right to the point.
I order you to return to HQ.
Oh, of course!
Return to HQ, is it?
HQ?!
Return?!
What?!
You have kept Sakaki waiting
for your results from Alola for far too long.
What’s that?! You don’t think
we’ve produced any results?!
Stop that. How unsightly.
Calm down, Nyarth!
I expect great things from you.
R-Roger!
What do we do? About our...
...results...
You’ll be starting
a long vacation tomorrow.
I hope you’ll all
chase your own Rainbow Feathers...
...and Stockpile your own Secret Power!
Of course!
I promised to go shopping
with Mother today...
...so that we could gather
everything we need for our journey.
Lilie!
I’ve been working on
a lot of Pokémon dishes.
I’ve got a special one
just for Snowball, too.
Will you take the recipe?
I’d love to!
All right, stop by my place
tomorrow for it!
Certainly.
The plan worked.
Anyway, have you told Hidoide?
Not yet...
You gotta tell her, y’know.
Don’t put it off
‘til the last second, okay?
What about you?
Have you told Mimikkyu?
Mimikkyu’ll be fine.
It can adapt, just like me.
Look, now’s your chance. Do it.
Tell her, meow, Kojirou.
Actually, Hidoide, we...
...have to go back to HQ.
We’ll be zooming back...
t-to HQ.
Hidoide... You and Mimikkyu
are staying here...
You’ll be living with Kiteruguma and Nuikoguma,
just like before...
Hey, do you understand?
I have a bad feeling about this...
I don’t think I got through at all.
She seems to have
totally misunderstood.
Nyarth, do something.
She won’t listen to a word I say
when she gets like that, meow.
The Alolan sunset...
...really is beautiful, huh?
Satoshi.
When will you tell the others-roto?
Tell them?
That you’re leaving Alola-roto.
I’ll tell them tomorrow.
I promise.
Pikachu!
It’s Team Rocket’s
Mimikkyu-roto!
Pikachu! Use 100,000 Volts!
Iron Tail!
Mimikkyu!
What’s wrong-roto?
Mimikkyu.
Are you okay, Mimikkyu?
It’s acting different-roto.
Can you get home on your own?
We should go home, too.
Solgaleo!
It’s been a while-roto!
Mimikkyu!
Where were you, meow?
Musashi was worried about you, meow.
The brat boy and Pikachu, meow?
Well, life isn’t always easy
for Pokémon, meow.
I see... You saw your own face
in the water, huh, meow?
Nothing comes from hatred, meow.
It might be time for you
to move on, too, meow.
Hidoide.
This is like a second homeland to us.
We’ll be back, I promise.
So...
Look after Team Rocket Alola Branch
while we’re away.
Well, you know...
I guess you’ve taken
pretty good care of us.
This was a good home.
It couldn’t have been
more comfortable, meow!
Thank you!
H-H-Hey, wait...
What a great feeling...
Well, it’s a shame, but...
We’re leaving!
What?
“Are you going to Kanto?”
Why would you ask that...?
What even is this feeling?
Be careful with the stairs,
Magearna.
Alola Surprise!
Ta-dough!
Welcome!
To the You Can RealLilie Do it...
...Party!
Everyone...
Mao!
Yes!
Satoshi still isn’t here?
No... I wonder what’s wrong.
Could he have gotten
sidetracked again?
Look!
Solgaleo!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Everyone!
Sorry we kept you waiting-roto!
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Satoshi!
Sorry I’m late.
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
Please, tell us why you were just
flying on Solgaleo!
Well, Solgaleo came to
get me last night,
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
and we went on a big adventure!
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
We went through the Ultra Hole
with Pikachu and Rotom!
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Through the Ultra Hole?!
Tell us more!
Learning until you’re all worn out,
It was neither Utsuroid’s world
nor Bebenom’s world.
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
And then we helped...
You were the one who taught us
...an Ultra Beast that was in trouble
in that world!
Helped?
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
It was like... Whoa! Whoosh!
Crash! Zap!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
I can tell that it was amazing, but...
Your explanation kinda sucks.
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
I’ll show you all the footage
I recorded later-roto.
Step forward!
Then you’ll understand-roto.
You will? Thank you, Rotom!
That’s wonderful!
President Lusamine
said the same thing-roto!
Mother?
The truth is, I’m going to be working
at Aether Paradise-roto!
They evaluated my analytical
and Index recording capabilities,
and headhunted me-roto!
Right after coming back here,
we went to Aether Paradise
with Professor Kukui.
And this is the Index data on
the Ultra Beast we met this time-roto.
Let’s see...
Rotom, this is wonderful!
You’ve already done
a detailed analysis on it!
This is just great!
Say, Rotom...
What-roto?
Would you like to work here?
You mean work at Aether Paradise-roto?!
That’s a fantastic idea!
Let’s make the most of your invaluable skills,
and complete the greatest
Pokémon Index in the universe, together!
The greatest Pokémon Index
in the universe-roto?!
That’s great!
Your dream’s coming true, Rotom!
And there you have it.
The greatest Pokémon Index
in the universe, huh?
I wish I could have gone
on a great adventure...
I’m sorry, Suiren.
Solgaleo was in a hurry, too.
Sheesh...
I guess this is just how you roll...
Oh, and...
There’s something
I have to tell you all.
I’ve decided to go home
to Masara Town.
Coming to Alola with Pikachu...
Meeting you guys
and the Pokémon here...
Learning all kinds of stuff
at the Pokémon School...
It’s been incredible.
So I’ve decided...
...to go back to Masara Town,
and then head on to someplace new.
Meet more new people
and Pokémon...
Become even better
at Pokémon Battling...
And then someday...
I will become a Pokémon Master!
That isn’t...
just a plan for the vacation, is it?
No.
Sheesh...
You should’ve told us sooner!
Yeah... What a surprise.
We were supposed to
surprise Lilie today, but...
This day has been
nothing but surprises.
If anyone can become
a Pokémon Master, it’s you!
We’ll all be rooting for you!
Thank you!
Take care of yourself, Lusamine.
I will.
Well, then... This is it.
I’ll have a souvenir from Tokusane City
waiting for you when you come back.
I look forward to it!
I hope you find your father soon.
Thank you, Mao.
Remember to let us know
if you run into any trouble.
I will!
Promise you’ll write us!
I promise!
See you, Lilie.
Yes, see you...
Satoshi.
The world seems vast,
but it’s really quite small.
If we meet again out there...
Of course, we’ll have a battle!
I’ll immortalize this moment in a photo-roto!
Hurry, everyone-roto!
Say “Namakobushi”!
Satoshi!
I’m glad to have met you!
Because I met you,
I got to befriend the Pokémon!
Thank you!
Lilie...
Me, too!
Thank you!
Remember, you want to get on
the plane heading for Kanto.
I know that!
Professor.
What?
Please... take good care of
Mokuroh and the others.
Don’t worry. They’re our family.
Kukui’s gonna bring them
to the Pokémon School, too.
Then they’ll be ready for
Ultra Guardian missions any time, right?
Yeah.
Professor Kukui.
Professor Burnet.
I’m off.
T-Take care.
Give it your all.
Yeah!
Don’t forget...
Burnet and I will always be there
to give you a Helping Hand.
Wherever you go,
and whatever you’re doing.
Kukui is right.
Thank you.
All right...
Off you go!
Yeah!
Thank you, Alola.
Alola Surprise!
Hey!
Good luck!
So long!
Seeking a new world,
the adventure now begins anew!
How long has it been since I bid Masara Town farewell?
See you!
Have a nice trip!
Your training with Ms. Lychee
is finally starting!
Got so many cuts, scratches, and friends
I’m kinda proud of that
Hang in there!
Yeah!
The sneakers I rushed out to buy
back when they were the latest trend...
I’ll bring back a fish print
of Manaphy for you.
...are now one of a kind, no others like them in the world
A fish print of Manaphy?
Later.
They’re the best worn-out shoes around!
Welco—
Big Brother!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
I’m home, Mao.
Little by little... Type: Wild!
Those flowers!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
I found a bunch of them blossoming
on the way here.
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
Figured I’d pick some for you.
Thank you.
'Ulu.
Hi, Dad.
You’ve come home...?
Yeah.
I see.
What’s wrong?
I don’t need a suitcase, photos or a guide on this journey
but I’ll keep the warmth of everyone I’ve met as a souvenir!
I had some really harsh memories along the way, too
Xiemi?
but they must’ve fallen out of a tear in my backpack!
I see... You’re going with your friends...
Thank you, Xiemi...
...for being with me all this time.
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
Before I know it... Type: Wild!
Little by little... Type: Wild!
I’m gonna become... Type: Wild!
...way stronger than I am! Type: Wild!
And someday I’ll have the chance to say...
“Hello, my dream”