Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Swimming contest
Flea market
Haunted house
Movie screening
What do we host
at the Pokémon School today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Right...
Let’s go home, Pikachu!
Us too, Suiren!
Suiren?
Hey? Is something wrong?
Sorry!
You see, yesterday...
I’m home!
Welcome home, Big Sis!
Welcome home!
I’m home...
You know what?
Um... Did something happen?
Yeah, it did!
It was kinda scary...
But really fun!
We wanna go to
a haunted house!
They’ve been talking about
a haunted house non-stop ever since.
A haunted house, huh.
Seems they saw one on TV
and got interested.
Then let’s all go to one
someday soon!
It would be nice
if we could, but...
I haven’t heard of any in Alola.
Where are you going, Mimikins?
Acerola! Alola!
Alola, Satoshi!
Let me introduce you to
my friend from Ula'ula Island...
My name is Acerola.
It’s a pleasure to meet you!
Alola! I’m Mao!
I’m Suiren.
I’m Māmane.
Kaki.
My name is Lilie.
I’m here today because
I was asked to deliver a book.
The library I work at has
some pretty rare stuff.
I see.
Wait, what’s up, guys?
I’ve never seen
a flying Mimikkyu before!
It’s a different color than
Team Rocket’s.
Oh, that... Well you see...
My Mimikins is a real ghost.
A ghost?!
What was that?!
Dunno...
Oh, right! You got any
haunted houses near where you live?
Suiren’s sisters
want to go to one.
Nope.
Thought so.
But if you don’t have one,
you should just make one!
I didn’t think about that!
If so...
If you want to use the School,
then feel frEevee!
Principal Okido!
I will accompany you today.
The Pokémon School is
positively dripping with atmosphere at night.
Use it however you pleasEmperte!
All right!
Then let’s start preparing!
Isn’t this great, Suiren?
Yeah!
And so, Satoshi and the others
ended up making a haunted house.
What will happen next?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A Ghost Pokémon Outbreak!
A Haunted House for Everyone!!
Remember what I told you,
and have a great time.
Yes!
Well then,
I’ll be in the Principal’s office.
Call me if something goes wrong,
and I’ll do my best to assisTamanta!
Tamatama!
Tamazarashi!
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Hey!
Follow Rotom
once you’re inside, okay?
No wandering off on your own!
You can leave them to me-roto!
Ghosts! Ghosts!
Ho! Sui!
Sheesh...
Listen to what Rotom tells you, okay?
Sure!
Well, shall we go?
Yeah.
Take care!
So exciting!
So thrilling!
Well then,
let the haunted house tour begin-roto!
Roto!
Begin by heading
straight down the hall-roto.
Roto!
Okay, I’ve got them on camera.
Lilie, they’re headed your way!
Understood.
They’re here!
All right...
Oooh, what a creepy mood-roto!
Ghosts! Ghosts!
Here I go...
What’s this?
It’s cold!
Oh, no-roto!
This could be a ghost-roto!
Huh? A ghost?!
Ghost! Ghost!
You mustn’t touch it!
Found the ghost!
Got it!
Ghost! Ghost!
This is bad-roto!
Moving on-roto...
Starting to get scared-roto?
This is super fun!
Fun!
But if you get too careless...
I’m a ghost!
Are there any
naughty children around?!
Ghosts are here!
Ghosts!
Did they get shocked?
Satoshi! Kaki!
Hang in there-roto!
Don’t say their names...
You’ll ruin the illusion...
Next ghost! Next ghost!
Huh?
What’s this?!
Okay, now Kagebouzu
will use Will-O-Wisp.
Right. And then I’ll...
Huh?
Geez!
What’s going on?!
I don’t understand!
Does not compute...
Are these ghosts?
Amazing! Amazing!
Satoshi!
Hey, what is this?
I dunno.
What happened?!
Ghosts! Ghosts!
Perhaps...
Kagebouzu! True Sight!
I knew it...
There are so many
Ghost Pokémon!
This was their doing?
I can’t believe
you figured it out, Acerola!
Actually,
this has happened before.
Ghost-type Pokémon tend to
gather around Mimikins sometimes...
Maybe because it’s
a real ghost itself...
Ghosts! Ghosts!
Wait!
Play with us, ghosts!
That tickles!
Play with us!
It vanished!
Where’d it go?
Lucky them... Looks like
they’re having a ton of fun!
Indeed.
But they should probably
be careful.
What do you mean?
When Ghost Pokémon
like a person too much,
they’ll sometimes whisk them away,
never to be seen again.
Never to be seen again?!
That’s really bad...
Guess we should
call it quits for today...
I agree...
Come here!
We’re going home, Ho, Sui!
They aren’t listening...
Hey, you two!
What is this?!
So cool!
Where are we?
We were at the Pokémon School, right?
This has never happened before...
The wind’s awesome!
Awesome wind!
Hey, look!
Could they be trying to
whisk them away?!
Wait!
What are these?!
Pumpjin! But they’re not
native to Alola!
Ho! Sui!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pumpjin
Type:   Ghost/Grass
That’s all of them...
The pumpkins turned into Pokémon?
Such a strange phenomenon...
I have no data on this-roto!
I don’t get this... It’s not like we’ve
passed through an Ultra Hole, either.
This must be Mumagi’s doing.
Suiren?
I’m worried about
Ho and Sui.
Yeah. Let’s move!
You can leave the pursuit
to Mimikins.
To Mimikins?
It’s good at detecting
the presence of others.
Mimikins, if you would.
Looks like it found them!
Let’s go!
Yeah!
In here?
What’s going on?!
Ow...
Where are we?
There’s ground in the sky, too?
This makes no sense.
Mimikins! That way?
Ho... Sui...
Amazing! Amazing!
You’re so fast!
So are you!
Ho! Sui!
Ah! Big Sis!
We finally found you!
Unbelievable!
Ho and Sui were really
fairies all along-roto?!
Of course not.
Look at this, it’s amazing!
The ghosts gave us wings!
Come play with us, Big Sis!
Come down, both of you!
The haunted house tour is over!
Again?!
Huh?
Why was I sleeping out here?
Where are the others?
We have to find them.
Look, Mao!
This house is made of candy!
Huh?!
The walls are cookies and
the door is chocolate!
Pardon me...
It’s delicious!
You try some, too!
It’s super delicious!
You’re right!
Here, Amajo, you try, too!
Right?
This is just...
Me, too!
Where is everyone?
Is that a puppet show?
My, how cute!
Just for a bit, okay?
Is this a...
Tea party?
We don’t have time for...
Big Sis and the others
disappeared...
They disappeared...
Oh! Wait!
Hey... Isn’t there
something wrong with us?
You think so, too?
This is so fluffy and
smells so sweet...
I just feel my strength
fading away...
Maybe we’ll just
turn into marshmallows...
Well... Whatever.
That was so cute,
wasn’t it?
All right, let’s go.
Huh?
Sorry, just wait a second.
There’s something...
That’s weird...
I can’t move!
Me neither!
Oh, no!
We have become dolls!
Dolls?!
What’s this?!
What’s happening?!
Hold on tight!
Amazing!
We might not be
out of danger just yet.
What do we do?!
Ashimari!
Put a balloon around us all!
Huh?
We’re flying!
We’re actually flying!
Ho, Sui, where are you?
Say... Is this real?
I was just thinking,
what if this is just a dream that Mumagi created?
A dream?
If that’s true,
we just have to wake up!
I’m not waking up...
We can’t get out on our own.
Fuwante! Fuwaride!
This could be bad...
Nekkoala!
Is this also part of
Mumagi’s dream?
But it drove the Fuwante away...
What if we’ve exited Mumagi’s dream
and crashed into Nekkoala’s?
I don’t know...
But Nekkoala
might be able to do it!
Wake us up! Please!
If this goes on, we won’t be able to
get out of this dream!
We want to go back
to our own world!
Did it understand?
That’s...
The Pokémon School’s bell!
Go, Nekkoala!
The Pokémon School...
We made it out?!
It really was just a dream!
Please turn us back...
Stop it!
Huh?
Thank goodness...
Looks like Mumagi and
the others have left.
Where are Ho and Sui?!
Huh? Our wings!
They’re gone!
There you are, Nekkoala!
Ringing the bell at this hour...
Did you react to something in your dreaMinun?
A dream that Mumagi created?!
That explains why it was so crazy.
We need to thank Nekkoala!
Thanks to you two, too,
for fighting ‘til the end!
But it was our fault
in the first place...
Sorry for getting you all
mixed up in it.
It’s not your fault!
My sisters were
the ones acting unreasonable...
The ghosts are gone...
Gone...
And we were having
so much fun, too...
Yeah...
Now, now!
We were all worried about you!
What? No way!
We’re fine, we’re fine!
Yay!
You sure are carefree...
Ho. Sui.
I’m starting to get
really angry!
But it was kinda fun,
wasn’t it?
I guess it became
a haunted house tour for all of us.
Right, Suiren?
Yeah!
Thanks for today, everyone!
Well then,
shall we clean up and go home?
Yeah!
There was plenty of trouble...
But thankfully,
everyone made it back safe!
So, what did the two of them
think of the haunted house?
Big Sis is way scarier...
...than the haunted house...
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Eevee, Where Are You Going?
Thank you for waiting!
We hosted a haunted house
at the Pokémon School!
The Magical Pokémon Mumagi
is a Ghost type.
It appears as if from nowhere—
placing curses, and giving people terrifying visions.
If Nekkoala hadn’t been there,
we might not have made it back...
This is mine!
No, mine!
Ho! Sui! Go to sleep!
No way, no way!
I wanna be up a little longer!
I’m starting to get
really angry!
Good night...
Good night.
Next episode
Ultra Guardians, assemble!
What’s happened?!
Three mysterious reactions
have been confirmed on Wela Volcano!
What?! On Wela Volcano?!
Three of them, too?!
Could they be Ultra Beasts?
We’ll have to get ready!
We’ll do it!
We’ll Ultra-get them!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Wela Volcano, the Gorone,
the Gorogna and the Hikers!
Oh, hi there!
If you want to know
about Wela Volcano...
Then leave it to us!
Next time
Wela Volcano, the Gorone,
the Gorogna and the Hikers!