Alola!
The PokéProblem segment starts today!
Our first question is as suChillarmy!
Washing
machine
Pokémon Index
Electric fan
Refrigerator
Into which of these electronic appliances
does Rotom nest itself today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
At last, we’ve reached the Alola Region.
It’s time to start a new life in this distant land,
with both our bodies and spirits cleansed!
And it’s all for our great boss Sakaki,
leader of Team Rocket, meow!
That’s right!
Sonansu!
Many kinds of rare Pokémon
reside in the Alola Region.
Wretched Persian...
You should enjoy lazing about on
Sakaki’s lap while you still can, meow!
In the near future,
I will become Sakaki’s favorite...
...and drag you off your throne!
You are to fly to the Alola Region immediately,
and get me Pokémon we have never before seen.
For the sake of
my Team Rocket’s ambitions!
Roger!
Our Pokémon-catching...
...and our conquest of Alola...
...start now!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
It’s a Pleasuroto to Meet You,
I’m the Index Rotom-roto!
Satoshi and Pikachu have started
their new life in the Alola Region,
and the Pokémon School’s
Professor Kukui...
...just gifted them a rather
strangely-shaped Pokémon Index.
Now then, in order to
activate this Index...
All right, we’re connected!
Here it comes...
What?
What’s coming?
You’ll see...
It’s a Rotom!
Now we just have to wait
for Rotom to go in.
Rotom’s going...
...into the Pokémon Index?
Did it go in?
Rotom?
T-This is...
The Index is a Rotom,
and Rotom is the Index!
Alola, Rotom!
Language selection complete.
It spoke!
Rotom, please give Satoshi
a Helping Hand from now on!
Understood.
“Satoshi” has been registered
as this unit’s user.
Rotom Index
running startup program...
100% complete.
Alola, User Satoshi!
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
You can even greet people?
Naturally-roto!
The Index Rotom is equipped with
a wide assortment of languages,
and has been programmed to
be able to communicate with humans-roto!
Awesome!
“Awesome!”
Does not compute... Does not compute...
Does not compute...
Satoshi was admiring your functions,
saying that they were incredible.
Understood-roto!
“Awesome” means “Incredible”.
Which means I, the Index Rotom
am incredible!
You seem quite dependable!
I’m Kukui! I might not look it,
but I’m a professor!
Greetings, Professor Kukui.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
Rotom, this is my partner, Pikachu.
They live here with
me and Iwanko.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you,
Pikachu and Iwanko.
Photos taken.
Pikachu.
Iwanko.
Why did you take pictures of them?
To store data on the Pokémon I have met
in the Index-roto!
The Index Rotom is a self-updating
Pokémon Index...
...whose data updates whenever
it meets a new Pokémon-roto!
I’m not sure I get it...
But you really are
awesome, Rotom!
User Satoshi, I am no longer a mere Rotom.
I am a Rotom Index.
To be specific,
I am Rotom, Pokédex Forme!
Rotom. Poké... Pokéd...
I have no choice...
I will permit you to just
call me Rotom-roto, User Satoshi.
You can just call me Satoshi, too.
A shorter name is
easier to use, right?
“Satoshi”. Understood-roto!
Say, Rotom...
Can you tell me how Pikachu is
described in your Index?
By all means-roto!
Pikachu. Mouse Pokémon.
Electric type.
It keeps its tail raised to monitor its surroundings.
If you yank its tail, it will try to bite you.
I was wrong!
It doesn’t bite, it zaps-roto!
I’m Mao! It’s a pleasure
to meet you, Rotom!
It’s a pleasure!
The pleasuroto’s all mine!
An Index that activates
by having Rotom enter it...
It’s incredible!
Incredible...
“Incredible” means “Awesome!”
Which means I, the Index Rotom,
am awesome!
Indeed!
Most awesome!
Huh... It’s learned
Satoshi’s speech patterns.
I wonder how this thing
is programmed.
Let me analyze your programming
one of these days, okay, Rotom?
I must decline-roto!
Huh? Oh, come on,
don’t be such a stick-in-the-mud!
Please, Rotom!
I must refuse!
I must refuse-roto!
Index Rotom, is it?
Quite the interesting item
you’ve got there, Satoshi.
Principal.
Rotom, this is the
Pokémon School principal, Okido.
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
I thinKoduck! Arbok!
I thinKoduck? Arbok?
Does not compute...
Don’t think too hard about it.
That was just a greeting.
The principal loves
his Pokémon wordplays.
Pokémon wordplays...
It’s a pleasure to meet you, I thinKoduck... Arbok...
Well, Rotom? Is it nice being
inside the Index, do you think?
“Is it nice, I think?”
I-I-Is...
Is it nice, I thinKairyu!
Udeppou!
It’s not a bad forMaaiika!
Thank yoWooper!
Oh, my, you’re really good!
It looks like you and I
will be good friendSonano!
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
I thinKucheat!
Thank yoWooper!
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
I thinKucheat!
Thank yoWooper!
It’s a pleasure to meet you,
I thinKucheat!
Everyone, let’s do some fieldwork
for today’s class.
Satoshi, now that you’ve got
the Index Rotom, it’s finally time...
...to get a wild Pokémon!
All right!
I love fieldwork!
This will be Satoshi’s first try at
catching Alolan Pokémon.
You guys go Drag Along
and help him out.
Drag Along!
Drag Along. A Ghost-type move.
If the user is incapacitated in battle,
they drag the opponent down with them.
In other words, a move that
incapacitates both fighters.
Knew I could count on you, Rotom.
If you want information regarding Pokémon,
then you can depend on me-roto!
All right, let’s go, Rotom!
Roger that-roto!
Hang on!
Have fun,
but be carefuLizardon!
Let’s get ourselves
some Pokémon, right away!
We’ll catch each and every Alolan Pokémon
as soon as we find them!
Easy for you to say... Sonansu and I
are the ones who’ll have to battle them, meow...
Well, of course you will!
We handed off every other Pokémon we had
to Team Rocket HQ.
When in Alola,
do as the Alolans do!
But is it just me,
or is this place kinda creepy?
You think so?
Of course I do!
I get the feeling a ghost could come out
at any moment, or something like that!
Pikachu?
P-Pikachu’s...
...h-h-head! It’s...
L-Looking closer,
it isn’t Pikachu, meow...
It’s a different Pokémon,
wearing a Pikachu-like piece of cloth, meow!
Now that you mention it...
Hey... What’s gotten into you two?
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Iwanko
Type:   Rock
What is it saying?
Don’t ask, meow!
The things it’s saying are so scary,
you’re better off not knowing, meow!
Scary?
But looking at it up close...
Isn’t it kinda cute?
All right...
That Pokémon will be
our historic first catch in the Alola Region!
Nyarth,
hit it with Erratic Scratch!
Now it’s do or die, meow!
Erratic Scratch doesn’t work!
Please stop saying
such scary things, meow!
Ditch the cheap Pikachu costume,
and fight fair and square, meow!
This is a pretty long tunnel, meow...
And anyway, why am I walking
through here, meow?
Where am I, meow?
Musashi...
Kojiro!
Sonansu!
It’s the exit, meow!
Those cute Sirknight, Glacia and Mimilop
are calling for me, meow!
Wait for me, meow!
This is pure bliss, meow!
Nyarth!
I said, Nyarth! Come on!
Pull yourself together!
You haven’t even been hit yet!
Help, meow!
Get a grip, Nyarth!
I’m drowning, meow!
He’s awake!
Musashi! Kojiro!
There, there...
Thanks for bringing
me back, meow!
Bringing you back?
When I put my paws on that thing’s cloth
to take it off just now,
I caught a glimpse of
what was underneath, meow.
And then my consciousness
started slipping,
and when I came to,
I was walking through a dark tunnel, meow!
Then these super cute Sirknight, Glacia and Mimilop
appeared and told me to come with them...
But then the whole area became super creepy,
and I found myself falling into the darkness, meow!
“Cute Sirknight, Glacia
and Mimilop”?
“Into the darkness”?
You mean the underworld?
It’s the truth, meow!
If you hadn’t brought me back,
I’m sure I would have been...
It’s all that thing’s fault, meow!
I’ve got a hunch that we’re just about to
meet a wild Pokémon!
Really?
Let’s hope your hunch is right.
I’m so tired of walking...
The likelihood of encountering a
Pokémon in this area is 83.9%
It’s the brat boy
and Pikachu, meow!
Plus others!
What’s going on?!
I got it! This is our chance!
A huge chance to get both
the Pokémon of Alola and that Pikachu...
...and offer them all up to Sakaki!
Look! There’s one!
Your hunch was spot-on!
That’s... not a Pikachu, is it?
It’s Mimikkyu!
I read about it in a book once!
I believe its typing was-
Hold it-roto!
Leave the Pokémon
descriptions to me-roto!
Mimikkyu. Disguise Pokémon.
Ghost/Fairy type.
It’s known to wear a rag
that looks just like Pikachu,
but other than that,
this Pokémon remains shrouded in mystery.
It’s said that a scholar who saw what was under its rag
died from the shock.
Died from the shock?!
I’m so glad I lived, meow!
Hey, look at that
weird Pokémon Index!
It’s moving about and talking
by its own accord!
Now that you mention it...
All right!
Let’s do this, Pikachu!
We’re gonna get that Mimikkyu!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
The Iron Tail didn’t hurt it!
It’s strong!
Fighting at close range
is dangerous!
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
Amazing!
It’s so strong-roto!
Hey, did you see that?
That, um... what was it?
They called it a “Mimikkyu”
or something, right?
It’s evenly matched with
the brat boy’s Pikachu!
As if we’d let the stinking brat boy
get something as powerful as that!
Are you okay?
Pikachu, our next move-
Hold it, you!
Who are you?!
When asked “Who are you?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket?
Do you fly into space
or something-roto?
“What an awful feeling!”
...is what we used to say,
but we’re done blasting off into space!
Team Rocket...
...is the name of a super famous
evil organization, you see!
You don’t even know that?
What a sorry excuse for a Pokémon Index, meow!
No data! It’s a Nyarth that can
speak human language-roto!
This could very well be the discovery
of a new Pokémon species-roto!
S-Stop that, meow!
You’re such a pest, meow!
Evil organization?
I’ve never heard of them...
Me, neither.
Nor me.
They’re bad guys
who steal people’s Pokémon!
“Steal people’s Pokémon”?!
So you’re Pokémon thieves!
Team Rocket!
You’ve come all the way to the Alola Region
just to cause more trouble?!
Right back at you!
I don’t know why you’re here,
but now that we’ve
found you here, you’re toast!
We, Team Rocket, will be taking
your Pikachu and your friends’ Pokémon!
And Mimikkyu, too.
We found that one first,
you hear?!
All right, Nyarth, you’re up!
Pikachu! I know full well
how powerful you are,
but today we’ll be going all out,
and I will not lose, meow!
Erratic Scratch, meow!
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
An Electro Ball
right off the bat?!
Mimikkyu!
Your attack saved me, meow!
Thank you, meow!
Wait... Are you trying to protect us?
Oh, my! Mimikkyu is saying it will
help us out, meow!
What?!
I mean, I guess that’s
what we wanted, but...
Why?
It seems Mimikkyu
loathes Pikachu, meow...
Loathes?
Mimikkyu didn’t take on the appearance of Pikachu
out of any fondness for it, meow...
Apparently, this appearance is the very thing
Mimikkyu hates the most, meow!
A-And the rest is so scary,
I’d really rather not hear it, meow!
Looks like there’s some
pretty deep stuff going on here...
But if it’s going to help us out,
then let’s get right to it...
Mimikkyu! Use some sort of move!
Whatever you feel like!
Here it comes, Pikachu!
Be careful-roto!
Yes! Go! Take them down!
What?!
W-What’s going on?
Hey... Wait, what?
Hey... Huh?
Where are you taking
Musashi and Kojiro, meow?!
W-W-What are you doing?
Musashi! Kojiro!
Excuse me... Please put us down!
Who’s that Pokémon?
Kiteruguma. Strong Arm Pokémon.
Normal/Fighting type.
It waves its arms in a friendly way,
but this is a warning gesture.
Do not approach carelessly.
This immensely dangerous Pokémon
possesses overwhelming physical strength.
Immensely dangerous...
Mimikkyu! We have to save
Musashi and Kojiro, meow!
You said you’d help us, meow!
Leave Pikachu for later!
Now we have to save our friends, meow!
What even is this feeling?
What was their deal?
In the end,
you couldn’t catch that one...
Yeah...
But there are so many other Pokémon
to be found in the Alola Region!
There’ll be plenty more chances!
I’m sure you’re right!
All right, Pikachu, Rotom!
Let’s go find the next Pokémon!
The chance of finding a Pokémon in this forest
has risen to 96.5%-roto!
And so, the mysterious Index, the Index Rotom,
has become the latest member of Satoshi’s group!
What kind of role will the Index Rotom play
in the adventures to come?
Our story in the Alola Region...
...has only just begun!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for your patienCelebi!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was the Pokémon Index!
The Plasma Pokémon, Rotom, is known for
diving into many different electronic appliances.
Its forme changes depending on the appliance it enters,
Rotom
Washing
machine
Wash Rotom
Rotom
Pokémon
Index
Pokédex
Rotom
Electronic
fan
Spin Rotom
Rotom
Refrigerator
Frost Rotom
........................                             ...........
................                                     .............
................                                      .............
........................                           ...........
........................                             ...........
................                                      .............
and ones that enter an Index, like this one...
...are known as Pokédex Rotom!
Rotom, will you take my photo?
Roger that-roto!
Let’s see...
Rotom, your photographing skills
still need workiN’asshi...
Next episode
That’s so many Monster Balls!
Well, of course!
I’m going to get my first-ever
Pokémon in Alola, after all!
How many is that?
He certainly is motivated...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
Perhaps he’s just bad at throwing?
Is that so?
6, 7, 8, 9, 10...
All right! It’s time for some
special Monster Ball throwing training!
11, 12, 13, 14, 15...
Huh? Training?
No, I’m good at this!
I’ve got no problems throwing-
16, 17, 18, 19, 20...
No excuses!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
21, 22, 23, 24, 25...
Next time
Enter Mokuroh!
I Caught a Pokémon in Alola!!
Enter Mokuroh! I Caught a Pokémon in Alola!!
26, 27, 28, 29, 30...
31, 32, 3-