Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem-roto!
Something unbelievable happens to me
in today’s episode-roto. What is it-roto?
Being eaten by Gonbe
Coming out of the Index
Being burned by Nyabby
Being put to sleep by Purin
Get the answer at
the end of the episode-roto!
The Pokémon School is off today.
It seems Satoshi and the others
are headed off somewhere.
All right, we’re going now, Rotom!
Everybody’s napping.
Sorry...
They seem to be sleeping peacefully,
but will they be all right?
We’re just going shopping nearby, after all.
I’d feel bad if I woke them up.
That’s right-roto. It’ll be fine-roto.
Okay, look after the house while we’re out.
We’ll be right back.
Understood-roto!
Have a nice trip-roto!
Everybody’s sleeping soundly-roto.
This is my chance
to get some pictures-roto!
What’s that-roto?
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Rotom's
Non-Stop Forme-Changing!
Package for you!
Excuse me!
Here I am-roto!
An Index Rotom!
I’ve never seen one before.
Is anybody home?
I’m looking after the house while they’re out-roto.
I’ll take the package-roto.
Looking after the house?
How clever of you!
Please don’t treat me like a child-roto.
Looking after the house is easy-roto.
Please touch this.
Touching-roto.
Thank you very much.
Well done-roto!
They bought a
washing machine-roto?
Hey! Cut that out-roto!
What a shock-roto!
We’re back!
What’s this?
Oh? It’s here already?
This isn’t what we bought.
Excuse me!
It seems we just delivered
the wrong item to you.
I’m sorry to have troubled you.
No problem.
Huh?
Rotom? Hey!
What’s wrong?
Well, it’s Rotom...
Let me see...
Index Rotom booting up...
It seems to have rebooted.
Did it break?
Who knows.
Alola! It’s a pleasuroto
to meet you! Wash!
Huh? It’s acting weird.
I... I... I... I...
I am Rotom-wash!
My name is Rotom-wash!
Hey, Rotom... It’s me, Satoshi.
Voice setting complete.
Alola!
I be the Index Rotom-wash!
It’s still acting weird.
User Satoshi verified.
Alola, Satoshi-wash!
Yeah, Alola...
Seems it’s moving, at least...
But don’t you think
it’s acting strange?
It might be a side effect
of rebooting.
Maybe. Let’s see
how it goes for a while.
Got it.
Rotom, are you all right?
Wash!
Where am I-roto?
S-Something’s wrong-roto.
Thank you.
Likewise.
We hope to see you again!
What’s going on-roto?
This is a washing machine-roto.
I woke up to find I had Forme-Changed
into a Wash Rotom-roto!
Where is my Index-roto?
Now I can clean all the
piled-up dirty laundry.
First, I have to turn it on...
Um... and then next is
the wash button...
What’s going on?
Isn’t it brand new?
My Index!
Being inside the power lines like this
doesn’t feel right at all-roto!
I’m being dragged into something-roto!
Be nice.
This way!
No, this way!
This way! This way! This way!
Now I’ve become a Spin Rotom-roto!
Where am I-roto?
This is Suiren’s house-roto!
This way!
No, this way!
Stop-roto!
What are you doing?
Being an electric fan
makes my eyes spin-roto...
I have to find my Index-roto.
I have to go back to Pokédex Forme-roto!
Since that was Suiren’s house just now,
that means Professor Kukui’s house
is this way-roto!
All right! I’m back-roto!
Now things can go
back to normal-roto!
Wait, no-roto!
This isn’t the Index-roto!
It’s the TV-roto!
Satoshi! Professor Kukui!
Professor Burnet!
They left me behind
and went off somewhere-roto!
Where did they go-roto?
It’s time for Alola’s
weather forecast.
Not here-roto!
Coming up next:
“Local Famous Gourmet Restaurants Feature”.
Not here either-roto!
Great catch-roto!
But it’s not here-roto!
Where am I now-roto?
The one who committed this crime
was smart indeed.
It’s Lucky-roto! I’m in
Master Detective Lucky-roto!
The culprit is in this room.
And we’re right at the climax-roto!
The culprit is...
Who is it-roto?
...you!
What?! Me-roto?!
I’m the culprit-roto?!
No, wrong-roto!
Satoshi and the others are gone,
as is the Index...
Does that mean they went to
throw away my empty shell-roto?!
No-roto!
I have to look for them-roto!
Satoshi! Where are you-roto?!
There’s definitely
something wrong here.
Guess we should take it
to the Pokémon Center.
A rare Pokémon-wash!
Where?!
Got it-wash!
What’s this?!
Is it listed in the Index?
How should I know-wash?
I can’t really tell from this photo.
We should have Professor Kukui
take a look later.
That’s...
A rare Pokémon-roto!
I have to take a picture-roto!
Wait, I’m not an Index-roto!
I want to get back to my Index, already-roto.
Where is Satoshi-roto?
I’m being pulled into
something again-roto!
Where am I-roto?
It’s Lilie-roto!
What do I do?!
Hey, Lilie! It’s me-roto!
Cut Rotom?
Why is it chasing me?!
Oh, no! Young Ms. Lilie,
I will save you now!
Odoridori, use Revelation Dance!
What a shock-roto!
Are you all right, Young Ms.?
Y-Yes...
Where is my Index-roto?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon-wash!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Wash Rotom
Type:   Electric/Water
Where am I-roto?
Kaki, I’m sorry for calling
on such short notice.
Isn’t this Mao’s voice-roto?
Here’s what you ordered.
Thank you...
How rare for you to
run out of Moomoo Milk.
Yeah. We kept getting orders
for stew and gratin, you see.
As thanks for delivering this,
have some hot pudding!
I was making some just now.
Wait just a sec.
Here they come-roto!
This is my chance-roto!
It opened on its own?
Is it finished?
Not quite.
Notice me-roto!
What’s wrong, Mao?
The microwave’s come to life!
That’s a Heat Rotom?!
Hey, Kaki! Mao! Amamaiko!
Go, Garagara!
What was that?
I don’t know...
Now I’ve Forme-Changed into
a Frost Rotom-roto!
And for some reason,
I feel really full-roto...
If you’re gonna eat during
your break from programming,
it’s just gotta be ice cream,
you know?
Māmane-roto!
Which one do I pick?
Do you want some too,
Togedemaru?
Māmane, notice me-roto!
What’s wrong, Togedemaru?
Here I am-roto!
Sheesh!
I froze them-roto!
Māmane, I’m so sorry-roto!
If you’re gonna eat during
your break from cleaning,
it’s just gotta be ice cream,
you know?
Oh, my.
I have nowhere else to go-roto...
At this rate, I’d rather stay in
the washing machine-roto...
Rotom’s acting strange.
Wash! Wash! Wash!
Oh my, you’re right.
It’s speaking strangely,
and it found a rare Pokémon
and took a picture of it,
but it didn’t even try
to get it in focus.
A rare Pokémon?
Rotom, can you
bring up the picture?
Wash!
Oh? It’s completely white.
Why?
The data was unnecessary,
so I deleted it-wash.
I prefer it be pure white-wash.
What?! Why would you do that?!
I really don’t think anyone other than Professor Kukui
understands the Index Rotom.
The Professor just said to
see how it goes for a while...
Will it get better?
Come to think of it, the washing machine here
was acting really strangely too,
even though I only just bought it.
Washing machine?
That one.
I thought I’d have it exchanged.
That washing machine seems
familiar, somehow-wash.
Familiar?
What?!
It’s Rotom!
Rotom. Plasma Pokémon.
Electric/Ghost type.
It infiltrates electronic devices
and wreaks havoc.
A Rotom who enters a washing machine
becomes Wash Rotom-wash!
This Rotom assumed its form once
it entered the Pokémon Index.
In that case, maybe a Rotom entered
that washing machine and wreaked havoc?!
Rotom went in!
I finally found a place where
I can relax-roto...
But will I have to live in
this washing machine forever-roto?
Wait, it’s Satoshi-roto!
I found him-roto!
I found Satoshi-roto!
I’m here-roto!
Hydro Pump?!
Pikachu, use Electro Ball!
No-roto! I’m not trying
to battle you-roto!
Pikachu, be careful!
It’s preparing another attack!
No, no! What must I do
to make you understand-roto?!
Bubble Beam?!
It’s not a move-roto!
These are my tears-roto!
They won’t stop-roto!
Pikachu, use 100,000 Volts!
What a shock...
Rotom?
It stopped moving again.
Index Rotom booting up...
It’s back on!
Language selection complete.
Hey, Rotom.
Alola, Satoshi!
I finally made it back-roto!
Rotom!
“Made it back”?
Oh, it’s going again!
Wait! Wait-roto!
Actually, we...
You switched bodies?!
That’s right-roto.
I don’t really understand it, but...
I switched places with the Rotom
who lived in this washing machine-roto.
Oh, I see!
This index really is
where I feel at home-roto!
I’ll keep doing my best as an
Index from now on-roto!
...But it appears my data has been
tampered with-roto...
Oh, that’s a photo of a rare Pokémon
that Wash Rotom took.
I want to see it-roto!
Well, it was...
But Wash Rotom deleted it.
I’m sure it’s the same one
I wanted to get a picture of-roto!
I’ve gotta go find it quickly-roto!
Oh, Rotom! Wait!
Rotom!
Hey, Rotom...
Don’t tell me it happened again?!
This one doesn’t seem to be it.
What? Then where’s my Rotom?
Hey, Rotom!
It’s not here... Where did it go?
Hey, Satoshi! I’m here-roto!
Rotom Forme-Changed into
all sorts of different things.
Let’s hope it gets back to normal
quickly this time.
To be continued!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting-roto!
The answer to the PokéProblem was
coming out of the Index-roto!
That really was awful-roto!
I was so used to
being in the Pokémon Index...
...that the washing machine and the other devices
just didn’t feel right at all-roto!
I’ll have to be careful with
Pikachu’s electricity in the future-roto.
Rotom!
I’m back-roto!
Next episode
I close my eyes and see...
...your silhouette from
that day when you left me.
I still haven’t forgotten our promise...
...and in my heart,
I seek it alongside the shine of that day.
Young fists clash on the beach,
trying to steal each other’s true love!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Don’t Cry, Hidoide!
Next time