Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Marshadow
Solgaleo
Bebenom
Zeraora
A rare Pokémon appears
in today’s episode.
Who is it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Alola!
What’s for breakfast?
Huh?
Nobody’s here-roto...
There they are!
Alola!
What’re you doing?
We haven’t really had a chance
to recharge lately,
so we’re getting some power
from nature.
From nature?
Take a look.
It might be a familiar view to you,
but it’s all
really quite incredible.
The refreshing morning sun...
The clear blue sea and sky...
The lush trees and greenery...
The beautiful flowers...
And the Pokémon.
This scenery is only here because...
...the people, nature and Pokémon...
...live together in a delicate balance.
“We will live together”...
You could say it’s
the spirit of Alola.
Indeed-roto!
“We will live together”...
All right! I’m gonna get plenty of
power from nature, too!
I’ll join you-roto!
First off, assume pose for Meditation...
Keep a calm mind and
direct your focus inwards...
Then take a deep breath,
as if drawing power from Mother Nature herself.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
The Lightning that Slices the Wind!
Its Name is Zeraora!!
Satoshi, why are you
so fired up-roto?!
Kaki and I promised to battle
today after school!
If you’re this hyped up already,
you won’t have any energy left after school-roto...
Oh, it’s fine!
Let’s win this, Pikachu!
What is it now-roto?
Kapu-Kokeko...
I wanted to see you!
I want to get stronger for
my Grand Trial on Poni Island!
Could you battle us?
Is it telling you
to follow-roto?
Think it’s gonna battle us?
Right!
Hey!
How far are we gonna go?
Kapu-Kokeko’s ability is
creating an Electric Field-roto!
That means it will battle us, right?
Right, let’s fight at full power!
Lightning Speed!
It’s Magical Shine-roto!
Pikachu, dodge it!
Well done, Pikachu!
100,000 Volts!
That startled me-roto...
Satoshi? Pikachu?
Where are you-roto?
Pikachu!
Pikachu, are you all right?!
What a relief...
Where are we?
A desert?
Hey! Rotom! Kapu-Kokeko!
So weird...
Am I dreaming or something?
Clearly not dreaming...
Hey!
What’s up, Pikachu?
It’s coming from over there.
Let’s have a look!
What’s that noise?
Are they working?
Over there!
A Pokémon?
It’s huge!
I don’t think I’ve seen this one before!
What is it doing?
Shoot!
It’s eating that stuff?!
For real?!
A dead end?!
Pikachu!
Now I guess we just gotta battle!
Let’s go! 100,000 Volts!
It ate the 100,000 Volts, too?!
Pikachu!
If we get hit by this stuff...
Pikachu, let’s use our Z-Move!
Here we go!
Huh?
Why is the Z-Ring...?!
Let’s go!
Why?!
Pikachu!
Infight.
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon.
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Zeraora
Type:   Electric
Infight.
Zeraora... Plasma Fists!
We’re leaving!
You come, too!
Focus!
Unless you want to get
eaten by Akujiking...
Follow me!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Hurry!
That thing is called Akujiking?
Yeah.
And who’s that Pokémon?
Be quiet for a bit.
What will you do if it hears you
and finds this escape route?
Oh, right...
Slump...
How’s it look, Zeraora?
Thanks for the help.
My name is Satoshi.
And this is my partner,
Pikachu.
I’m Dia.
Mr. Dia?
Just Dia.
This is Zeraora.
That move just now
was so cool!
You mean Plasma Fists?
Yeah! I could tell it was
effective against Akujiking!
That wasn’t enough.
Zeraora, you’re amazing!
That move you used
is called Plasma Fists?
The fur on your back
is awesome, too!
Is this a tail?
It’s so bushy!
It’s electrifying...
That’s what happens
if you touch it carelessly.
Right...
It’s acting just like Pikachu
when we first met!
What are you doing here?
This is a restricted area.
It is? We were just
battling Kapu-Kokeko...
Battling?
Yeah.
Then Pikachu and Kapu-Kokeko’s attacks
collided with each other, like, boom,
and the electricity went all
zap and bang!
...and before I knew it,
we were running from Akujiking.
Say, is Akujiking a Pokémon?
It’s an Ultra Beast.
It appeared without warning...
It destroyed buildings,
chipped away at the mountains,
eating anything in its path...
It tried to consume this entire city.
The Ultra Beast special ops team,
the Ultra Rangers, stood against it, but...
...it was no use.
After that,
Akujiking kept on destroying...
...and eating everything in its path.
The Ultra Rangers withdrew,
and the people abandoned this land.
Then who’s still here now?
Just Zeraora and I.
But why didn’t you flee?
This place used to be
filled with Pokémon, too.
People and Pokémon lived together, surrounded by lush nature.
I want to defeat that thing
and make things as they once were.
That’s all.
Then I wanna help!
I love Pokémon, too!
I’m sure Pikachu
feels the same way.
So...
No way.
Why?
You’ll hold me back.
H-Hey, I’m part of a team called
the Ultra Guardians!
We battle Ultra Beasts, too!
I don’t know about these
“Ultra Guardians”...
But that thing is different from the rest.
This isn’t some sort of children’s game.
I don’t think of it as a game!
It’s too dangerous for you.
Drop it.
If you really can’t trust us,
then face us in a Pokémon Battle!
If we lose, I’ll give up on this.
You make the first move.
Right... Let’s do this, Pikachu!
Lightning Speed!
Zeraora, use Lightning Speed.
It’s a Lightning Speed clash!
Follow it up with
an Iron Tail!
Infight!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
Use Electric Net!
All right... 100,000 Volts!
Slash!
Plasma Fists!
It’s that move!
Pikachu, dodge it!
Pikachu!
Are you okay?!
Is he awake?
Yeah.
I didn’t expect the Electric-type Pikachu
to get beaten by an Electric move...
This settles it.
Go home.
Okay...
But how are we supposed
to get home?
Good question...
I guess I’ll contact the Ultra Rangers,
and have them
come pick you up tomorrow.
You can do that?
I was one of them.
What, really?! But wait, “was”?
I quit once the Ultra Rangers
decided to pull out.
The only reason I’m here
is my own selfishness.
I can get behind that!
Right! Let’s go, Pikachu!
Let’s find somewhere to sleep.
Hey.
You should rest at my base.
Can I?
It’s dangerous to
set up camp just anywhere.
We made it out earlier,
but Akujiking can show up at any place.
Thank you.
Don’t get the wrong idea.
You’re only staying until
the Ultra Rangers come to pick you up.
Once they do, you’re leaving.
I know!
This way.
There’s nothing here...
Hey, did Akujiking do all this?
That’s right.
Whoa...
I’m starving...
I should’ve brought my backpack...
I had my lunch in there and all...
You sure talk a lot.
Here. Some emergency rations...
Huh? Thanks!
...for Pokémon.
Thank you...
You suck it up.
We’re almost there.
Sure...
What’s wrong?
Isn’t that...
...the Pokémon School?
Satoshi and Pikachu find themselves before
a ruined Pokémon School!
What does this mean?
And what will become of
Satoshi and Pikachu?!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon featured today...
...was Zeraora!
Since Rotom isn’t around, I’m not sure what kind of Pokémon
the Electric-type Pokémon Zeraora is...
But Plasma Fists is one crazy strong move!
That’s what it used to save me!
That startled me-roto...
Satoshi? Pikachu?
Where are you-roto?
Hey!
Satoshi!
Pikachu!
Next episode
This is awful!
The Pokémon School’s in ruins!
What’s more,
Akujiking will eat anything...
...and it’s plunged Melemele Island
into disaster!
If I’m dreaming,
then I wanna wake up!
Thank you, Zeraora...
This really isn’t a dream...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Fire!
The Twin Sparking Gigavolt of Friendship!!
Next time
Fire!
The Twin Sparking Gigavolt of Friendship!!