Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Peekara
Pickara
Pinkara
Pikarla
What is the Pikachu-loving lady
in this episode called?
Blue: Peekara? Red: Pickara?
Green: Pinkara? Yellow: Pikarla?
That’s Blue: Peekara? Red: Pickara?
Awesome!
There’s so many Pikachu!
We found the Pikachu Valley-roto!
The rumors were true-roto!
Me, too!
Whichever way you turn...
...you’ll see Pikachu, Pikachu,
and more Pikachu!
Now, let the Pikachu festival begin!
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
It's a Pikaoutbreak!
The Pikachu Valley!!
Alola-pika!
Alola!
My, what a lovely Pikachu!
Welcome-pika!
Wait a Pikasecond!
I see-pika!
This fur... These cheeks...
You’re a Kantonian Pikachu-pika!
Huh? You can tell?!
I can tell by
the sheen of its fur-pika!
A Kantonian Pikachu’s fur
sparkles in the sun,
but an Alolan Pikachu’s silky smooth fur
shines in the sun-pika!
I see.
Quite informative-roto.
That’s so cool!
Everyone,
it’s a pleasure to meet you!
I’m your Big Sis Pikarla-pika!
Nice to meet you!
We heard about this place
and came by for a visit!
That makes me happy-pika!
Let the Pikachu wash over you-pika!
Well then,
let’s waste no time and...
Pikachu ears,
or Pikacoronets, as I call them!
Pikachu tails,
or Pikachails, as I call them!
So cute!
Yeah, it’s so cute!
It’s a Hoshichu!
I’ve become
a Pikachu, too-roto...
What do you think, Pikachu?
I’m a Pikachu, too!
All right,
now your Big Sis Pikarla...
...will teach you the three rules
of Pikachu Valley-pika!
First, to make
your heart Pikachu-pika!
Second...
To love all Pikachu-pika!
Third, to put “-pika” at the end of
all your sentences-pika!
I call it Pikanese-pika!
Like this-pika-roto?
Hey, you!
No “-roto” here-pika!
If you must, then please
make it “-rotopika”-pika!
I’ll try-pika... ro... to....
Fsssh-roto... pika...
You got it-pika!
Anyone who can uphold these rules
will be a resident of Pikachu Valley; a PikaFriend-pika!
So, everyone, tell me your names
in Pikanese, please-pika!
I’m Satoshi-pika!
Hoshi-pika!
I’m Kaki-pika...
I’d like you to make it
“Satopi”, “Hopi” and “Kapi”-pika!
Satopi?
Hopi!
That’s so cute-pika!
K-Kapi?!
Good grief-roto... pika...
And you’ll be Rotopi!
Rotopi?! Rotopika...
It’s fine! You’ll get used to it
in no time-pika!
“Pika” is nourishment
for the heart-pika!
All five senses must fully
embrace the Pikachu-pika!
If they do, the love for Pikachu
will spread through your entire being...
...making the whole world
turn Pikachu-pika!
Now, you try, Satopi!
All right! I’m Satopi-pika!
Hopi’ll get you-pika!
I-I’m...
Give it a try-pika, Kapi.
Big bro,
are you embarrassed-pika?
O-Of course not!
You didn’t say “-pika”-pika!
Pika...
What’s that? I couldn’t hear you-pika!
Kapi, just be a Pikachu-pika!
That’s right-rotopika!
It’s easy-rotopika!
Make your heart Pikachu-pika!
Put all your love into saying it-pika!
Big bro!
Be a Pikachu with Hopi-pika!
W-With Hopi...
With...
I’ll be a Pikachu
with Hopi-pika!
Great, big bro-pika!
Good-pika, good-pika!
Saying “pika” clears the clouds in your heart!
It feels wonderful-pika!
This is the best-pika!
Big bro!
You’re so cute-pika!
Thank you-pika!
Pleasure to meet you-pika...
Pikaleasure to meet you-pika!
Everything here’s
Pikachu-colored-pika!
That’s right-pika!
That’s the Pikachu’s house-pika!
I wanna see inside-pika!
All right, your big bro
will take a look-pika!
So many Pikachu...
So much fun-pika...
Are all the Pikachu here
yours-pika?
That’s right-pika! Morning, afternoon and night,
I’m always getting more Pikachu-pika!
And I’m not done-pika!
Any Pikachu-lovers will always
be welcome here-pika!
We’ve been adventuring together
since the beginning-pika!
Right, Pikachu?
Huh?
Over there-rotopika!
They’re cautious
about him-pika.
Cautious-pika?
Because he’s from Kanto-pika.
He’s like a new
transfer student-pika!
It’s a valiant female
Pikachu-rotopika!
The tip of her tail is heart-shaped.
That means she’s female-rotopika.
She’s got curly bangs,
so I call her Curly-pika!
Curly! That’s so cute-pika!
H-Huh? They all left-pika!
Your Pikachu misunderstood their greeting,
and thought he was a real stud-pika.
Greeting-pika?
Zapping and sniffing one another is
how Alolan Pikachu greet each other-pika.
The female Pikachu
come to say hi first...
...so he thought that meant
he was popular with the ladies-pika.
C’mon! My Pikachu
is so cool, though-pika!
After the girls, it’s the boys’ turn
to come say hi-pika!
It’s a thundercloud-rotopika!
They’re so silky and glowy-pika!
This is the secret behind
Alolan Pikachu’s silky fur-pika!
When the Pikachu
rub their tails together...
...it generates a large
electric current-pika!
That summons thunderclouds,
and... Bang!
...brings down a massive bolt
of Thunder-pika!
The natural electric power boosts
their energy a hundredfold...
...and makes them all
silky and glowy-pika!
Pikachu’s gotten
all silky, too-pika!
I want them to come to
our farm, too-pika!
Great idea-pika!
Big bro agrees-pika!
Why’d you let Mimikkyu out?
This was obviously
gonna happen, meow.
It came out on its own,
though!
But you know,
this might be our chance.
Chance?
If Mimikkyu goes wild against those Pikachu,
it’ll make for a brilliant distraction!
We can use the confusion to
get the brat boy’s Pikachu!
It’s perfect!
Yeah, that’s a great idea, but...
Which one’s the brat-Pika?
Well, we might as well catch ‘em all.
Spare ourselves the trouble of finding him.
How?
Isn’t it obvious?
Right, Mimikkyu?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon-pika!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Pikachu (♀)
Type:   Electric
It’s silky smooth-pika!
Let me feel it, too!
It really is smooth-pika!
Really-pika?
T-This is...
Such a luxurious feel-pika!
It’s almost like silk or velvet-pika!
Right? Just looking at these darlings
makes you happy-pika!
Pikachu, aren’t you glad
we came-pika?
You can make
so many friends here-pika!
Huh? It’s Curly-pika!
Maybe...
...her heart’s gone aflutter over
Satopi’s Pikachu-pika?!
It’s possible-pika. His silky smooth fur has
boosted his appeal-pika!
Hey, don’t run away, Pikachu!
Pikachu’s just spineless-pika.
But it looks like her heart really has
gone aflutter over your Pikachu-pika!
Huh?
Someone fired a bolt-rotopika!
It’s a shiny Pikachu-rotopika.
Really?! I’ve never seen Pikachu’s
shiny form before-pika!
We call that shiny Pikachu Boss-pika!
Seems he’s been interested in Curly
for quite some time-pika!
Oh, my goodness!
Doesn’t that make this...
...a storm of love, caused by two men’s clashing feelings for one woman-pika?!
L-L-Love-pika?!
Where did you learn
about that-pika?!
And it’s possible that he doesn’t want
to accept an outsider-pika!
Pikachu, no fighting-pika!
Yeah, that’s better-pika!
A clash of electricity signals
the start of a duel-pika!
It’s a rule of this valley-pika.
Duel?!
Pikachu, don’t—
This is the Pikachu’s problem-pika.
Humans have no place in this-pika.
What are the rules
of this duel-rotopika?
The first one to bite
the opponent’s tail wins-pika.
So close-pika!
That’s a Voltteccer!
Dodge it-pika!
Electroweb!
You did it, Pikachu!
Your Pikachu is
an experienced battler-pika!
This is awesome-pika!
That’s... Pika!
Oh, my!
A Pikachu cosplayer-pika!
That’s a Pokémon named
Mimikkyu-rotopika!
Mimikkyu? Wow!
Your cosplay’s great-pika!
Now, let’s go, Mimikkyu!
Operation...
...Instant and...
...Pain-Free!
Team Rocket-pika!
When you say
“Team Rocket-pika!”-pika...
Let us tell you
our names-pika!
Blindly following
at lightning speed!
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi-pika!
Gods of wind and lightning strike
with thunderous momentum!
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro-pika!
Be careful around high voltage currents!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth-pika, meow!
Team Rocket is here-pika!
It’s infectious, meow!
All right, wait a second-pika!
Good-pika, good-pika!
Your thunderous puns are
filled with Pikachu love-pika!
What is this?!
Whatever! Let’s go!
Mimikkyu! It’s time to show off
your power, meow!
This is...
...our...
...Z-Move!
Snuggly Friend Time!
What is that?!
Noooo!
This is our latest discovery!
Keeping the full power pose with fighting spirit
to hold onto the full Z-Power: Full Power Keep!
Full Power Keep
And the Full Power Keep
affects Mimikkyu, too,
letting it keep
the Pikachu trapped, meow!
That pose is
way too forced-pika!
Hang in there, Musashi!
Keep them trapped, meow!
Keep... Keep the full power pose!
Let everyone go-pika!
Darn... Brat-Pika,
you’re not even trapped?
Hey, Pikachu!
We can let the other Pikachu out for you,
if you’ll just come to us!
Pull me up already!
You got it, meow!
Heave, ho!
Pika... Mimikkyu’s...
Another new discovery!
The air inside Mimikkyu’s body heats up
while it’s using Snuggly Friend Time, allowing it to float!
Well?
What’cha gonna do now?!
In that case...
Wait-pika!
Pikarla-pika!
Boss!
Those are my Pikachu-pika.
I’ll save them-pika!
A Z-Ring-pika!
Boss!
Let’s go-pika!
A Pikachu-Z-rotopika?!
Pika-Pika, Pikachu’s electrifying power
at it’s peak!
When its sparkling zaps pick at you,
it’s over-pika!
Fatal Pikachoot!
Got ‘em-pika!
What an awful feeling!
Pikachu!
Electroweb-pika!
Huh? They’ve fallen in love-pika!
“Fallen in love”?! No really,
where did you learn about that...?!
Hopi!
Huh?
What even is this feeling?
That was amazing-pika!
Fatal Pikachoot!
Your Pikachu should use it, too-pika!
You need to know Voltteccer
to use that Z-Move-rotopika.
Everyone, I’m so glad
you’re safe-pika!
Now then,
I’m gonna do a roll call!
Gather up-pika!
Here we go!
The one who battles
with a bang, Boss-pika!
The one with the curly bangs, Curly-pika!
Don’t tell me, she’s gonna...
It’ll be evening by the time
she’s finished-roto...
Pikachu Valley;
A paradise of Pikachu lovers,
by Pikachu lovers,
for Pikachu lovers-pika!
The fun times will
go on and on-pika!
Pika?
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pikachu-loving lady’s name
was Pikarla-pika!
The Mouse Pokémon Pikachu
is an Electric type!
They say its stress builds up if it doesn’t get to
discharge all its electricity every now and then!
Pikarla gathered an enormous crowd of the super popular
Pikachu in a single valley... She’s amazing-pika!
Ka, the one with
the somewhat short tail!
That’s all!
Everyone’s here-pika!
It really did last
until evening-roto...
Pika...
All right, everyone...
Dismissed! Pika!
Next episode
My name is Sauboh.
Today, I’d like to tell you about
a certain man I admire.
His name is Royal Mask!
He’s Alola’s greatest...
No, the whole universe’s greatest hero!
Do you all know who Royal Mask truly is?
You see, it’s...
Top! Se! Cret!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Kukui Up Against the Wall!
Another Royal Mask!!
All right, all together now...
Next time
Kukui Up Against the Wall!
Another Royal Mask!!
Enjoy!