Everyone doing good?
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Who comes to Alola in today’s episode?
Sakaki
Matori
Takeshi
Kasumi
The bowl-headed four-eyes?
The brat girl?
The bigger brat boy?
Or Sakaki?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Let’s get going, all smiles as usual!
Yeah!
What?
Um... Isn’t that...?
A call from HQ, meow!
Really? Hm? Uh...
Why are you flailing around like that?
Most unsightly.
“Unsightly”?!
Watch your mouth!
Now, now, calm down, Musashi.
I have a message from Sakaki.
From Sakaki?!
“Send that Pokémon you caught in Alola,
Kiteruguma, to HQ at once.”
Whaaaaat?!
You are in no position
to say “Whaaaaat?!”.
We can’t do that.
We never even caught her.
But we said we did, meow...
Have you only caught
one single Pokémon?
N-No, we have more, meow!
That’s Kiteruguma, meow.
That’s right. Kiteruguma is
a very strong Pokémon, as well.
We have so many, we’re not even sure
who’s strong and who isn’t!
Well... First off...
Didn’t I tell you your flailing
was unsightly?
What?!
“Stop whining and just send it”?!
You’d best enjoy bossing us around
while you still can, meow!
We’ll pull off a tide-turning
homerun before long...
So just watch your neck, meow!
Now, now, Nyarth...
Um... We kinda can’t really
let Kiteruguma go right now, see...
Sakaki had one more thing to say.
“In the event that
they don’t do as I say...
“Then accept no excuses.
Bring Kiteruguma to HQ by force.”
See you in Alola.
“See you in Alola”?
She’s coming here...
But there’s no way Kiteruguma will
come quietly to HQ with Matori, meow...
Now, what will you do,
Team Rocket?
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
You're Being Watched!
Team Rocket's Alolan Forms!!
Alola!
Very nice! Your Z-Rings are shining
as brightly as a Sunshine Smasher!
I’ve been researching
how to use Z-Moves lately.
That’s wonderful, Māmane.
W-Well... Yeah...
I will do my best so that I can pull off
a Raging Geofreeze together with Snowball!
It... It hasn’t sunk in for me
that I even have a Z-Ring yet...
So I still can’t even imagine
using actual Z-Moves.
I’m sure you can do it!
Then I guess Mao,
Māmane and Lilie...
...should start training
Z-Move poses out in the courtyard.
Yes!
What about us,
Professor Kukui?
Don’t be in such a rush!
I mean, the Alola League’s
coming up!
I wanna get way, way stronger!
Me, too.
And me!
You have a point...
Well then I guess...
...you could practice using Z-Moves as
part of your battle strategy.
Using Z-Moves as part of our...
...battle strategy?
When you have a move as strong as the Z-Moves,
depending on how you use them,
it’s no exaggeration to say that they can
make the difference between winning and losing a battle.
When will you launch the Z-Move,
and with which Pokémon?
Also, for anyone who has
multiple Crystals,
which Z-Move type will
be most effective?
There’s countless things a trainer must
consider and decide on in the heat of battle!
Well? Doesn’t that sound exciting?
Yeah!
Well then, we’re heading
to the courtyard for some training!
Yeah!
Well, here goes...
Y-Yeah...
Will she go in?
Well... When it all comes down to it,
we’ve been together for a pretty long time.
So when it comes down to it,
she might be at the point where
she’s okay with being caught by us, too?
Perhaps...
When it all comes down to it...
We just gotta go for broke, meow.
All right...
All it takes is one good hit!
We went for broke...
But the only thing that broke
was the Ball, meow!
I give up... Even if we did
manage to catch her,
Kiteruguma would never be okay
with going to HQ.
Yeah.
And that doesn’t just go
for Kiteruguma...
But Mimikkyu, too.
Hidoide, too.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Don’t do that?!
Nuikoguma, too, meow.
Where is Kiteruguma?
She’s already here!
That was too fast, meow!
What is that?!
Spectacular! Its physical prowess
is something to be feared.
You will hand it over... Now!
W-Well, that’s a bit...
“A bit”... what?
When it all comes down to it,
it’s kinda...
“When it all comes down to it”?
Well, we just...
“Just...”?
...can’t!
Say what you will,
but we really can’t give her up, meow!
Why is that?
W-Well...
You see, we’re making plans to catch
some super strong Pokémon right now!
Y-Yes, that’s right!
S-Some absolutely incredible Pokémon!
They’re sure to make
great gifts for Sakaki, meow!
And we really need Kiteruguma’s power
to get those Pokémon!
Very well.
However...
What? “However”?
I will be keeping an eye on you
until you can get these “incredible Pokémon.”
And if you fail to get them,
I will take Kiteruguma and leave immediately.
Bear this in mind.
Fine by me!
Feel free to keep an eye on us!
We are Team Rocket,
bringers of righteous evil in Alola...
You’d best keep a real close eye on us!
Don’t even blink!
This is the Pokémon School, meow.
And these “incredible Pokémon”
of yours are in here?
That’s right! There’s one that’s real tiny,
but eats mega massive loads of mechanisms!
A super rare evolution
that doesn’t even show up in the Index!
And an insane crackling,
flashing electricity-firing...
...mega-strong Pikachu!
I see...
Z-Z-Moves?!
Hey!
When did they all get Z-Rings?!
This is awful, meow!
We’ll take three Z-Moves straight to the face, and...
What an awful feeling!
Run, meow!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kiteruguma
Type:   Normal/Fighting
Z-Moves...
Three at once!
What?! “It’s fine, meow”?!
You wouldn’t be saying that
if you knew how terrifying Z-Moves are, meow!
“You’re the ignorant one,”
you say?!
Calm down and look closer.
Now that you mention it, I’m not seeing that
fully powered smoke thing that usually pops up...
Indeed.
Yup, meow.
Look at their Z-Rings.
They don’t have Z-Crystals, meow!
All right! All three of you are doing great
with your Z-Move pose training!
Thank you!
We’re getting more and more in sync,
aren’t we, Snowball?
The pose needs to be exactly right,
Kuwagannon.
Think it’ll look even better if we point our fingertips
towards the sky while doing it, Amajo?
Good grief... You may be the lowest of grunts,
but you are still members of Team Rocket.
You are to keep a cool head
and make sharp judgment calls at all times.
Sure, sure... Very sorry...
We’re neither cool-headed
nor sharp, after all...
This is our full power!
Super Spiral Combo!
What an awful feeling!
Is there really an incredible Pokémon
around here?
“We can’t expect anything
from these fools”?!
Musashi! Kojiro! We’re gonna get
that incredible Pokémon...
...and prove these guys wrong
for sure, meow!
Got that right!
We’re entering its territory.
Let’s go get it!
Speak of the devil, meow...
Kojiro! Bring the you-know-what!
I got it!
Have some of your beloved
Haban Berries, Jijilong!
Jijilong?
When Jijilong is angered, it completely destroys
its surroundings with its intense breath.
It’s a super strong Pokémon!
The terror of its breath...
...is something we have
personal experience with, meow.
I see. That sounds very promising.
There it is!
This time...
...we’ll get our revenge, meow!
I suppose we’ll see what they can do.
Come out, Mimikkyu!
H-Huh? Hey, Mimikkyu!
Mimikkyu is as difficult as ever...
No interest in any opponent that isn’t Pikachu, meow.
Well then, come out, Hidoide!
Good grief...
Kojiro!
G-Got it...
Take a real good look,
bowl-headed four-eyes!
Watch us...
Let’s go, Hidoide!
The three of us will stand together,
even if all we can share is our drive!
The “Ro” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Romanticism”!
This is our...
The “ke” in “Team Rocket” stands for “Keenness”!
...Z-Move!
The little “c” in “Team Rocket” between the two stands for...
“‘Course, we’re villains!”
“Come on, come at us!”
“Clearly, Pikachu’s too strong, meow!”
Go!
Black Hole Eclipse...
“What an awful feeling!” we scream as we blast off,
and beneath us we see a little, tiny Earth,
forests, mountains and Pokémon...
They all blend together!
Nui...
...koguma...
That’s...
What even is this feeling?
Wh-What?
Again, what?
What is this?!
Kiteruguma wants to be
a good host to her guests, meow.
Guests?
We simply need to
catch Nuikoguma.
It will eventually evolve
into Kiteruguma.
This is what I mean by keeping a cool head
and making sharp judgment calls.
Oh no, meow!
Matori kidnapped Nuikoguma, meow!
What?!
She’s probably planning on
sneaking it back to HQ, meow!
Where’s Kiteruguma?
Not here.
We have to get it back!
What do we do?!
I’m sure she’ll say...
“Give Nuikoguma back?
“I will report this as
an act of rebellion against Sakaki.
“I take it you are okay with that, then?”
or something annoying like that!
Well, then what do we do, meow?
Think... Think!
There must be a way!
Bowl-headed four-eyes!
Oh, sorry, I got that wrong!
What I meant to say was, Matori!
Have you come to see me off?
How polite of you.
You were just gonna leave without saying bye?
Isn’t that a bit cold?
I just got a call from HQ.
Something’s come up,
forcing me to go back immediately.
I thought it would be cruel to wake you
when you were sleeping so comfortably.
Oh, it would’ve been fine, really!
Well, but I guess you had no choice,
if it was an order from HQ!
Go on back!
And say hi to Sakaki for us!
W-Well then... Farewell!
Good grief...
But Sakaki should be happy now.
What are you doing here?!
Think this’ll work?
He’ll figure something out, I’m sure.
Wh-Where is Nuikoguma?!
Answer me!
I know full well who you are!
We are the indestructible Team Rocket!
Kiteruguma!
We’ll chase Pikachu ‘til the end of the earth!
What even is this feeling?
So peaceful, meow...
Peace is good...
When it all comes down to it, it’s all good.
Yeah...
When it all comes down to it...
Come to think of it, what happened
to Matori and her crew, meow?
Who knows...?
It seems Kiteruguma, Nuikoguma
and Team Rocket...
...will get to stay together after all.
All’s well... that ends well?
It’s time for the regular upd—
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
It was the bowl-headed four-eyes
who came to Alola!
The Strong Arm Pokémon Kiteruguma
is a Normal/Fighting type.
It’s said that Kiteruguma has the habit of
affectionately hugging its trainers,
but that its hugs are
immensely powerful...
Nobody knows that better than us!
That should do it!
We’ll send this high quality Kiteruguma robot,
the More-Or-Less Kiteru Lad, to HQ!
That’ll make ‘em happy, meow!
How are you gonna
get it outside, though?
Next episode
We’re holding a Z-Move
boot camp for Māmane!
Yeah!
Then I’ll have to make
some preparations!
Listen closely...
Feel the breath of Alola and
offer your thanks to Mother Nature!
I’ll pack as many snacks
as I can fit in this bag...
Then I’ll need my PC and notepad...
Oh, and a pillow!
That’ll cause your power
to naturally well up!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Master Your Z-Move!
Kaki’s Fiery Boot Camp!!
Oh, no!
What?
Now that Denjimushi’s
evolved into Kuwagannon,
I don’t have any spare batteries!
Next time
Master Your Z-Move!
Kaki’s Fiery Boot Camp!!
Oh...