Alola!
I, Suiren, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem.
Yowashi
Shirodeathna
Kiteruguma
Dekagoos
Which one of these Pokémon
do I battle today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Hey, can we really catch this
“Lord of the Lake” here?
Yes, we can!
This is top secret information
that I got a hold of!
Even that Fishing Guru over there
said he’d seen the Lord of the Lake here.
See? I’m sure we can catch it!
No, we will catch it!
Undoubtedly!
All right, I got it.
Then let’s keep reeling in
Lords of the Lake...
...and make Sakaki happy!
Bring on the Lords of the Lake!
I’m pretty sure there’d only be one,
since it’s a Lord, meow.
This must be the
Lord of the Lake, meow!
Be careful, Nyarth!
I know, meow!
Let me see...
Looks like a Yowashi.
We don’t need this
wishy-washy thing, meow.
All right! This is a big one!
Don’t let it go!
Fight, meow!
What even is this feeling?
Did they go home?
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
The Mighty Yowashi,
Lord of the Lake!
Satoshi and the others are enjoying
the extracurricular lessons on Akala Island.
Today’s a free day.
I wonder where everyone will go?
What’re you doin’, Suiren?
Checking my fishing rod.
I’m gonna catch a wild Mega Gyarados!
Mega Gyarados?!
Awesome!
You can fish up one of those?!
Just kidding.
Kidding?!
There’s no such thing as a
wild Mega Gyarados-roto.
But I really am going fishing.
Since we’re on Akala Island,
I want to try catching some of the big shots around here.
Fishing, huh?
We all went fishing together,
didn’t we?
Wanna come with me?
Yeah!
All right, I’m gonna catch
a big one too!
Oh... I don’t have a fishing rod.
Here.
My family’s motto:
“Keep a rod with you in case of emergencies!”
You can borrow this.
Thanks, Suiren!
Fair enough, but if you’re gonna come along,
do help out a bit.
Sure, sure.
Where’re you going, Kaki?
They say they want to come to my house.
I mean, it’s a farm!
Butter, cheese and yogurt
made from fresh Moomoo Milk!
Oh, we can’t forget
about ice cream!
It would be a wonderful opportunity...
...to make some new Pokémon Food
using Moomoo Milk as a base!
So that’s that.
You wanna come too?
I’m gonna go fishing with Suiren!
We’re gonna catch a big one!
All right.
Well, we’re off.
Bye!
Pardon us.
Catch a big one!
All right, Suiren.
Let’s get going!
Yeah!
I’m gonna catch a big one!
Oh, you two...
Ms. Lychee!
Are you all right?
Going on a fishing date today?
N-N-N-No, that’s not it!
We’re gonna fish up
something spectacular!
I see. Well, this might be done
by the time you get back.
The Z-Ring!
Isn’t this exciting, Suiren?
Oh... Sure.
Huh? You’re not happy?
You might be able to unleash
your own Z-Moves, you know!
It hasn’t quite sunk in yet.
I’m sure it will soon enough.
Oh, I know!
You’re going fishing, right?
At the pond near Brooklet Hill,
there’s this really impressive beast called
the Lord of the Lake. Why not check it out?
Lord of the Lake?!
Whoa, it’s huge!
This is where the
Lord of the Lake lives-roto?
We’ll know once we start fishing!
Once we start fishing!
Hold up, fishermen over there!
Who might you be?
I’m Akala Island’s Fishing Guru!
Fishing Guru?
You’ll need my permission
in order to battle the Lord of the Lake!
Really?!
Indeed. It is a terrifying beast that, even after
countless struggles in my forty years as Fishing Guru...
...I’ve yet to be able to reel in!
This scar is a trophy I gained from
a life-or-death struggle with it!
And anyway, the Lord of the Lake will only battle
those whose skill it acknowledges.
I, the Fishing Guru, will determine
whether you’re worthy!
Please do!
Please!
I really want to reel in
the Lord of the Lake!
Really!
Then reel in a Hinbass,
right here!
Hinbass. Fish Pokémon.
Water type.
A tough Pokémon that is perfectly fine
even in dirty water.
Oh, we just need to
reel in a Hinbass?
Too soft!
This is why amateurs
are such a pain.
Huh?
Listen up! The Hinbass around here
are not so easily reeled in.
They’re so difficult to catch that,
after fifty long years as Fishing Guru...
...I only recently succeeded
in reeling one in!
Fifty years?
He said forty years earlier-roto...
In any case, it’s not something
an amateur can just reel in!
What?!
I caught one!
Now I can battle the
Lord of the Lake, right?
Such skill, to be able to
catch a Hinbass so easily...
In my sixty long years as Fishing Guru,
this is the first time I’ve seen it!
All right! Very well!
Yes!
That’s awesome, Suiren!
Now he’s saying sixty y-
However, you’ll need a boat
to fish for the Lord of the Lake!
Do you have a boat?
Um, no...
I can lend you one!
It’ll be a bit expensive, though.
All right, just this once as a special service,
I’ll lend you a boat in exchange for this Hinbass.
Ta-daah!
Will we really be all right
with this boat?
It has battled the Lord of the Lake alongside me
through my seventy long years as Fishing Guru!
Behold, the proof of
our deathly struggles!
Now he’s saying seventy years!
And his scars just came loose-roto...
Nobody who frets over the small stuff
will be able to reel in the Lord of the Lake.
Huh?
Yowashi?
What’s a Yowashi?
Yowashi. Small Fry Pokémon.
Water type.
When in danger, its eyes start to waver,
making it look like it’s crying.
I see!
Huh? Is it injured?
You’re right!
Wait a moment.
There! It’s okay now.
You did well.
Let’s meet again somewhere.
All right, let’s go!
Whoa! I’ve got something already!
Looks like the Koiking like you,
Satoshi.
I sense a big one!
What is it, Ashimari?
Suiren!
This one’s big, all right...
Unidentified! Unidentified!
The Lord...
...of the Lake?
In my eighty long years
as Fishing Guru,
this is the first time I’ve ever laid eyes
on the Lord of the Lake! La la la la!
Didn’t you battle it?!
Never mind that,
focus on the Lord of the Lake!
It’s acknowledged that girl
as a worthy opponent!
Suiren’s gonna fight
the Lord of the Lake?!
Yes! I’ll battle it!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I choose you!
Name: Yowashi
..                    (Solo Form)
Type:   Water
Hey! I told you to help out a bit!
But this fresh cheese is too good!
Gotta try the butter next!
Ah, bliss!
Amazing!
All I did was add
Moomoo Milk to the recipe...
...and Snowball seems to
absolutely love it!
Kaki! Another double scoop
of ice cream!
This is hopeless...
I’m sure Satoshi and Suiren are
having fun fishing right now.
I won’t lose!
Pikachu!
Suiren!
I’m okay!
But it’s incredibly powerful!
Satoshi!
Satoshi spotted-roto.
That caught me off-guard.
Huh? Where’s Pikachu?
Pikachu!
That’s...
Get out of there, Pikachu!
Not good!
Pikachu, this way!
Ashimari, help Pikachu!
Pikachu, are you all right?
Thank you, Ashimari.
I won’t lose!
In my ninety-nine years as Fishing Guru,
I’ve never seen a battle like this!
It keeps getting longer
and longer-roto...
It feels like it’s gonna drag me under!
We have to do something!
Of course!
Draw the Lord of the Lake’s attention
with a Bubble Beam!
Ashimari...
I understand, you’re frightened.
Thank you.
Leave the rest to me!
Suiren!
Stay back!
There’s no way for you to
reel it in on your own-roto!
That’s not true!
Ashimari!
Just a little more!
What?
It’s a Mamanbou!
Mamanbou. Caring Pokémon.
Water type.
It heals its friends’ wounds
with Heal Pulse!
Leave it to me!
Go!
There!
Satoshi, stay calm-roto!
I know!
Suiren, now’s your chance!
Right!
Hang in there,
both of you-roto!
Pikachu, let’s do it!
Now, Pikachu! Electro Ball!
We did it!
We’ve done our part.
Thank you...
I’ll do my best, too!
The Lord of the Lake
is mighty indeed!
It’s a worthy nemesis for me, who has been Fishing Guru
for ninety-nine years and one month!
Good grief-roto.
She’s so close!
Ashimari!
Now, Ashimari!
Aqua Jet?!
You did it!
Yowashi?
This is a big discovery-roto!
The Lord of the Lake was a school of Yowashi!
Its School Form-roto!
T-T-That’s right! I’m impressed
you figured out the answer!
To reel in the Lord of the Lake and
expose its true identity...
For ninety-nine years
and two months, I have-
Even a tiny Yowashi can be really strong
when it starts schooling, huh.
That’s the one from before...
Isn’t that a Water Z-Crystal?!
I can have it?
Thank you for
a fun fishing battle.
It was a good fight!
Ashimari, you were amazing!
You’ve learned Aqua Jet?
All right, thanks for your patience!
Thank you very much...
So cool! It suits you!
Suiren, isn’t that...
Could it be...?
Yes. A Water-Z.
I got it after fishing up
a Mega Gyarados.
Mega Gyarados?!
Just kidding.
After a heated battle with the Lord of the Lake,
Suiren has obtained a Z-Crystal.
What sort of moves will she be showing us
with her Z-Ring in the future?
To be continued!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you for waiting.
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Yowashi!
It’s true!
The Small Fry Pokémon
Yowashi is a Water type.
When in trouble, it gathers its friends
and enters its School Form.
I didn’t expect the Lord of the Lake
to be a School Form Yowashi!
Yowashi with the band-aid...
Thank you for a heated fishing battle!
What’s wrong, Suiren?!
I forgot to get a fish print
of the Lord!
Next episode
It’s a festival!
You can’t have a festival
without food stands!
What should we eat?
Hey, this festival is...
You can’t have a festival without
Tosakinto scooping!
What? You can scoop them up?
With a huge net!
There’s Gyarados-fishing too!
Hey, listen...
All right, let’s go!
Yeah!
This is a sacred festival!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
A Fire Battle! Garagara Appears!!
Next time
A Fire Battle!
Garagara Appears!!