Alola!
I will be the one
presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Burnet
Satoshi
Sauboh
Kojiro
What is the true identity of
the fake Royal Mask who appears today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Royal Mask and Gaogaen
are the winners!
Mad Boobur and Booburn
have once again failed to get their revenge!
Damn it!
I’ll get you for this!
Attention, everyone!
We have been wanting to spread the word
about the Battle Royal’s greatness...
For that reason,
Royal Mask and Gaogaen...
...will be going to each of your towns
for a Meet-and-Greet tour!
What? Really?!
All right!
First stop, Melemele Island!
At the shopping mall
on Melemele Island...
Come shake my hand!
Well then, everyone...
Enjoy!
Another great battle today!
Good work, Gaogaen.
I’m home.
Big news, Kukui!
You have to hear this, Professor!
Royal Mask is coming to
the Melemele Island shopping mall!
O-Oh, I see...
We’re going, right?!
There’s no way
we can miss this, right?!
Um...
There’s no way
this will end well...
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
Kukui Up Against the Wall!
Another Royal Mask!!
You came to see me just for that?
This is no laughing matter for me!
Oh, sorry.
So, let’s see...
You have to accompany
Professor Burnet and Satoshi...
...to Royal Mask’s Meet-and-Greet event
at the Melemele Island shopping mall.
But you are Royal Mask.
Yeah.
Burnet is particularly fired up
about going to meet him together.
I can’t believe she still hasn’t
figured you out...
Well, there have been many times
where I thought my cover was finally blown...
Enjoy!
Food’s done!
Kukui?
Be right there!
You look just like him!
But somehow,
she still hasn’t figured it out...
...and I feel like I’ve
missed my chance to tell her.
Besides...
Royal Mask is super cool!
He’s so strong and kind...
That’s why I really want you
to meet him in person!
A wonderful hero and my husband...
I have two princes in my life, don’t I?
I feel like I’d be crushing her dreams
if I told her...
During the Meet-and-Greet...
When it becomes
Professor Burnet’s turn...
...Royal Mask comes up with
some reason to slip backstage.
I borrow your mask, and come up front
to shake Professor Burnet’s hand.
You watch this by her side.
When that’s over, I go backstage again
and switch places with you.
How does that sound?
That’s perfect, Mullein!
My best friend needs my help.
I’ll roll up my sleeves.
Amazing!
It looks just like
the real Royal Dome!
It’s a Mini-Mini Royal Dome-roto!
Professor Burnet!
Mullein!
What are you doing here?
Kukui couldn’t make it
until the last second, right?
He asked me to accompany you
until he arrives.
He went and asked
you to do that?
You have a kind,
compassionate husband.
L-Let’s get going!
B-Before all the best seats are taken!
Wait!
Let’s get some good seats-roto!
We’re not selling a thing...
Looks like everyone’s too caught up
in the whole Royal Mask thing, meow.
Of course. They’re going to
meet their hero, after all.
Maybe we should just
close up for the day, meow?
Guess I’ll go take a break, then!
Buy me something from the food court
while you’re out, too...
...That was fast!
Gaogaen! Build Up!
DD Lariat!
Royal Mask really is cool!
Yeah!
Nyaheat,
you can’t go up front today.
Keep it up, Royal Mask!
Excuse me? Would you please
quiet down a bit?
You’re the best! So awesome!
Oh, I’m very...
What are you doing here?!
No, that’s what I should be asking!
Th-That T-shirt!
It’s the one that Royal Mask himself
had a hand in producing!
After six months in the design phase
and three months of production time,
it was sold out a mere three minutes after its release!
A super rare item!
Oh, this?
I spent three days in line
to buy it on release!
Wait, how do you know all that?
Does that mean...?
It would seem that
we are kindred spirits.
What, really?
Which match is your favorite?
I thought his match with the Revengers
the other day was really intense!
I know what you mean!
I got to see that match up close...
For real?!
So that was when you got hooked?
Yeah!
Yahoo!
Enjoy!
That’s it for the demonstration!
Now it’s time for the Meet-and-Greet!
Professor Burnet, it’s finally time
for the Meet-and-Greet!
What’s wrong?
What do I do...?
I-I got all nervous...
Heart rate increasing...
I knew this would happen!
That’s why I wanted Kukui to come along!
Professor Kukui is late-roto...
Sheesh! What is he doing?!
Keep it up!
Thank you!
Now then, next up is...
Royal Mask!
Please shake my hand!
Oh, Satoshi!
It’s great to see you!
Thank you!
And that means...
I’m ready.
All right!
And now it’s time for a break!
I’ll be right back!
Everyone, please relax Royally!
Later!
I-I think I’ll take
a Royal break, too!
Oh, come on...
What’s going on?
It would seem that he’s
taking a short break.
If I don’t get back soon,
Musashi will be so mad at me!
Are you in a hurry?
Kinda...
I’d prefer to get this done quickly,
if at all possible...
Actually...
You know Royal Mask?!
Quiet!
Th-That’s incredible!
With that said...
It’s not entirely impossible that maybe we could
sneak past the line and shake his hand backstage...
R-R-Really?
So, if all goes well, we might get
access to his dressing room...
...and maybe even get him to give us
his autograph in the confusion?
Oh, what a splendid idea!
Thank you so much...
I hate to ask this of you.
I told you I’d roll up my sleeves
to help my best friend.
But are you sure
about this, Kukui?
This will mean that Professor Burnet
won’t really get to shake Royal Mask’s hand.
Well then, I’m going to
the dressing room to get changed.
You go be with Professor Burnet.
Oh, right...
Um, now where’s
the dressing room...?
That’s...
Royal Mask’s mask!
Could that be...?!
No, that’s not him.
From what I can gather, it must be just another fan
cosplaying as Royal Mask.
But...
That was the special version he started using
at the single match the other day!
The horns are a bit larger than
they were on the old model...
There’s a bit more space
around his mouth...
The material’s more elastic, more breathable,
and even heat-resistant!
In other words...!
In other words...?
Well, then...
I said I’d roll up my sleeves...
...but I didn’t think
I’d have to take them off.
Enjoy!
W-Well... I’ll manage...
Just gotta put on the mask...
Pocket Monsters...
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Rarecoil
Type:   Electric/Steel
Royal Mask is really late...
Professor Mullein
isn’t back yet, either-roto.
Kukui’s missing, too...
Hey!
Professor Kukui-roto!
You’re late!
So sorry... Where’s Royal Mask?
He went off for a break,
and hasn’t come back since.
I-I see...
Well, it’s always important
to take a break...
He’ll take a break and then come back,
ready for another Royal effort...
Come out, Royal Mask!
I’ve returned from the depths of hell
once more, to defeat you!
Stealing Royal Mask’s
sacred mask...
You deserve
divine punishment!
Indeed!
I will take the utmost care
of this mask!
No, no, I will take the utmost,
most meticulous care of it!
No, I will take the utmost,
most meticulous, perfect care of it!
Oh, no, no, no... I’ll take thrilling, surprising,
astonishing, naturally...
...Royally good care...
Come out, Royal Mask!
Fight me again!
Don’t move, unless you want
that to happen to you!
He’s taken the audience
hostage-roto!
That’s low, Mad Boobur!
Yeah, that’s right!
Can it!
If you get in my way,
I’ll use Booburn’s Fire Punch...
...to smash you and this tent!
Why aren’t you coming,
Royal Mask?!
You lose your nerve?!
Why won’t Royal Mask
come back?
If only I had Gaogaen’s
Monster Ball here, at least...
I can’t believe that Mad Boobur would come
all the way out here just to get revenge for his last loss!
Why isn’t Royal Mask coming?!
Since we have his mask
and Monster Ball,
he can’t help even if he wants to!
Didn’t take you for such a coward,
Royal Mask!
This just proves that I, Mad Boobur,
am the true champion!
Any further insults towards Royal Mask
will not be tolerated!
Wh-Who’s there?!
We’re terribly sorry to have
kept you waiting, everyone!
The star has arrived!
Today’s leading man and
the true Battle Royal champion...
Our hero... Yes, indeed!
It’s Royal Mask!
Enjoy!
Enjoy...
R-Royal Mask?
He seems to have
changed Forme-roto...
There we go...
All right, bring it on,
Mad Boobur!
If you won’t attack, then I will!
Gaogaen!
Now, Gaogaen!
Use DD Lariat!
Dar! Kest! La! Ri! At!
Here it comes!
It’s Gaogaen’s DD Lariat!
Booburn,
use your Fling attack!
Oh, no! Royal Mask!
You and Gaogaen
can’t be down already!
Stand up! On your feet, Royal!
Are you all right?!
I’b dot dode yed...
Sau...
Please, stand up!
What a farce!
You’d bring out that pathetic fake
to get away from me?
Royal Mask really is
just a fraud and a coward!
That’s not true!
Royal Mask is no fraud!
He’s no coward, either!
Royal Mask is...
...the strongest, kindest...
...and coolest man in Alola!
Yeah! Royal Mask
would never lose to you!
He’s right!
That’s right!
Royal! Royal! Royal!
Gaogaen.
Can it! Can it, I say!
He still refuses to show himself!
That proves that he’s a coward!
Wh-What?!
What’s going on?
I’m sorry I took so long, Kukui.
Mullein!
It took a while
to untie the ropes...
“Ropes”?
Never mind that,
just put on the mask!
O-Of course!
You’re...
Sorry I’m late.
I-It’s Royal Mask!
He’s back!
Mad Boobur, I won’t let you
cause any more trouble!
Damn you...
Booburn, Fire Punch!
Burn with passion, Gaogaen!
Set the ring ablaze
with the flames of victory!
Hyper Dark Crusher!
Gaogaen’s Z-Move finishes
the match with style!
Royal Mask wins by a landslide!
Damn it all!
I’ll get you for this!
He did it!
Try again never!
Thank you, everyone!
Enjoy!
Royal Mask, you’re the best!
He’s so freaking cool!
Royal Mask, Sir...
Are you all right?
You’re not hurt, are you?
N-No, Sir!
Thank you for
cheering me on back there.
Everybody!
Let the Meet-and-Greet continue!
All right!
Wait for me!
Professor Kukui!
Where were you-roto?
Um...
W-With Mullein! That’s right!
I was seeing him off!
You mean you didn’t see me
shake hands with Royal Mask?
No... I’m so sor—
Listen up!
Royal Mask said
“Thank you” to me!
As he did,
he reached out his hand, and...
Royal Mask really is...
Kind, strong and cool, right?
Exactly!
Your cheers are the foundation of
my unwavering strength!
Now, shout it out loud...
I love Royal Mask!
Right! My counterattack
begins now!
Huh?
Yahoo!
Enjoy!
Waking up refreshed with the sun, bid everyone a good morning
Relaxing with some milk, gonna have another great day (Happy!)
The Backpacker, the Gentleman, the Swimmer Girl
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Badges we’ve earned are proof of our friendship
Searching for a treasure you can’t see
Flaming, sparkling, hulaing, and fanning, dances in every color
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
When we’ve had a fight, and I’m feeling down
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “I’m sorry about earlier...”,
a smile and a shake, it’s sorted, we’ve made up already
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The fake Royal Mask was really...
...that old geezer, Sauboh!
Mad Boobur’s partner,
Booburn, is a Fire type.
It can blast fireballs burning at 2000 degrees
from the tips of its arms,
but apparently it hurts its own arms
if it fires a whole barrage.
But man, Royal Mask
really is unbeatable!
Come on over!
Have some of the Honey Doughnuts
that even Royal Mask loves!
What’s gotten into Kojiro?
He’s been all pumped up ever since
he came back from his break, meow.
Yahoo!
Next episode
I, the genie in the lamp,
will grant you three wishes!
I wanna be a Pokémon Master!
I want to fish up Kaiogre!
I want to befriend
even more Pokémon!
I want to make Aina Cafeteria bigger!
I want to eat
an unlimited supply of ice cream!
I said “three,“ didn’t I?!
And anyway, practice the play!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Liliel the Hero and the Scepter of Alola!
Next time