Alola!
I, Lilie, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem!
Eevee
Buoysel
Xerneas
Azumao
Which of these is the Pokémon Ilima,
today’s featured character, has with him?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Dodge, please!
Go! Take Down!
Speed Star!
You’re good.
I’m flattered.
This is what I’ve trained for.
Take this with you!
It’s finally ours, Eevee.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Ilima and Eevee Make
Their Ilimappearance!!
The sun shines brightly over the Pokémon School
as Satoshi and his friends practice their moves.
Nyaheat, use Nitro Charge!
Bakugames, use Dragon Tail!
All right, that’s enough!
That was great, Bakugames.
You did your best, Nyaheat.
What a surprise.
Before, Nyabby would
have gotten pushed back.
Evolution is amazing!
Yeah!
I wonder whose Pokémon
will evolve next?
It might be a bit hard for you.
Satoshi, you’re not
going to have Pikachu evolve?
Good point.
Pikachu evolves into Raichu,
doesn’t it?
Think he’d turn Alolan
if he evolved here?
Pikachu is fine the way he is.
The way he is?
We’ve made up our minds.
Right, Pikachu?
Sir Ilima!
Alola, Professor Kukui!
Who’s that?
That’s Ilima. He’s a graduate
from this school.
Well this is a surprise.
When did you come back, Ilima?
This morning. I had a few things
I needed to take care of.
Pardon me,
I should have said hello sooner.
I see. Principal Okido will
be happy to see you, too!
All right, that’s enough for today.
Class dismissed!
All right!
He seems quite popular.
He’s special.
They call him the
Pokémon School’s prince!
Prince, is it?
He’s amazing!
There are legends about him!
They say he’s the smartest student
the school’s ever produced,
and that he skipped grades to
graduate in a flash!
Or how he wanted to learn more,
so now he’s studying abroad in the Kalos Region!
Or how half the trophies in the Principal’s office
were won by Ilima!
Really?
Or how he has a fanclub in the school
who were so desperate to get him a birthday present,
that Ms. Junsa had to come
and regulate traffic!
Or that withered flowers he touches
will come back to life...
That he jumped from the top of
the tree in the schoolyard...
That he’s so beloved by Pokémon that
even Nekkoala opened its eyes just to see him...
Nekkoala?!
Awesome!
That would be the discovery of the century,
worthy of being recorded in the Index-roto!
I gotta see that!
Me, too-roto!
But I’m sure Ilima must be busy.
What if Nekkoala has
eyes like a Gonyonyo?
Its eyes might be
like a Dorobanko-roto!
Um... Is there any possibility
its eyes might sparkle like Purin’s...?
That would be great, too!
I need to know!
These Miare Galettes are
absolutely super! Raikou! Entei! Suikun!
I’m glad you liked my souvenir.
So, how is life in Kalos?
There are many strong trainers
in the Kalos League,
who sharpen their skills
through intense battles.
It’s truly stimulating and enjoyable!
I knew it’d be like that!
You know, Ilima,
I’d like to show the people of this region
how fun the Pokémon League is, someday.
Meaning...?
I’m going to form
a Pokémon League here in Alola, too.
Well, not right away, but...
When the time comes, I’d like you to participate,
since you have experience with the League.
But of course!
Please let me know when it’s time.
Thank you!
I’m sure the others will be happy too.
Professor!
Speak of the devil...
What brings you all here?
We wanted to ask Ilima something.
Please show us your legends!
All right...
Eevee. Evolution Pokémon.
Normal type.
It conceals many possible evolutions.
So, what would you like to see?
Nekkoala, of course!
Nekkoala?
Go ahead. It’s a reunion
long in the making, right?
It went to him on its own!
We can expect great things
from this-roto!
Recording mode on!
Long time no see, Nekkoala.
It’s working!
What, that’s it?
It did respond just now, though!
I won’t give up-roto!
I will get the scoop of the century-roto!
Pull yourself together-roto!
Ilima is right here-roto!
So it came at us, like, “Wham!”
but then we dodged, like “Whoosh!” and then “Slam!”
Yer as cool as ever, Bro!
So?
It was just like ya said, Bro!
That super-pretentious-lookin’ jerk
was at the Pokémon School!
I see. He was the talk of the town.
That creep still insists on
standin’ out wherever he goes!
Bro, ya know that
pretentious jerk?
He stole somethin’
super precious from me!
I can’t ever forgive’im for that!
Somethin’ super precious?!
Seriously, what a villain!
You two! Get word out
to our buddies, right now!
Roger that, Bro!
I see. I didn’t know there were such
grand legends about me.
We just had to know.
Rumors certainly do tend
to grow out of control.
Then Nekkoala...
It’s always been sleeping.
I thought it seemed strange.
I mean, him jumping from
the top of the school’s tree?
Oh, that’s partially true.
What?! Really?!
I didn’t know this was a PokéDive spot.
PokéDive?
Yeah.
It’s a water sport where people and Pokémon
dive from the board together.
Simplicity is best!
You should simply
enjoy diving with your partner.
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Feels great!
Satoshi will be diving from here!
You’re starting from that high up?!
Go, go!
Here we go!
Satoshi!
I’ll show you how it’s done!
You’re diving with Garagara?
Of course! Let’s go, Garagara!
Figures...
Huh? Garagara? Huh?
All right! What next?
Here we go!
Special Move: Mid-Air Flip Dive!
Twirling Dive!
Then let us try too.
Nice try!
Imitating Kapu-Kokeko!
Massivoon!
You’ve made good progress,
everyone.
I want to see you jump, Ilima!
Agreed!
I really wanna see it!
Well, if you insist...
Here I come!
He’s starting with a handstand?!
Ilima’s jump was amazing!
You and Eevee were in perfect sync!
We’ve been friends for a long time,
after all.
But I’m sure you’d get even better if
you evolved it into Showers or something...
Why do you keep it as an Eevee?
It’s true, evolving a Pokémon is
one way to make it stronger...
but it’s not the only one.
Eevee possesses incredible power,
even as it is.
A Z-Ring!
I don’t know this crystal...
I read about this in a book!
Is this not the Z-Crystal that
only Eevee can use?!
Yes. One of the reasons I came back
was because I wanted to get this Eevee-Z.
I want to make Eevee much stronger,
while keeping it as an Eevee.
As an Eevee...
Just like me and Pikachu!
I’ve decided to make Pikachu strong
while keeping him as a Pikachu!
So Pikachu and I are on
the Island Pilgrimage,
and challenging ourselves
with Z-Moves and stuff!
You, too?
I wanna see Eevee’s Z-Move!
So if you don’t mind,
please battle me!
Very well. I accept your challenge!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Eevee
Type:   Normal
Satoshi is amazing!
I can’t believe he’d battle Ilima!
This is so exciting!
Sir Ilima!
Look this way!
Go, go! Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Amazing...
All right, then let’s all
cheer Satoshi on!
You can do it!
Go, go! Let’s go, Satoshi!
Thanks!
Well then, shall we begin?
Here we go, Eevee!
It’s all on you, Pikachu!
This is a sacred learning institution.
I cannot allow outsiders to enter.
Whatever business you have,
I, Ilima, will deal with it.
He’s as pretentious as he looks!
He’s just oozing with unpleasantness!
Perfect. I came here because
I had business with you.
How lame, Ilima.
Ya still ain’t evolved that Eevee?
The Normal type is way too plain!
Bro’s Pokémon is way cooler!
The Fire/Poison-type Yatoumori...
He’s got plenty of battle experience, so here’s the facts:
He’s gonna evolve any day now!
It’s finally time to—
Um, pardon me,
but who might you be?
Ya dun’ remember?!
How could ya?! Ya stole somethin’ super precious
from Bro, and ya forgot?!
I stole something from you?
Yeah, that’s right!
You stole the irreplaceable...
...springtime of my life!
Tupper!
What’s up?
Amazing, you already
have a Pokémon!
Nah, it’s nothing special!
Ilima, what’s that?
It’s my Eevee.
Oh my gosh! It’s mega cute!
In that case, I’ll fight with my own innate appeal!
I can be popular with the chicks, too!
Hey, babes!
Wanna have some tea with me?
Oh my gosh! He’s so cool!
Yeah, I’m such a stud!
Ilima!
Ilima! Because of you, the springtime of my life
came to a swift end!
How is that his fault?!
Shut it!
It’s all his fault!
With him goin’ around being a stud all the time,
the rest of us never got a chance to be popular!
I sincerely apologize for that.
Don’t apologize!
Man, you piss me off!
I’ve decided that I’m gonna
take back the springtime of my life!
These guys’re my buddies who
share my pain!
Yeah, yeah!
Gimme my
springtime of life!
I hate studs!
Ilima! The time has come
for me to knock ya out...
and make all the girls go
“Oh my gosh, Ilima is so freakin’ lame”!
Of course,
we gonna help Bro out, too!
Let’s go, y’all!
Yeah!
Let’s do this, too!
There!
This is crazy!
Ilima, we’ll fight, too!
Please stand back.
I’m the one they’re after.
Oh, he’s so cool!
Man, he makes me sick!
Down with the hot guy!
Get ‘im, guys!
Got it!
Go!
Go, go, Sir Ilima!
You can do it, Sir Ilima!
Here we come.
Eevee, Lightning Speed!
Yer wastin’ time! We’ll beat ya down
with our overwhelmin’ strength in numbers!
Eevee! Baby-Doll Eyes!
So cute!
Now, Speed Star!
No mercy?
Our strength in numbers
just got cut in half?!
Don’t give up!
We still outnumber ‘im!
That stinkin’ Eevee ain’t gonna beat us!
Come out, Yatoumori!
Zubat!
Dustdas, use Venom Shock!
Eevee, get some distance from them!
Wing Attack!
Dodge, please!
Now! Flame Burst!
Eevee!
Sir Ilima!
I’ve finally won!
Spring will come to my life!
Ya did it, Bro!
I knew ya could!
Um...
I hate to interrupt you when
you’re so excited, but...
The battle is not yet over.
No way...
It’s doing perfectly fine?!
The Normal type might not be very flashy,
but it has a great advantage:
it has very few weaknesses.
It becomes more reliable the more you train it...
Truly, simplicity is best!
What will ya do, Bro?
Why wouldya even hafta ask?!
I can’t lose to this guy!
Yeah!
You’re quite determined, I see.
In that case, it is only proper
that we respond with our full power.
Allow me to show you
the special Z-Move that only Eevee can use.
Special Z-Move?
Come here, friends!
Now, cross the land and sky,
to share your power
with my Eevee.
Nine Evol Boost!
What?
Those are...!
Eevee?
No-roto!
Blacky, Eefee, Leafea, Nymphia,
Glacia, Booster, Thunders!
And add in Showers, too-roto!
So pretty!
Hey, what was that?!
Eevee’s friends have
boosted all of its abilities.
Eevee is now far stronger
than it was before.
Well then, shall we continue?
Huh? What’s this I feel?
That Z-Move is no fair!
So cute! So cool!
That full power pose
was so good!
Bro, this is bad! Wrap and the others
are completely lovestruck!
What?!
That’s against the rules, Ilima!
Numbers were all we had,
and then you go relyin’ on
strength in numbers against us?!
That’s not really what this is, but...
Well then, it’s time for a last-ditch effort!
Let’s go, Zip!
You got it, Bro!
Down with the hot guy!
Yatoumori, use Flame Burst!
Dustdas, use Venom Shock!
Eevee, use Last Resort!
See you later, Sir Ilima!
Sir Ilima, you’re the best!
Ilima, Eevee’s Z-Move was amazing!
I’m flattered.
I suppose we’ll have to postpone our match
to some other time, Satoshi.
There’s more than one way to
make a Pokémon strong, huh?
Pokémon are creatures who possess
immeasurable potential.
We and our partners ought only to pursue
whatever heights we most believe in, yes?
Yes!
Satoshi and the others have
witnessed a fragment of Ilima’s legend.
Ilima and Satoshi’s story
continues next time!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thank you for waiting.
The Pokémon Ilima
brought along with him was Eevee.
The Evolution Pokémon Eevee
is a Normal type.
Possessing an unbalanced and unstable genetic makeup,
Eevee is a Pokémon who conceals many possible evolutions.
Despite that,
Ilima won’t evolve his Eevee...
His dedication to the Normal type
is wonderful!
Simplicity is best
when it comes to pancakes, too!
I’m flattered.
Next episode
Starting today,
I’m in the Racket Gang.
Racket Gang?
Championing the ace of truth and love!
The lovely, charming Racket Gang!
What’s going on, meow?
I’m joining a Pokémon
Ping-Pong tournament!
Huh? Then I’m joining, too!
Huh? Then me, too!
No. I’m joining with Sonansu!
Sonami, are you ready?
Musashi,
aim to become the Serve Ace!
Yes, coach!
What even is this feeling?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Smashing with Sketch! The Fierce Poké-Ping Pong Match!
Next time
Smashing with Sketch!
The Fierce Poké-Ping Pong Match!