Alola!
I, Suiren, will be giving
today’s PokéProblem.
Ms. Aina Cafeteria
Maomao
Maorin
Chatterbox
What nickname did I give Mao
when we were younger?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s another peaceful noon in Alola.
Everyone’s enjoying their lunch together.
Delicious!
I’ll help you out if you can’t finish it all.
I’m perfectly fine, thanks.
Oh yeah...
Yesterday, the moment I looked away,
Ho and Sui ran off somewhere.
Oh, my...
Oh, it’s all right.
We found them by nightfall.
Sheesh! Where were you two?
In the forest!
What?! What if you got lost in—
Yup! We sure got lost!
Lost! Lost!
Huh? But then...
And then we met this huge Pokémon!
He was this big!
He helped us!
We got these!
A Pokémon helped Ho and Sui?
Awesome!
Those berries were red,
about this big,
and smelled really nice.
Rotom, do you know?
Leave it to me-roto!
Calculating... Calculating...
Calculating...
If it was red,
it must be one of these-roto.
This one.
Isn’t this...?
Oh, a Haban Berry.
You remember, Mao?
Of course I do!
Then, Ho and Sui met...
The Forest Grampa!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Mao and Suiren,
Bittersweet Memories!
You see,
back when Suiren and I were little,
we got lost in the forest, too.
But a huge Pokémon helped us.
Just like what happened
to Ho and Sui.
How mysterious.
Hey, what kind of Pokémon was it?
I want to know, too-roto!
Well, I don’t really
remember it that well...
Roto?!
Have you not met him again
since then?
No. Suiren and I went looking for him
many times, but...
We never managed to find him.
As time went on,
we started to forget...
I see.
I wonder if we could meet him now?
Suiren...
He helped Ho and Sui, too.
I want to thank him!
Me, too!
Then let’s go looking today!
I want to meet him, too!
Me, too-roto!
We just heard something great, meow.
A Pokémon the local brat girls
were never able to find, huh?
Doesn’t that mean it’s crazy rare?
If we gave Sakaki a Pokémon like that...
You’re so clever, Nyarth!
Pet me more! More, meow!
All right!
We’re finally getting a promotion!
Special bonus! Special bonus!
I’m sure that’s
what’ll happen, meow!
Sounds great!
Sounds fabulous! Let’s do it!
We’re definitely gonna
get that Pokémon!
First, let’s tail the brat boy and friends,
and find out who the Pokémon is!
All right, let’s do this!
What a shame...
I wish we could all have
gone together.
Sorry! I’m supposed to go with Dad
to a Denjimushi Car Club event today!
I had promised to
go shopping with Mother.
I have to help out at the farm.
Well, it was on really short notice.
Yeah.
But I hope I get to meet
the Forest Grampa.
We will meet him!
Suiren, you’re on fire!
That was the day
Suiren and I first met.
Good day!
I’ve come to make a delivery.
Sorry for the trouble.
Oh, not at all.
I had to go out, anyway.
What’re you doing?
I’m Mao, from the Aina Cafeteria!
Nice to meet you! Who are you?
Suiren...
Let’s go!
Dad, I’m gonna go play with Suiren!
Sure!
Don’t go too far!
This way! This way!
Here we are!
This is my favorite spot!
There! A bracelet!
It’s lovely, Ms. Aina Cafeteria!
No, call me Mao!
M-M...
Let’s chase it!
All right!
Aburibbon!
This?
It looks great on you!
Pollen Puffs!
Pollen?
They’re delicious!
Let’s have some!
Sure.
So sweet!
Delicious, right?
I see, so you guys bonded
over Pollen Puffs.
I’d like to try some too.
They taste amazing.
Nice, meow.
Sounds delicious, meow.
I wanna have some, too...
Let’s see...
Seems like it’s nutritious and
really, really good for you.
All right!
Hey, you!
Give me one of those Pollen Puffs!
Thank you!
All right! I got a snack!
Oh, nice, meow.
No fair.
Musashi?
It looks like it can use Puffs
offensively, too.
Why didn’t you say so sooner?
Look! Isn’t this the place?
Yeah! We found it!
Wasn’t this where we met
the Forest Grampa?
Ms. Aina Cafeteria...
Dad told me that
if I run into an unknown Pokémon...
I should run away, but carefully...
Right...
What?
Oh, I see.
It was a pretty terrifying
first meeting, right?
Yeah. It’s all coming back to me.
This is my chance to shine-roto!
If you tell me its characteristics,
I can guess which Pokémon it is right away-roto!
Oh! Rotom, you’re great!
Heh-roto!
Oh, my. Seems the talking Index
actually has its uses.
All right! Counting on you, Rotom!
What Pokémon is it, meow?
Leave it to me-roto!
Now, let’s hear it-roto!
Um... It really did look
like a grandfather.
Grandfather...
It was green.
White, too.
Can you believe it?
I already worked it out-roto!
What? Really?!
But of course! From the information you gave me,
I have arrived at this...
Awesome!
I haven’t even
said anything yet-roto!
Sorry, sorry... It just slipped out.
Keep going.
From the information you gave me,
I have arrived at this...
Yukinooh-roto!
This one, huh?!
Wrong.
Why-roto?! There’s an over 90% chance
that this is it-roto!
But it’s not.
I-If this goes on, my pride as an Index Rotom
will be in shambles...
I swear I’ll get it right next time-roto!
Now, tell me more characteristics-roto!
Easy for you to say...
Suiren, what happened
after that, again?
We were lost deep in the forest.
Oh, yeah! We were so scared...
...that we ran away at full speed, right?
When we stopped,
we didn’t know where we were.
Where are we?
I don’t know.
Of course not...
This is your first time...
I’m sorry.
This is all my fault for wanting to play.
It’s not...
What do we do?
What if we can’t get home?
Ma...
Hey...
Look.
Do you think we can eat these?
I dunno...
I’ve never seen these before!
Smells nice...
All right.
These are delicious! Try one!
Huh? Really?
It’s bitter! Suiren, you liar!
I’m sorry. But I’m glad.
About what?!
You stopped crying, Mao.
You’re right...
You just called me Mao, right?
Hey, say my name again!
Huh?
It’s not as bitter as last time.
You’re right. It’s getting sweeter!
Then they’re Bittersweet Berries!
Yeah, Bittersweet Berries!
I’ve been here before!
Now we can get back!
Yeah!
Thanks to the Bittersweet Berries!
Thank you,
Bittersweet Berries.
Wait, Bittersweet Berries!
You rode on his back?! Awesome!
Yep. That was a close call.
Yeah, we really were in trouble.
Lucky you...
I got it-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Jijilong
Type:   Normal/Dragon
Jijilong. Placid Pokémon.
Normal/Dragon type.
It is commonly found on tall mountains.
Its favorite food is berries.
It loves playing with human children.
Forest Grampa!
That’s him! You’re amazing, Rotom!
Heh-roto!
I’m sure we can find him,
now that we know his species!
Let’s search for Jijilong!
Yeah!
Come along, all of you!
Good grief... I was getting worried,
but they finally figured out what it was.
Jijilong, huh?
I want to ride its back!
Were you seriously moved
by the brat girls’ story?
You’re not a kid!
That’s it, meow!
I just came up with
an awesome plan, meow!
So, where is Jijilong?
Jijilong loves berries-roto.
That might be a hint-roto.
Maybe there?
The place where
we played a lot with Grampa!
Is this a Pokémon home?
Bittersweet Berries!
These came rolling earlier, too.
Wait, were you...
...watching us the whole time?
How weird.
Maybe Grampa is playing with us?
Grampa?
Yeah! Forest Grampa!
So fluffy!
So smooth!
There were lots of
Bittersweet trees there!
Yeah. It was a lot more open
than where we are now.
That’s gotta be the place!
What’s up, Pikachu?
Ashimari?
They might have found something.
These are Bittersweet trees!
Does that mean this is the place?
It feels familiar...
Kinda...
Forest Grampa!
Jijilong!
Shtop right dere!
Huh? What?
If asked “Huh? What?”...
Let ush tell you ouw names!
Naïve, innocent and pure of heart.
A girl who loves dolls and playing house!
Musashi!
Reckless and thoughtless.
A mischievous little boy!
Kojiro!
Crying at night,
only thinking of himself.
A baby who loves milk and napping!
Nyarth!
The Kid Team Rocket ish here!
We won’t let you have Jijilong!
You bwats go ovuh dere!
Hey, Mr. Jiji!
We wanna pway with you too!
Well to be pewfectly honest,
we want you to join us, pwetty pwease?
It’s an innocent bunch
of kids’ wish, meow.
No, pwease, wait!
Hey, Nyarth! Wasn’t the idea behind this whole
“pretending to be kids” plan...
...that this thing loves kids?!
Dis ish vewwy stwange, meow...
But I planned for
every possible outcome...
Ker-thwack! Whirr, whirr, whirr!
Whirr! Spark!
Wham!
Jijilong!
Oh! Isn’t that the
No-Playing-Mean-Launcher I invented?!
Yay! I’ve had my milk, too!
What a great feeling!
Now Gwampa is ouws!
How could they?!
Unforgivable!
Pikachu, save Jijilong!
Huh? It got out easily...
No playing mean! You know...?
What even is this feeling?
Do you remember us?
Forest Grampa...
It’s been so long!
I’ve missed you!
I’m... I’m...
...so glad to meet you!
Jijilong!
Thank you, Forest Grampa.
You helped Ho and Sui yesterday.
And way back then,
you helped us, too.
Hey, everybody!
I wanna try one of these, too.
Bittersweet Berries!
Let’s have some, Mao!
Yeah!
All right. Pikachu, here’s one for you.
Following memories thought forgotten,
Mao and Suiren got to meet Jijilong again.
After all this time, will the Haban Berries
taste as they remembered them?
Time to eat!
Bitter...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
I used to call Mao
“Ms. Aina Cafeteria.”
The Placid Pokémon Jijilong
is a Normal/Dragon type.
Jijilong gets along great with people
and loves to play with children...
So the nickname “Forest Grampa”
fits it perfectly!
By the way, the female of the species
is called Babalong!
Just kidding, sorry.
No, it was more like this!
What? No, that’s not it!
All done!
Well?
Yeah, it’s great!
Next episode
Hey! What would you wanna do
if it started snowing?
Snowball fight!
Go skiing!
Go sledding!
Sit under the kotatsu!
Maybe we can make a snowy mountain
with Snowball’s Powder Snow!
This might be enough for
some shaved ice, I guess?
Here, have some syrup!
You were carrying that around?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Lilie’s Flying High!
The PokéSled Jump Tournament!
Next time
Lilie's Flying High!
The PokéSled Jump Tournament!