Alola!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Which Ultra Beast appears
in today’s episode?
Kamitsurugi
Massivoon
Tekkaguya
Akujiking
Blue: Kamitsurugi?
Red: Massivoon?
Green: Tekkaguya?
Or Yellow: Akujiking?
Get the answer at the end!
The stars shine brightly over Melemele Island,
where Satoshi and his friends live.
What’s that?
Yeah!
Now dat th’ Bourgain Stadium’s
finally complete,
we gotta practice fer
da openin’ ceremony!
After my super flashy
mic performance,
th’ countdown starts fer
th’ most high-class fireworks!
Den, above my most high-class
gold shiny Bourgain statue,
we’ll make th’ most high-class flowers
bloom in da night sky!
Got it?
Yeah!
Den here goes!
Three...
Two...
One!
Great, y’all! Den, once th’
most high-class flowers bloom,
da customers’ll be
in a spendin’ mood,
an’ I’ll make a killin’!
What a show!
Tcejbo sselhtrow a tuc evah i.
Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno. Tuc evah i.
M-My most high-class
gold shiny Bourgain statue!
What do we do?!
Today is the day the Nuikoguma Meteor Shower
approaches the Earth.
Who will you all be
watching it with?
Now it’s time for a song:
Wakamina 42’s “Shooting Star.”
All right,
first I’ll slice the cabbage...
Mao.
Could you turn off
the heat on the boiler?
Sure!
Check the taste, too.
Of course.
Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno.
Tcejbo sselhtrow a. Niaga ecno.
Dad, did you do this?
Slice the cabbage.
No.
I’ll see you after school,
Magearna.
Oh... Are you tending
to the garden?
Indeed.
I thought to trim the trees’ leaves...
...to resemble various Pokémon.
Oh, my!
I look forward to seeing it!
Tuc evah i. Tcejbo sselhtrow a.
A. Niaga ecno.
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
You’ve gotten a lot tanner since we first met
And your clothes are a bit dirtier, but that’s the best look for you
Look, the tears of frustration you’ve hidden beneath your cap
will be dried up by the sun in no time
Learning until you’re all worn out,
playing until nightfall,
go on, chase after the Rainbow Feather
You were the one who taught us
how important it is to speak our dreams out loud
Don’t fear things you’ve never seen or done
Now run, future hero, and feel the Tailwind at your back!
Never forget your dreams
With your backpack full of stuff, you’re ready to go
It’s your adventure which nobody else can picture
Step forward!
A Perfect Cutting Edge!
Kamitsurugi Arrives!!
Alola!
Today’s lesson will be on...
...using Pokémon moves
to cut objects.
Really? Sounds fun!
Is that a makiwara-roto?
Oh, you know of them?
In Alolan Detective Laki
season 3 episode 4,
the sword master Nogawa
was cutting one-roto!
Of course that’s
where you learned of it...
They can be used to test
a sword’s cutting edge,
so I thought I’d have you strike them
with your Pokémon’s moves.
Right here! Let me try!
Okay, Satoshi goes first.
All right! Now, if it’s
cutting moves you want...
I choose you!
Wake up, Mokuroh!
Mokuroh!
Use Leaf Cutter on that thing!
I’m next.
Amajo! Magical Leaf!
Didn’t cut it at all.
Sturdy.
Now it’s my turn!
Let’s go, Lizardon!
Use Slash!
What?!
It’s tough, right? Even master swordsmen
have trouble cutting down makiwara.
That just gets me
even more pumped up!
All right! Now let’s try with
Pikachu’s Iron Tail!
When...
Lizardon, did you do that?
Professor Kukui. Something similar
happened to me this morning.
The trees in my yard
changed shape in an instant!
Oh, yeah... A cabbage was sliced up,
and I have no idea who did it.
What’s going on, Professor?
An emergency dispatch order...
...for the Ultra Guardians!
They’re multiplying!
Alola, Ultra Guardians.
Alola!
First off,
have a look at this footage.
This is your target this time.
Could that be what
cut the makiwara?
And the trees in my yard?
And the cabbage?
We’ve received reports of
several other things being sliced, as well.
What’s its name-roto?
We’ve named it Kamitsurugi.
Kamitsurugi. Drawn Sword Pokémon.
Grass/Steel type.
Its body, which is as thin as paper,
is like a sharpened sword that can cut anything.
We don’t know
where Kamitsurugi came from.
Surely it must have come
from an Ultra Hole?
But we’ve detected no signs of
an Ultra Hole opening.
We did detect a strong Ultra Aura
for just a moment, however.
We’re still investigating.
For now, we need to
prevent further damage,
so you have to apprehend it.
Ultra Guardians, move out!
Ult-Roger!
Let’s split up and search.
Oh, my!
What’s wrong, Ms. Moani?
Look at this!
How did this happen?
It must have been Kamitsurugi.
It might still be nearby-roto!
Now, the expert hair stylist,
Scissors Yoko...
...will present the most cutting-edge
Pokémon hair fashion!
Scissors!
Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno. Tcejbo sselhrow.
Tuc evah i. Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno.
Mythical?!
The Trimmien’s fur?
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Tuc. Tuc evah i.
Name: Kamitsurugi
Type:   Grass/Steel
Bourgain Shopping!
President, what sort of wonderful item
will you be presenting today?
I got a special presentation fer
y’all watchin’ on yer TVs right now...
I, th’ most high-class man,
have used th’ most high-class alloy ta develop...
...th’ most high-class
Bling Bling Gold Safe!
Amazing! It’s shining!
Da sellin’ point o’ dis ‘ere safe’s
gotta be its sturdiness! Feast yer eyes!
Elecible!
Give it a Thunder Punch!
Goronda!
Give it a Fire Punch!
How’s dat?
Whatever shock it may take,
dis most high-class safe’ll
keep yer valuables 100% secure!
100% secure...
High-class gold safe, is it?
How tacky, meow.
Th’ most high-class Bling Bling Gold Safe,
made from th’ most high-class alloy...
Buy now, an’ ye’ll get dese portraits o’
my most high-class naturally toned body as a free bonus!
Niaga ecno. Tcejbo sselht. Niaga ecno.
Tuc evah i tuc evah. Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno.
What?
What’s yer deal?! Wait, was it ya who
sliced up my Bourgain statue yesterday?
I ain’t lettin’ dat slide!
There’s something there, meow!
Is that a Pokémon?
I smell a mega rare!
Let’s catch it and
offer it up to Sakaki!
We were just informed that
Kamitsurugi is at Bourgain Tower.
Investigate at once!
Ult-Roger!
Let’s go!
Hurry-roto!
Niaga ecno. Tcejbo. Tce.
Tuc evah i tuc evah. Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno.
Where’s Kamitsurugi?
Inside the tower.
There it is!
So tiny!
Wait, Kamitsurugi!
If it’s in the city,
it’ll put people in danger!
Let’s lead it to the mountain!
Ult-Roger!
The Pokémon School
is that way!
Stop, Kamitsurugi!
You might not understand this,
but in this world, there are things
that we don’t want cut!
Did it understand me?
We’re going to send you back
to your own world.
Could you stay
in this Ultra Ball for a while?
Here I go!
Niaga ecno. Niaga ecno. Tcejbo sselhtrow.
Tcejbo. Tuc evah i niaga ecno.
I guess we have to battle it.
Leave it to me.
Let’s go, Garagara!
You could cut the tension with a knife.
It’s like watching
sword master Nogawa-roto!
Flare Drive!
Tuc. Niaga ecno. Tcejbo sselhtrow
a tuc evah i niaga ecno. Niaga ecno.
So strong!
Out of the way!
The Pokémon that cuts anything...
...belongs to us, meow!
There you are, Team Rocket!
When you say
“There you are, Team Rocket!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Fighting fair and square,
cutting everything!
My lips are a red, red rose!
Musashi!
The ultimate, legendary,
double-edged blade!
The apostle of love,
reflecting his prey deep in his evil eyes!
Kojiro!
Cutting cakes clean in half!
A shooting star of evil
in the sky!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Wh-What’s going on?!
Tcejbo sselhtrow a. Tuc.
Tuc evah i niaga ecno.
What?!
Everyone, abort mission!
A Nuikoguma Meteor Shower comet
has changed course...
...and is plummeting
towards the Earth!
Where will it impact?
We’re calculating it right now.
I got it!
The Pokémon School!
We’ll issue an emergency evacuation order for
everyone within a kilometer of the Pokémon School!
Hey, everyone!
The other students were all evacuated
at Lightning Speed.
Run for it, you alLucario!
But I can’t let anything happen
to the Pokémon school!
Nor me.
Me neither.
Same for me!
Indeed.
I’m glad you feel that way, but...
They’re arguing about something.
Hey, what’s that?
A plane?
A shooting star of evil
in the sky, meow!
What even is this feeling?
Let’s go!
Ult-Roger!
Hey, wait, everyone!
Looks like it’s too hot
for us to get close. What do we do?
We have Tyltalis’s Ice Beam
and Snowball’s Powder Snow.
Hakuryu’s Ice Beam, too.
Excellent idea-roto!
If we rapidly cool down the meteor,
it should become brittle-roto!
Then first we’ll cool it down...
Then we’ll get close...
And smash it!
Got it!
Well then, here we go.
Yeah!
Tyltalis, use Ice Beam!
Snowball, use Powder Snow!
Hakuryu! Ice Beam!
Let’s go, Mokuroh!
Use Leaf Cutter!
Amajo! Magical Leaf!
Lizardon, use Slash!
Metang! Metal Claw!
Oh, no!
We won’t make it!
Yeh. Yeh.
Kamitsurugi?!
Em ot ti evael. Em ot ti evael.
Are you...?!
Eof. Yhtrow, yhtrow a. A.
Awesome!
All right!
Tahw-w?! Tahw?!
Kamitsurugi, even you
can’t cut the rainbow.
Are you all safe?
Yes!
What a relief...
Sheesh...
That was far too dangerous!
But you did well, everyone.
Yhw! Yhw!
It’s an Ultra Hole-roto!
Did it... cut a hole in space?
And then an Ultra Hole
appeared in the rift...
I see.
Kamitsurugi must have cut through space
when it came here, too.
So that’s why we detected
that strong Ultra Aura for just a moment.
I see.
Kamitsurugi!
Thank you!
You are the hero of Alola!
Come visit again sometime!
Kamitsurugi and the Ultra Guardians
have saved the Pokémon School.
If sometime you find something sliced in two
for seemingly no reason,
it might be Kamitsurugi’s doing!
Niaga teem su tel. Tel.
Damp from the morning rain, the rice field paths soak up the sunlight
Gazing on the clear blue sky, we remember the days we shared
The moon is melted by sunrise, as the clock marks the new day
I, too, must go out into the future we’ve sought
Open a blank notebook in your heart
Write down your dreams on the first page, your memories on the last
You are on a great journey, a life that lives on today
I can hear a warm voice calling out to me
Thanks for waiting!
The Ultra Beast was Blue: Kamitsurugi!
The Drawn Sword Pokémon Kamitsurugi
is a Grass/Steel type.
It doesn't seem to
attack enemies on its own.
Thank you for
saving Alola, Kamitsurugi!
We just have to connect the two halves,
and it’s fixed, yeah?
Yeah. It’ll be a piece of cake!
Let’s get right to work, meow!
Next episode
Professor! Let’s play catch!
All right!
Give it your full power!
Here I go!
This is my full power!
A Monster Ball?!
Mokuroh?!
Nice catch!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Satoshi — A Timeless Encounter!
Professor,
you gotta throw the ball back!
Throw Mokuroh back?!
Just kidding!
Next time
Satoshi — A Timeless Encounter!