I’m Lilie. Alola!
I shall be presenting today’s PokéProblem.
Cottonball
Snowball
Sugar
Winter
What do I name the newly hatched Rokon?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
O-Oh, no!
It’s hatched!
Snowball!
I’m so glad you hatched safely.
Lilie, don’t tell me...
You can’t touch her?
Even though you could
when she was an egg...
It’s not that I’m afraid...
But I...
Everyone!
This is quite the spectaCleffy!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
The Proof of Courage:
Lilie and Rokon!
The egg found on Lanakila Mountain
has finally hatched!
And the egg Satoshi brought from Kanto
seems ready to hatch, as well!
What kind of Pokémon
will it become...?
Rokon! That’s a Rokon!
They were both Rokon eggs?
I figured they were both
about ready to hatch,
but I didn’t expect them to
hatch on the same day.
A wondrous sight to sEevee!
I’ve never seen a Pokémon egg hatch before!
And I got to see two, at that!
I’m so moved!
A new life’s birth
is such a miracle!
This is the Rokon I know.
Is the white one its Alolan form?
Leave it to me-roto!
Rokon: Alolan Form.
Fox Pokémon. Ice type.
It’s covered by a coat of white fur.
It was discovered on Lanakila Mountain.
It exhales air colder than -50 degrees,
which it uses to freeze all manner of things.
And this one is a Fire type.
As each tail grows,
its fur becomes more lustrous.
Wow, they’re even different types?
One’s Ice, the other is Fire!
You don’t see red Rokon often!
I will gather data on both-roto!
Nice to meet you, Rokon.
I’m Satoshi! Let’s be friends!
Satoshi?!
I see... That was Powder Snow.
Hot!
What are you doing?!
I got burnt-roto!
A-Are you all right?
You got to experience its -50 degree breath right away...
Ember, too, as a bonus.
Of course she’d get startled
if you try to touch her out of nowhere.
Oh, yeah, I guess.
They’re both Rokon, but they seem to have
quite different personalities.
They’re saying they
want to be friends with you.
Friendship is a beautiful thing.
Now, we should talk about
what to do next...
Oh, right! We finished
watching over the eggs, so...
What do we do
with these Rokon?
How does continuing to look after
and raise them sound?
Can we?!
I will take this one.
You kids can take the other.
All right! That means we
get to stay together, right?
So, one of us is gonna catch her?
And we all know who!
Yeah!
Yeah. It can only be Lilie!
That’s right!
She’s the one who’s been
taking care of the egg all this time!
But... Can I really do this?
I can’t even touch her...
Rokon’s saying
she wants you, too!
Yeah!
Hang in there!
It’ll be fine!
You’ve even given her
a name already!
Th-That was just something
I called her on a whim...
It’s a great name, though!
Good job, Lilie!
Are you really okay with me?
Will you be my partner?
Snowball?
Now, Lilie.
Yes!
H-Here I go!
Monster Ball!
Ow!
I-I’m sorry!
She went in!
She chose for herself
to be your partner!
All right! You got Rokon!
Now, send her out, Lilie.
Yes!
Snowball!
Snowball...
That makes Lilie
a Pokémon Trainer, too!
A Pokémon Trainer!
Oh, too bad...
Almost had it.
Is it really possible...
...for me to be a Pokémon Trainer
if I can’t even do this?
How can I interact with Pokémon
the way all of you can?
I’m really not sure what to say...
Same.
We’re always together, so...
I just thought I wanted to
be friends with these guys.
Relationships between people and Pokémon take many different forms.
How do you want to
interact with the Pokémon?
What kind of trainer
do you want to be?
That’s something you’ll simply have to
figure out on your own.
On my own...?
I already know!
I wanna be a Pokémon Master!
Nobody asked you.
That’s good, though.
It’s very “you”.
Yeah!
Later!
Bye bye!
See you!
Yeah, see ya tomorrow!
Lilie, your escort’s here.
Yes.
I apologize, but today
I would like to walk home.
Understood.
Why aren’t you taking the car?
Um... I thought I would
walk home with her today.
With Snowball?
We were together
when she was still in the egg,
but I don’t really know her yet,
and I want her to
know me better, as well.
I want time for us to learn.
Yeah, that’s a great idea!
Spending time together
is a great way to start!
Yeah! I’m sure Snowball
will be happy, too!
Yes!
Well then, have a nice day!
Sure! You got this!
Later!
Let us be off, Snowball.
Don’t worry!
Lilie will be just fine!
See ya, Mao.
Now, let’s go, Satoshi!
Go? Where?
We’re following Lilie!
I can get some data-roto!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Rokon
..                (Alolan Form)
Type:   Ice
Snowball, we’ll be taking
a bit of a detour,
to visit a store that
sells delicious malasada.
Mao told me about it,
and I thought I’d have you try it, too.
You see, Snowball...
I’ve loved Pokémon
since I was little,
but I just can’t manage
to touch them...
I’m not sure what I should do.
But I feel that I
have to do something.
I can’t let things stay as they are.
I love you, Snowball.
It’s going great!
Thank goodness.
You really do worry
about Lilie, don’t you?
You came to check on her
when she was looking after the egg, too.
Yeah...
Maybe I’m just a busybody.
But she loves Pokémon so much.
I want her to be able to
have fun being with them, too.
Right, Amakaji?
I know what you mean.
Every day is so much fun,
right, Pikachu?
Hey, this is no time to
be laughing-roto!
Huh? Where are Lilie and Snowball?!
Oh, no!
You guys are hopeless.
Oh, malasada doughnuts are
so much better than pancakes!
Delicious!
She must be really disappointed that she couldn’t get
that one-year gift card for pancakes the other day.
She’s such a sore loser, meow.
She’s still gonna eat more?!
I’m stuffed, meow...
These aren’t for you!
Then what, meow?
Does it matter?
They’re for eating back at the base.
Nyarth, what did we have
planned for after this?
Getting parts to build
the hidden base, meow.
It’s still not
a fully functioning base, meow.
Oh, right. Well, first we need...
Wasn’t that the brat boy’s...
What’s that white one?!
Hmmm... Looks like
it’s an Alolan Rokon.
Rokon?!
It’s pure white and so cute, meow!
Sakaki would be delighted
to get that one, for sure!
Get it! Get it!
Yeah, meow!
Which do you prefer?
I want to know your tastes.
I want to make Pokémon food
specially for you, as well.
Oh, so that’s your favorite?
Where did Lilie and Snowball go?
We’ve utterly lost sight
of the target-roto.
Maybe they took a detour?
All right!
Mokuroh, it’s all on you!
Go look for Lilie and Snowball!
There’s a spot up ahead
with an absolutely gorgeous view!
Would you like to see?
Hold it!
Brat girl with the fancy hat!
It’s you people!
When you say “It’s you people!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
What do you want?
What we want
is that white Rokon!
Mimikkyu, go get it!
Huh?!
Hey, where are you going?!
Mimikkyu just doesn’t care
about anybody but Pikachu, meow...
Huh?!
This way, Snowball.
Hey, wait!
Will you...
...stop?!
What do I do...?
Oh, I know!
Snowball!
Use Powder Snow
on the ground!
Ow!
It’s frozen, meow!
That thing did it, meow!
Alolan Rokon are Ice types!
Whatever! We’re going after—
This is our chance,
Snowball! Run!
Hold it, meow!
I’m so glad that worked!
Thank you, Snowball!
Wait!
Did you find them, Mokuroh?
Seriously?
Over there!
We’ve got you cornered!
Give up, meow!
Come out, Hidoide!
Not me!
Over there... Get that one...
What are you doing?!
Mimikkyu!
Hidoide! Sludge Bomb!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
No use!
There’s nowhere to run, meow!
Oh no... If I don’t do something,
Snowball will be...
Sludge Bomb!
Snowball!
Mokuroh! Leafage!
Lilie!
Mao?
We made it!
Are you all right, Lilie?
Oh... Yes!
Snowball,
you’re not hurt, are you?
Gah! It’s the brat boy!
Team Rocket! You guys again?!
Huh, you’ll fight?!
All right, get ‘em, Mimikkyu!
Here we go, Pikachu!
Snowball! Powder Snow!
Well done, Lilie, Snowball!
Awesome!
Huh?
Don’t tell me...
What even is this feeling?
You were great, Snowball!
Amazing, Lilie!
You’re touching a Pokémon!
Snowball!
I told you she’d be fine,
didn’t I?
A gift for you.
I mean, you are taking
pretty good care of us,
so I figured doing something like this
might be fine, once in a while...
Don’t get the wrong idea, though!
It’s a one-time thing!
Oh, I see.
I should’ve known, meow.
Wh-What?!
W-Wh-What?
Are you happy? Angry? Hey!
That hurts!
I think it’s happy, meow.
Really?
M-My bones...
I... I can’t breathe...
There they are!
Alola!
Alola, Lilie!
How are you doing?
Do you have to ask?
She’s carrying her in her arms!
That’s great!
Yeah, I’m glad.
You finally did it, Lilie!
Yes! Thank you!
Snowball, here are your friends.
Oh, they’re greeting each other!
Looks like other Pokémon
are still a no-go...
Well, you’ll get used to them
sooner or later.
That’s right.
H-Hang in there...
I will... do my... best!
With new friends,
the Pokémon School
became even livelier.
What kind of partner
will Snowball be to Lilie?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you very much for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Snowball!
I suppose that might have been an easy question
if you saw last week’s episode...
Rokon from Kanto are Fire types,
and Snowball is an Ice type.
I was unable to touch Pokémon at all,
but now thanks to Snowball, I can!
Thank you, Snowball!
Sure is hot today...
Snowball is cooling me down,
so I feel great!
Right, Snowball?
Oh no! Lilie!
Next episode
Iwanko is acting strange-roto!
I thought so, too,
so I set up a camera!
All right! Let’s solve
the mystery of Iwanko!
Start playback!
Oh, this is Satoshi coming home.
Satoshi!
Wh-What is the meaning of this?!
Professor, don’t look!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Clawmark Hill, Iwanko and Lugarugan!!
Next time
Clawmark Hill,
Iwanko and Lugarugan!!