Alola!
I, Lilie, will be presenting
today’s PokéProblem.
Lilie
Kaki
Hala
Satoshi
Today, a competition known as
the PokéSled Jump tournament is held.
Who’ll be the winner?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
This is Ula'ula Island.
On this island lies
Alola’s tallest mountain, Lanakila Mountain.
What have Satoshi and the others
come here for?
It’s pure white!
It’s real snow!
My dad brought me here when I was younger,
so the snow is no big deal at all to me!
Bullseye!
Now you’ve done it, you...!
Snowball looks so happy.
Well, of course.
She hatched from an egg that was found
here on Lanakila Mountain, after all.
On the other hand...
They all look so cold-roto...
So neither Nyabby or Mokuroh
can handle the cold...
You should stay
in your Balls for today.
Mr. Hala, you’re sure to catch a cold
dressed like that.
I don’t want to hear that
from you, little Kaki.
Besides, if I just use Belly Drum
like Hariteyama does,
my fighting spirit will
drive away the cold!
Indeed! My heart’s hotter than a Blast Burn,
so I’m not cold at all!
Well then, I’m burning hotter than a
Dynamic Full Flame, so I’m not cold either!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Lilie's Flying High!
The PokéSled Jump Tournament!!
Winter clothing these days
sure is light and warm.
I feel antsy.
This isn’t bad at all.
Well then, shall we go?
I can’t wait to see Makenkani evolve!
Well, we did come all the way to Lanakila Mountain
just to see that, after all.
Look!
Yukiwarashi!
A white Sand!
It’s my first time seeing one!
Sand, Alolan Form. Mouse Pokémon.
Ice/Steel type.
Its steel shell is very hard—
so much so, it can’t roll its body up into a ball.
There aren’t many places in Alola where
you can meet Pokémon who live in snowy mountains.
Shall we take a break here?
Good idea.
All right, everyone!
We’re taking a ten minute break!
I’ve brought warm tea.
I baked chocolate cookies.
I brought some Old Gateau.
I have some Moomoo Milk bread
from our farm.
All right! Time for some snacks!
You forgot snacks?
No! Look at that!
I’ve never seen footprints
like these before!
Amazing-roto!
This is a huge discovery-roto!
From the size of its feet, I can infer...
...that this might be a new Pokémon species
that’s over three meters tall-roto!
Where are you going, Snowball?
Wait!
Let’s go, too!
Snowball! Where are you?
Snowball!
Look out!
Kyukon, please!
Are you all right?!
Oh... Yes!
What a relief...
I’m sorry.
I didn’t think anyone was here.
Don’t worry. Anyway...
What a lovely Kyukon.
Snowball must have started running
because Kyukon was there.
Um...
What was that beautiful move
you used just now?
That was Aurora Veil.
Aurora Veil?
Do you want to try
using Aurora Veil, too?
Hey! What happened?
It’s a white Kyukon!
Awesome!
C-C-Could you be Sara?!
Yes, I am.
I knew it!
Please let me shake your hand!
Me too-roto!
Huh? Who is she?
You don’t know Sara?!
She’s a PokéSled Jump
competitor from Alola...
...who’s already been signed up
for the next world championship-roto!
Really?
I’m Satoshi.
And this is my partner, Pikachu!
I’m Rotom-roto!
It’s a pleasuroto to meet you!
I’m Māmane.
This is Togedemaru.
My name is Lilie,
and this is my partner, Snowball.
What a cute nickname.
A white Kyukon... How cool!
Kyukon, Alolan Form. Fox Pokémon.
Ice/Fairy type.
Possessing a calm demeanor,
it will sometimes rescue people in distress.
I see...
You sure are clever!
I have to get going
to the contest venue!
Do your best!
I know! There’s a
PokéSled Jump tournament tomorrow.
Would you like to participate?
It’s a lot of fun!
What?
All right, let’s meet again somewhere!
So cool!
Yes!
Hey! Hurry on back!
Ah! It’s battling!
It’s up against a Nyura!
Makenkani,
use Grow Punch!
Makenkani wins!
It’s finally starting!
Don’t miss this, everybody!
So cool!
Kekenkani. Woolly Crab Pokémon.
Fighting/Ice type.
It’s said that, being forced to endure intense cold,
this Pokémon evolved and grew white fur.
Now you and I match!
It looks just like
the footprints from earlier-roto!
Those weren’t footprints,
but fistmarks from a Kekenkani-roto!
Oh? It wasn’t a new
Pokémon species after all?
But still, this is
an awesome discovery.
What should we do now, Mr. Hala?
Well, the truth is,
I had one more goal in coming here.
I’m planning to participate in tomorrow’s
PokéSled Jump tournament with Kekenkani here, you see.
Isn’t that the one
Sara mentioned earlier?
It must be.
Sara?! You mean the famous
PokéSled Jump competitor?!
Yeah! We just met her!
What?!
Lucky you!
Oh yeah. Sara had been invited as a guest
for tomorrow’s tournament, hadn’t she?
First off, let’s go take a look
at the Jump venue!
Awesome!
So that’s PokéSled Jump!
Lilie!
Sara!
Well? Doesn’t it look fun?
Yeah!
Very!
You can rent sleds,
so anyone who wants to can join.
All right! Let’s join!
In that case, Bakugames and I
are joining, too!
You want to try, too?
But...
Lilie, we’ll be cheering for you!
You can do it if you try!
Very well. Snowball and I
will participate as well!
Well then, let’s start training
for tomorrow’s tournament right away!
Well, then I’ll practice with you!
Are you sure?
All right!
I can’t believe the brats
are also participating in the tournament.
As if we could lose to those guys,
who are just doing this for fun!
Our livelihood depends on this, meow!
We’ll win and get the valuable prize!
What a great feeling!
Look at that.
This is where I practiced
when I was young.
For starters, just a basic jump.
All right, try doing it in turns.
I’ll give it a go!
We did it!
You forgot to have Pikachu
use a move-roto.
Oh, that’s right!
But for your first jump,
that was well done.
All of you should just focus on
sticking the landing, first of all.
All right!
W-Why?!
Bakugames is too heavy-roto.
Do your best!
Relax! Relax!
Yes.
Here I go!
S-So fast!
Look in front of you!
Lilie!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Kyukon (Alolan Form)
Type:   Ice/Fairy
100,000 Volts!
Quite an impressive jump...
But that technique
is just dangerous.
Looks like Snowball wants to jump.
How about you?
I...
You’re scared of jumping?
I can jump! It’s entirely logical to conclude that,
if I were to put my mind to it...
But...
Falling can be frightening,
and that fear can easily get the better of you.
We jumped so high,
but Snowball still kept trying...
The same thing happened to me, too.
Really?
Yeah. Back when this one
was still a Rokon...
My mother wanted me to
learn to play the piano...
but when I heard the other kids
were competing in PokéSled Jump,
I started practicing, too,
mostly just for fun.
But I had a bad fall,
and got scared of jumping.
I was just about to give up,
but then...
Rokon’s feelings got through to me,
as if it was saying “Let’s do this!”
That gave me the courage
to try again.
I’ll never forget how I felt back then.
While we were jumping, I felt as if
Rokon’s feelings and my own had become one.
Your feelings had become one...
Snowball...
I will try one more time!
Good!
Well then, you should get
used to the speed first.
You want to ride Lizardon?
Yes, please.
But you were scared stiff
last time, right?
I want to conquer that fear!
I’m not scared! I’m not scared!
I’m not scared!
I did it!
You did it!
Keep it up!
It’s a resounding success!
Next up is the move.
What will you do?
If we could use Aurora Veil...
A move she hasn’t learned yet?
You want her to learn that for the
PokéSled Jump tournament?
Yes!
Then why don’t you have Sara
give you some pointers?
Aurora Veil can only be used
when it’s hailing.
Does Snowball know Hail?
Yes! She’s pulled it off
a few times during training.
Aurora Veil!
Let’s take a little break, Snowball.
Guess it’s not that easy.
Yeah.
Hey! Wasn’t that...?
Yeah! It looked like an aurora!
That’s the spirit, Snowball!
All right, that’s enough practice!
Let’s Dragonfly Turnaround back to
the Pokémon Center at the foot of the mountain.
Snowball!
You did it!
Amazing, Lilie!
Alola!
It’s time to begin the annual PokéSled Jump tournament
here at the Lanakila Mountain venue!
I will be commenting on this competition
together with the Jump Guru here.
Pleasure to meet ya.
This tournament’ll be a battle of
jumpin’ distance an’ artistry.
I’ll be providin’ explanations,
drawin’ upon my forty years o’ experience with da sport.
The first pair is
Competitor Kaki and Bakugames.
They make their approach
with a Flamethrower.
Takeoff!
There it is! A grand finisher
by spinning in the air!
Lemme tell ya right now,
dat’s a failure.
Touchdown! We can expect a
high score right off the bat.
Nah, forty years ago,
I woulda jumped furtah.
Next up is the self-proclaimed Jump Queen:
Competitor Musakkinen and Mimikkyu.
We’re counting on you, Musakkinen.
You gotta win, meow!
They make their approach.
They accelerate with Shadow Ball.
Dat’s da technique
I invented fifty years ‘go!
Takeoff! It’s doing
a Wood Hammer dance!
Victory is mine!
What happened?!
What even is this feeling?
Guru, they’re gone.
What even is dis feelin’?
Next up is the pair of
Competitor Hala and Kekenkani.
They’re making a heavyweight approach.
They take off using Grow Punch!
Sixty years ago,
I woulda gone higher!
He’s taken out fans!
I get it, I get it! A fan dance!
Island King style Belly Drum!
The Island King of originality!
Next up is a very close pair:
Competitor Satoshi and Pikachu!
Let’s see what they do.
So fast!
They’re taking off.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Could this be...?
I get it! It’s an Electric Shock!
This is our full power!
Sparking Gigavolt!
The Z-Move has backfired!
It sent them jumping the wrong way!
Dey beat my record of jumpin’ backwards
dat I set seventy years ago!
Next up...
The last pair is
Competitor Lilie and Snowball.
Snowball, we practiced so hard.
I know it’ll work!
Let’s go!
Hang in there, Lilie!
Do your best-roto!
After a careful approach,
they’re taking off.
A Hail directed skyward!
A gust of wind
throws them off course!
Dey’ve failed.
Now!
They’ve pulled off an Aurora Veil!
A successful landing!
A magnificent jump!
No, I did a much more
magnificent one eighty years ago!
You did it, Lilie!
That was perfect!
You’re the best-roto!
A great jump!
Well done!
Now all the jumps have finished.
While we wait for the scores
to be tallied...
please watch our special guest
Sara’s exhibition jump.
The silver goddess Sara
makes a flawless approach.
They take off using
Kyukon’s Frost Breath!
They follow it up with a Dazzling Gleam,
and then an Aurora Veil!
A seven-colored curtain of light!
But she isn’t done yet!
It’s the Galactica Shooting Star technique! Such beauty!
Dat’s me! Me from ninety years ago!
Sara, Kyukon,
you’re amazing!
Now then, we will announce
the results from the judges.
I’m sure Lilie will win.
I think so, too!
Yeah!
Oh, I wasn’t that good...
Sorry, but the winner will be me!
The winners are...
...Competitor Hala and Kekenkani!
We did it, Kekenkani!
The pair of Hala and Kekenkani will be awarded
a prestigious prize from the Guru!
My sled, dat I’ve cared fer
fer ninety-nine years!
I’m sorry. I wanted to win,
since you’d worked so hard.
What a shame.
Sara!
Are you frustrated?
Yes, a little bit.
That’s all right. Your frustration
will push you to try again.
Yes.
Sharing in my Pokémon’s feelings
and doing things with them is so much fun!
Thank you so much!
Don’t worry.
Seeing all of you reminded me...
...how great it is to have friends.
Yes!
This was another valuable lesson.
All right! Let’s go back to
Melemele Island at Lightning Speed!
Yes!
Lilie’s bond with Snowball
has deepened.
What kind of trainer will she
become in the future?
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
I apologize for keeping you waiting!
And the winner was...
...Mr. Hala!
Kyukon’s Alolan Form
is an Ice/Fairy type.
Apparently it was revered as a deity incarnate
before it was identified as a regional variant of Kyukon.
Its divine beauty makes that
quite easy to believe!
Come here!
It ate it!
It seems we’ve caught a cold, huh.
I habed’t cau’t a co’d!
Don’t lie.
There’s no shame in falling ill.
Next episode
A mysterious shadow approaches Alola.
A faintly shining red body.
A long extending, dreadful needle.
Alola is about to meet...
...its most powerful enemy ever.
This has a pretty different vibe
from normal, huh?
Enemy... Most powerful ever...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Move Out! Our Ultra Guardians!
Next time
Move Out! Our Ultra Guardians!!
Can we protect everyone?