Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
Hidoide
Nyarth
Sonansu
Mimikkyu
If we, Team Rocket, were to use a Z-Move,
who would be the one to fire it?
Blue: Hidoide?
Red: Nyarth?
Green: Sonansu?
Or Yellow: Mimikkyu?
We’ve finally mastered it!
Are you ready, Mimikkyu?
Now, let’s go!
Yeah!
Oh, yeah!
Wh-What? Just when things
were getting good!
It’s time for your regular report.
Has your trip to Ula'ula Island
produced any results?
We’re doing just fine.
We’ve got a Z-Ring, too!
We were just thinking of
going and getting Pikachu.
I see. If you can use Z-Moves,
you are more likely to obtain rare Pokémon.
Yeah, so tell Sakaki that
we’re gonna get Pikachu and deliver it to him.
It’s good that you seem
to be confident for once, at least.
Very well. I look forward to the report
of your successful capture.
Leave it to us!
Will she ever leave us alone?
As they say, never hesitate to do what’s evil!
So let’s go get Pikachu!
It’s “Never hesitate
to do what’s good“, meow.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
What a great feeling.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
What a great feeling.
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Super Showdown!
Pikachu VS Mimikkyu!!
With Kapu-Bulul’s help,
Lugarugan has conquered his weakness.
Today, he’s doing one last training session with Pikachu,
to prepare for the Grand Trial.
Lugarugan, Pikachu, are you ready?
Can he train on his own?
Satoshi does this
all the time-roto.
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Use Lightning Speed on Lugarugan!
Lugarugan, dodge
and use Accelerock on Pikachu!
Pikachu! Iron Tail!
Pikachu! Electric Ball!
Lugarugan, dodge it!
He’s not angry-roto!
Well done, Lugarugan!
Looks like he’s worked it out.
And you, Pikachu?
You okay?
There, there.
I’ll wash you and Lugarugan later.
But what happened with
that Electric Ball just now?
It looked as if
the Electric Ball popped-roto.
Ow!
Fine, I got it!
All right!
Let’s go to Mr. Kuchinashi
and have him give us a Trial!
Pardon us!
What, it’s you?
What did you all
come here for?
You know where
the brat boy is, don’t you?
The one with the Pikachu
and the Luganga!
You talking about
the kid from Masara Town?
Yeah, that’s the one!
We want to let our Mimikkyu battle his Pikachu.
So show us where he is, pronto!
What a bother...
That kid would be...
...right here.
Where?
The ruins of
Mega Cheap Supermarket.
The brat boy and Pikachu
are there, huh?
Mimikkyu’s on fire, meow!
All right! Then let’s go!
Yeah!
Hang in there.
Pardon me!
What, now you, too?
Lugarugan’s gotten stronger!
Please let us take your Trial!
Why do all of you always
come straight to me?
“All of you”?
Was someone else here?
Yeah, some guys were here looking for the kid,
saying they wanted to battle...
I know!
Huh? What?
I’ll let you take a Trial.
Really?!
Then if I clear it,
I get to take the Grand Trial?!
You bet!
All right!
Let’s do our best, Lugarugan!
So, what sort of Trial will it be?
There are some trainers with a Mimikkyu
at the ruins of Mega Cheap Supermarket.
Defeat ‘em in a Pokémon Battle.
A Pokémon Battle?
That’s perfect!
Acerola, you be the judge.
Sure!
Mimikins,
we have work to do!
All right, let’s do this!
Is the brat boy really here?
The Island King said so,
didn’t he?
But there doesn’t seem to be
anybody here, meow.
Wh-What? What?!
What’s wrong?
Look, meow!
...Wait!
It’s just Mimikkyu!
Don’t scare us like that!
Bebenom! We’re not here to play!
There’s no helping it.
Bebenom loves pulling pranks-roto.
So there you are, brat boy!
Who’s there?!
When asked “Who’s there?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Team Rocket?!
Does that mean
my Trial opponent is...
...Team Rocket’s Mimikkyu?!
Why’s the ghost girl here, meow?
I’m the Trial judge!
Pleasure working with you!
Likewise!
No, wait a second!
What do you mean, “Trial”?!
That’s got nothing to do with anything!
Today is the day we finally
get your Pikachu!
As if I’d lose to you guys!
Well, then,
try to defeat our Mimikkyu...
...with that Pikachu
of yours!
All right!
I accept your challenge!
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Mimikkyu! Today you’ll finally
bring down Pikachu!
All right,
let the Trial battle begin!
V-V-V-V-Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
W-Wh-What a great feeling.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
C-C-C-C-Clever as always,
N-N-N-Nyarth. Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth—
Clever as always,
Nya— Nya— Nya—
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Mimikkyu
Type:   Ghost/Fairy
What do you need to be cautious about
when battling Mimikkyu?
Does anyone know?
Me! Me!
Well then... Lilie!
Yes! It’s that Normal, Fighting and Dragon-type moves
have no effect on it.
Exactly! It’s got the traits of Fairy-type
and Ghost-type Pokémon.
Come to think of it,
Team Rocket has one, don’t they?
I wonder why it’s wearing that
rag that looks like Pikachu?
I’m curious about
what it looks like underneath.
Would you like to see...
...what’s inside?
N-No, thank you...
Huh?
Mimikkyu can be seen all over Alola,
but it seems particularly common on Ula'ula Island.
Ula'ula Island, huh?
I wonder how Satoshi’s doing right now.
Think he’s gotten to
take his Trials yet?
Pikachu, use Iron Tail!
It’s Disguise-roto!
It really is strong!
Fighting up close
gives them an advantage...
Pikachu! Electric Ball!
Another one, Pikachu!
What?
It’s a repeat of the morning
training session-roto!
Pikachu!
Dodge with Lightning Speed!
And then use 100,000 Volts!
Pikachu!
That one’s strong,
isn’t it, Mimikins?
This is our chance, meow!
Mimikkyu!
Let’s finish it with a Z-Move!
Kojiro,
did you want something?
What’s up, Nyarth?
What’s up, meow?
Hey, don’t make weird noises!
You’re here, I see...
Couldn’t stay
Kiterugone for long...
Wait, wait! Wait a second!
Kiteruguma,
this is our chance to defeat Pikachu!
Would it kill you to wait a little?!
Does this mean...
You’ll allow it, meow?
Here it comes, Pikachu!
Iron Tail!
Pikachu, behind you!
That Mimikkyu and Pikachu
are both amazing. Right, Mimikins?
Don’t lose, Pikachu!
Electric Ball!
Watch it!
Never mind that, look!
Mimikkyu’s got
the clear upper hand, meow!
All right!
Now it’s Z-Move time!
Is that...?
Pikachu, can you stand?
Mimikkyu’s Z-Move is coming!
Hang in there, Pikachu!
This is...
...our...
...Z-Move!
Go, Mimikkyu!
Apparently the move is called
“Snuggly Friend Time,” meow.
Okay, Mimikkyu!
Snuggly...
...Friend Time!
Pikachu! Electric Ball!
He’s trapped-roto!
Pikachu!
Snuggly Friend Time...
What a terrifying Z-Move, meow...
Get a hold of yourself, Nyarth!
We’ve almost won!
Oh, you’re right, meow!
It’s been such a long time!
Now Sakaki will finally praise us!
Endure it, Pikachu!
There’s no way he can “endure”
taking a Z-Move head-on!
We’ve won!
We’ll finally get Pikachu!
Huh?
What’s that?
Are you all right, Pikachu?
That’s...
Calculating... Calculating...
It’s Electric Net-roto!
He covered himself in a net of electricity
to protect himself-roto!
Really?!
Amazing, Pikachu!
So you’ve learned Electric Net?
All right!
Then, use Electric Net again!
What was that?!
He stopped it from moving?!
We’ll use a Z-Move, too!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
Huh?
The Z-Crystal changed-roto?!
It’s the same as back then!
All right, Pikachu!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Let’s show them our full power!
I gripped my small palms tight
Tucked my quivering heart into my bag
Far greater than 100,000 Volts...
1,000,000 Volts!
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
No, way, way greater than that!
Our super full power!
In this world I wandered into all alone
Pikachu!
10,000,000 Volts!
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
Because all the time, see, we’re shining!
10,000,000 Volts...
You’re my sunshine and I love you
Pikachu has that strong a Z-move...?
Satoshi and Pikachu
win this battle!
We did it!
We won, Pikachu!
Mimikkyu!
You can still keep going, can’t you?!
Wh-What?
What, what, what?!
You’re buying us?!
What even is this feeling?
Thanks for cheering us on,
Bebenom!
Congratulations, Satoshi!
Thank you!
Think he’ll let me take
the Grand Trial now?
What, you went and won?
Listen to this! Satoshi and Pikachu’s
10,000,000 Volts was amazing!
He learned Electric Net, too-roto!
It’s all because you worked so hard!
This means we’ve
cleared the Trial, right?
Guess I got no choice...
A promise is a promise.
Fine.
You can face my Grand Trial!
All right!
Thank you so much!
Okay, let’s do the Grand Trial!
Satoshi and Pikachu have
cleared their Trial.
Up next, it’s finally time for the Grand Trial battle
against Island King Kuchinashi!
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
It was Mimikkyu
who fired the Z-Move.
Mimikkyu’s exclusive Z-Move,
Snuggly Friend Time, is a Fairy-type Z-Move.
Despite its cutesy-sounding name,
it was super powerful...
But who could have thought that
Pikachu would unleash a new move of his own?
We were so close, too...
Yeah!
This doesn’t sit right with me!
Let’s do some more
Z-Move training, meow!
But before that,
let’s have some food!
Next episode
Uncle Kuchinashi!
Not here.
Yes you are!
I mean,
nobody else is here but me!
This is awful! We got a complaint that
a bunch of Nyarth are napping on the neighbors’ lawn!
Got it! I’ll be right there!
That’s the Island King for you!
You come through when it counts!
Napping with the Nyarth
is part of my job, too!
You’re going there to nap?!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Kuchinashi’s Grand Trial! Lugarugan Awakens!!
Next time
Kuchinashi's Grand Trial!
Lugarugan Awakens!!
Look forward to it!