Alola! Kukui here!
I’ll be presenting today’s PokéProblem!
Kiteruguma
Nyabby
Tsutsukera
Kapu-Kokeko
Which Pokémon does Satoshi
try to catch in today’s episode?
Let’s see!
See ya later!
One morning, Satoshi
encountered a certain Pokémon...
This Pokémon staring
intensely at him is known as...
That’s Nyabby-roto!
Nyabby, huh?
We’ve seen it a couple of times
since we came here, yeah, Pikachu?
Nyabby. Fire Cat Pokémon.
Fire type.
It doesn’t allow its emotions to be easily seen.
It prefers solitude. Earning its trust takes time.
What’s up?
Maybe it’s hungry?
This is my lunch for today.
Ta-daah!
A croquette sandwich!
Here you go.
It’s real good!
Electrifying!
Wait-roto!
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Nyabby,
the Marketplace Wanderer!
Oh, Perrie!
Did you take
another walk outside?
Oh, you met that Nyabby?
You know it?
It likes to nuzzle up to people like this,
like, “Can I have some food?”
It’s so cute when it does that!
You just can’t help but feed it!
That’s exactly how it tricked me!
And now my precious
croquette sandwich is...
Y-You mean Nyabby stole it?
Yeah...
It’s always on its own,
isn’t it?
Nyabby doesn’t like
dealing with people.
Its species is known for
taking a long time to warm up to their trainers.
It doesn’t take to people?
That’s the same thing
I explained earlier-roto!
I guess it’s kind of
a lone wolf Pokémon?
It comes to our cafeteria
a lot, though.
I see it at the market, too.
It just grabs berries and runs off.
It is cute, though.
I can’t really hate it, you know?
So, what do you want to do
about that Nyabby, Satoshi?
Put it in its place!
A grudge over food’s
a scary thing!
“Put it in its place”?
How, exactly?
Uh, how?
Well...
I’ll catch it!
What?!
When they break the ice, saying
“Nice weather we’re having, right?”...
Let us tell you our names.
Natural elegance in full bloom,
headed for a better life.
A robust flower in this laid-back world.
Musashi.
Going with the flow,
not fishing for faults.
A whiff of refreshment in this world.
Kojiro.
Family fun time and traffic safety.
A shining Charm in the sun.
Nyarth.
Team Rocket is on break today.
Huh? Wasn’t there one more?
That’s weird.
That one stole it, meow!
Wait, meow!
Now we just need
some detergent...
Detergent?
Refills for the bath,
kitchen and window cleaners.
Nyabby spotted-roto!
Hey, wait!
What’s wrong, Satoshi?!
Allow me to explain.
Huh? Where’d it go?
Oh, welcome!
Um... We were looking
for a Nyabby...
There it is!
Now, don’t get so angry...
Wait, you’re giving it that?
Here in Alola,
we share in nature’s blessings.
Eat it slowly.
Does that Nyabby
come here often?
Yes. It’s like it’s part of
its daily routine.
I wonder if maybe
it’s worried about me?
That’s why I give it berries
every time it comes by.
Did it steal food from you
by any chance, young man?
Yeah!
My precious
croquette sandwich!
I’ll make you another, Satoshi.
I don’t know where it lives,
but I do know it’s
not a bad Pokémon.
Later!
Nyabby!
Rotom, who’s that Pokémon?
It’s Persian-roto!
Persian? That’s not what
the ones I’ve seen looked like!
This is the one
you’re familiar with-roto.
But its Alolan form
looks like this-roto!
Persian has an
Alolan form, too?
Alolan Persian is a Dark type,
so it has a crafty, brutal personality-roto.
What?
So it’s...
Hey! Stop!
Nyabby!
Hey, you!
Is a berry really
worth all this trouble?
Stop, Persian!
Pikachu! Electro Ball!
100,000 Volts!
Are you all right, Nyabby?
Nyabby is at 90% damage.
Hey, Nyabby!
Don’t push yourself too far!
C’mon. I’ll carry that for you...
Ow!
Nyabby!
Let’s go to the
Pokémon Center together.
Nyabby...
I get it. It’s yours, right?
C’mon... I’m telling you,
I won’t steal it!
But I can’t leave you like this.
Come on... I’m taking you
to the Pokémon Center, no matter what!
Owwww!
I won’t let go!
Rotom, carry the berry.
Roger that-roto.
Ow! Cut that out!
Don’t bite me!
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Nyabby
Type:   Fire
What is this, Ms. Joy?
It’s called an Elezard Collar.
It’s to prevent it
from licking its wounds.
I see.
Elezard Collar has been registered-roto.
You look really cool, Nyabby!
And now it’s your turn.
Huh?
You’re covered in scratches.
Whoa, you’re right!
This is rough...
Hey, wait!
Don’t let it hurt itself, Satoshi!
Got it!
Out of the way, Kaki!
All this over a
croquette sandwich?
Wait, Nyabby!
Cut it out, already!
Do not move! Get it?
Disobey again, and...
...And so, you brought it home?
Can’t I keep it here...
at least for tonight?
But Satoshi, you’re...
These are just bruises.
You really don’t like that, huh?
I’ll take it off for you.
But don’t lick your wounds.
How’s that?
All right...
Stay still.
You know, I have no idea
what you’ve been through...
But do you think you could
trust us a bit more?
You’re awesome,
working so hard on your own!
You’ve got people cheering you on,
like that lady at the market...
Your Ember hurt pretty bad.
You’re asleep, huh?
Good night, Nyabby.
All right... I’ll open it for you...
Nyabby?!
Where are you going?
This does not compute-roto!
The best course of action for recovery
is to stay still and rest-roto!
Where are we?
Impossible to determine.
Mooland?
It seems quite up there
in years-roto...
Wait, have you been gathering food
for this Mooland?
Sorry it took so long, Mooland.
Nyabby got hurt in a fight,
you see.
So I had it rest at my place for a bit.
Nyabby.
I was thinking of catching you...
But I guess you’re needed here...
I’ll give up on it.
All right, I’m going home.
The Professor’ll get worried.
Um... I’ll bring
some food here later!
I can come back, right, Nyabby?
What’s wrong?
Something draws near-roto!
What?
The Alolan Persian!
Everyone, get out!
What a vindictive one-roto...
It’s come back for revenge-roto!
Stand back!
You really don’t know
when to quit!
Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
Just scratches!
All right!
That drove it off-roto!
You did it, Nyabby!
Ouch!
All’s well that ends well-roto!
Too bad you couldn’t catch it.
Later!
Nyabby, I’ll be back tomorrow!
And I’ll bring plenty of food!
Alola, Nyabby!
Nyabby!
Hey, Nyabby?
Nyabby?
Oh, I see...
I feel real bad...
Did I do something wrong?
Pokémon are Pokémon.
People are people.
They each have their own worlds.
It’s not your fault.
Somewhere under the Alolan sky...
I’m sure Nyabby’s doing just fine.
Nyabby!
There it is-roto!
See?
Little Nyabi, did you move?
What will the meeting between
Nyabby and Satoshi lead to?
Nyabby!
Perhaps only the Alolan
ocean breeze knows...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Nyabby, huh?
Satoshi couldn’t get this Pokémon,
but did you get the right answer?
The Fire Cat Pokémon Nyabby
is famous for being whimsical.
The Nyabby that Satoshi brought home
went from Scratching to trying to Charm him...
It did whatever it wanted.
Well, I’m sure Satoshi’s Endeavor
must’ve had some effect on Nyabby!
I heard they moved... I wonder where
that Nyabby and Mooland are now.
Next episode
Something’s on the floor...
Whose pen is this?
Oh, that’s mine! Thank you!
Who ate my malasada doughnuts?
Can someone water
the flower beds with me?
Sure!
Who was running in the hall just now?
I didn’t wanna be late, you see...
Oh, right!
Who’s in charge of the Pokémon Egg?
What? We had someone
in charge of that?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Who’s On Egg-Watch Duty?