Alola!
I, Lilie, shall be presenting
today’s PokéProblem.
Pippi
Iwanko
Pikachu
Mokuroh
Which Pokémon
becomes my partner today?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
It’s another beautiful day
at the Pokémon School.
So naturally,
the schoolyard is full of...
Oh?
Go, Pikachu!
Don’t lose, Amamaiko!
Ashimari!
Go, go, go!
Nice going, Pikachu!
Will we see a dead heat-roto?
First place!
Well done!
You did your best!
Aw...
I thought we
might finally win today.
Pikachu does have an advantage
when it comes to speed.
You were amazing, Pikachu!
Seems you all know
how to Play Nice.
Professor!
Alola!
Well then, I want you to...
...trade your partner Pokémon.
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Lilie, Take Good
Care of Pikachu
Trade our partners?
What do you mean by that?
Ashimari’s going away?
Oh, sorry.
That’s not what I meant. I meant you
temporarily trade your Pokémon with each other.
I want you all to get to know
more Pokémon than just your partners.
And I figured living with each other
would be the best way to do that, hence this assignment.
Oh, so that’s what you meant.
Sounds fun!
I’d been wanting to gather data on
non-Electric-type Pokémon!
I’m a little worried about
being apart from Ashimari.
But I think this is
a good opportunity!
I must learn to touch
Pokémon other than Snowball.
Well, let’s give it a try.
Have you decided whose
Pokémon partner we’re trading with?
We’re deciding that with these!
There’s two straws for each color.
Whoever draws the same color,
you’ll be trading with each other.
All right!
I look forward to working
with you, Pikachu.
Snowball. We’re going to be
separated for a while,
so be good and
listen to what Satoshi says.
Let’s try to get along,
Snowball.
Leave the care of
Snowball to us-roto!
Snowball’s habits and food data and such
are all in my memory banks-roto!
You’re so dependable, Rotom.
Indeed I am-roto!
Take good care of
the Aina Cafeteria’s mascot Pokémon.
Togedemaru, are you
gonna be okay without me?
You have two little sisters
at your place, don’t you?
Won’t they be scared of Bakugames?
They’ll be fine, I think...
The partner trade
will last for two days.
You’ll all get your own back on Monday.
I’m looking forward to seeing you all
after you’ve befriended your new partners!
Yes!
See you later!
Kaki, look after Ashimari!
Of course! And you
take care of Bakugames!
Ashimari, hang on real tight.
I hope Ashimari
will be all right.
Here we go, Togedemaru!
Mao! Take good care
of Togedemaru!
Of course! You, too!
Now, shall we go, Pikachu?
Pikachu,
don’t zap her in your sleep.
Satoshi, Snowball,
I’ll see you on Monday.
Leave it to me!
C-Coming in...
See ya!
We’re here!
Snowball, this is where I live!
Come on out, everyone!
You come on out, too.
Everyone, be nice to Snowball.
Welcome home, Ms. Lilie.
Thank you, James.
We have a guest.
Oh?
So Snowball is staying
with Master Satoshi?
Indeed. There is no need
to worry about them.
But still... I...
I already proved I’m able to touch Pokémon
by touching Snowball!
Therefore, it is entirely logical to conclude
that I should also be able to touch Pikachu!
Okay, Pikachu.
Go ahead and play as much you like.
I thought I’d start off by
doing some observing.
Getting to know one another
is the first step to becoming friends.
Pikachu’s movements are quick,
and filled with curiosity.
Order’s up, Mao!
Counting on you!
Thank you for waiting! Coming!
So cute.
Would you like to eat with us?
Why not join me, too?
Whoa...
Togedemaru!
No being rowdy in the cafeteria!
Oh, dear...
What a lively mascot Pokémon...
Aww, Togedemaru...
Okay!
Ready, Amamaiko? Start running!
Don’t you understand?
Like this.
Togedemaru would cooperate
with me right away.
Wow! So big, so big!
Ho, Sui. Don’t play tricks
on Bakugames, okay?
Okay! Okay!
All right, then...
Now what do I do?
I don’t know how to deal with Water types...
Ashimari!
Ashimari? Play with me, please?
I know, Hoshi!
Why don’t you two get some
fresh Moomoo Milk over there?
You can drink it together.
Let’s go, Ashimari!
Hey, Snowball! Come here!
C’mon, Snowball!
Cold!
No good, huh?
Communication is proving
exceedingly difficult-roto.
Hey! Food’s done!
All right! I’m starving!
Here! Eat up, everybody!
You too, Snowball.
That’s strange-roto.
Rokon are quite fond of
this particular blend-roto.
So why won’t she eat-roto?
I-I’m fine! I’m not scared!
Not at all!
No way!
It’s just hopeless.
I can’t sleep without Togedemaru.
Amamaiko?
That smells so good...
Good... ni’d...
Oh, Togedemaru...
Stay still for a bit.
Watch out!
Wow! It’s getting cleaner!
Good going! Keep on rolling!
Once we’re done cleaning,
it’s time for breakfast!
What’s up, Ashimari?
If you want to play, there’s...
Big bro, bad news!
The Kentauros are fighting!
Stop it, Kentauros!
What are we gonna do?
We’ve got to stop them.
Bakugames!
...Right, not here!
Ashimari? Look out!
Will you help me?
All right, then... Balloon!
Just a little bit bigger...
Now, concentrate...
Now!
That was amazing, Ashimari!
All right, now let’s
take care of them.
They should calm down
once we wash them.
Yeah!
Ashimari! Use Bubble Beam,
but gently!
Doesn’t that feel good?
I’ll help, too!
Bakugames’s so big!
Looks super tough!
Oh, I forgot to mention, if you touch
the spikes on Bakugames’s back, they’ll—
Wow! That surprised me!
Surprised me!
Aww... I’m sorry, Bakugames.
Like this...
Gotta brush you
without touching the spikes.
I’m gonna help, too!
And me! And me!
Thank you. Please do!
Yay!
You haven’t eaten anything?
Then how about a walk?
Lilie told me you really
like to go for walks.
All right! Let’s go!
Satoshi, I’ll come, too-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Amamaiko
Type:   Grass
Alola!
Oh, Alola!
Little Nyabi, it looks like
you’re doing well!
Yeah, he’s doing fine!
I have some of his
favorite berries here.
Here, eat up.
You eat up, too.
Fresh Obon Berries are
exceptionally nutritious-roto.
How nice.
Oh?
Now, what’s wrong?
You can have some!
We all share in
the blessings of the earth.
Oh, she’s eating!
It was good, I see!
That’s great, Snowball!
Hey, Snowball,
we always train together.
You should give it a try, too!
Nyabby, use Ember!
Like that. It’s a great way
to relieve stress!
Okay, Snowball.
Powder Snow!
Magnificent-roto!
Snowball, that was awesome!
You’re really cool!
Snowball! Let’s make you stronger
and surprise Lilie!
All right. Let’s start training!
Here, Pikachu. Please, eat.
I’m so sorry!
But I...
I really want to become
better friends with you...
How did Satoshi
become so close to you?
Pikachu, use Lightning Speed!
James, please do not hold back!
Are you sure about this?
Please, Pikachu!
Will you battle alongside me?
When Satoshi and Pikachu battle together,
they’re always perfectly in sync.
That’s how much
they trust one another!
If battling will allow me to get
even a little bit closer to their level...
Pikachu, use Lightning Speed!
Odoridori, dodge!
Revelation Dance!
Are you okay, Pikachu?!
Use Wobbly Dance!
Pikachu!
Don’t look at their dance!
Use Round-Trip Slap!
Pikachu!
Another Round-Trip Slap!
What do I do now?
Pikachu?
A Pokémon Battle is fought by
both trainer and Pokémon together.
If I lose heart,
then Pikachu cannot battle!
Right now,
Pikachu’s partner is me!
I have to go through with this!
But can I?
If I run away,
I accomplish nothing!
I decided I would do this!
Pikachu, will you believe in me?
Here goes! Pikachu! Lightning Speed!
Dodge it!
Pikachu cannot be outsped!
Now, Pikachu! 100,000 Volts!
We did it...
We won, Pikachu!
We did it! We did it!
You’re incredible, Pikachu!
Pikachu, you’re so warm!
It’s been so long, Amamaiko!
You’re exaggerating.
It’s only been two days.
Really? As if you weren’t
lonely without Togedemaru?
W-Well, yeah... Togedemaru?
Huh?
It looks like she really took a liking
to our cafeteria’s food.
Oh, no...
Bakugames’s shell
is practically glowing!
Well, Ho and Sui helped clean him.
It seems the partner trade
had some great results!
It was perfect!
I replicated
Amamaiko’s Sweet Scent,
put it in dough, and made
malasada doughnuts! Eat up!
So good!
It smells like fruit.
I wish I could sell these!
Oh, how about you, Lilie?
Did you and Pikachu get close?
Pikachu?
Lilie! You can touch Pikachu now!
Yes! It’s all right!
Nice going, Lilie!
You too, Pikachu!
Well done, Lilie.
Thank you!
I will keep working hard, and slowly get used to
touching other Pokémon as well!
How about you, Satoshi?
Well, I...
I trained with Snowball!
Lilie? Let’s battle!
Battle?
You and Pikachu.
Against Snowball and me.
Pikachu, let’s see how far
we can go together!
Let’s show the results
of our training, Snowball!
Go, all of you!
Good luck!
Do your best!
Satoshi and the others got to become closer
with each other’s Pokémon after trading partners.
And, in the process, they’ve learned even more
how precious their own partners are!
Professor Kukui’s somewhat unusual lesson
was a rousing success!
And with that...
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you very much for waiting.
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Pikachu!
I learned a lot from
trading partners!
Even Togedemaru, who took a liking to Mao’s cafeteria
and didn’t seem to want to leave,
is back with Māmane!
Māmane, you worry too much.
Snowball, time for your meal.
Here you go.
Snowball... Have you started
eating faster?
Next episode
Lovely weather we’re having today,
right, Happinus, Cuwawa?
The Pokémon Center is really quiet today,
On days like these, why don’t we go
toss some Namakobushi on Hanohano Beach?
We’re aiding them...
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Enter Lychee! Laugh and Cry, Island Queen!
Next time
Enter Lychee!
Laugh and Cry, Island Queen!!