Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem!
Yamirami
Absol
Donkarasu
Waruvial
Which Pokémon does the Island King
send out in today’s episode?
Blue: Yamirami?
Red: Absol?
Green: Donkarasu?
Or Yellow: Waruvial?
Satoshi and the others are burning with excitement
for their upcoming third Grand Trial.
Where are they headed?
Satoshi, I can see it-roto!
Ula'ula Island is in sight-roto!
The dream I’m working towards these days
is to create a Pokémon League...
...for the trainers
in the Alola Region!
A Pokémon League in Alola?!
Did you hear that, Pikachu?
A Pokémon League!
You guys, too!
You guys!
Our goal is victory
in the Pokémon League!
I’m fired up now!
So passionate.
The Gym battle in Kanto
stoked their fire.
We’ll be aiming for victory, too!
Satoshi and his Pokémon
are on fire, as well.
There’s no way I’ll lose!
That’s the spirit, Satoshi, Kaki!
This will be the first attempt at
forming a League in Alola.
So I’d like a Helping Hand
from all of you, too.
Of course!
I will support you with
my knowledge as a Pokémon Index-roto!
Thanks!
I’m counting on you!
Let’s do our best in
our Ula'ula Island Pilgrimage!
Oh oh! Let’s go!!
A light peeking in was the signal to set off
Wishing for a change, I focused on the run
In this world I wandered into all alone
I found a piece of the dream I’d been seeking!
I choose you!
Future Connection—start afresh and anew today
Oh oh!
It’s ultra! We’re gonna have sunshine then rainbows
Future Connection—don’t worry about tiny doubts
Oh oh!
When we hold hands, see, we’re shining!
You’re my sunshine and I love you
This Nasty Old Guy is
the Island King?!
Sparkle!
Mimikkyu, doesn’t this make you want to
fire off a Z-Move right now?
Right?! You think so, too, right?!
They’re totally set on
using their Z-Move, meow.
We want to fire off
our Evil-type Z-Move too, don’t we?
How’s this? Or this? No good?
Well then how’s this?
Doesn’t look like she’ll be letting go
of the Z-Ring any time soon...
What’s up?
Isn’t that the brat boy?!
You’re right, meow!
Well, this is unusual!
The other brats aren’t with him!
A Z-Ring...
Mimikkyu-Z and...
Evil-Z.
We can win, meow!
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
I’ve settled on this plan, meow.
Clever as always, Nyarth.
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
Nyarth, you’re the best.
I guess I’ll go
take a nap somewhere.
Kuchinashi, Sir!
Hard at work patrolling, I see!
Y-Yeah...
You are patrolling...
aren’t you?
Sure!
You weren’t thinking about
taking a nap somewhere, were you?
A nap? O-Of course not!
Oops! I forgot something.
Your hard work is appreciated!
Sure!
Okay, I got it.
You really do nothing
but eat, huh?
Is it good?
I see.
You’ve reached
the Ula'ula Island police station.
It’s been a while.
Sakaki?!
I felt like hearing the voice
of my old friend.
But I must say, I didn’t expect you to be
the Island King and a police officer.
Mind your own business.
But it makes sense, Kuchinashi.
So, what is this... “Radiant One”?
“Radiant One”?
Dunno, never heard of it.
I figured you’d say that.
But I didn’t ask just because.
Alola!
Island King Kuchinashi, Sir!
I’m hanging up.
Kuchinashi—
Mr. Kuchinashi, Sir! Alola!
Ow!
Are you all right-roto?!
Bebenom! This is your fault,
you know-roto?!
You all right, kid?
What did you think would happen
if you got their Charms dirty?
Are you Kuchinashi?!
The Island King?!
Kuchinashi?
Um, no.
But... Professor Kukui
told me...
...that the Island King, Kuchinashi would be
at the Ula'ula Island police station.
Oh, right...
He’s a coworker of mine.
He’s out on patrol right now.
And who are you, kid?
I’m Satoshi from Masara Town!
I’m living with Professor Kukui
on Melemele Island.
I came to challenge
the Island Pilgrimage.
Between your Lugarugan
and this thing,
you sure have gotten yourself
some pretty rare Pokémon.
Yes! Its name is Bebenom!
Bebebe...?
I’m sorry!
Hey, Bebenom! Don’t do that!
Apologize!
You’re hungry again already?
Oh, dear...
Hey, kid.
Think you could stay here and play with the Nyarth
until Kuchinashi comes back?
I’m not asking much.
Just play with them for a bit.
They’ll get tired and
go to sleep soon enough.
All right! I’ll do it!
Could you please play with
the toy, and not me?
Ow!
Hey... Sheesh!
Jump-roto!
Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Odoridori
..                 (Flare-Flare Style)
Type:   Fire/Flying
Alola, Uncle Kuchinashi!
A-Alola...
Alola!
Mr. Kuchinashi is out right now.
Out? And who might you be?
Another officer asked me
to watch the station.
Another officer?
So he ran away again!
Ran away?
You see, Uncle Kuchinashi is
the only officer who works here!
What?!
You mean the guy from before
was Mr. Kuchinashi?!
Does not compute!
I wanted to take a picture of
this strange, floating Mimikkyu...
But for some reason, all of the pictures
end up like this-roto!
This is very unscientific-roto!
Of course.
Because Mimikins is a ghost.
A ghost?!
Don’t worry! If you wanna see Uncle Kuchinashi,
then I’ll take you to him.
Really?!
Sure!
Despite how he looks,
he’s actually really kind...
Uncle Kuchinashi, I mean!
Huh?! You live in the library?!
I work here.
I organize the books,
and read stories to the little kids.
Pikachu, what’s with that face?!
Turn this way!
What’s up, Bebenom?
You like books?
This book tells the legend
of the Radiant One.
The Radiant One?
It’s said to be a Pokémon that shines
brighter than anything else in the world.
Hey, this is Solgaleo!
And Lunala-roto!
“A long, long time ago,
when the Alola Region had only just been formed,
“it was a dark world,
devoid of light.
“Eventually, three Legendary Pokémon
appeared in the sky...
“...and began sprinkling
beautifully shining light all over Alola.
“The light kept pouring down
for days on end,
“and the Alola Region was born anew,
into a beautiful world overflowing with light.
“The people named the Pokémon
who shone the brightest ‘The Radiant One,’
“and passed on both its name and their gratitude
to future generations.”
Uncle Kuchinashi says that
the Radiant One could be an Ultra Beast.
An Ultra Beast?!
Then I must update
my data-roto!
Did you hear that?
Sure did!
The Legendary Pokémon,
the Ultra Beast “The Radiant One”, meow!
That means it’s a Pokémon with
amazing power, right?
We must hurry...
...and report this...
...to Sakaki, meow!
I’ll go check the police station.
Mr. Kuchinashi might
be back by now!
There’s no need, Satoshi.
We’ve got a hostage here.
Hostage-roto?
This!
Acerola, you ran off
with my kendama again, didn’t you?
See? I told you there was no need.
Mr. Kuchinashi, Sir! Please let me
face your Trial and Grand Trial!
What, you blew my cover?
Please!
You’re raring to go,
huh, Lugarugan?
Go back to Melemele.
You’re not ready for my Trials yet.
How come?
I can tell...
...’cause I’m an Island King.
You can’t mean that...
You still think it’s
too much of a pain?
No, that’s not...
Glare...
Don’t both of you glare at me!
Then give them a chance.
A chance?
Test them to see if they’re
skilled enough to take the Trial!
A Pre-Trial, if you will!
Mr. Kuchinashi, Sir!
Please let me take your Pre-Trial!
Glare...
Fine, fine...
Thank you, Uncle!
Thank you very much!
Let us commence Masara Town’s Satoshi
and Ula'ula’s Island King Kuchinashi’s...
...Pre-Trial battle!
Please give me a good fight!
It’s Waruvial!
Waruvial. Intimidation Pokémon.
Evil/Ground type.
Its unique faculty of sight can detect small prey
more than 60 kilometers away,
even in the midst of a sandstorm.
Good, Waruvial.
Your opponent’s been Intimidated.
Lugarugan, Tackle!
Good.
Keep making it angry.
Calm down, Lugarugan!
Lugarugan, use Rock Throw!
We’re safe-roto...
Thank you!
Lugarugan! Bite!
Sand Hell.
Lugarugan!
Follow it up with Mud Spray.
Not good!
Calm down, Lugarugan!
Lugarugan, get back!
Good grief... Looks like it
isn’t listening to you one bit.
All right...
Don’t move just yet, Waruvial.
Get back, Lugarugan!
Waruvial... Counter!
Crunch!
Lugarugan is unable to battle.
The Island King wins!
Lugarugan!
Are you all right?
I told you,
you’re not ready for my Trials.
Go back to Melemele.
No!
We’ll stay here and train!
We’ll get stronger,
and challenge you again!
Suit yourselves.
The Radiant One?
Sakaki is already aware of that.
Whaaat?!
If you wish to please Sakaki,
then please report some bigger,
more special information.
She is so full of herself!
In that case, we should go catch
the brat boy’s Pikachu right away...
...and offer it up to Sakaki, meow!
Just you wait and see,
stinking bowl-headed four-eyes!
Very impressive.
We’ll get Pikachu, meow.
You’re upset, right?
So am I.
We couldn’t... We couldn’t do anything.
Not a single thing.
Battles are what I do best, but...
Sorry. Sorry.
Acerola.
Is there anywhere on Ula'ula Island
where we can train?
Train?
Oh, I know!
You should go see Kapu-Bulul!
Kapu-Bulul?
The Guardian Deity of Ula'ula Island!
We’ve met it once before-roto!
I’m sure Kapu-Bulul
will help you train!
Really?! Well in that case...
Let’s eat plenty and
build up our power!
Satoshi has decided to train on Ula'ula Island,
in order to face Kuchinashi’s Trials.
Will he be able to
train with Kapu-Bulul?
Everyone relaxing in the tropical breeze
Sittin’ on the sand, chattin’ about our dreams
The Swimmer, the Youngster, the Beauty
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The Trials we’ve overcome are proof of our bond
Someday they’ll be tales we can brag about
I wanna go home with some malasada for my mama in Masara
Everyone’s on an adventure of their own
The day comes to an end under sunset skies
Somehow it’s bringin’ a tear to my eye
But with a “Bye! Today was a lot of fun!”,
a smile and a wave, it’s all sorted, goodnight, I’ll see you tomorrow
Pu-Puri-Pu-Puru-Pu-Purin
Hurrah! Hurrah! Leap out, lil’ brat boys, into the unknown!
Let’s go! Flap your wings, lil’ brat girls, you’re not alone!
Don’t worry if you fail, we’re only just getting started
‘Cause you can be anything and do anything you want
Thanks for waiting!
The Pokémon
the Island King sent out...
...was Waruvial!
The Intimidation Pokémon Waruvial
is a Ground/Evil type.
It bites down on its opponents with its powerful jaws,
and then twists their body around to defeat them.
Lugarugan was defeated before he got to use his full power,
but next time, we’ll win for sure!
Next episode
Do you think Island Kings
resemble their island’s Guardian Deity?
What do you mean-roto?
Uncle Kuchinashi and Kapu-Bulul
are quite alike!
Like how they like napping,
or how they think everything is too bothersome!
A fascinating observation-roto!
But you know...
Mr. Hala resembles Kekenkani
a lot more than he does Kapu-Kokeko!
They’re both really big
and round and muscular!
We’re not talking about
their looks here-roto!
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Kapu-Bulul!
Intense Slacker Training!!
Kapu-Bulul! Intense Slacker Training!!