Alola!
I’ll be giving today’s PokéProblem.
You’ll find out my Denjimushi’s
nature in this episode.
Calm
Timid
Gentle
Mild
Which is it?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Go!
The Type-3 Kit!
Now in stores!
Get ahead of your rivals with this!
What’s this? It’s super cool!
Right? It’s called a Denjimushi Car.
Denjimushi Car?
Never seen it before.
The Denjimushi Car is a vehicle that runs on
electricity generated by Denjimushi.
They say it’s faster than you could ever imagine
a regular Denjimushi moving.
That’s impressive.
And they have a huge race
every year!
Sounds fun.
Yeah.
Really?
Did it pique your interest?
I really, really want to
join the Denjimushi Race.
But you need a
group of three to enter.
Please, join the race with me!
I’m totally in!
All right! Kaki?
Very well.
However...
If we are to join forces,
we must aim for victory,
and nothing less!
Victory...
Isn’t that nice, Denjimushi?
We’ve got some reliable teammates.
Let’s fight to win this!
Yeah!
It’s so hot...
Don’t you think it’s
too hot in here?
That might be the reason.
Yeah!
Oh?
Snowball?
Yeah!
(I’ll get Pokémon!)
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl’s skirt
It’s really, really, really, really hard to handle,
but I’m gonna get them all! I’m gonna get Pokémon!
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
I’m going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
I’ll win each battle with the moves I’ve mastered,
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
There’s no way to know for sure
if things will always work out
But with my companions by my side, we’ll live life to the fullest!
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Dash! Denjimushi
And so, Satoshi and the others decided to
participate in the Denjimushi Race.
It’s time to start practicing.
...So I bought the Type-3 Kit!
Cool! Let’s start
driving it right now!
There’s something we have to
decide first.
What roles will the each of
the three of us play on the team?
One’s the director,
who gives instructions.
Then there’s the mechanic, who performs
maintenance on the vehicle and switches the tires.
And finally there’s the support runner, who runs
alongside Denjimushi and helps it get past obstacles.
They’re all vitally important jobs.
Then, Māmane, you should obviously be the director,
since you know the most about these races.
Then you be the mechanic, Kaki.
Me?
You do complicated stuff like
fixing the fences at your farm all the time, right?
Well, I guess you’re right.
Then I’ll be the support runner!
Let’s do this, Denjimushi!
There we go...
All right, Denjimushi.
Let’s get started!
Māmane’s Denjimushi looks
just like the ones in the commercial!
Denjimushi! Discharge!
Here it comes!
Wait, Satoshi!
T-This is...
Something’s not right.
Oh, you see, it seems
my Denjimushi has a Mild nature.
But I’m sure he can go fast
once it gets used to—
Really, Denjimushi?
This is so sticky, I can’t get it off!
All we can do is train, I suppose.
Then let’s all run!
Huh? Why?
Denjimushi can get used
to the machine,
and it’ll be more fun for us
if we do it together!
Yeah! It might help
unify the team!
But I’m not good at running...
It’s fine!
You can do it if you try!
He’s keeping up!
This is going well!
Truly, this is youth.
Work hard to prepare for the
race tracKairyu! Kairiky!
That should do it for the motor...
The frame needs a good balance
between lightness and durability.
Do you want to get faster,
Denjimushi?
Let’s win!
You’re making good time-roto!
Done!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Hang in there-roto!
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
You did it!
It’s a new record-roto!
Here, have some Moomoo Milk.
Thank you.
Let’s walk while holding hands,
and stay together even through painful times
Drink. It’s nice and cool.
Thanks, Kaki.
It’ll really help if we can get some
for the actual race, too.
Right, Denjimushi?
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
I’m revived!
Ready to run some more!
They’re at it today, too.
The Denjimushi Race, was it?
Boys sure do love that kind of thing.
Let’s go drink some tea.
Agreed!
And eat some pancakes!
Then let us go visit Noa!
Great idea!
Let’s go!
It’s... It’s huge!
Whoa, there’s so many people!
Are all these guys participating?
Princess Elec
Looking forward to
this year’s race, too.
I’m itching for a challenge!
Twin Starmie
Science Speed
It’s science!
Looks like a lot of these guys
are regulars.
We trained like crazy.
We’re sure to win!
Sorry, not happening.
What’s with you guys?
After all, we, Team Red Meteor,
are obviously going to win!
You think you can win with
a mediocre Denjimushi like that?
I don’t even know
what to say to that, yo!
What?!
Have a look at our big brother’s
super rad Denjimushi, yo!
A red Denjimushi?!
It’s Hayate with
the red Denjimushi.
So here come the
favorites to win...
This is the ultimate Denjimushi, whom our daddy
went to great lengths to find for us!
It’s alternate-color, even!
And with its Timid nature and the perfect ability,
Run Away, it’s as fast as can be!
The car frame is
custom-made too, yo!
It’s completely unrivaled, dude!
You small-fry couldn’t win
even if you all ganged up on us!
How about you go home
before you embarrass yourselves?
Yo, yo!
Right back at you. How about you
withdraw before you lose?
What?!
I don’t care how special
your Denjimushi is.
That doesn’t mean
my Denjimushi has to lose!
You can talk big,
I’ll give you that.
We’ll show you in the race
whose Denjimushi is the fastest!
Unpleasantness: 100%-roto.
You were really cool, Māmane!
Yeah, well said!
As if we’d lose to those guys!
Ugh. The brat boy and his friends
are in this race too.
How bothersome.
Well, no matter.
Our disguises are flawless.
Let’s just focus on the competition!
Our target is
the super luxurious prize!
Nothing’s impossible
for Team Rocket!
Right, my dear Denjimushi?
Wrong!
It’s ”Deji! Deji!”, remember?
It’s not working, meow!
It’s too hot for me to—
Nothing’s impossible!
The inside’s awesome, too!
This is where we split up.
We’ll stay in touch with
these earpieces.
Thank you for waiting!
The elegant race dedicated to
Denjimushi fans across the country...
The 25th annual Kokeko Cup
begins now!
As is the case every year,
the rules are as simple as can be.
The Denjimushi and support runner will
race all the way around the track, aiming for the goal.
But along the course,
there are three tricky areas!
There, obstacle Pokémon
will hinder their progress!
Whether you win or lose depends on
how you deal with those obstacles!
This year, these three Pokémon
will serve that role!
Well then, here are
the three danger zones!
Awesome!
Hmm, pretty much
what I expected.
There are pits in front of
each tricky area,
where you can freely change tires
and let your Denjimushi rest.
Naturally, using attacks to hinder other racers’ progress
will result in immediate disqualification.
Now then,
all competitors stand by.
I’ll be in the control tower
in the middle.
I’ll be waiting at the pit.
Okay!
Counting on you!
Twenty seconds until start!
Right...
I’m counting on you, Denjimushi!
Satoshi, go for the win-roto!
Yeah!
Start!
Go, Denjimushi!
Let’s go!
Deji!
As expected, Team Red Meteor
takes an immediate lead!
Oh! Kiterugumax are
off to a good start, too!
Great! Go, go!
This is pointless.
Now, they’re coming up
on the first corner!
Oh no, it’s an accident!
A huge crash already!
Denjimushi!
Pocket Monsters!
Sun & Moon!
Dude!
Yo!
I choose you!
Name: Denjimushi
Type:   Bug/Electric
Satoshi!
The ones who avoided
this big crash are...
Team Red Meteor and
Team Kiterugumax!
Sheesh! Don’t make me nervous!
Sure...
And here come Princess Elec,
Twin Starmie and Science Speed!
But most of the teams
are out of the game!
What a tragic end!
Oh! There’s one more team
that’s still standing!
Team Māmane Lab!
They made it through!
Denjimushi!
You were so slow that
you didn’t crash with the rest?
The real battle begins now!
Now, the front runners are
entering the rocky course!
Here comes the
Totem of the course, yo!
W-What, yo?!
Oh!
Denjimushi?!
Denjimushi!
We don’t have time
for dilly-dallying, yo!
Let’s go!
The shock isn’t even affecting us...
These special tires’re amazing, yo!
Team Red Meteor is increasing the lead
they have over the second-place team!
Hey! Now!
We’ve got a custom-made
frame, too!
One more time, meow!
All right, we made it!
We’re in trouble, Māmane.
What?!
Oh? You give up already?
Of course we won’t!
Satoshi! Could you be
Denjimushi’s launch pad?
Launch pad?
That’s right! He’ll climb straight over the wall
by driving across your legs and your back!
Got it!
All right, come on, Denjimushi!
We made it over!
We’re doing that, too!
Oh, no!
The body wasn’t sturdy enough!
So luck was on your side.
I expected these kinds
of challenges!
Hey! How are we doing?
We’re at the pit, yo!
Next up is the
sand course, right, dude?
Since the tires are custom-made,
swapping them is a piece of cake, dude.
Hurry it up, Dana!
Let’s swap tires... Push, meow!
What a great feeling!
But that red team
is an eyesore, meow!
Then take them out
in the next area!
You’re up, Kaki!
Right!
I wonder, can you even
do it in time, dude?
Perfect, these tires have the exact same diameters
as Moomoo Milk bottle caps!
I can do this on
muscle memory alone!
F-Fast!
The desert’s up next.
Leave this to me!
Here, Denjimushi!
Use these, too.
Goggles?
Māmane’s orders.
Here’s your pair.
I’ll be waiting at the next pit!
Yeah, let’s turn the tables!
The cars are leaving the pit
one by one!
But the leading team is already
well into the sand course!
These custom high-tech
sand tires are great!
All right, commence operation!
This stun dart will
get rid of you, meow!
What’s wrong, Denjimushi? No...
This is where Run Away will shine, yo!
This is incredible!
Red Meteor is speeding up
in the sandstorm!
Hey! It sped up!
The plan backfired, meow...
Emergency escape. Emergency escape.
Emergency escape.
What happened to Kiterugumax?!
What’s this?! Another Pokémon
came out of their Denjimushi!
This won’t do.
You’re disqualified!
What are you doing?!
It’s time to enter serious mode!
What?! You’re stuck?!
If you accelerate too fast,
you’ll get stuck in the sand.
Move at a constant speed.
The desert will drain your stamina.
Is Denjimushi doing all right?
The Moomoo Milk from earlier
is working!
And it looks like the headwind isn’t a problem either,
thanks to the goggles!
This is where being Mild
comes in handy!
We’re catching back up!
You’ve reached the
final pit by now, I hope.
Well... Sorry, bro!
Denjimushi got worn out
along the way...
No breaks!
I won’t allow you to lose!
Yes, sir!
It looks like one of these three teams
will be the winner!
How troubling, dude. And we’ve still gotta
clear the last area, dude.
Should we give it some nutrition too,
like those guys did, yo?
Never mind that!
Just run straight through the last stretch!
Yo!
Hurry!
Okay!
We’re in trouble, dude!
Go!
You will win this!
Yo!
Counting on you, Kaki!
This is the last stretch.
Hang in there!
Yeah! Denjimushi’s full of energy.
Let’s keep this up and win!
Please leave!
Spoilsport!
You don’t have to throw us out
just because we cheated a bit!
Yeah, spoilsport!
Meow meow meow meow!
As I was saying...
What even is this feeling?
Hit it, for our bro’s sake!
Red Meteor is still in the lead.
Can nobody catch up to them?
No, what’s this?
Princess Elec is in hot pursuit!
Let’s turn this around!
Do your best, Denjimushi!
Let’s run straight past them!
Oh, what’s this?!
Powarun’s adding hail to the mix!
The course is freezing over
right before my eyes!
This’ll be rough!
I can’t change their tires
outside the pit!
Ice?!
Go! Run through it,
Denjimushi!
Look out!
Satoshi!
This is awful!
Princess Elec is out of the game!
And Māmane Lab’s support runner
got caught up in the crash and is unconscious!
Oh, no...
This guarantees our victory.
Actually, it might not be
that easy, yo!
What?!
What’s this?
They’re so close to the finish line!
The remaining team, Red Meteor,
has gotten stuck on the ice and can’t get any further!
Then you push it!
That’s against the rules!
We’d get disqualified, yo!
And Denjimushi’s
completely worn out.
Damn it!
I’ll give you a pep talk!
Are you all right, Satoshi?
I’m sorry.
This is our team’s fault.
No, this is to be expected in racing.
Kaki!
I’ll finish the race!
You get Satoshi some first aid!
But Māmane, what are you
gonna do about the ice?
I know!
How much money and time
do you think this has cost?!
You’re not allowed to lose!
Coming through!
What?!
That’s cheating, yo!
Switching tires in the
middle of the course is cheating, yo!
I’m not cheating!
Then how?
These are Denjimushi’s strings!
It’s an instant anti-slide solution
made using String Shot!
Hey! We’re doing that, too!
Yo!
Denjimushi, just a little further!
Let’s do this, Denjimushi!
Dash!
Dash, Denjimushi!
Goal!
We did it!
Yes!
Awesome!
Has there ever been a race
this intense?!
Victory-roto!
Māmane Lab refused to give up,
and they took home the win!
H-How could I lose?
Big bro!
Now let’s interview the winners.
Please give us a quick comment on
what you feel secured your victory.
Um, well...
Moomoo Milk!
We chose this!
Here’s the prize: a complete set of
high quality Denjimushi merchandise!
Wow, I’m so happy!
We did it, Denjimushi!
You’ll never win
if you don’t keep trying.
Māmane and Denjimushi’s bond
must have grown even deeper from this!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Dark, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Freezing Ice will make you shiver with cold
Toxic Poison will eat away at your body
A Psychic will leave you dizzy and confused
Do things the Normal way, because simplicity is best!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thanks for waiting!
The answer to the PokéProblem
was Mild!
The Battery Pokémon Denjimushi
is the evolved form of Agojimushi,
and is a Bug/Electric type.
It’s got the power to
release stored energy like a battery!
He sure turned things around
during the race today, didn’t he?
Thank you, Denjimushi!
You did great, Denjimushi.
Have a nice, long rest.
Oh, Togedemaru...
Next episode
Big news!
What is it?!
It’s the Pokémon School’s 20th anniversary, and to celebrate,
we’re going on a special extracurricular class!
Really?!
Where are we going?
The Kanto Region!
Then I’ll get to see
Kantonian Fire Pokémon!
Rafflesia!
Tattsu and Seadra!
Kyukon!
Professor Okido!
Um, that’s not a Pokémon.
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Next time
Alola, Kanto!
Takeshi and Kasumi!!
Alola, Kanto! Takeshi and Kasumi!!