Alola!
I, Suiren, am in charge of
presenting today’s problem.
Water
Fire
Grass
Electric
What type is my adorable little Ashimari?
Get the answer at the end of the episode!
Professor Kukui,
I’ll be going now!
See you later, Iwanko.
Iwanko feels comfortable
if you scratch it on the chin.
Data updated-roto!
And while you were busy saying that,
Satoshi ran off at Divine Speed.
Oh, my!
Satoshi and Pikachu have enrolled at
the Pokémon School in the Alola Region.
Another day of their
exciting school life begins!
Suiren!
Hey, Suiren! Alola!
Satoshi! Pikachu!
We’re going on ahead!
See you!
Yeah!
Ashimari, let’s keep going!
Alola!
I was wondering where you’d gone...
He was in Satoshi’s
backpack again-roto...
“I’m Satoshi from Masara Town! My dream is to be a Pokémon Master!”
“This is my partner, Pikachu!”
“Let’s all search for Pokémon together, at full power!”
Just standing around waiting won’t get us anywhere
I want to go on a grand adventure that’ll make
the sun, the moon, the Pokémon, and that girl all turn to look in awe
(Ay-ya-ya!)
It’s a thrilling, surprising, astonishing, naturally endless journey
Things to find here and there and everywhere, it’s almost too much
Now let’s keep going on and on and on and on and on!
(Ay-ya-ya!)
For heated battles, I choose you! (For heated battles, I choose you!)
Now, let’s finish it! I got you! (Now, let’s finish it! I got you!)
(Go!)
Sun, sun, burn hotter! Break into a sprint with your blazing heartbeat! (Yeah!)
Moon, moon, your overflowing courage will brighten our dreams! (Ay-ya-ya!)
With your full body and soul, give it all you’ve got
and shout it out loud: “Alola”!
Ashimari, Do Your Balloon-est!
The extracurricular lesson tomorrow will be on
interacting with sea Pokémon.
We’ll be going to the ocean!
All right! The sea!
The Trump Card to
interacting with sea Pokémon...
...is...
...a fishing rod!
We take a peek to see what he’s up to,
and what do we find?
The brat boy’s a school boy now!
He really doesn’t seem like
the studious type, meow.
Alola!
Care to intoduce yourselFushigidane?
Hello, Sir, meow...
W-We were just passing by...
Just some adorable tourists!
New students are always welcome!
If he’s a student, that means
he’ll be here for a while, right?
If that’s so, we ought to research
his daily schedule, meow!
Therein lies our chance
to get Pikachu!
Huh? Sounds kinda boring.
And when dealing with the ocean,
Suiren’s our expert!
O-Okay!
Tomorrow, I’d like you to act as
their special teacher!
Good luck, Suiren.
All right... I’ll do my best!
Oh yeah, Suiren, weren’t you fishing
when we first met, too?
She’s a fishing master!
She knows loads
about sea Pokémon, too!
Incredible!
Well, I love sea Pokémon...
If we’re going fishing,
that means we’ll have to touch Pokémon...
Will you be all right, Lilie?
Absolutely!
I have a secret weapon ready!
No need to worry, then.
Oh, come on, Ashimari!
Oh! Be careful, Ashimari!
I’m sorry, Lilie...
Ashimari, you say sorry, too.
I-It’s quite all right...
Well, then, don’t forget your
fishing rods tomorrow, everyone.
Fishing rods?
I don’t have one!
I’ll lend you one.
We have plenty.
Really?!
Um, do you have a moment?
They’re gonna take a detour, meow!
“Plans to take a detour after School”...
Don’t get mad!
Of course Ashimari would
do better on the beach.
Ashimari. Sea Lion Pokémon.
Water type.
This Pokémon can control water balloons.
It practices diligently so it can learn to make big balloons.
So when I saw you this morning,
you were practicing making balloons?
That’s right.
This is our favorite spot.
Favorite spot?
This was where we met.
Ashimari was being bullied.
Grab on to this!
Laplace, go!
Ashimari was heavily weakened.
She was badly injured...
I didn’t want her to hate people.
That’s why I chose her
as my partner.
Aren’t you glad you met Suiren?
So you’re practicing balloons?
You can do it!
Thank you, Satoshi!
Awesome!
When she gets better at this,
we’ll let you inside a balloon, too!
Huh? “Let me inside”?
I have a dream...
...to go inside a massive balloon,
and explore all over the sea,
underwater!
And then, I just might meet deep sea Pokémon
that nobody’s ever seen before!
That sounds great!
I wanna try it, too!
Let’s make them big,
Ashimari!
But Ashimari is normally incapable of making
anything but tiny balloons-roto...
They’ll never know if they don’t try!
Suiren and Ashimari can do it!
That reasoning is utterly illogical-roto...
Well, then, shall we continue?
Take your time.
It’s so big! You’re doing great!
Keep it up, Ashimari!
Impossible! It’s expanding at
150% the normal rate-roto!
It’s huge!
She’s never made one
this big before!
What is that?
I want it!
200%... 250%...
Awesome!
Go, go!
It really did defy logic-roto...
Never mind. I don’t want it.
That’s my house.
Oh, Laplace!
Alola!
It’s my family’s Ride Pokémon.
I was riding it
the first time we met.
I’ll be counting on you tomorrow!
A Ride Pokémon, is it?
We’ve seen so many people riding Pokémon
since we got here.
I want that one!
Sheen! I’ve had
a spark of inspiration, meow!
In order to carry out our plans in the Alola Region,
which is surrounded by water,
we’ll need a Ride Pokémon
like Laplace, meow!
Yeah! Yeah!
If we steal Pokémon,
then run away into the sea,
Team Rocket will...
What a great feeling!
We’ll call ourselves
the Ride Pokémon Unit, meow!
Great idea, Nyarth!
You can do it if you try!
Heh!
So, how are we gonna do this?
Haven’t thought up a plan yet...
I’m home!
Hello!
Welcome home!
How fishy!
“Fishy”?
Let me introduce Ho and Sui.
They’re my...
...little... twin... sisters...
So soft! So cute!
So warm! Super cute!
Ho! Sui!
You’re bothering Pikachu!
It really is a Pikachu?
I saw one in a book!
It’s super cute in real life!
Pikachu is a popular Pokémon
in the Alola Region-roto!
Isn’t that great, Pikachu?
Is this guy your boyfriend, Sis?
N-No! Absolutely not!
For really, really, real?
For really, really, real!
Bzzz...
Now you’ve done it...
Bzzzzt-roto...
Awesome!
Go ahead.
Take whichever one you like.
There are so many to pick from,
I don’t really know...
Alola!
So this is your secret weapon?
So cool!
Now I can fish and ride the Ride Pokémon
without any issues whatsoever!
Well, then,
Suiren...
From here on out,
you’re the teacher.
Y-Yes, sir!
Um... Well...
You can do it, Ms. Suiren!
Hang in there.
D-Do you all have fishing rods?
Of course!
Whoa, that’s so cool!
Well... yeah!
This is my Hyper Rod,
strong enough to withstand even a Whaleoh!
With its Super Reel reeling in its prey
at a speed of 300 rotations per second!
All of this combined in the Fishing Rod of Dreams:
Ultra DX Master 02 !
Well, then, please mount
your Ride Pokémon.
Aside from Laplace, Whaleko will also
accompany us to the fishing spot.
Pocket Monsters!
I’ll get Pokémon!
Name: Ashimari
Type:   Water
This is the spot.
There are all sorts of sea Pokémon.
Some live in shallow waters, others in the deep.
This is a mystery spot where
both kinds of Pokémon intermix!
You can even hook Kaiogre here!
Kaiogre?!
That’s right! The Legendary Pokémon!
No, no, you can’t.
Come on, Suiren, don’t tease them.
Right!
Whatever the case,
I’m gonna reel in something great!
Well, then, prepare your
fishing rods, everybody!
And then, throw the lure into the sea
as hard as you can!
Here’s the trick to fishing:
Watch for reactions from the floats,
and then as soon as that happens...
You reel it in at once!
Oh! It’s a Mamanbou!
After you reel it in,
feed it some Pokémon food,
and then give it a nice,
friendly pat.
You really are an expert of the sea!
Yo! Ocean Guru!
The master’s moves cause an Explosion!
How are you all doing?
Got one!
You reeled it in too quick-roto.
Here it comes!
You reeled it in too slow-roto.
Quit bothering us!
Kaki, you’re not catching anything?
Don’t get the wrong idea.
I’m a Fire type user.
I don’t do well with Water types.
And you, Māmane?
Don’t talk to me!
I’m inputting the height of the waves,
strength of the wind and temperature of the water...
...to find the best spot
to fish for Pokémon.
I’m also calculating
the appearance rate—
Perhaps you should
put your lure in the water first?
I told you,
don’t talk to me!
Koiking?!
I... I have something!
Milokallos!
Well done, Lilie!
Q-Quite a rare case!
Lilie, calm down!
Hang on! We’re coming!
Wh-Where’s Milokallos?
That’s enough! Time for a break!
Wait there for us, everyone!
The break will last
for fifteen minutes!
Alola, my dear students!
That’s awful!
What’s your deal?!
When asked “What’s your deal?!”...
Let us tell you our names!
Flower’s face, willow’s waist,
moon and flowers hide in her wake.
A single flower of evil in this fleeting world!
Musashi!
Nobility and elegance like
a dragon dancing in the clouds.
The apostle of darkness fighting back
against a tragic world!
Kojiro!
It’s all for one and one for all!
Even in close friendships,
an evil star shines with a golden glow!
Nyarth!
Team Rocket is here!
Oh, yeah!
Dear brats!
These Laplace and Whaleko have been appointed to
Team Rocket Ride Pokémon Unit!
Hold it, Team Rocket!
Hold it!
Stop!
Is it just me, or did we get some
unnecessary extras, too?
You’re right.
There’s loads of small ones!
We don’t need any non-Ride
small-fry, meow!
“Small-fry”...
Let’s go, Pikachu!
Whoa, hold it, meow!
You can fire if you like...
But you’ll just
hurt the Pokémon!
Dirty cowards!
Rotom, don’t move!
Pikachu, we’re gonna
let them all into the sea!
Iron Tail!
What?!
All right!
Not good!
They’ll crash into the rocks!
Ashimari,
we have to save them!
It’s huge!
Oh, my!
Launch the balloon!
We did it!
Awesome!
Astonishing phenomenon:
Confirmed-roto!
You did it, Ashimari!
You saved everyone
with your balloon!
Why, you!
How could you?!
Our Ride Pokémon Unit is ruined!
What you have done...
...is unforgivable.
Can it, you!
Go, Mimikkyu!
Shadow Ball!
Balloon!
We did it!
Mokuroh! Leafage!
What even is this feeling?
A Kiteruguma who
runs across the ocean surface...
Data updated-roto.
I’m so glad you’re all okay!
Suiren, Ashimari,
you really saved us there!
Ashimari, you were really cool!
She’s the MVP of the day, huh?
Indeed!
I feel like “MVP” might be
pushing it a bit...
Oh? You have
a problem with that?
N-No, not really...
I was really moved!
Does not compute...
That expansion rate was 1000% of
the balloon from yesterday-roto...
How’s that, Rotom?
I told you Suiren and Ashimari
could do it, right?
Suiren’s wish to save the Pokémon
helped Ashimari’s Shell Smash.
That was excellent!
This is exceedingly illogical-roto...
Hey, Suiren!
Try making another balloon
like the one you just made!
I wanna see it, too!
And me!
Let’s give it a try, Ashimari!
You did it!
It’s complete, Ashimari!
What?
Oh, it seems you’ll have to Quash your enthusiasm...
It’s not quite complete yet.
Satoshi’s classmates
Suiren and Ashimari...
The ocean sparkles,
having received their feelings.
The extracurricular lessons
will continue!
Yo! Champ in the making! Now, let’s keep up the enthusiasm today!
Get them, get them! (Get them, get them!) Now, let’s keep making friends!
No Super Ball, Hyper Ball, or even a Master Ball
can capture your heart
But if we dance together, things’ll keep getting more lively!
Normal, Fighting, Poison, Ground, Flying, Bug, Rock, Ghost
Steel, Fire, Water, Electric, Grass, Ice
Psychic, Dragon, Evil, Fairy
Whether they’re evolved or not, get them all together
and strike a full power pose!
Blazing, crackling Fire fires you up
An Electric shock makes you tremble
A Ghost looms over you, cackling ominously
The world’s greatest Fighting men go Ka-thwack! Ka-thwack! Ka-pow!
I’m glad I met you, I’m really glad I chose you
Once we’ve stuffed plenty of memories into our pockets
Let’s walk while holding hands, and stay together even through painful times
So that we can meet here again once we’ve grown up
Thank you very much for waiting!
The answer was Fire type!
Just kidding.
The answer was Water type!
The Sea Lion Pokémon, Ashimari,
loves making water balloons.
It can make all kinds, like balloons as thin as soap bubbles,
and robust, bouncy balloons!
Ashimari’s giant water balloon today
was incredible, wasn’t it?
Good, Ashimari! Keep it up!
One more!
Next episode
Wh-What?
Togedemaru?!
Stop! Stop!
You’re hurting Pikachu!
Are you angry?
No, Togedemaru’s in
a great mood. Aren’t you?
Next time, on Pocket Monsters Sun & Moon:
Shocking Prickles Togedemaru!
Next time