So you did come!
Thank you!
Since you’ve been such a good girl,
I’ll let you in on something good.
Look!
This is the tale passed down
by our ancestors, the Meteor Tribe.
And now,
I’ll pass our history on to you!
A thousand years ago,
an enormous meteor struck this planet.
Natural energy from deep beneath Hoenn
poured out onto the land.
Primally Reverted Groudon and Kaiogre
fought endless, furious clashes over that energy.
The people could do nothing.
Nothing but wait for the danger to pass.
And so, the people prayed,
hoping for salvation.
Praying for the appearance of the
scintillating emerald Legendary Pokémon... Rekkuuza!
Then, the prayers bound
the people and the Pokémon together...
...and the Pokémon
changed its shape!
It’s just like
Mega Evolution, right?
Primal Groudon and Primal Kaiogre
vanished into the depths of land and sea,
and peace returned to the world.
After that, to worship Rekkuuza
and the rainbow stone that created that power,
our ancestors
built this enormous tower.
The Meteor Tribe prophesied
that another meteor would fall...
Even more enormous
than the previous two...
Large enough
to destroy the entire world!
I asked myself,
what could I do to protect the most people?
As my fate, for carrying both
power and knowledge...
Now, our story is finally over!
Welcome to Dragonhark Altar.
A new tale will begin right here.
Ever since I was young,
whenever I felt like the weight on my shoulders
was so heavy it would crush me,
I... would always
gaze at the stars.
You understand
what I’m about to do, don’t you?
I will summon Rekkuuza with the Key Stones
and destroy the meteor heading for Hoenn.
That is my duty.
If something happens to me...
...take care of her.
Now then...
Here goes!
Rekkuuza!
Hear my prayers!
Show me your true form!
Hey! Show it to me!
It can’t be...
After everything I’ve done...
After everything, Rekkuuza
was the one not strong enough?
I never considered...
That meteorite...
Could it be...?
A Mega Stone?!
Our Guardian God, Rekkuuza,
chose you...
...instead of me.
Do it! Catch it!
Thank you.
And... This is our...
This is the last of our legacy
to pass along.
Ever since I was young,
I would always...
...gaze at the stars.