Now, the day is finally here!
This crucial match has garnered
worldwide attention, and no one wants to miss it!
Thanks to that, Shoot Stadium is
packed, packed, packed full of spectators today!
The Champion Match between the unbeatable
Champion and the sensational Challenger...
This match is bound to go down
forever in the history of Galar!
Their last match being interrupted
before it could even begin...
...has only served to raise expectations
higher and higher for this...
What could have happened
to the Champion atop Knuckle City Tower?
With very few witnesses to the events,
speculation is rampant!
Bro!
Lizardon!
Hey, Lizardon...
What’s... happening...?
The Challenger who heroically
stepped up to battle Mugendaina!
He has become a new
Legendary Hero of Galar!
Go for it, Baiwooloo!
There’s only one question
on our minds today!
Will the Challenger be able to break
Competitor Dande’s astonishing winning streak?!
Now!
Right!
Feast your ears on these incredible cheers
for the Challenger who took down Mugendaina!
And now, he’s about to enter the arena...
The man who won the
Galar Champion Cup on his first attempt!
The strongest trainer in Galar!
The unbeatable Champion...
Our very own... Dande!
Bro!
Dande! Dande! Dande!
Now... It’s Champion time!