Daddy! Daddy!
Hey, wait up!
Five minutes until showtime!
A long time ago...
...the people of Enju
built two towers.
Nine-storied towers
so tall they seemed to reach the heavens.
The Bell Tower...
...and the Gong Tower.
One day, two Legendary Pokémon
from far away appeared before them.
The god of rainbows, Houou...
...and the god of the sea, Lugia.
Houou descended
upon the Bell Tower...
...and Lugia
upon the Gong Tower.
The people communed
with those Pokémon,
and before long,
formed bonds with them.
And those bonds lasted until a fateful night
150 years ago, when moonlight shone upon the towers.
150 years ago,
Lugia’s rest was disturbed!
Fierce lightning, violent winds...
A storm enveloped
the city of Enju,
culminating in a tremendous
lightning bolt...
...which struck the Gong Tower.
Flames engulfed
the tall tower in an instant.
Before long,
it became an inferno!
Lugia ascended high into the skies
and brought forth strong winds.
And yet... the flames did not fade,
only seeming to spread further...
Lugia summoned rain
to the skies above Enju.
The rain fiercely
combated the fire...
...until it was
completely quenched.
Once the dreadful night was past,
the sun began to rise,
heralding a new day.
Lugia had lost its bonds with the people,
and with a broken heart...
...it departed.
And now,
deep beneath the sea,
it waits for one
with a pure heart...
...to this very day.
The Gong Tower...
To remind us
of what we have lost,
and to never allow the same tragedy
to happen again...
It remains, even now.