How exactly do you intend
to rescue Cosmog?
What do you think
you can do, Lilie?
You don’t even have
any skill as a trainer!
Nebby...
I can’t...
Mother...
What an odd thing to call me.
After all, I have neither
a daughter nor a son.
No wretched children who would run off,
incapable of accepting my love.
What ugly behavior.
I will use this Cosmog
to open the Ultra Hole,
and that cute, little light-stealing Pokémon...
Necrozma... will be mine.
Stop it, Mother!
Nebby...
People must help
one another, mother.
That’s what my friends
here in Alola taught me.
That’s what I’m here to teach you.
I know what I have to do
to rescue Nebby, and to rescue you.
Nebby!
Nebby?
Nebby...
I... want to see my mother!
She doesn’t have to catch Necrozma
all by herself in order to protect Alola...
An Ultra Hole...
Mother!
Lilie...
Run away...
That thing...
...is a monster!
That thing is Necrozma...
The moment it awoke, it flew into a rage...
and took out everything in an instant...
Nebby!