I need to attain the Legendary Pokémon’s power
and send it to that weapon once again!
Damn it all!
Everything beautiful...
...should stay that way...
...forever.
You can’t equate youth with beauty.
It’s inevitable that everything changes.
But I would make a world where
everything beautiful lasts forever.
This world will eventually reach
a point of no return...
I will put an end to Pokémon.
Even if that may be the case,
that doesn’t mean you’re right!
Kalos is beautiful.
I can’t stand the thought
of the world becoming uglier.
I don’t expect that you will understand
how I think and feel.
The original purpose of this device
was to give life, not take it!
There’s not much power left...
But there is enough to use it once.
I shall grant you eternal life.
I’ll give you the pain of endlessly waiting
for a beautiful world to finally be built!
The device was activated!
Quick!
The exit’s that way!
Hurry!
Right!
Let us live forever!
Revelations from recent events
have left the people of Kalos in great shock.
Today, let us reflect on this message
that Mr. Fleur-de-Lis once recorded.
Pokémon Trainers...
The future is not yet decided.
You have the power
to change the world.
Please lend me your help...
...to build a brighter future.
I bid you adieu.