Go!
I’m gonna become
a Pokémon Trainer.
I’ll be the greatest trainer ever...
and battle my dad!
Pochama!
Go! Bubbles!
We did it!
That Gym Leader
sure was challenging.
He was really, really cool!
I wonder who’s better
between him and Dad...
Oh, sorry.
I spaced out thinking about stuff.
Let’s go!
Turning Swallow Strike!
Yes!
I’m gonna become Champion!
Bring it on!
Let’s settle this right here!
My, you sure sound tough.
Bubble Beam!
What’s going on?
Go.
Finished already?
Did you really think
you could beat Team Galactic?
You kids should stick to dreaming.
Darn it... Just you wait...
I’ll never beat Dad like this!
Hey, I said wait up!
Don’t you dare
start the fun without me!
My, if it isn’t the little boy
who ran off crying.
Did you get any tougher
since then?
I’m here to get my revenge!
Crossroad Kill!
Go, Emperte!
You did get tougher...
Go!
That was a magnificent battle.
You finally managed to defeat me.
So, who will you aim for next...
...son?