Are you after that super strong
and cool Pokémon too, lady?
Let’s see which one of us
finds it first!
I’m going to catch it!
Let’s go!
Go!
That was close...
Are you kidding me?!
Utsubot! Razor Leaf!
You’re incredible...
It’s gotta be that Pokémon...
So that means
we aren’t the only ones here.
I’m going to catch it!
There it is!
Y-You’re not a Pokémon...
Huh?
Mewtwo!
Whaaaaaaaaaat?!
You already caught it?!
I was going to catch it!
Return!
Show me your full strength...
your Mewtwo!
Go! Mewtwo!
Kamex!
You really are strong...
You can have these.
How about both you and Mewtwo
become my Pokémon?
Just think it over, okay?
The last Pokémon is Mewtwo...
Mewtwo...
I was this close
to completing the Index...
Regardless...
You’ve done well.
Take a good look
at your Pokémon.
You’ve formed marvelous bonds.
And look at all the Pokémon
you did find!
You’ve been an enormous help
with my research.
And you weren’t alone
in the undertaking.
This world is filled with dreams and adventures...
and battles and discoveries...
A world of trainers and Pokémon.
With your help,
my dream is finally a reality!
The Pokémon Index is complete!
Excuse me...
Yes, hello?
This is Okido.
Oh, it’s you.
What was that?!
A Pokémon with a body
made out of metal?!
That’s a monumental discovery!
Right... Yes.
Let me know when you know more.
Did you hear that, kids?
The Pokémon Index isn’t finished after all!
We have yet more Pokémon to...
...catch?
Hey!