How long have I awaited this?
I’ve kept my silence,
so no one could learn my plans.
The truth is this...
I was unable to become a hero
and acquire a Legendary Pokémon.
So, I prepared someone
for that purpose.
Look, over there!
I won’t forget!
A warped boy...
...who knew of nothing
but Pokémon.
Ever since that moment,
I’ve provided him with everything.
Everything he needed to become a legendary hero...
...and king of Team Plasma.
I spurred N
into pursuing ideals.
If I could kindle within him
the desire to make the world a better place,
I knew we would surely
seize the hearts of people.
Looks like something’s
about to happen in the plaza.
Well, should we take a peek?
Up you go.
Thank you
for gathering here today.
I am here today
to talk to you about Pokémon liberation.
There is so much
we can learn from Pokémon.
All of you listening, what should we
be doing for these wonderful Pokemon?
That’s right!
We must liberate the Pokémon!
Then, for the first time in history,
humans and Pokémon can become equals!
I tested him...
To find out if he could become a hero
capable of reviving a legendary Pokémon.
N demonstrated
he was worthy of bearing my name.
I even procured a castle
fit for a king.
A castle that can engulf
and shroud the Pokémon League.
A symbol showing
that Isshu will change!
Go! Ulgamoth!
G-Cis is a liar!
Your “liberation”
is just stealing Pokémon from people!
He’s tricked you!
He’s tricked everyone!
Now, the strongest trainer,
commanding a legendary Pokemon...
...has fought the champion...
and won!
I beg you...
Please don’t separate
people from Pokémon!
If you would not
call him a hero,
who could you ever
call a hero?
Forget about destiny,
and follow your heart.
Your heart is
pure and innocent.
But there’s nothing more beautiful
and terrifying than innocence.
It’s time.
Yes...
How long have I awaited this?
Now, those painful days are at an end!
My perfect plan
is about to come to fruition.
So that I may
take control of the world,
Team Plasma will steal everyone’s Pokemon
and release them, “liberate” them!
Oh!
So you’ve acquired
the Light Stone.
If you truly desire to prolong a world
where you can live alongside Pokémon,
do battle with our king.
Now, go onward!
Discover whether or not
you can become a hero!
Come here,
Zekrom!
I will not allow anyone
to stop me.
No matter
what they may try.
The world belongs to me!