Hello, everyone!
Welcome to the Pokémon Resort!
I’m Haru, your concierge!
On this island
overflowing with nature,
Pokémon and trainers alike can engage in
all sorts of activities and relaxation.
As your concierges, we’ll be devoted to helping you,
to ensure that you’re all free to unwind.
Please enjoy your stay
at the Pokémon Resort!
Hi!
Hello!
Hey, Haru!
Tyler-san!
All that luggage...
Are you heading out on the ship?
Yup!
Wait, does that mean...
you’re off work today, too?
Oh, I’m working!
I’m gonna stock up on berries!
Huh?
Weren’t you doing that next month?
That was the plan, but then I got a call outta nowhere
this morning saying to come grab ‘em today!
B-But Alisa isn’t back
until tomorrow, is she?
Yeah, that’s right!
It’s her sister’s wedding today, right?
She deserves to
take it easy for once, eh?
‘Kay, you handle the rest, will ya?
Good luck!
No way...
Well, Watanabe-san’s coming back from
her business trip today, so you’ll be fine, yeah?
Huh?! You can’t make it back?!
I’m afraid not.
I haven’t even made it out of the hotel yet.
There’s a terrible storm here.
No way.
But Kolynk and Roentorar are supposed to
make their first visit today, right?
I’ll try my best to be back
by the afternoon.
Watanabe-san, feel free to
stay where you are for today!
What?
We don’t want you getting injured,
after all!
One way or another,
I’ll manage on my own.
Are you sure?
I am! Leave it all to me!
Well...
Thank you.
I’ll be counting on you, then.
If you need something,
ask the receptionist and she’ll help.
The Pokémon, I’m sure,
will also be there for you!
Got it!
Let’s see... “For Baoppe’s food,
fry all the way through”...
And the ones I peeled before,
I’m supposed to fry in oil, then blanch them, and...
Ah!
No, Yabukuron!
Oh, sheesh!
Won’t you two
try and get along?
What’s wrong, Roentorar?
Huh? The fire...
Mizugorou!
Thank you!
But why are you here?
Oh, right!
I have to go to the vegetable patch!
Oh, Digda!
I just planted seeds there!
Huh?
Ah! Roentorar, don’t dig holes!
Kolynk, Mizugorou, calm down!
Koduck, wait a sec!
Kairyu! Pidgeot, you too!
Sorry, but could you
play somewhere else today?
Eevee? What’s the matter?
Oh, I forgot!
There you have it!
Your summer cut!
A nice, refreshing look!
Umm...
How’s this?
Bam!
It looks wonderful on you,
dear guest!
Ah!
It’s okay.
I’m just going to clip your nails.
It won’t hurt!
At this rate,
I’ll never last the whole day...
Your paw’s like a little hand,
it’s so nice.
Hand... Oh, of course!
You just handed me an idea!
Everybody, please lend me a hand!
Wow, Heigani!
You’re so good at massages!
Ouch, it’s hot!
Ah! That’s perfect!
Thank you, Roentorar and Kolynk!
I’d like to call you “Chef” from now on,
if you don’t mind.
“Even a Pokémon’s assistance comes in handy,”
isn’t that so?
I’m so glad you guys
have enjoyed helping me.
But I must say...
Tyler-san, Alisa, and Watanabe-san...
They always look like they’re having fun with work,
but they’ve actually been working really hard, huh?
Behind that fun,
there’s a lot of effort,
and the effort is driven
by that very fun itself.
What? What?
Huh? Huh?!
Yes? This is reception.
Oh, thank goodness!
I finally got through!
Oh, Haru-chan?
The whole island’s had a blackout!
We’re in a bind!
What could have happened?
Sounds like the power storage device
might’ve malfunctioned.
Apparently power’s
stopped coming through.
What?! No way!
If we can restart it,
it should work again.
But we already
have our hands full here.
Could you please handle it,
Haru-chan?
What? Me?!
But can I even...?
Oh, no! Wait, Gänger!
C-Calm down! Ahh!
There it is!
Okay!
And next...
Um...
This is the switch
I should flip, right?
Now to restart!
Wha...?! Why?!
What do I do now?
The sun’s about to set...
It looks like the windmill
can generate electricity, too...
If only there was wind...
Of course!
If there’s no wind,
we can just stir some up!
Kairyu! Pidgeot! If you would!
It’s moving!
Calm down!
Thank goodness!
Oh, no...
Are you okay?
Thank you for working so hard!
You’ve done more than enough.
Is that...?
Kolynk! Roentorar!
Are you gonna help?
Okay, we’re good to go!
Well then... Please go ahead!
Yes! It’s charging!
Huh?
It’s just like I thought...
I couldn’t do a thing on my own...
I’m sure Tyler-san would take control
of the situation and get us out of it easy.
And Alisa would come up
with some brilliant idea, too...
And Watanabe-san...
I don’t know how,
but I’m sure she’d solve it, too!
And the Pokémon were
nice enough to help me out, too...
Everyone must be
having a tough time.
Huh?
What’s that?
Wow!
It’s beautiful.
Incredible.
Wow...
Amazing!
Kabigon!
Pokémon are so amazing.
Uh... Haru?
Why in the world
are you sleeping out here?
Alisa!
What happened?
It’s only been a day...
Good mornin’, Haru!
Tyler-san!
Yeah!
I’m back, Haru-san.
Watanabe-san!
Was the weather okay?
It all cleared up as soon as
I stepped out of the hotel.
I had forgotten that
I’m a real sunshine magnet!
Huh?
Looks to me like Kolynk and Roentorar
have enjoyed themselves here.
So, how was yesterday, Haru?
Lookin’ after the place alone?
I heard you went through a lot, eh?
Yeah, it was so...
It was so much fun,
because the Pokémon were there with me!
Look at you, talking like that.
Well, you did great.
Thanks.
Here. A little souvenir.
Thank you!
And this is from me.
Keep it up, Haru.
And here’s something from me.
You really did great. Thank you!
Ooh, thank you so much!
Huh? These... are all chocolate!
Eh? For real?
Careful you don’t get cavities!
My reward!
Wait, Koduck!
All right, everyone!
Let’s give it all we’ve got today!
For so long, I’d been looking for you
And at last, I found you on this island
What a beautiful sunset this is
I’m glad I got to see it with you
When I was alone
When I felt lonely
I would think of you
Teach me, and only me
Those secret onomatopoeia
Let me hear even more of them
This is a healing island
A spark-sparkly island
Overflowing with fluff-fluffy love
Seeing you all shy, and just a bit embarrassed
I press my cheek against yours
Time for a hug
(Time for a hug)
Time to hold hands