I have to get up...
I have to wake up,
brush my teeth, put makeup on,
eat some breakfast,
put my suit on, check my email...
No, I don’t!
Can you believe it?
The door-to-door commute to
my work station is just ten seconds!
Plus, I can wear whatever.
No heels necessary!
And no email to check in the morning!
It’s time to wake up, already.
It’s strange, isn’t it?
When I can sleep as late as I want,
I wake up early.
Now... Let’s have
another fun day at work!
Ah, the weather’s so nice.
I wonder which Pokémon
will be coming today.
Mizugoro?
What are you looking at?
Alisa?
Rock climbing
this early in the morning?
Is that a Gorone?
Hey! You’re supposed to
go home today.
Your trainer’s waiting for you!
Don’t be so selfish.
You’re making trouble for your trainer.
You can come back anytime.
We’ll be waiting for you.
Mizugoro, can you take
our guest to the harbor?
See ya, Gorone!
Bye! See you soon!
Alisa, you can rock climb?
I used to do it
when I was in middle school.
Don’t try to copy me, though.
It’d be too dangerous for you.
You’re incredible!
You can do so much.
Meanwhile,
I just mess up all the time...
Instead of obsessing over
stuff you’re bad at,
it’d be way more productive
to find what you’re good at.
Pidgeot flies much better
than it walks.
Gorone is faster when it rolls
than when it runs.
Humans are just like Pokémon.
Huh?
Did we have a Popokko
staying with us?
Ooh.
Guess the Hanekko
who came in yesterday evolved.
Its trainer said it was about time.
Lucky...
I want to evolve too, right now.
I love the water, but I was never
very good at swimming.
I’m a slow runner,
and can’t really cook, either.
Ah... Does making materials for
presentations count as a special talent?
You’re a Water type,
aren’t you, Koduck?
And that makes you
good at swimming, right?
Oh! That Koiking has a star birthmark!
That’s so cute!
But a floatie?
Even though he’s a Koiking?
That Koiking’s a regular.
He’s been coming here for ages.
He’s no good at swimming,
though. Just kinda sinks.
So we lend him a floatie!
Still looks like he’s having fun,
even if he can’t swim.
You should follow his example.
Instead of driving yourself nuts looking for something
you’re good at, try to find something you enjoy.
I see.
Dunno if that’ll get you
on my level, though!
A refreshing attitude
without even a shadow of modesty!
Koduck?!
Oh? Mind Power!
The floatie...
Don’t worry, esteemed guest!
I’ll go get your floatie back for you!
Please look after our guest!
Let’s go, Koduck!
Where could it have gone?
Kairyu!
Wow! What a view, eh, Koduck?
Kairyu! Over there!
Camome, wait up!
If you land, I can get that off you.
Koduck, just a little more!
Hang in there!
This is the best!
The floatie!
Wait, Kabigon!
You have to be kidding me...
Thank you, Lampler.
The concierges all take turns
staying the night in the forest area.
I’m told every now and then
a wild Pokémon will get rowdy.
Don’t worry. There doesn’t seem
to be anyone like that tonight.
How do I explain this to Koiking?
He’ll be so disappointed.
All right! I’ll do what I can to fix it!
After all, it’s going to be a long night.
Thank you!
But these won’t fix the holes.
Right! Might as well
make it look pretty, at least!
And it’s done!
I wonder if Koiking will be happy
when I show it to him tomorrow.
What’s that?
Gyarados...
That star marking!
Does that mean...? Could it be...?
Um... Here’s your floatie...?
You don’t need it, do you?
You evolved, after all.
If you work hard,
you might just suddenly evolve.
It’s bedtime!
Wonder if I can evolve from
Koiking to Gyarados, too.
Huh? They’re playing with it!
Wooper!
Are you saying
you want more floaties?
Okay, then let’s make them
for everybody!
It’s nice to see you having fun.
Yeah!
See? You do have
something you’re good at.
When will this end...?
Welcome to the place where you can be yourself
Just try to have fun, that’s all you should do
Welcome to this green, dazzling island
You don’t need a smartphone or a watch here
Forget your worries and weariness
Your job is just to have fun
You kept your nose to the grindstone
Just spinning your gears each day
But positivity isn’t the only way
You’ll learn that while you’re here
See what you have found, love is all around
This beautiful island always welcomes you
So have a good time here