Your head’s in the clouds again.
I mean, it’s a group of twelve Pikachu!
Is this what they call a miracle?!
You really love Pikachu, huh?
That fluffy look of theirs...
Those big, round, cute eyes...
It’s like they’re all
idols in the making...
Oh...
Even just watching them
from over here makes me so happy!
We have work to do,
so don’t get too carried away.
You got it!
Yeah, I know.
We’ll head out soon, Koduck.
Huh? What?
Pikachu?!
What’s wrong?
Don’t you want to
play with the others?
Pikachu!
So this is where you were!
Are you his trainer?
Yeah. Who are you?
I’m a concierge here
at the Pokémon Resort.
My name’s Haru.
Nice to meet you.
I’m... Nao.
Nao-kun, is that little guy
not so good with strangers?
Yeah. He’s really shy,
and he’s so soft-spoken.
I want Pikachu
to act more like a Pikachu!
Huh?
After all, a Pikachu’s always
gotta be cute and energetic!
I wanted to get him
to speak louder at least,
but no matter how much we train,
nothing ever works.
Is that so?
But then I asked
other Pikachu trainers for advice,
and they invited me to
this offline meetup at the Pokémon Resort.
I see.
Okay, Pikachu. Go play!
Come on! Brighten up!
They all look like
they’re having fun.
Hey, how about you
come and play with us, Nao-kun?
Huh?
There’s lots of places here
where you and Pikachu can play together.
Hey, Pikachu...
Would you like to play with me?
Is he gonna be all right?
Let’s let Haru-san
take care of things.
You see? There’s all kinds of things
to play with here.
I wanna get on that!
Pikachu, come with me!
Come on, Koduck.
Show Pikachu how fun this can be.
Koduck is so funny!
Pikachu, you have to do it
even cooler, okay?
Okay, Nao-kun,
why don’t you go with Pikachu—?
I’ll go first, okay?
So you just copy me!
Here I go!
Huh? You’re going?!
I’m off!
There’s nothing to be scared of!
Come on, Pikachu!
Time to give it a shot, Pikachu!
Huh? Pikachu?
Could it be
you’re afraid of heights?
That wasn’t cool at all, Pikachu.
I’m sorry. I didn’t mean
to scare Pikachu.
Miss, can you think of anything else
that could help Pikachu speak louder?
Huh?
Yahoo!
Isn’t that fun?
Go on, give it a try!
Pikachu!
C’mon, you try it too, Pikachu!
Ready, set...
Operation Mountain Echo: failed.
Next one!
Oh, yeah...
Time to dig in!
It’s spicy!
Operation Crying Out
With Spicy Food: failed.
Next one!
Operation Big Scare: failed...
Haru... Is she gonna be okay?
She’s just fine.
Just another day
for Haru-san, you know?
That’s for sure.
Delicious!
Miss, do you think that
my Pikachu might be sick?
I’m no doctor
so I couldn’t say for sure,
but he doesn’t look sick.
What’s up?
It’s nothing.
What else...? We could try making him sneeze,
or give him a pressure point foot massage?
Oh...
Looks like they fell asleep.
Th-They’re so cute!
A picture!
I have to take a picture of this!
Oh, no! I forgot to charge it!
A battery!
Is there another battery?
This doesn’t really
look like Pikachu at all.
Pikachu are supposed to have
big, round, cute eyes,
and they’re everyone’s idols, and...
Hmm?
After all, a Pikachu’s always
gotta be cute and energetic!
Nao-kun,
once Pikachu and Koduck wake up,
how about we go to the beach?
They look like they’re having fun.
All kinds of guests come here.
We’ve had a Yomawaru
who was afraid of the dark,
a meek Delvil,
and an Odoridori
who was too embarrassed to dance.
Isn’t that something?
When I first started here, I thought to myself
“I need to pull myself together and grow up!”,
and “I need to be a cool concierge!”
I thought that way for a long time.
But once you start thinking like that,
it’s hard to shake it off.
So, as for Pikachu... Do you really need to
force him into being more “Pikachu-like”?
Even if he isn’t loud,
or isn’t any good at battles,
a Pikachu is still a Pikachu.
Don’t you think?
To be frank,
I brainstormed a bunch more ideas to bring out
Pikachu’s voice, but none of them sounded promising.
I’m sorry!
But to make it up to you,
let me show you something fun!
Huh?
Let’s go, Koduck!
What was all that about, Koduck?!
Come on! Now it’s your turn, Pikachu!
Let’s do it together, Pikachu!
Well then, see you
at next year’s meetup!
Fare thee well!
Miss!
He never did speak up, did he?
I’m sorry I wasn’t much help there.
Nuh-uh.
I had so much fun!
And I think Pikachu
had a great time, too.
You think so?
I’m happy to hear it!
Not only that, but I learned a lot of
great things about my Pikachu!
Really?
Can we come and
play here again sometime?
Of course!
Let’s play together when you come back!
Pikachu, consider this
your souvenir photo.
The ship’s about to depart!
C’mon. Let’s go, Pikachu!
Pikachu, I’m glad
you made some friends!
We should be heading back.
Yeah.
And I should get started on lunch.
Huh?
Welcome to the place where you can be yourself
Was that the shy little Pikachu?
Just try to have fun, that’s all you should do
Let’s play together again, Pikachu!
Welcome to this green, dazzling island
You don’t need a smartphone or a watch here
It’s all thanks to Haru.
Not bad at all, Haru.
Not at all...
I didn’t do a thing.
It was Koduck.
Huh? Are you crying?
Forget your worries and weariness
‘Cause...
I’m so happy for you, Pikachu!
Your job is just to have fun
All right! Time to
do my best again today!
You kept your nose to the grindstone
Let’s go, Koduck!
Just spinning your gears each day
But positivity isn’t the only way
And after all that...
You’ll learn that while you’re here
I find myself here!
Let me show you around the dreamy place you stay
Everyone is smiling
Hello. This is the Pokémon Resort.
Oh, yes.
You’ll feel better soon
Yes, of course. We’ll be waiting.
Haru-san, could you
come here for a moment?
Okay!
I hear a guest with a reservation
will be arriving soon.
I wonder who it is!
Maybe Pippi?
Or maybe it’s Mimikkyu?
At a paradise with no rules...
My goodness gracious.
Haru-san, could you go and greet
our guest at the port?
Y-Yes!
...all the freedom might feel a little strange
Huh? Nobody’s here yet...
But you’ll soon discover your true self, and what matters most
Huh...?!
Welcome to the Pokémon Resort!
If you dream of singing a tune as you cross a colorful bridge
You’ll see it doesn’t take much for happiness to be yours
See what you have found, love is all around
This beautiful island always treats you well
Just try to have fun, that’s what you should do
This beautiful island always welcomes you
So have a good time here