And there you have it.
Well... goodbye.
Last week, on Saturday, my boyfriend of
six and a half years broke up with me by text.
The next day, Sunday, I stepped in gum
while wearing my favorite shoes.
On Monday,
I was late for a vital presentation.
On Tuesday,
a colleague I was close to quit.
Wednesday,
I trimmed my eyebrows all wrong.
Thursday, the curry I spent
three hours making tasted terrible.
Friday, I messed up
a vital presentation.
And on Sunday,
I stepped in gum again!
And because of that,
I am now here.
Daddy! Look at the Camome!
You can see the island!
Come on, let’s get going!
The Pokémon Resort...
I’m really here!
Fushigidane!
Huh? Is that for me?
Thank you!
You’re the new employee, yes?
The boat ride must have
been exhausting!
Oh! Are you part of the staff?
I’ll be working here starting today.
My name is Haru.
I’m Watanabe.
Haru-san, welcome to
the Pokémon Resort.
Right!
Thank you so much.
The Pokémon really do
come here as guests!
See you later, Metagross!
As you can see,
people and Pokémon
can have fun separately.
Wow!
We also have Pokémon on staff.
And sometimes...
What’s this? A Wooper?
Much like this one,
some wild Pokémon settle down here.
Around here,
our motto is “Pokémon first.”
And our job...
...is to look after these Pokémon.
In other words,
you’ll be the Pokémon concierge.
Concierge...
What is this?!
What’s going on?
Koratta?
H—
Huh?
Okay, that’s enough.
Ootachi, no fighting here, got it?
Let’s get you somewhere
a little more spacious.
It’s also a concierge’s job
to keep our guests safe.
Now then, I know you’ve just arrived
but I’ve got a very important job for you.
R-Right!
I’d like for you
to spend the day as a guest.
A guest?
But I’m staff...
Well, then... Make yourself at home!
Right...
Could it be... I’m being tested?!
Whoa!
I think I’ll have this!
Hey, I wanna try those lessons!
Heya! There ya are!
Wanna give it a try?
Pleased to meet you.
It’s my first day of work today—
Yeah! You’re Haru, right?
Name’s Tyler. Sanitation.
And fitness lessons, just for fun.
Nice to meetcha!
Ah, I see...
Wh-Who are these?
Staff Pokémon. Guess you could
call ‘em my right-hand crew.
They can be real pranksters,
so you’d better watch out.
Huh?
So, I’ll be—
Yeah! You’ll be doing it, right?
Excuse me?
Are you kidding me?
Good thing you did warm-ups, huh?
Come back any time!
I also teach swimming,
yoga, and wakeboarding!
Right...
You’re taking a trip
‘round the resort, yeah?
Go ahead and use those kick scooters!
Hurry up! I’m leaving without you!
Wait for us!
I’ve never been on
one of these before!
That said...
So much for seniority.
He didn’t teach me anything.
It really is a Pokémon paradise!
All right! Just like that!
Excuse me!
My name is Haru,
and I started working here today.
Nice to meet you!
I’m Alisa.
I work here part-time every summer.
Pleasure.
Oh, the pleasure is all—
Huh? Part-time?
Mizugoro!
Wait, is it...?
Yeah.
Just started following me around one day.
Did you really?
You’re so cute!
It does that sometimes,
even when it’s happy.
So... What’s up?
Well, today is my first day.
And I have no idea
what I’m supposed to be doing.
Do what you want.
Weren’t you supposed to
spend the day as a guest?
I mean... That’s what
I was told to do, but...
Whoa! The pressure is intense!
Am I going to get lectured?
Come with me.
The old “meet me
behind the gym” cliché?
Yeah, I guess that’ll do.
In here Pokémon can
get all stylish too, right?
Trimming makes up the basics, but...
Getting something like
a new hairdo or a matching outfit...
...seems to make Pokémon
pretty happy, too.
Well, this kind of thing’s
what the job is all about.
This kind of thing...?
Hey! Lunch is almost ready!
Huh? We get free meals here?
Tyler’s cooking. It’s pretty good.
Blue skies...
Blue sea...
A tasty lunch amid the sea breeze...
This is bliss!
Thanks for the food!
The Pokémon Resort is the best!
I’ve needed this...
Um... Is it true that
I can get a massage here...?
Yes.
Please come right this way.
What? From you, Watanabe-san?
That’s right.
I’m so skilled I can make
any Pokémon fall asleep with a touch.
Yeah, but maybe... I don’t know...
Just leave it to me!
Um... I met some of the other staff...
They’re all pretty interesting, right?
Yeah. They’re definitely unique...
Come to think of it...
Both of them had Pokémon with them...
That’s right.
As a matter of course, you become friends
and then they just stay with you.
I’m sure there’s a Pokémon
you’ll get along with, too.
I can’t wait...
Ma’am?
Okay, that was not good!
I got way too relaxed!
And I fell asleep
in front of my supervisor!
I need to fix this.
Did you sleep well last night?
Uh... Sure.
So, then...
What did you think?
Could you give me your impressions?
Right here!
What’s this?
Right! I built a report on my activities yesterday
and drafted a personal work plan!
The Pokémon Resort prides itself
in its luxurious atmosph—
Hold on.
As much as I appreciate
that you compiled all that data,
that was not quite
what I wanted to hear.
I-I’m so sorry!
I just compiled it in a way that would
work for me... I’ll give it another...
Say, Haru-san...
How did yesterday go?
When you ask me “how”...
What am I supposed to answer?!
Haru-san?
Is something the matter?
No... It was just... funny...
What’s funny?
The Pokémon here are doing
what they want and having fun,
and when I saw that, I started feeling
like I was stupid to worry so much.
I’ve just had nothing but
bad experiences as of late.
And it made me wonder,
what even is my life?!
But I’ve been having so much fun that
all those gloomy feelings just faded away!
Oh... I’m sorry!
This is supposed to be my job,
and here I talk about it like a little kid...
No, that is exactly
what I wanted to hear.
Huh?
As long as you understand that,
you’ll do just fine.
This here is proof
that you are a concierge.
The only rule is
you need to wear this.
Aside from that, you can do
whatever you please.
Here.
Thanks...
So then, what exactly is my job?
Well, I have one request.
Find one Pokémon—any will do—
and before the sun sets,
I want you to make that Pokémon
feel the same way that you do.
A crazy hard mission right off the bat!
I acted like I understood,
but I have no idea what was
“just fine” about what I said.
What do I do?
Koduck?
Welcome to the place where you can be yourself
Just try to have fun, that’s all you should do
Welcome to this green, dazzling island
You don’t need a smartphone or a watch here
Forget your worries and weariness
Your job is just to have fun
You kept your nose to the grindstone
Just spinning your gears each day
But positivity isn’t the only way
You’ll learn that while you’re here
See what you have found, love is all around
This beautiful island always welcomes you
So have a good time here