Wha—? Are they fighting?!
E-Esteemed guests!
We all have to play nice here!
Oh, you were just playing around?
Gosh... You just have
such scary faces...
Ah, Ootachi?
Are you at it again?
Don’t do that!
You need to play nice.
Uh... Um...
Hey... Calm down...
Hold on!
Ootachi! Koratta!
Geez!
Does this work?
Maybe over here?
What is she... doing?
Trying to get better reception.
She said she wants to look some
stuff up about Pokémon.
Ah. Reception’s super lousy here.
More like, don’t even
bother with your cell phone.
I did the same kind of stuff
when I was new here.
I gave up by day three.
Mm-hmm...
Totally getcha, Haru.
No luck here either, huh?
Oh...
Sure, you can tell me
to entertain the Pokémon...
But I have no idea how to do that.
I want you to make that Pokémon
feel the same way that you do.
Watanabe-san...
For someone with such a gentle face, she sure dumped
one crazy hard mission on me right out the gate.
What am I gonna do?
Why the long face?
Oh, no reason...
So, Alisa-san, you can paint too?
Anybody can paint.
Anyway, could you drop
the formal tone already?
But you’ve been here longer...
And?
Here, take this.
Huh? You want me to...
So? Going through the “No idea
what I should be doing” thing again?
I want to help the Pokémon have fun,
but nothing I try seems to work out.
For a start, you should just figure out
what they want and then make it happen.
The Pokémon don’t tell me
what they want me to do, though.
Not like humans are gonna
give it to you straight either.
They’ll go, like, “Take a guess.”
Huh?
That’s true.
Hey, is that a Koduck?
You a fan? Nice work!
Uh, no... Well, yeah.
It’s actually a Pikachu.
Well, figuring it out yourself
is what makes it fun.
You sure went all out here.
Well, I guess you don’t get to
fly around free much in the big city.
You were just
letting off some steam.
Don’t worry about the paintings.
You should play somewhere
more open, so nobody else gets hurt.
See?
You can’t really predict what
a Pokémon’s gonna do, right?
Right.
Ow, ow, ow...
So, if you could
give me any advice or...
It’s always hard at first.
Guess you should just start
with what you can do, yeah?
And, uh... Is there
anything that I can do...?
Don’t ask me!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Huh?
Tyler-san, what’s with that one?
Koduck, you mean?
Heard Watanabe-san took it in.
It’s been here about two weeks.
But it’s super shy, so it hasn’t really
tried to make contact with anybody
It doesn’t seem to be having fun.
All right! I choose you!
Hey! Koduck!
Koduck?
Koduck!
Oh, Koduck...
Hmm... If that’s how
it’s gonna be...
Let’s see... “Koduck perpetually
suffers from a headache,” eh?
Poor thing.
“And the more intense the headache,
the more potent its Mind Power becomes.”
“The way to control
its Mind Power is...”
Huh?
What? What?
Whoa! Paranormal activity?!
Huh...?
Huh?
Huh?!
Koduck...
Its Mind Power is going berserk!
Oh, come on! Where’d you go?
I’m not mad at you,
so come on out.
Ah!
There you are!
T-Tyler-san!
Aw, man...
Are you okay?
I-I-I... I’m sorry!
Why were you in such a rush?
I was chasing Koduck
when this Digda popped up...
And I tried to dodge but the scooter went all
“Wuoom!” and I couldn’t stop and then, “Boom!”
Whoa, now...
No need to panic.
But... What about...?
It was jam for the pies
I’m making for dessert, but...
...I can make it again
with those berries there.
I reckon my crew
are picking some now.
I’ll go carry them!
All... right...
Hey! Take the cart with you!
Thanks for all your help,
Yanape, Baope, Hiyape!
But where did Koduck go?
Huh?
What’s...? Err...
Ugh, just...
Wait!
You’re a lifesaver!
I’m so glad you were there!
You don’t have to run, Koduck.
No one here’s
upset with you, all right?
Are you, perhaps, self-conscious
about your Mind Power?
When you get a headache,
Mind Power activates, right?
I wonder if there’s any way
to prevent it from going berserk...
Look, it’s ‘cause you keep
shooting all the water out at once.
If you spray just a little,
you won’t knock the flowers over.
Why don’t you try using Mind Power in small
bursts so you can control it better, Koduck?
Don’t just let the pain build up.
Try using Mind Power.
Tyler-san!
Hmm? Ooh!
You got caught, huh, Koduck?
Whoa! Automatic berry splitting!
Way to go, Koduck!
All right! Let’s keep it up!
Whoa!
Dad!
What the heck?!
No, no! This! Focus on this!
Koduck! Let me down!
Nice one, Koduck.
Thank you.
The lids on these tins
are so hard to open.
These chocolates come in
all these different cute colors.
They kinda look like Pokémon.
See, this color is Hanekko.
Here’s Mizugoro. Fushigidane.
Ah, the yellow one is Pikach—
Actually, it’s Koduck!
When I was a kid, I’d dream of getting to eat
all the chocolate I wanted when I grew up.
It’s nice how much
freedom adults have.
Koduck... Can you toss me
some chocolates with Mind Power?
Here, like this.
You’re amazing!
Hang on!
I can’t eat that many!
Koduck.
Well? Are you having fun?
Koduck!
May tomorrow be another
fun day with the Pokémon.
Welcome to the place where you can be yourself
Just try to have fun, that’s all you should do
Welcome to this green, dazzling island
You don’t need a smartphone or a watch here
Forget your worries and weariness
Your job is just to have fun
You kept your nose to the grindstone
Just spinning your gears each day
But positivity isn’t the only way
You’ll learn that while you’re here
See what you have found, love is all around
This beautiful island always welcomes you
So have a good time here