Are you all doing okay?
Hold on, Todoggler! Calm down...
Hey!
You good?
I’m... all... good...
Huh? The ship’s being suspended?!
Yes. I’m afraid a member of the crew
is quitting next week,
and they just can’t
make it work without them.
Sounds like they’re way overdue
for some new staff.
We’re short-handed
over here, too.
You have a point...
Um, have you seen Todoggler?
Todoggler!
Hey!
Stop!
Now there’s a lively one!
Haru! Alisa!
Can I get a little help?
Coming!
Yeah, coming...
Hey! Wait!
Go! Yanappe, Baoppe, Hiyappe!
All right!
Todoggler! Stop!
All right! Good!
Sorry my Todoggler
is causing you so much trouble.
Man, you’re a lifesaver, Uncle Dan!
“Uncle”?
He used to look after me
when I was only like, this big!
Uncle’d let us on his boat
all the time!
Boat?
I was a fisherman
until fairly recently.
Amazing!
Uncle used to be
this macho back then!
He was real scary!
And if I ever played pranks,
he’d go “Hey, you!”...
...yelling with the scariest
look on his face!
What?!
I can’t picture that at all!
All right. Here you go!
You’re a real pro, Todoggler!
Now, now! Quiet down.
Todoggler really loves you, Mr. Dan.
I actually met it on my ship.
It was still
just a Tamazarashi back then...
I was out at sea, fishing on my boat
as usual, when suddenly...
...a Tamazarashi that was swimming by
hopped right onto my boat.
I kept trying to put it
back in the sea,
but every time I did,
it would leap back onto the boat.
Seemed to love being petted.
It grew real attached to me,
and before I knew it, it had won me over.
We’ve been joined at the hip ever since...
...and then one day, it finally evolved
from Tamazarashi to Todoggler.
You really must have worked hard,
Todoggler!
Good stuff, Uncle!
I never thought
it’d grow this big, though.
How’s Todoggler at home?
You live in an apartment, right?
You don’t live near the ocean?
No...
Unfortunately, my son and his wife
insisted I live near them.
I moved back when it was still a Tamazarashi,
and thought I could manage then...
They’re not even close to
the same size, after all.
Guess you keep it in its Monster Ball
most of the time, then?
About all I can do is let it out
at the nearby park every now and then.
It’s been ages since it’s been able to
run and swim in such an open space,
so it’s really excited, y’know?
But if it’s causing trouble
for all of you...
Don’t you worry!
This is a place for Pokémon
to have the time of their lives!
See you soon!
I brought snacks!
Mr. Dan! Ready when you are!
Wow!
Todoggler really seems to be having a blast.
Isn’t it just adorable?
Yeah...
I haven’t seen Todoggler this happy
in a very long time.
How long have you been
with Todoggler?
Fifteen years by now, I’d say.
It was so small
back when it was a Tamazarashi.
It’d waddle around on its stumpy little legs
and roll around like a ball whenever it was in a good mood...
It’s given me... so much joy...
Ah, Mr. Tyler...
Good morning...
I see... I see...
Huh?!
Yes...
Right.
Please keep looking
over on your end as well.
Like we figured,
he hasn’t gone back to his room.
It seems there’s nobody in the salon
who’s seen Mr. Dan either.
No, huh?
Where could Mr. Dan have gone
that he’d leave Todoggler behind?
You checked around the tents
over here, right?
He wasn’t here, either.
Tyler, did you check by the river?
Tyler?
Oh... Right.
Sorry.
Uh...
I’ll go check by the waterfall again.
I’m coming with you.
A-Ah... Todoggler!
Mr. Tyler...
You don’t think Mr. Dan might have...
...gotten on the ship...?
Huh?
It’s just about to set sail!
I’ll go take a look!
Ah! There!
Mr. Dan!
Mr. Dan...
Why?
Todoggler?
We have currently stopped for safety checks.
Mommy! What’s the Todoggler doing?
We ask that you remain patient...
...until we are able to proceed.
Pardon... Excuse me.
Please let me through.
Todoggler! It’s dangerous here!
Get away from the ship!
Go back to the port!
We will be temporarily returning
to the Pokémon Resort.
We apologize for any delays
to passengers in a hurry...
Todoggler!
Sorry...
I’m so sorry.
Mr. Dan... Why?
Uncle...
You were attempting to
abandon Todoggler here, were you not?
Ms. Watanabe...
“Abandon”? Don’t say that...
That is what leaving your Pokémon
without permission is called.
May I ask why?
Todoggler is a real rowdy Pokémon,
as you can see...
I felt it was just getting to be
too much for me to handle...
You should have known from the beginning
that Pokémon get bigger as they evolve.
If you’re unwilling to stay with it until the end,
then you are not qualified to raise it.
I know.
Uncle...
Mr. Tyler?
Ms. Haru.
Mr. Dan. Mr. Tyler always talked about
how strong and manly you were,
and how proud he was
to have you as his uncle.
You were his hero, one could say.
Sorry for all the trouble
I’ve caused you.
You’ve always been
crazy single-minded.
You’d never go back on
anything you set your mind to.
That’s what I thought.
I can’t believe how pathetic I am.
Back when it was still a Tamazarashi,
things were manageable.
But then it evolved into Todoggler,
and suddenly I started worrying about the future.
The future?
It will keep on growing.
Someday, it might even
become a Todoserga.
And that’s why I thought
living a laid-back life...
...in a wide open place like this
might make it happier.
That’s just a lame, easy excuse!
Tyler...
Back when I was a kid, didn’t you always say
“No making excuses!”?
Uncle, are you really fine with
parting ways with Todoggler?
I don’t want to leave it either!
But watching Todoggler yesterday made me think
that it’d be a lot happier living here...
...instead of living
in a tiny apartment with me.
I see.
I know what to do, Uncle.
Huh?
Please!
Let Todoggler stay here!
Tyler...
Please! I beg you!
Him trying to leave it without permission
was totally unacceptable,
but Todoggler’s done
nothing wrong!
So...
Looking after Todoggler
will be no easy task.
I’ll take full responsibility for it!
You can’t.
You’d be neglecting your work duties.
Please keep in mind
that you are still a concierge.
I’ll help, too.
So please let Todoggler stay here.
Alisa...
What do you think, Ms. Haru?
Huh? Me?
I also...
...plan to help out, of course...
But...
I’m not sure
if that’s really for the best.
Haru...
Being separated from Mr. Dan...
I have to wonder what will actually
make Todoggler the happiest...
You have a point.
Only Todoggler
knows the answer to that.
Very well.
We will look after Todoggler.
Todoggler seems to get along quite well
with the other Pokémon.
I’m sure it will liven up
the island for everyone.
Thank you so much!
But I have one condition.
Yes! Whatever you ask.
Mr. Dan.
Come work here.
That way, you can stay
with Todoggler, yes?
But I...
I could never, not after what I put
all of you and Todoggler through...
What you did was wrong.
But it was a mistake made
out of love for your Pokémon.
I believe you can do good
by the Pokémon who stay here.
Well done, Todoggler!
You’re great!
I’m sorry...
I’m so sorry, Todoggler...
Ms. Watanabe...
Thank you so much!
Ms. Watanabe!
Ms. Watanabe, you’re the best!
I look forward to
working with you all!
All right, Todoggler!
Time to play!
Great, Todoggler! Keep it up!
Over here too, Todoggler!
For so long, I’d been looking for you
And at last, I found you on this island
What a beautiful sunset this is
I’m glad I got to see it with you
When I was alone
When I felt lonely
I would think of you
Teach me, and only me
Those secret onomatopoeia
Let me hear even more of them
This is a healing island
A spark-sparkly island
Overflowing with fluff-fluffy love
Seeing you all shy, and just a bit embarrassed
I press my cheek against yours
Time for a hug
(Time for a hug)
Time to hold hands