It might be hard to ride at first,
but if you just learn the trick to
keeping your balance, you’ll be fine.
Balance, you say...
When you turn, you just gotta shift
your body weight a little bit over to one leg.
Right.
It might not be smooth sailing
right away...
I see. The trick’s pretty similar
to taking the helm, then?
Got it.
No way!
You learned that way too fast!
Well, that just goes to show
how well you taught me, Ms. Haru!
Todoggler! You’re here!
Now, now...
Wait for me, Todoggler.
Wait!
Ah, wait! Please don’t just
go off on your own!
Sheesh!
Mr. Dan, please wait up!
Now what...?
Hup!
Yes! Very good, Koiking!
When did you teach
Koiking party tricks?
Party tricks?
Oh, you give me too much credit.
Anyone can do this if they know
how to make use of Koiking’s talents.
Todoggler!
You’ll soak me again!
All right, stop!
No splashing water on Ms. Haru.
I’m so sorry. Seems like it got carried away
from having too much fun.
The water temperature might be
a tad too low for Koiking...
Given today’s water temp,
we might want to move them somewhere else.
Would that be okay?
Y-Yes, of course!
Ah! I’ll help you!
No need to concern yourself.
Todoggler! Take them downstream!
Counting on you, Todoggler!
He’s already acting like
a proper team player!
Mr. Tyler!
Could you take over the job
of educating Mr. Dan for me?
Educating?
Why don’t you just have him
look at what you usually do?
But I really don’t have
much experience yet...
Which makes me think it’d be better
to have him learn from your example.
Nah! Uncle used to be
super scary back in the day.
If he glares at me,
I’ll freeze up on the spot!
So there’s no way I could do it.
Huh? H-He’s that scary?
It’ll be fine, it’ll be fine!
You won’t get yelled at.
Huh...?
So, you take good care
of Uncle for me, Coach Haru!
Ms. Haru!
What should we do next?
Th-This is tough...
My, what a magnificent field!
Heyo, Mr. Dan!
Hard at work, I see.
Whoa... Haru really is teaching you.
Things going okay?
Or is she causing you trouble?
Far from it.
I’m learning plenty!
I-I’m giving it my all...
Well then, Mr. Dan,
should we help out in the field?
Sure!
Ooh, you’ll help too?
How diligent!
A berry? Isn’t that nice?
Water! Water! Water, water!
The wind’s strong today,
so let’s not light any bonfires, okay?
A-Are you all right?!
I’m just glad
that didn’t turn into a big fire.
I am so sorry, Mr. Dan.
I know there’s so much I need to teach you,
but I just keep messing up...
Oh, no, I...
Huh?
Koduck?!
What is it? Is it feeling unwell?
Alisa!
Here!
Firewood chopped!
What is this?
My little pal isn’t good at
controlling its Mind Power.
So whenever it looks like it’s about to activate,
I try to find something it can let the power out on.
There’s been times where I was too slow,
and it caused a huge ruck—
Oh!
K-Koduck?
Ah! Not those!
Nice catch, Haru!
Ohh, I’m hopeless!
Right? I was completely hopeless,
wasn’t I, Koduck?
And here I wanted to
act like a good coach...
I thought for sure
I’d grown a little bit more than that...
At the end of the day,
I’m just not cut out to teach.
I’ll tell Ms. Watanabe and have
someone else take over from this afternoon!
Yeah! That’s what I’ll do!
Oh, you...
I mean it!
I was honestly impressed!
Um, Ms. Watanabe...
I’d like to ask you...
Ah, Ms. Haru.
We were just talking about you.
Huh?
I-I’m sorry!
I’m sure I must have been a bother...
Oh, not at all! I was telling them
how admirably you do your work!
B-But all I’ve done today is trip, get splashed,
drop berries... Absolutely nothing worth...
I never would’ve thought someone would be
that direct in dealing with Pokémon!
Huh?
I’m certain that’s why Koduck trusts you so much,
and always stays by your side!
Well, it’s true...
...that Haru caused no end of trouble
together with Koduck when she first got here...
But she’s gotten way more calm
and relaxed these days. Not to mention capable!
Huh? Wha...?!
Wh-What?
I never thought I’d get to
hear you praise me!
I-I’m kinda happy,
but this is so embarrassing!
I shouldn’t have praised you.
It may be difficult for me
to become quite like you,
but I’ll work hard
with that goal in mind.
G-Goal?
We’re counting on you
as his coach.
Good luck this afternoon.
Huh? Ah... Okay.
Uhh... This morning,
we went from here to here, right?
We had a look at the field, too, so...
Mr. Dan! Next up...
Huh? Mr. Dan?
All right!
Nice!
Dedenne! You’re here too?
Mr. Dan.
Ah! Oh, I’m so sorry!
I shouldn’t be playing around
while I’m at work!
I took plenty of photos
when I first got here, too.
Is that so?
Well, you don’t get to
see a Kabigon all too often,
so I was really happy
to get a shot of it with Todoggler!
Here, have a look!
Oh! You’re right!
They’re adorable!
There are so many Pokémon
I’ve never seen before...
Oh, I know! Do you mind if
I send this to my son and his wife?
Ah... Well, no, but...
They said they’d come visit
one of these days.
Huh? That’s weird.
I’m not getting a signal...
The signal’s bad on this island.
I was running around trying to get a signal too,
back when I first got here.
Oh, I see.
That’s a shame.
Somebody help!
Alisa? Let’s move!
Ah, yes!
Hey, I said stop! Sheesh!
What’s wrong?
They were just playing around at first,
but now they’ve gotten really riled up...
Todoggler!
Are you okay, Todoggler?
What should we do?!
Hey, you!
Quit your squabbling!
Well? I want you to make up!
Mr. Dan... really is terrifying, huh...?
Totally wild...
Oh... I was better at that
when I was younger,
but I hope I was some help,
nonetheless.
Yes... Glad you were here...
It’s just...
It looks like
you’ve scared everyone stiff.
I-I’m so sorry!
I didn’t mean to...
Well, then...
Next, let’s play with the Pokémon!
Wow! Mr. Dan and Todoggler
are doing something that looks really fun!
All right! Here I go, Todoggler!
Hup!
Yes! Very good!
‘Kay, let’s all give it a try!
Here I go, Koduck!
Ready, and...
Huh...? How come?
Mr. Dan!
Once more, if you would!
‘Course.
Hup!
Whoa, amazing!
You want to try, Eevee?
Hup.
Incredible!
Well done, Eevee!
Man... It never would’ve turned out
this well if I was in charge of him.
Ms. Watanabe, did you have Haru train him
‘cause you knew it’d go like this?
There are some things
only Ms. Haru can do.
For so long, I’d been looking for you
And at last, I found you on this island
What a beautiful sunset this is
I’m glad I got to see it with you
When I was alone
When I felt lonely
I would think of you
Teach me, and only me
Those secret onomatopoeia
Let me hear even more of them
This is a healing island
A spark-sparkly island
Overflowing with fluff-fluffy love
Seeing you all shy, and just a bit embarrassed
I press my cheek against yours
Time for a hug
(Time for a hug)
Time to hold hands