Attention, all trainers.
Due to today’s bad weather,
we are closing all outdoor facilities.
All trainers, as well as all Pokémon,
please make use
of our indoor facilities.
Haru, watch out for the mud!
All right...!
The water level’s
way higher than usual.
Oh, dear...
I’ll go check on
the Koiking upstream!
You go on ahead and
get these Pokémon to the lobby!
A-All right!
But don’t push yourself too hard!
Of course! You be careful, too!
The river’s flowing crazy fast!
Even the bridge was washed away...
Eevee?!
What are you doing over there?!
I’ll save you right away, okay?
Fushigidane, help me out!
Slowly... Slowly, now...
Don’t worry, Eevee!
You’re safe now!
Wait, Eevee!
Huh?
Windie?!
Thank you!
W-Wait! Hey!
Huh?
Do we... know each other...?
Windie!
Are you all right?
Ah, yes, thank...
Kento?!
Huh?
Haru?!
Haru?
Huh?
Your hair’s still wet.
Ah, sorry...
Thank you.
You’ve been here
since yesterday, huh?
I was off work yesterday, so...
I see.
So, uh... Sorry that our reunion
after so long turned out like this.
Don’t be.
I’m glad to see you’re doing well.
Mommy, there’s something outside!
That’s gotta be her ex, yeah?
For real?
He’s not someone sketchy, is he?!
Now, now, Uncle.
You’re not her dad.
What’s up, Koduck?
Bet it’s worried
that he might steal Haru.
But... I sure didn’t expect this.
Huh?
For you to be working
in a place like this.
A place like... this?
I mean... Around this time last year,
you were working crazy hard on presentations...
...and going all over for work
wearing high heels. And now...
Now I’m completely drenched, covered in mud,
and going around wearing sandals and jerseys.
Well, uh...
Sorry.
No worries.
I became area manager.
Really? Congratulations!
Thank you.
Thought I’d reward myself a little,
so I came here with Windie.
I see.
It seems like the rain’ll let up tomorrow,
so enjoy your stay, okay?
Thank you.
What a shock!
I never would have thought
Kento would come here!
Oh, the nostalgia!
I think this is from we went on a trip,
just the two of us...
Look, Koduck.
What’s that look for?
Yes, I went through that phase.
Kento’s gotten more mature.
But... he seemed kind of exhausted.
Yup.
The rain’s passed, so tomorrow we should
give Kento and Windie the time of their lives!
What’s going on over there?
Ah, that’s an obstacle course where...
Goodness, all of you...
Is there a rare Pokémon here
or something?
U-Uh... Gotta get back to work!
Todoggler!
Hey!
Full of energy, as always...
Yup.
Let’s eat!
Let’s eat.
It’s great.
Mizugorou! There, there...
I got soaked again!
Sorry. I’m just a mess today.
No...
Kento? What’s wrong?
Haru...
Were you really doing so bad
that you had to escape to a place like this?
I’m sorry I never noticed.
Huh?
Uhh...
Haru! Can you come
help sort through these berries?
Ah, okay! I’ll be right there!
Sorry, I’ll be right back.
Okay.
Even in a place like this,
Haru-san is giving everything her all.
Uh, no, I didn’t mean...
Sorry.
Haru-san may be a bit clumsy, but it’s my opinion
that she is well suited for this kind of work.
Because there’s nobody who thinks
and cares about others more than her.
She came by early and told me
Windie’s leg looked terribly dry,
and so she wanted
some massage cream for it.
She is a highly adept worker who can notice
small details that even the trainer would miss.
Huh?
And this?
That goes over here.
Ah, okay.
Same for this one.
Mm-hmm.
The view from here is the best!
Wow!
I really love this island.
You’re not wrong,
I basically ran away here at first...
But now I’m really glad I came.
I see...
Of course.
Look!
The whole staff built it together!
It was really hard.
Took us two wholes months.
But it’s a big hit with the Pokémon!
Watch this, Windie.
Woo! Feels great!
Whoa!
See? You try it too, Kento, Windie!
Sure.
Geez... Stuff like this
really makes her act like a kid.
Kento, what was all that?
Don’t laugh...
Koduck, what are you doing?
I’m glad.
Huh?
You finally laughed.
It really is fun being with you.
Huh?
What is it, Koduck?
Huh? Where’s Windie?
Hmm? Didn’t it come down
with Koduck...?
What’s the big idea, Windie?
C’mon, I’ll pull you out.
Hey...
Kento, I think that’s hurting Windie.
Sorry, Windie!
Oh, I know! If I just put it back
in the Monster Ball...
Uh... Ball... Ball...
Huh? Where’s the ball?
Koduck, help me out.
Huh?
Windie.
I want you to
relax your muscles, okay?
Tickle, tickle, tickle...
How’s that?
Tickle, tickle, tickle,
tickle, tickle, tickle, tickle...
Haru?
Windie!
What a relief!
Are you okay?
You’re not hurt anywhere?
Yeah, looks just fine.
Haru, what did you do?
I just made it laugh,
so that it would stop overexerting itself.
Overexerting?
Windie just now was a lot
like how I used to be.
Huh?
Always working hard,
trying to refine myself...
Struggling like crazy,
but never actually making any headway.
But I was really just
overexerting myself for nothing.
Desperately trying to
tense up my arms and legs...
Haru...
Once I realized that, I thought I’d just
try and stop overexerting myself.
Let loose all my tension,
laugh as hard as I could...
And then I was able to
move forward with ease.
Ever since I came here,
I haven’t needed to overexert myself...
But because of that,
I’ve been able to give it my all.
I must say...
You’re really cool
the way you are now.
Huh?! Th-Th-That’s not true at all!
Haru, I...
Yeah?
Never mind.
I’m all refreshed, so starting tomorrow,
I think I’ll be able to give it my all at work.
Really? That’s great to hear!
Right, Windie?
Haru.
Hmm?
Thank you.
No, thank you!
What’s wrong, Koduck?
There’s a good Windie...
You too, Koduck...
So, ready to start another day?
There are sunny days...
There are rainy days...
Sometimes even stormy days...
But no matter the weather,
you can find a way to have fun.
Sure, sometimes things just
don’t turn out the way you want,
but you can get over it
if you just keep smiling.
Because there are so many
fun friends here!
Hey!
Over here!
Did you have fun, Windie?
Bye bye!
Come back sometime!
Let’s have fun together again!
With all that said...
Right here...
...is where I am!
For so long, I’d been looking for you
And at last, I found you on this island
What a beautiful sunset this is
I’m glad I got to see it with you
When I was alone
When I felt lonely
I would think of you
Teach me, and only me
Those secret onomatopoeia
Let me hear even more of them
This is a healing island
A spark-sparkly island
Overflowing with fluff-fluffy love
Seeing you all shy, and just a bit embarrassed
I press my cheek against yours
Time for a hug
(Time for a hug)
Time to hold hands
My heart was only ever looking down
Locked into a straight-neck
Though I was in no way unhappy
The weight of life left me wobbling
But that’s all in the past now
Blown away with the wind
Gadgets to bring smiles
Now fill up my heart
Spilling out, I can’t hold them all
Come to the healing island
A thrill-thrilling island
With fuzz-fuzzy love to sink deep into
This big and complicated puzz-puzzling maze
Throw open the door
(The door)
And unravel it all
With you, on the healing island
A silk-silky island
Even zig-zaggy love is all right with me
There’s no need to grow up
We can all put it off forever
On cheerful
(On cheerful)
Moratorium
An onomatopoeia island
A spark-sparkly island
A fluff-fluffy island
A fuzz-fuzzy island
A silk-silky island
A squish-squishy island
I press my cheek against yours
Time for a hug
(Time for a hug)
Time to hold hands